<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[•  keeping it loc





                                                                                                                     al •

















































                                                             SPECIAL FEATURE




































                                            1                                                                            2









                                 Strengthen your                                                                        Invest in


                                   local economy                                                               your community














                                           3                                                                             4










                                  Reduce climate                                                                        Support


                                 change impacts                                                              community groups











                                       BRANDON’S RECRUITMENT SPECIALISTS





                                                                                                         Join our confidential

                                                                                                  network and be connected

                                                                                                      with great local career
                                                                                                                opportunities!





                                                      Unit A – 940 Princess Ave  |  info@wchrs.com  |  204-727-0008]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[B2     SHOP WESTMAN     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                                         THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  JUNE 24  2021
                           n
          n

















































              BY COLIN SLARK                                     in which you live.”                                efforts to seek out businesses where they can spend money.”
                                                                  This isn’t the case for all businesses, but as a cooperative,   Not only does shopping locally keep money in the area, he
               Manitoba’s COVID-19 vaccination rates are getting to the  Heritage Co-op sends its profits back to its members in the  said, but it also helps contribute to local taxes, which are in
              point where the lifting of health                  form of equity payments. Other than employing approximately  turn used to pay for maintenance and improvements to public
               restrictions are in sight, but it’s still too early to become  500 people in  Westman who will use their wages at other  services.
              complacent about the effects the virus has had on the province.  Westman businesses, Heritage Co-op sends money back out to   Additionally, the money used to employ people locally gives
               Letting our guards down around the virus doesn’t just put  the people it serves.                     them the freedom to volunteer for local sports, activities,
              people’s health at risk, but also the health of locally owned and   However, it’s not just customers that have a part to play in  fundraise, boards and more outside of their workplace.
              operated businesses.                               shopping locally.                                   “All of those things become important in building that sense
               It’s been a rollercoaster for businesses in the 16 months since   “The pandemic has forced the entire world, for lack of a  of community,” Cooper said. “I also think it’s critical that when
              the virus was first detected in Manitoba.          better term, to limit travel,” Laing said.         we talk about shopping local that we don’t let business off the
               A fairly mild first wave of the pandemic saw businesses start   “To really be thankful for what we have in our own local  hook.
              to be able to reopen before the second wave hit hard, causing  communities and the support we have experienced has been   Businesses also have a responsibility to shop where they live
              some businesses to have to close entirely while others had their  outstanding. In return, we as a business have been really grateful  and support other local businesses.”
              operations scaled back.                            for the other local businesses that we can source product from   Cooper believes that in a community the size of Brandon,
               Just as things seemed to be improving earlier this year, the  or contract to do things for us. It’s really put a focus on working  it’s hard for someone not to know some of the people working
              third wave hit even harder than the second, again forcing  together with our neighbours for the betterment of the entire  in local businesses. When you shop locally, you’re frequently
              businesses to close or operate under heavy restrictions.  community.”                                 giving a helping hand to friends and family.
               Surviving these challenges has required businesses to   Laing believes that as the pandemic comes to an end, there   “They in turn support you because of the things they do in
              cultivate the support and hard earned dollars from local  will be almost certainly be lessons learned and new practices  the community,” he said.
              customers and convince them not to spend outside of the  developed by businesses that will carry on while other practices   At the Brandon Sun, publisher Jim Mihaly doesn’t want local
              community.                                         revert to the way things used to be done.          businesses’ plights to be ignored in their time of need.
               At Heritage  Co-op,  newly-appointed general  manager   The importance of shopping locally hasn’t been lost on new   “As the  local paper and  a direct link to businesses in the
              Dennis Laing told the Sun he’s worked for eight different Co- Brandon Chamber of Commerce president Barry Cooper,  Westman region, we can’t stress enough the need for individuals
              ops across Canada and saw the importance of shopping locally  who addressed the topic during the presidential changeover  to shop local whether it bee online or in-person,” he said. “At
              even before the pandemic.                          ceremony in early June where he took over from outgoing  times we take our local businesses for granted thinking they
               “Supporting local is a high part of what makes our business  president Spencer Day.                  will always be there when needed.
              different,” Laing said. “It can be cascaded in so many ways.   “I said last week — and I meant it — that I am incredibly   Well, they need your support throughout the course of a year,
              From a business perspective, supporting local means we invest  humbled and appreciative that people have gone so out of their  now more than ever!”
              our profits back into the communities in which we live, work  way to look for ways that they can support local companies,”
              and play. From a consumer level, supporting local business  Cooper told the Sun in a June 14 interview. “With all of the  » cslark@brandonsun.com
              means that your dollars are helping support the communities  roadblocks put in front of them to buy local, they’re still making  » Twitter: @ColinSlark



                                                                                                                                                         ENTER
                                                                                                                                                      ONLINE OR
                                                                                                                                                 DROP OFF ENTRY
                                                                                                                                                    FORM AT THE
                                                                                                                                                   BRANDON SUN

                                                                                                                                                        OFFICE










                                   SHOP WESTMAN









                                                       Contest








                                              OVER $500 IN PRIZES TO BE WON!




                                                                                                         ND
                                                               DRAW TO BE MADE ON JULY 2 , 2021


                                                                                 Contest Entry Form












                      NAME:  ________________________________________________________________________________________________
                      ADDRESS: _____________________________________________________________________________________________
                      PHONE: _______________________________________________________________________________________________


                      Rules: Simply find the “hidden” letters in the ads throughout this feature. Once you find all 15 letters, unscramble them into the 4 word phrase as shown above. To enter, either visit
                      www.brandonsun.com/surveys and fill out our online entry form or clip out the printed entry form in your paper and drop it off to our Brandon Sun Office located at 501 Rosser
                      Avenue from 10 a.m. to 3 p.m., Monday-Friday. Entry deadline is June 30th at 11:59 PM. Must be 18 years or older to enter. One entry per person. No purchase necessary.

                                          Draw to be made Monday, July 2, 2021. The Brandon Sun will not barter or share any of this information with other organizations.





                                                               Sponsored by:]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  JUNE 24  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                WETSMAN THIS WEEK     SHOP WESTMAN     B3
                                                                                                                                                      n
                                                                                                                                                                        n






             SHOP LOCAL,




             WIN PRIZES








             Two Brandon institutions are once again coming together to

             promote the importance of shopping locally.


             As they did last July and this February, the Brandon Chamber
             of Commerce and  The Brandon Sun are showcasing the
             importance of keeping it local as they navigate the challenges

             that have been presented to them with the COVID-19 pandemic.


             The Shop Local Westman section in the paper will feature all
             that as well as a contest for readers. Savvy perusers of the
             paper will have an opportunity to win a combination of cash

             and gift certificates from participating businesses.
                                                                                                  VISIT US AT OUR NEW LOCATION

             Readers of the Westman Shop Local Guide will find hidden                           UNIT A–1625 1  STREET, BRANDON
                                                                                                                              ST
             letters in ads throughout the section. Once the letters have
             been found, unscramble them to complete a four-word phrase                              • Brakes & Exhaust          • Full Diagnostic Repairs
             (15 letters in total). Entries with the correct phrase can be                           • Full Suspension           • Four Wheel Alignments

             submitted in person via a draw box at The Brandon Sun offices                           • Oil Changes               • Tire & Tire Services
             or online.                                                                              • Manitoba Safeties
                                                                                                            Open: Monday to Friday 8 a.m. - 5 p.m.
             The entry form will be featured in Westman This Week in the                                              (closed for lunch 12-1 p.m.)
             Brandon Sun on June. 24, as well as on our website.                                                  Please remember to support small,

                                                                                                                    local businesses when possible!
             All correct entries will have a chance to win more than $500 in
             prizes. The deadline to enter is June 30, 2021. The winners will
             be contacted on July 2.


             Further details regarding the contest and our online entry form
             can be found at brandonsun.com.                                                                   Locally Owned & Operated.


                                                                                                           We’re Here When You Need Us!


                                                                                                    UNIT A –1625 1  STREET, BRANDON  |  204-727-0020
                                                                                                                      ST





            The Brandon Chamber of Commerce




                                       NOW MORE THAN EVER, #STRONGERTOGETHER.








                                                                                                                            WE
                                   DEVELOP                                                                                  ADVOCATE

                     YOUR BUSINESS                                                                                          FOR YOU


                                            Through                                                                         In support of businness issues to all
                seminars,workshops,webinars,                                                                                levels of government through
                   leadership opportunities, and                                                                            business attractuin and retention
                       professional development                                                                             that stimulates the economy. We
                                          programs.                                                                         make sure your voice is heard.






















                                                                                                                    INCREASE
                                              ACCESS                                                                YOUR VISIBILITY IN

                               MEMBER-ONLY                                                                          THE COMMUNITY

                                          SERVICES                                                                  By just being a member, your business

                             From Affinity Programs and                                                             instantly gains credibility and profile in the
                           member-to-member discount                                                                business community. Build on that through
                               programs and discounted                                                              our marketing, refferals, sponsorship and
                                     Certificates of Origin                                                         committees opportunities.









              Want to learn more about how you business can grow with the Chamber? Contact us! 204 571 5340.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[B4     SHOP WESTMAN     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                                         THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  JUNE 24  2021
          n
                           n













                                                DID YOU KNOW?...

           We are celebrating 140 years in business and we are
               more than just your basic school supply store?
                            Come see us for the “PLUS”










                                                                     GAMES















                  TOYS
















                                                                    PUZZLES










                       Come visit us at 1300 Richmond Ave East
                       or check us out online at christiesop.com
        
                           CLIP & SAVE 10%


                        With only a $25 purchase (before taxes).                                      1139 ROSSER AVENUE • 204-727-8379
                          Please present coupon at checkout!                                                  DELIVERY & CONNECTIONS
                     Some restriction may apply. Expires August 31st, 2021








               ENJOY THE PATIO WITH THESE                                                           CRP Patio Furniture                Corinthian Wind Chimes


                         FINE PRODUCTS FROM                                                          Fountains and Fire                     Henckels Knives

                                                                                                              Tables                            Boyd’s Beef

                                                                                                      Ceramic Pots and                           Gimli Fish


                                                                                                            Planters                   Sauces and Seasonings

                                                                                                        Tropical Plants                    Summer Fashions





























































           1329 Rosser Ave. E., Brandon, MB   |  Call: 204.727.5884    Summer Hours: Starting July 1   10:00am – 5:00pm Monday to Saturday • Closed Sunday
                                                                                                           st
                                                   It’s Time For A Change at the Green Spot Home & Garden]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  JUNE 24  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                WETSMAN THIS WEEK     SHOP WESTMAN     B5
                                                                                                                                                      n
                                                                                                                                                                        n
                                                                                                      SERVING WESTMAN SINCE 1997





                    ACTIVE



            DETERRENCE


                 CAMERA




               STOPS THE CRIME

             BEFORE IT HAPPENS

                                                                                                        FREE
                                                                                                  ESTIMATES!





                            SWITCH YOUR ALARM
              MONITORING TO WESTMAN SECURITY

                FOR NO CHARGE WITH 3 MONTHS OF
                               FREE MONITORING


                  Residential and commercial security systems put

               your mind at ease knowing your family, business, and
                possessions are safe. Operated by live people at our
               ULC listed monitoring station, you never have to worry

               about navigating voice prompts when it matters most!


                   LOCALLY

               OWNED AND
                 OPERATED


               With over 40 years of
              combined experience,

                 we welcome all
                 customers in the
                 Westman area!                                                                              BOOK NOW FOR 2021


                                                                                                                  PLEASE PHONE 204-726-8488
                                                                                                        FOR AN APPOINTMENT TO INQUIRE ABOUT OUR
                                                                  204-717-5599                            SUNROOMS OR OUR FANTASTIC PRODUCTS
                                                          www.westmansecurity.ca

                                                              Locally Owned & Operated          204-726-8488  |  View all our products at www.sunspacesunrooms.com
                                                                                                                  |  155 Prairie Crescent Brandon  |  sales@elitesunrooms.ca
























































                                                    Offering the Latest in Cosmetic Treatments for Men & Women













                                                              • Botox Cosmetic                    • Fractional Laser Skin            • Microdermabrasion

                                                              • Chemical Peels                      Resurfacing                      • Microneedling

                                                              • Cool Sculpting                    • Glo Mineral Makeup               • Photofacials
                                                              • Dermaplaning                      • Juvederm                         • Rosacea & Acne Management

                                                              • Dysport                           • Laser Hair Removal               • Vein Treatments

                                                              • FemiLift                          • Latisse Eyelash Treatment        • Vivier Skin Care




           Call today for your complimentary consultation!!        Unit K–1300 18  Street, Brandon, MB  •  204-727-1920  •  www.laserskinvein.com
                                                                                    th]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[B6     SHOP WESTMAN     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                                         THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  JUNE 24  2021
                           n
          n



























































                                                                                                      Giftware, Home & Cabin Decor





                                                                                              PURSES                                    • Bath Products

                                                                                                 • Matt and Nat                         • Kitchen Ware
                                                                                                 • Derek Alexander                      • Wine Lovers Gifts

                                                                                                 • Milo
                                                                                                                                        • Baby Gifts

                                                                                              JEWELLERY                                 • Kids Toys


                                                                                                                        %               • Water Shoes


                                                                                                        25OFF                              & Much More


                                                                                                       731-18th Street  •  204-725-4664



























             SHOP LOCAL AND INDLUGE












                                         LANDSCAPING AND HOME IDEAS THAT ARE

                                           TRULY BREATHTAKING AND IMAGINATIVE


                     From a large variety of plants, soils, decorative mulches, planters…to all your concrete pavers and wall

                                                    solutions, we have the largest stocking yard in Westman.

                 We have bagged organic soils, fertilizers, pest control, wooden garden boxes for inside and out and so much

                 more with expert advice on any growing or landscape questions you may have for your home and landscape.



             Shop In-Store or Online at www.alternativelandscapingltd.com
                            Curbside Pick-Up or Local Free Delivery
                                             (some restrictions may apply)













                Let our team make your dreams a reality!                                                                                       Richmond Ave.


                         Southeast corner of 34  Street and Patricia Ave.                                                                                34 th  St.  Shoppers   Mall  18 th  St.
                                                                 th
                            SALES 204-727-7289    |    TOLL FREE 1-866-727-7289    |    FAX 204-727-7531
                                     HOURS OF OPERATION:  Monday - Friday 9am-6pm • Saturday 9am-5pm                                           Patricia Ave.
                                                                                                                                                Alternative Landscaping
                                                                                                                                                Alternative Landscaping
                                 www.alternativelandscapingltd.com]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  JUNE 24  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                WETSMAN THIS WEEK     SHOP WESTMAN     B7
                                                                                                                                                      n
                                                                                                                                                                        n


               Stop by our Gas Bars for

               ANY SIZE COFFEE           $1
               OR SLUSHIE FOR


                                                                Heritage



                                                Redeemable at Heritage Co-op
                                                 Gas Bars at Richmond Ave, 6th
                                                Street & 18th Street in Brandon.
                                                 Expires September 30, 2021.
                                                   One coupon per customer                        ONE-STOP SHOP FOR ALL YOUR HEALTH
                                                          PLU# 9519                                             AND WELLNESS NEEDS!

                                                                                                                       Services Include

                                                                                                 • Full Service Pharmacy              • Braces and Supports
          FOOD FUEL HOME AG                                                                      • Free Prescription Delivery         • Lift Chairs
                                                                                                                                      • Mastectomy Supplies and
                                                                                                 • Equipment Sales & Rentals
                                                                                                 • Sports Medicine Products             Custom Mastectomy Bra Fittings
                                                                                                 • Surgical Appliances                • Consumer and Medical
                                                                                                                                        Compression Garments
                                             Proudly serving the                                                       And so much more!
                                             communities of Minnedosa,

                                             Brandon, Wawanesa,                                          SHOP NOW                               Now Available
                                             Erickson, Sandy Lake,                                                  & SAVE                        SILVERT’S
               Heritage                      Strathclair and Rivers                                                                      ADAPTIVE SLEEPWEAR
                                                                                                                                                Men’s & Ladies
                                                                                                                    $200 OFF
                                                                                                                     your purchase       Available in sizes XS to 2XL.
                                                                                                                     of any Power
                                                                                                                      Wheelchair
                                                                                                                       For a limited
                                                                                                                        time only









                                                                                                   Looking for Good Quality Pre-Owned  Mobility Items?
                                                                                                               Visit our new consignment website
                                                                                                      www.homehealthcarepharmacy.com




         DID YOU KNOW                                                                          MARK MERCURE, Pharmacist/Manager                       ALANA BAILEY, Pharmacist
         Heritage Co-op Members Will Share $3.7 Million                                                                                          OPEN MONDAY-FRIDAY 9–6
                                                                                                                                                     & SATURDAYS 9–4
                                      in Cash Back this summer?                                                                                  For Your Shopping Convenience
                                                                                                                                                 3000 Victoria Avenue, Brandon

                                                                                             1-204-727-2483   |   Toll-Free: 1-800-572-1002   |   www.superthrifty.com

























































                                                                              WEST END




                                                      LOCALLY OWNED FRANCHISE




                                           Proudly Supporting Manitoba Farms and Producers like:

                                        Sprucewood Colony, Schreimers Family Farms, Jeffries Bros,

                                                 Bygarski Honey Farm, Canadian Gold Beverages,
                                                              Smak Dab Mustard among many



                                                          SEE OUR MANITOBA BOXES


                                                            SHOP LOCAL - BUY LOCAL




                 3409 VICTORIA AVENUE   |   BRANDON   |   204-727-3443                                                  bdnsobeyswest           bdnsobeyswest]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>