<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Professionals TO Know








                             IN WESTMAN]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[B2     PROFESSIONALS TO KNOW     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                          THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  SEPTEMBER 9  2021
                               n
     n
     BARRISTER AND SOLICITOR





     JODI WYMAN B.A. LL.B



     PATERSONS LLP








     Q: Tell us about your professional background and experience.
     A: I’m a partner of Patersons LLP and I’ve been practicing law in Brandon since 1998. I work
        primarily in family law. I have a certificate in mediation and have done training in collaborative
        family law, advanced mediation and arbitration.

     Q: What inspired you to get into your chosen profession?

     A: I wanted to find a profession that would let me be self-employed and involved helping
        people through difficult times. I also wanted a profession that had a wide variety of options,
        in case I didn’t like the first thing I tried. I was sure I wouldn’t like appearing in court, but in
        fact that’s one of the parts of the job that is the most challenging, in a good way.

     Q: What is your specialty? What makes you unique?

     A: I’ve been practicing family law for 23 years and have appeared in all levels of court. However,
        my work in family law litigation made me realize that court is usually not the best place for
        couples, or for families. That’s why I began mediation training in 2012, and then went on to
        complete advanced mediation and arbitration training. Helping separated couples resolve
        their issues privately, creatively and a little more peacefully is very rewarding work.

     Q: Why/when should customers use your service?

     A: Separated couples often think their only option is to hire lawyers and go to court when they
        can’t sort out agreements about their kids and their assets themselves. However, hiring a
        private mediator or arbitrator lets them control the process. It can be, and is usually, much
        faster and less expensive. It lets them keep their personal and financial business private, and
        most importantly shelters their children from their conflict. They can come up with creative                      1040 Princess Ave Unit 1, Brandon
        solutions that aren’t possible in court. And with respect to children, of course it’s best that
        parents make the decisions about their own kids.
                                                                                                                          204-727-2424
     Q: What about your company makes or has made you the most proud?

     A: Our firm has expanded quite a lot in the last few years, and we’re able to offer clients the full
        array of legal services. We all take professional development seriously and make sure we’re                       jwyman@patersons.ca
        up to date and using best practices. We never lose sight of the fact that our business only
        exists because of our amazing clients, and we try our best to make sure they get the service                      www.patersons.ca
        they deserve.







     ORTHODONTIST





     DR. ROB MINTENKO



     WINBURN ORTHODONTICS









     Q: Tell us about your professional background and experience.
     A:  As an orthodontist I have had many years of post-secondary education to become an expert in my
        field. I started off by completing several years of undergraduate sciences at the University of Regina,
        then completed dental school at the University of Saskatchewan. I then practiced as a general
        dentist for several years before being accepted into a 3 year orthodontic residency at the University
        of British Columbia in Vancouver where I obtained my diploma in Orthodontics and Master of
        Science in Craniofacial Science. I returned to practice as an orthodontic specialist in Regina and
        then recently became the new owner and orthodontist of Winburn Orthodontics in Brandon in
        2020.

     Q: What inspired you to get into your chosen profession?

     A:  I grew up babysitting the children of an orthodontist in Regina and looked up to him as a mentor.
        He only had the best things to say about his profession as an orthodontist and it really had an
        impact on me at a young age.

     Q: What is your specialty? What makes you unique?
     A:  My specialty is in the field of orthodontics – straightening teeth, correcting bites and improving
        facial balance. As a general dentist you are able to complete any dental procedure, including
        orthodontics, however becoming an orthodontic specialist means you have completed three years
        of full time studies in just the field of orthodontics and that you limit your practice to orthodontics
        – when it comes to straightening teeth and fixing bites, you want to see an orthodontic specialist.

     Q: Do you have an upcoming event or milestone you want people to know about?
     A:  One major upcoming event is the official rebranding of our orthodontic clinic later this fall from
        Winburn Orthodontics to Mint Orthodontics. I took over in 2020 from the well renowned Dr. Jay                         1711 Kirkcaldy Dr Suite C6,
        Winburn, who had practiced as an orthodontist in Brandon for 43 years, and now that some time                         Brandon
        has passed I am wanting to update the clinic name and branding to reflect the direction of the clinic
        moving into the future.
                                                                                                                              204-727-0401
     Q: What about your company makes or has made you the most proud?
     A:  There is nothing that makes me prouder than seeing the pure joy and happiness of someone seeing                      info@drwinburn.com
        their new smile for the first time after removing their braces. The process and length of orthodontic
        treatment can be quite extended, so to have such a delayed gratification of seeing one’s new smile
        and bite after the braces are removed is truly unmatched. I feel thankful every day to work in such
        a profession that allows such a dramatic transformation for people to go through.                                     winburnorthodontics.com]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  SEPTEMBER 9  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                   WETSMAN THIS WEEK     PROFESSIONALS TO KNOW     B3
                                                                                                                                                                  n
                                                                                                                                        n
   MYOFUNCTIONAL                                                                      ACCOUNTING
   THERAPIST

                                                                                       MARC PROVENCHER
   JENNY PARTRIDGE                                                                     CPA, CA


    BRIGHTSIDE DENTAL                                                                  ALLIANCE

                                                                                       ACCOUNTING

   Q:  Tell us about your professional
       background and experience.                                                      GROUP, CPA INC.
   A:  I have been a registered dental hygienist
       since 2011, and have been practicing at
       Brightside Dental Care, here in Brandon,
       since 2014. In the last year I became                                           Q:  Tell us about your professional
       specialized in Orofacial Myofunctional                                             background and experience.
       Therapy or just Myofunctional  Therapy for short, which I actively practice at our   A:  I started public practice in 1990 and obtained my CA (Chartered Accountant)
       clinic as well.                                                                    designation in 1993. I bring to the table over 25 years of accounting experience,
   Q:  What inspired you to get into your chosen profession?                              and specialize in personal and business Canadian taxes, as well as resident and
                                                                                          non-resident U.S. taxes. I briefly stepped away from public practice in the mid-
   A:  Growing up I always really enjoyed working with people and I knew I wanted to
       do something within the healthcare system.  A friend suggested dental hygiene,     90s and early 2000s, where I focused on Chief Financial Officer responsibilities
       and it ended up being a really good fit. My real passion, though, lies in the field   and computer and technology servicing. I joined the Alliance Accounting
       of Myofunctional Therapy which I learned about in 2018. I soon realized both       Group, Chartered Professional Accountants Inc. team in January of 2021 as the
       of my children needed this form of treatment and I began taking the necessary      Senior Tax Manager and am excited for this new endeavor.
       courses to become a therapist myself.
                                                                                       Q:  Why should clients use your firm?
   Q:  What is your speciality? What makes your services unique?
                                                                                       A:  Myself, and the entire team at Alliance Accounting Group, Chartered
   A:  My goal as a myofunctional therapist is to restore normal function to the muscles   Professional Accountants Inc., bring extensive knowledge and experience
       of a patients’ face, lips and tongue. The way we use these muscles, along with     to the table. We are dedicated to providing the best possible service for our
       the way they “rest”, are extremely important. In a growing child, dysfunction of   clients. I enjoy solving business and tax-related problems and revel in the
       these muscles will change the way the child’s face and jaw grows, and can create   challenge of keeping up with the everchanging rules.
       symptoms like crooked teeth, poor sleep and behavioural issues. In an adult
       whose muscle dysfunction has gone unrecognized for so long, symptoms show
       up more in the  forms of facial or jaw pain, clenching/grinding teeth, chronic   Q:  What about your firm makes you proud?
       fatigue, snoring or use of a CPAP machine. To my knowledge, there is only one   A:  We pride ourselves at being at the forefront of technology. The firm utilizes a
       other Myofunctional Therapist in Manitoba – a speech pathologist in Winnipeg.      paperless file system, recently introduced a client portal for ease of access, and
                                                                                          operates a progressive project management program that truly sets us apart.
   Q:  When should clients use your service?                                              Technology use allows us to quickly adapt to change and consistently provide
   A:  There are a variety of symptoms a patient can present with. Common ones            timely and efficient service to our clients.
       would include mouth breathing, crooked teeth, poor sleep quality and snoring.
       If someone has these symptoms, there is likely to be some muscle dysfunction
       going on that requires treatment.
   Q:  What about your company makes or has made you the most proud?
   A:  We are the only dental office in Brandon, that I am aware of, offering                                                        E-2425 Victoria Avenue, Brandon
       Myofunctional Therapy.

                                                                                                                                     204-726-1995
                                                 #25 144–6th Street, Brandon
                                                                                                                                     mprovencher@allianceaccounting.ca
                                                 204-727-7136

                                                                                                                                     allianceaccounting.ca
                                                 brightsidedentalcare.com




     REALTOR





     CHRIS LOW



     RE/MAX VALLEYVIEW








     Q: Tell us about your professional background and experience.

     A: Born and raised in  Western Manitoba, I grew up  in the small  farming community of
        Foxwarren. After playing six seasons of professional hockey in the United States I settled
        down in Brandon  and started a family with my wife Tanis. We have two amazing children;
        Tiana and Brady. I spent 15 years with Chemtrade (formerly Canexus) as a power engineer
        before becoming a Licensed  Real Estate Professional. I worked with J&G Homes during my
        first year, selling new builds and condos. For the past five years, I have been with RE/MAX
        Valleyview Realty.

     Q: What inspired you to get into your chosen profession?
     A: I always had an interest in sales, and enjoy cultivating meaningful relationships with people
        both personally and professionally.  Real estate, as a profession, let’s me do that and has also
        allowed me to get back in touch with agricultural roots as well.


     Q: What is your specialty? What makes you unique?
     A: Social media marketing has become a critical means of advertising potential properties. It’s
        no secret that buyers are using online and the digital world as their main resource during
        their house hunting journey. I recognize the importance of utilizing these platforms to
        ensure your property not only reaches maximum exposure, but that it is advertised and                           Residential, Farms & Acerages
        marketed in a way to ensure its value is represented to its fullest.


     Q: Why/when should customers use your service?
     A: Whether you’re buying or selling a property, using a professional Licensed Real Estate
        Salesperson is in your best interest. I will make myself available 24/7 to answer your questions,                  VALLEYVIEW REALTY
        and you can count on my attention to detail, negotiation skills and market knowledge to
        make your experience as smooth and positive as possible. I can help point you in the direction
        of reputable tradespeople for work on your home or inspections, mortgage brokers/lenders                          204-573-5699
        or any other  professional services you may require.

     Q: What about your company makes or had made you proud?                                                              chrislow@remax.net

     A: RE/MAX agents are community leaders who donate both their time and money to countless
        charities and causes locally and nationally, including the millions of dollars contributed to                     westmanrealestate.ca
        Children’s Miracle Network member hospitals each year.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[B4     PROFESSIONALS TO KNOW     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                          THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  SEPTEMBER 9  2021
                               n
     n
   RESIDENTIAL AND                                                                    ACCOUNTING
   COMMERCIAL APPRAISERS

                                                                                       D. SCOTT ANDERSON

   BARRY CUSITAR CRA, P.APP                                                            FCPA, FCGA

   PAT WEIR AACI, P.APP, BI                                                            ALLIANCE

    ROLAND WEIR                                                                        ACCOUNTING

   APPRAISAL ASSOCIATES                                                                GROUP, CPA INC.






   Q: What inspired you to get into your chosen profession?                            Q:  Tell us about your professional

   A: We were in related businesses requiring professional appraisal                      background and experience.
       services and found a need for expanded services in the region,                  A:  I obtained my Certified General Accountant (CGA) designation in 1990 (now
       which was a natural fit for assisting our existing and a wide range                known as CPA) and was awarded my fellowship designation from CGA Canada
       of new clients.                                                                    in 2000.  I have 30 years public practice experience, with additional experience
                                                                                          in controllership, banking and association management positions. My focus
   Q: What is your speciality? What makes your services unique?                           is on solving client problems and helping them achieve financial success in
                                                                                          personal and business settings.  I am a founding and currently managing
   A: We are an independent, professional appraisal practice with our                     partner of Alliance Accounting Group, CPA Inc.
       Associates  certified  and  accredited  in  the  valuation profession
       with a long history of serving the western Manitoba region.                     Q:  Why should clients use your firm?

   Q: When should clients use your service?                                            A:  You will see quite quickly that our firm is client-focused, dedicated to providing
                                                                                          timely and personable service along with innovative solutions to their ever-
   A: Our  firm  and  associates  provide  professional  residential, farm,               changing needs.  We strive to provide an environment for our team that allows
       commercial, recreational and special use real estate appraisals                    them to grow and enjoy what they do.  As a result, the “Alliance Experience”
       to assist clients with their financial, family, future and business                ensures our clients feel well taken care of.
       planning.
                                                                                       Q:  What about your firm makes you proud?
   Q: What about your company makes or has made you the most                           A:  My pride is watching our clients succeed; allowing them to sleep better at
       proud?                                                                             night knowing that they are in good hands; how we treat them with respect.

   A: Our history and involvement in assisting Manitobans with many of                    I am proud of the team that we have created and watching each of them
       life’s most important decisions regarding real estate.                             grow into individual dynamic professionals.  Finally, I am proud of how we
                                                                                          have embraced technology using it to continually enhance our education and
                                                                                          improve on how we service our clients.








                                                                                                                                      E-2425 Victoria Avenue, Brandon


                                                                                                                                      204-726-1995


                                                                                                                                      sanderson@allianceaccounting.ca


            1015 – 26th Street, Brandon   204-727-7100       www.rolandweir.ca                                                        allianceaccounting.ca





     SKIN CLINIC, SALON, SPA





     DIANE FINLEY & MARIKA FRIESEN



     VANISH SKIN CLINIC









     Q: What is your specialty? What makes you unique?
     A: Vanish Skin Clinic & Beauty Bar is your one stop shop from head to toe. No other clinic in
        Brandon has a full-service salon and spa, as well as our Skin Clinic that offers everything
        from Botox, Juvederm, Laser services, facials and medical grade skin care.


     Q: Why should customers use you service?
     A: At Vanish, client satisfaction is our top priority. Our goal is to enhance the health, wellness
        and natural beauty of every client by delivering result driven care through state-of-the-art
        equipment and highly trained staff.


     Q: How have you grown your business?
     A: Vanish brought on Cathy  Woodmass in 2020, who successfully owned and operated
        Simple Solutions. Cathy has been injecting for over 25 years and with that she has gained
        immeasurable knowledge in the Medical Cosmetics field.


     Q: What about your company makes you the most proud?
     A: We hold our client relationships in the highest regard and our staff works hard to ensure that
        their loyalty to Vanish is unbreakable.

     Q: What is your favorite service?

     A: The Forever Young BBL, also known as a Photofacial. This treatment reverses the skin’s
        aging process by delivering intense pulsed light energy deep into skin’s layers. This targets
        damaged skin cells while leaving the healthy cells untouched as well as triggers the body’s
        natural collagen production, resulting in plump, glowing skin. Look younger in 10 years than
        you do today!






                                                                        131 18th Street, Brandon                        info@vanishskinclinic.com




                                                                        204-922-0862                                    vanishskinclinic.com]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  SEPTEMBER 9  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                   WETSMAN THIS WEEK     PROFESSIONALS TO KNOW     B5
                                                                                                                                        n
                                                                                                                                                                  n
   REALTOR                                                                            ACCOUNTING

   JILLIAN AUSTIN

   CENTURY 21 WESTMAN REALTY LTD.                                                      CAREY KNIGHT
                                                                                       B.A., CPA, CMA

   Q:  Tell us about your professional background.
   A:  As a former reporter, I spent a decade in the journalism                        ALLIANCE
      field — many of those years as a trusted member of the Brandon
      Sun. I got to know the community well, making connections with                   ACCOUNTING
      people in all walks of life. A few years ago, I decided to change
      career paths and pursue my dream of becoming a real estate                       GROUP, CPA INC.
      agent. I am a proud member of the Century 21 Westman Realty
      team,  and now serve the  community  in a  different capacity;
      facilitating and providing guidance to people as they make one
      of the biggest and most exciting decisions of their lives.
   Q:  What do you enjoy most about your career?
   A:  Helping people reach their real estate goals  —  whether it’s                   Q:  Tell us about your professional
      upgrading to a larger home to accommodate a growing family,                         background and experience.
      downsizing to a condo or a mobile home, or finding that perfect   2915 Victoria Avenue,
      starter home. I enjoy getting to know my clients and helping   Brandon           A:  I graduated from Assiniboine Community College’s Business Administration
      them find their dream home. It is such a joy to hand over the keys                  program and went on to complete my Business Administration degree at
      on possession day.
                                                            204-720-8724                  Brandon University. I received my Certified Management Accountant (CMA)
   Q:  Why should people choose you as their realtor?                                     designation  in  2000,  and my  Chartered Professional  Accountant  (CPA)
   A:  The process of buying and selling is complex, and I take pride in
      being there for my clients every step of the way. Between initial   jillian.austin@century21.ca  designation as a result of the amalgamation of the accounting professionals
      showings, negotiating an offer, satisfying conditions and finally,                  in Canada. I am one of three partners at Alliance Accounting Group, Chartered
      possession day, there is a lot involved in a real estate transaction.               Professional Accountants Inc. with more than 20 years of tax and accounting
      With my extensive training, market knowledge and experience,   www.jillianaustin.ca  experience for business and agriculture.
      my clients are in good hands.
                                                                                       Q:  Why should clients use your firm?

   GENERAL MANAGER                                                                     A:  We have a team of experienced professionals that manage the accounting,
                                                                                          tax, and strategy needs for businesses, so clients spend less time on the things
                                                                                          they don’t like and more time focusing on their passion.
   CAROLYNN CANCADE

   BRANDON CHAMBER OF COMMERCE                                                         Q:  What about your firm makes you proud?
                                                                                       A:  Our firm is committed to and successful at creating close connections with
                                                                                          our clients. We provide a multitude of services, so clients turn to us for all of
   Q:  Tell us about your professional background and experience.
   A:  I have been the General Manager at the Brandon Chamber of                          their accounting and tax needs. We are committed to finding solutions that
      Commerce since 2015, but I have held other positions within the                     are innovative, efficient, tax conscious, and understandable. No one leaves
      organization prior to my current role. As General Manager, I hold                   a meeting without a full understanding of the work being done and the
      a key leadership position within the organization to advocate
      on behalf Chamber of Commerce members.                                              expected outcome.
   Q:  Do you have an upcoming event or milestone you want people
      to know about?
   A:  We are happy to have been a part of the development of the
      Brandon Economic Restart Program (BERP) launched by The City
      of Brandon. This program was designed to stimulate investment
      in operational areas that will position eligible Brandon
      businesses to rebound and thrive as the economy begins to
      reopen. Businesses who qualify can receive up to $2500 to offset                                                               E-2425 Victoria Avenue, Brandon
      the costs of growing out of the Covid-19 pandemic. Visit http://  1043 Rosser Avenue,
      economicdevelopmentbrandon.com/berp to learn more.    Brandon
                                                                                                                                     204-726-1995
      Every October we celebrate Small Business  Week. During   204-571-5340
      this week, we celebrate our local businesses anniversaries,
      achievements and successes. This year will be no different as                                                                  cknight@allianceaccounting.ca
      we will be provided free workshops, a keynote speaker event   info@brandonchamber.ca
      and video content to help promote and celebrate our business
      community.                                                                                                                     allianceaccounting.ca
                                                            brandonchamber.ca




   REAL ESTATE & CORPORATE LEGAL SERVICES




   ANDREA EPP                                                                          ALEX KLIPPENSTEIN


    EPP LAW OFFICE                                                                     EPP LAW OFFICE






   Q: Tell us about your                                                               Q: Tell us about your
       professional background and                                                        professional background and
       experience.                                                                        experience.

   A: I have been practicing law in the                                                A: I was born and raised in Brandon
       Westman area since I received my                                                   MB but went to law school in
       Call to the Bar in 2009. Originally                                                Kamloops BC. While in law school
       my practice consisted mainly of                                                    I had the opportunity to assist in
       litigation but over the past few                                                   developing a mental health court
       years I have transferred to a solicitor’s practice which consists of               for the city. Over the summer of 2018 I had the opportunity to
       real estate conveyancing, corporate law, and estate planning.                      work on an ongoing class action lawsuit against the Province of
                                                                                          Manitoba. During my articling year I was exposed to a wide range
   Q: What inspired you to get into your chosen profession?
                                                                                          of law including real estate, wills and estates, family, civil litigation,
   A: When I worked in my previous career in banking, I was surprised at                  and corporate work.
       how easily I could interpret contracts and explain them to clients.
       Because of that, many of my clients and coworkers told me that I                Q: What inspired you to get into your chosen profession?
       should try law and it sort of stuck.
                                                                                       A: I had always imagined I would go into Architecture. After my first
   Q: What is your specialty? What makes you unique?                                      year of university, I switched from a physics to a philosophy major.
   A: My practice is mainly in residential real estate and corporate law.                 Asking questions about justice and ethics inspired me to go into
       These are both very exciting but stressful times for my clients and                law and look at how these academic topics affect real people.
       I enjoy taking the time to explain every aspect of the transaction
       or venture to my clients so that they can make informed decisions               Q: What about your company makes or has made you proud?
       and move forward with confidence.                                               A: Our firm is very personal and always works as a team. I believe our

   Q: What about your company makes or has made you proud?                                firm does a great job of making clients feel comfortable and at
                                                                                          home rather than like they have just stepped into a lawyer’s office.
   A: I am very proud of the team I work with at Epp Law Office. Everyone
       works hard and works together to get the job done for our clients.
       We have a very positive work atmosphere and enjoy each other’s
       company.






                                                                ANDREA EPP                                            ALEX KLIPPENSTEIN


                                                        204-717-3775           andrea@epplawoffice.ca                 204-717-3775            alex@epplawoffice.ca


                                                                Unit A - 642 18th Street, Brandon                                 www.epplawoffice.ca]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[B6     PROFESSIONALS TO KNOW     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                          THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  SEPTEMBER 9  2021
                               n
     n
     PROGRAM & DEVELOPMENT DIRECTORS





     TARA & AARON MURRAY



     ADULT & TEEN CHALLENGE OF


     CENTRAL CANADA INC.








     Q: What inspired you to get into your chosen profession?

     A:  Aaron struggled with an alcohol addiction and ended up going to Adult and Teen Challenge in
        Winnipeg, MB. Tara was addicted to painkillers which led to her to Adult and Teen Challenge in
        Pensacola, FL. Aaron and Tara both graduated the program and met at a leadership training school
        in Jesup, GA in 2014. They got married in 2016 and now have 2 daughters. Adult and Teen Challenge
        has helped change both of our lives. We look forward to serving the community of Brandon and the
        surrounding area to help people find freedom from their addictions.


     Q: What is the history of your organization?
     A:  Adult and Teen Challenge was founded in 1958 by David Wilkerson in New York City. There are now
        over 1,400 affiliate centers in over 129 nations around the globe.

     Q: What do you offer the community?

     A:  We have weekly groups for men and women struggling with life-controlling addictions. We offer
        support groups to the families of those in addiction. We also have long term programs. We have a
        Women’s Centre located 15 minutes northwest of Brandon and a Men’s Centre in Winnipeg.

     Q: How can the community support you?

     A:  Adult and Teen Challenge Super Thrift- donate, shop or volunteer. All of the funds raised from Super
        Thrift goes towards helping fund our programs. Vehicle Donation Program- you can donate your
        vehicle and receive a tax receipt for a minimum of $500. Monthly Sponsorship- for $30 a month you                      127 7th Street, Brandon
        can become a sponsor and receive a new students story every month.

     Q: Do you have an upcoming event or milestone you want people to know about?                                              204-730-7273

     A:  We have multiple fundraising events throughout the year. We have a snowmobiling event, a golf
        tournament and an ATV ride. We would like to invite you to our fundraising banquet on Friday,                          aaron@teenchallenge.tc
        November 12th, 6:30pm at the Clarion Hotel and Suites. Please call 204-730-7273 to sponsor a table
        or reserve your tickets.                                                                                               tara@teenchalkenge.tc

     Q: What about your organization makes you the most proud?                                                                 www.teenchallenge.tc

     A:  Seeing people’s lives changed. Watching a mom reunite with her children. Watching a daughter’s
        relationship with her parents restored. It’s amazing to see life-transformation right before your eyes.






     MEDICAL DOCTOR






     DR. BARB KELLEHER BSC, MD, DABVLM, FCSP


     THE SKIN & VEIN CENTRE







     Q: What is your background and professional experience in your chosen field?

     A: I was born and raised in Brandon and graduated from Brandon University with a degree in
        Science. I went on to earn my MD from the University of Saskatchewan and moved backed to
        Brandon in 1991 to practice as a General Practitioner at Western Medical Clinic. In 2006  I decided
        to branch out on my own to diversify my practice into aesthetics and further my interest in
        Phlebology (veins).

     Q: What inspired you to get into your chosen profession?
     A: I was interested in aesthetics because it helps people feel good about themselves. I also realized
        that with proper training in phlebology, I could help a lot of people avoid surgery and realize
        improvement in their varicose veins. Both aspects of my practice have inspired me to continue
        with life-long learning so I can provide the best treatments possible.

     Q: What is your specialty? What makes you unique?

     A: Medical aesthetics and varicose vein treatments are my specialty. In medical aesthetics I am the
        most experienced injector in Western Manitoba and that experience ensures happy patients. In
        phlebology, I am the only practitioner outside of Winnipeg who treats veins with injections - not
        surgery, and I am the most experienced phlebologist in Manitoba.  It should be noted that for
        treatment of large varicose veins, a referral from your family physician or nurse practitioner is
        required.

     Q: Why/when should customers use your service?
     A: If you don’t like your frown lines or you are starting to look tired, sad and saggy, you need to
        see me.  If you have excess fat in unwanted areas, see  us about CoolSculpting. If you have sun                   1300-18th Street, Unit K, Brandon
        damage or facial redness, excessive hair you are sick of shaving or waxing, skin laxity, unwanted
        tattoos, scarring, acne, uneven skin tone, or anything that has been bothering you, come see us!

     Q: Do you have an upcoming event or milestone you want people to know about?                                         204-727-1920

     A: As a matter of fact, this year marks 15 years since I opened, what was then called, Kelleher
        Cosmetic and Vein Treatment Clinic.
                                                                                                                          www.laserskinvein.com
     Q: What about your company makes or has made you the most proud?

     A: My staff is fantastic and great with our patients. I have earned the respect of my physician
        and nurse colleagues, but most importantly, I love what I do and plant to continue providing
        the best skin and vein care available in Westman.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  SEPTEMBER 9  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                   WETSMAN THIS WEEK     PROFESSIONALS TO KNOW     B7
                                                                                                                                                                  n
                                                                                                                                        n































































































































           Don’t miss out on this opportunity to give your business the
           exposure it deserves. Let Brandon and the Westman Community

           know your company’s history, changes or new growth. Showcase
           your employees, product lines, customer services or perhaps a new

                                          location or renovation.


           Advertisers purchasing a full page or more will be given editorial coverage which
                          provides greater focus on their business. Call for details.







             Distribution Date: Thursday, October 28 , 2021
                                                                                     th


                Booking Deadline: Friday, October 8 , 2021
                                                                                  th








               CONTACT THE BRANDON SUN AT ADVERTISING@BRANDONSUN.COM
               TO BOOK YOUR AD OR CALL YOUR SALES REPRESENTATIVE DIRECTLY:



                      KAREN LOW,  204.571.7419 | KLOW@BRANDONSUN.COM

             LISA MERCKX-DEUTSCHER, 204.571.7420 | LMERCKX@BRANDONSUN.COM

                  SUZANNE MIHALY, 204.571.7416 | SMIHALY@BRANDONSUN.COM]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[THE ROTARY CLUB OF BRANDON
              HEALTHY BOOK SALE






























                                                                                   Thursday, September 9, 2021


                                                                                                9:00am - 8:00pm



                                                                                     Friday, September 10, 2021


                                                                                                9:00am - 6:00pm




                                                                                  Saturday, September 11, 2021


                                                                                                9:00am - 2:00pm












                   Romanance, Fiction, Non-Fiction, Historical Romance, Pocket Books,

                     Oversize Pocket Books, Hard Cover Novels, Science Fiction (Sci-Fi),

                                                         Anime, War, Military, Crime



                                              Children’s Books - Bye age & categories


                  Books by Category - Cookbooks, Gardening, Health, Hobbies, Sports,

                       Music, Religion, Inspiration, Chicken Soup ...16 Total Categories







                    Over 75,000 books… something for everyone







































































                                                                                                         The Rotary Club of Brandon 1344





                                                                                                                                                     Leech Printing 300385]]></page></pages></Search>