<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="140"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Cover_Layout 1  18-07-23  11:25 AM  Page 1]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[3708547_RolandWeir_Layout 1  18-07-10  11:15 AM  Page 1






                                                 FAST & ACCURATE




                                                 FARM, RESIDENTIAL

                                                 & COMMERCIAL


                                                 PROPERTY APPRAISERS



                                                 Buying? Selling? Refinancing? Litigation?
                                                 Let our certified appraisers provide you
                                                 with a written appraisal at a great rate.





























































                                                                                  Serving Western Manitoba Since 1977
                                                                                                    th
                                                                                  Suite 30A, 1015 – 26 Street, Brandon
                                                                                  P: 204-727-7100, F: 204-727-1563
                            APPRAISAL ASSOCIATES                                  E: weir1@mts.net]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[EditorsNote_Layout 1  18-07-19  6:09 PM  Page 1






                                                  Editor’s Note




                                                   After my initial discussion with Tamarack Men’s Club president Jordan Trotter
                                                  about an 85th Anniversary Tamarack special publication, my ﬁrst thoughts were
                                                  that this project would be a lot of fun to work on. We talked about content ideas,
                                                  publication style, ﬁnancial implications, distribution and workload. It still seemed
                                                  like a great deal of fun.
                                                   Then reality ascended upon me like a down hiller to a front right pin on twelve.
                                                  How can you possibly encapsulate 85 years of memories - only the Tamarack can
                                                  produce - into limited space? After a deep breath and a sip of chardonnay I thought;
                                                  just eat this elephant one bite at a time.
                                                   So we arranged a freelance writer/researcher/layout person and I could just
                                                  submit ideas and watch it unfold. Wrong! Young love took my freelancer away and
              Glen Parker                         we needed Plan B. This plan worked. Christine Torrance would head up page design,

                                                  layout, creative services, along with technical guidance. David Bachewich would
                                                  help me with research and provide creative services – photo enhancements,
                                                  cleaning up old printed stories etc. And then we wanted someone with good
                                                  knowledge of golf, the Clear Lake Golf Course, the Tamarack, the players and their
                                                  families. When we signed up Bruce Penton, we covered all those bases. A former
                                                  sports editor of The Brandon Sun, currently living in Medicine Hat, Penton provided
                                                  the strong writing this project deserved.
                                                   So why this project you ask? As a somewhat frequent Tamaracker I get what all
                                                  the fuss is about. I’m as far away from Tamarack Royalty (North, Patrick, McDiarmid
                                                  et al) as you can get, but I know there is something special about the week that is
                                                  very hard to explain. Watching friends and family; three-putting with friends and
                                                  family watching; celebrating; commiserating; and congregating, it’s all part of the
                                                  Tamarack deal. With participants ranging in age from kindergarten to care-home,
                                                  to say this is about family would be a gross understatement.
                                                   The Tamarack also provides something for the average hack not many other
                                                  events do. While fun and family are front and centre, it’s a competition, and with it
                                                  there’s some formality. There’s the expectation the rules of golf will be adhered to
                                                  for one. The  ﬁrst-tee introductions are also an example of something not all
                                                  amateurs get to experience. This is quite often accompanied by the anxiety of hitting
                                                  your opening tee shot in front of a large gallery.  Many of the tee shots executed are
                                                  evidence of said anxiety. My brief foray into championship ﬂight made me realize
                                                  you’d better learn to play with a gallery or you’d be in for the longest short match
                                                  of your life. I guess what I’m saying is while it’s great fun, the organization and
                                                  formality lend a professional feel to the event. And research has revealed that this
                                                  tradition has been there since the beginning.
                                                   We were able to ﬁnd mention of the tournament in our archives as far back as
                                                  1935 when it was known as the Clear Lake Golf Tournament. As catchy and original
                                                  as that name was, it was renamed Tamarack in 1972 and a dashing young player
                                                  named Jack Matheson won his second of three titles. We have stacks of papers
                                                  back to 1934 and sought input from the public, to help compile the Tamarack story.
                                                  With name changes, date changes and a quirky archive network, ﬁnding all the
                                                  information we would have liked, proved quite a challenge.
                                                   We sincerely hope you enjoy seeing many of the names and images of the past,
                                                  present and future Tamaracks in this publication.  This was fun!




                                                                              Glen Parker
                                                                              Tamarack ’85 Editor




                                                                                                                          3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Masthead_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:56 AM  Page 1



















                                                                    Publisher  Jim Mihaly
                                                                    Tamarack 85 Editor Glen Parker
                                                                    Writer Bruce Penton
                                                                    Photographers As noted and Brandon Sun ﬁles
                                                                    Graphic Design Christine Torrance,
                                                                    David Bachewich, Nadine Krahn
                                                                    Research Glen Parker, David Bachewich
                                                                    Sales & Marketing Director Glen Parker
                                                                    Distribution Lori Timms




                                                                     501 RosserAve., Brandon, MB
             On the cover:
             Photo by Tim Smith                                      Tamarack 85 is a production of The Brandon Sun.
                                                                     Made in Manitoba.
             Cover design by Glen Parker                             Printed by Leech Printing.
             and Christine Torrance]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[3708659_DrKelleher_Layout 1  18-07-19  4:59 PM  Page 1







                                     85 years? You don’t look it!


                                    Congratulations Tamarack!










                “Talk to the Doctor to Get the Look You Want”


                The desire to “get the look you want” has more men and women
                seeking quick and safe in-office procedures to help maintain or
                reverse the effects of time, sun and living. Dr. Kelleher’s Laser,
                Skin and Vein Clinic provides effective non-surgical cosmetic
                treatments for both men and women. Patients are assured of
                receiving high quality, professional treatments performed by Dr.
                Barb Kelleher, BSc, MD and her qualified staff.

































                Emmy, Technician – Lori, Office Manager/Technician – Laurie, RN – Dalelene, Technician – Heather, LPN – Britta, Reception  Dr. Barbara Kelleher, BSc, MD

                Call today to book your free confidential consultation


                CoolSculpting              Restylane                  Chemical Peels             Latisse Eyelash Treatment
                FemiLift                   Botox Cosmetic             Photofacials               Glo Mineral Makeup
                Fractional Laser Skin      Juvederm                   Body Contouring            Skin TX & Vivier Skincare
                 Resurfacing               SilkPeel                   Skin Tightening             & Anti-aging Skincare
                Sculptra                   JetPeel                    Acne & Rosacea             Vein Treatments
                Dysport                    Laser Hair Removal          Management                Dermapen



                150–1300–18 Street  | Brandon, MB  | 204-727-1920  | www.laserskinvein.com
                              th]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Article_JackMcDiarmid_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:23 PM  Page 1









                                                                      Four times







                                                                      a champion,



                                                                      every time




                                                                      a gentleman






                                                                      By Bruce Penton





                                                                           he McDiarmid story, in Tamarack lore, goes back to
                                                                           the very beginning. The first year of the annual
                                                                      TClear Lake Golf Course championship, now known
                                                                      as the Tamarack, was 1934, in the middle of the Great
                                                                      Depression. One of the original competitors that year
                                                                      was Dr. W.O. (Bud) McDiarmid of Brandon. Dr. Bud never
                                                                      did claim the men’s title, but he was a perennial contender
                                                                      in the championship flight and had a couple of medallist
                                                                      victories to his credit.
                                                                       His daughter, Marg McDiarmid, later became Marg
                                                                      Patrick and dominated the women’s championship,
                                                                      winning seven titles between 1966 and 1988.
                                                                       And Jack — the son of Bud and brother of Marg — has a
                                                                      name that’s synonymous with the annual August golf
                                                                      tournament at Wasagaming. The 64-year-old Calgarian
                                                                      has won the men’s title four times and has won a couple
                                                                      of medallist titles, too.
                                                                       “I remember in 2001 or 2002, Kirk Penton, then with
                                                                      the Brandon Sun, approached me after the qualifying was
                                                                      over and told me he’d done some research and found that
                                                                      I had the record for most consecutive years in the
                                                                      championship flight,” said McDiarmid.
                                                                       “But that was it. I missed the championship in the next
                                                                      two or three years. Just like Nick Faldo on TV says ‘this
                                                                      guy is 20-for-20 on putts under five feet” and then of
                                                                      course he promptly misses the next one.”
                                                                       Other than legendary pro Johnnie Lawrence or perhaps
                                                                      Jack Matheson, it’s likely no one knows the Clear Lake
                                                                      golf course better than Jack McDiarmid. “Dad and
                                  Jack McDiarmid competing in the     Johnnie got me going when I was six or seven,” said Jack.
                                  2012 Tamarack golf tournament.      “My mom would drop me off at the course at 8 in the
                                                                      morning and pick me up at dark. We’d play 36 or 54 holes,

            6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Article_JackMcDiarmid_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:23 PM  Page 2







                                                                      “When I was six or seven… my mom
                                                                      would drop me off at the course at 8

                                                                      in the morning and pick me up at dark.
                                                                      We’d play 36 or 54 holes.”







                                                                      and chip and putt, or make up some long holes — like from
                                                                      the fifth tee to the eighth green, for instance — when
                                                                      things were quiet. Then I worked for Johnnie all through
                                                                      my university days.”
                                                                       In 1974, when McDiarmid was 20, he won the Grey
                                                                      Owl, the other major tournament at Clear Lake, “but the
                                                                      Tamarack was always a demon for me,” he said.
                                                                       He played in his first men’s Tamarack at the age of 16
                                                                      and, not surprisingly given his knowledge of the course,
                                                                      qualified in the championship flight. “My first match was
                                                                      against Barry MacKenzie of Winnipeg, one of the biggest
                                                                      names in golf in Manitoba, an amateur champ and a
                                                                      Willingdon Cupper.”
                                                                       MacKenzie beat him that year, and Jack remembers an
                                                                      early sequence of matches the following year, when he
                                                                      was 17 and qualified in the third flight. “I played Bill
                                                                      Davidson of Brandon in the first round (and won) and
                                                                      then I had to play my dad.”
                                                                       Those father-vs. son, mother vs. daughter, brother vs.
                                                                      brother matches are not an unusual occurrence at a
                Jack McDiarmid circa 1988 (above) and in 1979 (below).
                                                                      family event like the Tamarack, but Jack recalls the
                                                                      anxiety in taking on his father. “He beat me,” said Jack,
                                                                      without a hint of regret in his voice.
                                                                       McDiarmid reclaimed a spot in the championship flight
                                                                      four years ago at the age of 60, an accomplishment of
                                                                      which he was proud. Realistically, though, he had little
                                                                      chance of championship success, he said. “I remember
                                                                      Grant Coulter and I were in the same foursome playing a
                                                                      couple of young guys in their mid-20s and on the fifth
                                                                      hole, I busted a drive and was about 200 yards out. Grant
                                                                      had about 195 left. Great drives. But the young guys we
                                                                      were playing had about 150 or 160 left. It’s a different
                                                                      game.”
                                                                       During his prime, a 68 or 69 — four or three under par
                                                                      — would be the pinnacle for the
                                                                       Tamarack’s best amateurs, said McDiarmid. “Now they
                                                                      (big-hitting young players) shoot 65 or 66 as a matter of
                                                                      course.”
                                                                       With his competitive fires still burning, McDiarmid said
                                                                      he has acquiesced and will play in the Champion Men’s
                                                                      division this year for the first time. At age 64, he has
                                                                      nothing to be ashamed of. He’ll find himself up against
                                                                      players he battled 20 and 30 years ago. The competition
                                                                      will be keen and the stories will be old, perhaps, but the
                                                                      laughs and the good times will be as genuine as ever.
                                                                                                                          7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[3708129B_SourceForSports_Layout 1  18-07-17  9:23 AM  Page 1












                                             Congratulations







                                                                       Tamarack





                                                         on 85 Years of Amazing Memories!




                                                          All the best as you celebrate this milestone.

                                                           We wish you many more years of success.





                Brandon Source for Sports is proud to be celebrating

                   30 Years in Business and 30 years of supporting


                                     local golf in Westman!






                                                See us first f or all your golf

                                              and other sporting good needs



























                                                 2025 Brandon Avenue
                                                 204-727-0756

                                                 brandonsourceforsports.com     brandonsourceforsports          brandonsource]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Article_JackMatheson_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:21 PM  Page 1





              The institution:


              Jack Matheson






              By Bruce Penton


                      ne of the most familiar faces around the Clear Lake Golf Course
                      is that of Jack Matheson, a Brandonite who had a stellar hockey
              Ocareer with the Wheat Kings before taking up a school teaching
              profession in Winnipeg.
                These days, you’ll see Matty’s smiling face around the pro shop, where
              he helps to make sure things run smoothly in the world of booking tee
              times, paying green fees, organizing cart rentals, and clothing sales.
                “Great story about Jack Matheson,” harrumphs Bill Johnston of
              Winnipeg, a judge. “He won two consecutive Tamaracks — 14 years apart.”
                That hardly makes sense, of course, but Johnston adds the explanation.
              Matheson won in 1972 (beating George Sigurdson, Jr. of Winnipeg for his
              second title in three years) and then ran a summer hockey school in
              Winnipeg in August to augment his teaching income for the next decade-
              plus. The hockey school dates conﬂicted with the Tamarack, so it was 14       Jack Matheson circa 1968
              years later, 1986, before Matheson was again able to enter the                (above) and 1987 (below).
              tournament. He won that year, too.
                Matheson remembers beating Sigurdson, Jr., in the 1972 championship
              ﬁnal, and remembers an incident on the ﬁrst playoff hole that decided the
              match, but talked about it only when pressed by a reporter.
                Matheson’s drive on that ﬁrst extra hole came to rest on the upslope of
              the ﬁrst green, while Sigurdson hit a drive a little left and then wedged onto
              the green, about 20 feet away.
                The eventual winner settled over his ball to try to chip it close, but
              suddenly backed off, stood up and announced to Sigurdson and the gallery:
              “My ball moved. I’m hitting three.”
                No one but Matheson had seen the slight movement of the ball, but golf
              being a game played by honourable people who are expected to call
              penalties on themselves — it was the only thing to do.
                “It’s tough to live with yourself if that happens and you don’t call it,” said
              Matheson, who chipped close enough for a “gimme” par 4. Sigurdson,
              meanwhile, three-putted for ﬁve, and Matheson was crowned that year’s
              champion.
                Matheson chuckles while recalling a story from the 1950s involving Roy
              Bell, who owned the Mooswa cabins and whose brother Bill owned the
              Idylwylde resort at Clear Lake. Roy was not generally a strong
              championship-calibre golfer, but he got hot on qualifying day one year and
              tied for the low score with Winnipeg’s Harry Critchly, who had ﬁnished a
              few hours earlier and was back at his cabin enjoying a few adult beverages.
                “Harry had been told he was home free (about being the medallist),” said
              Matheson. “Suddenly, Roy tied him and somebody had to go the cabin and
              get Critchly to come back for the playoff.”
                Critchly, according to Matheson, was “in no shape to play golf” and, in
              fact, “had to have some help in teeing up the ball.”
                “He was madder than hell that he had to take part in this playoff,” recalls
              Matheson.
                Not surprisingly, Bell emerged the playoff winner and took the medallist
              honours.
            9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_34-59_Layout 1  18-07-19  7:05 PM  Page 1































































































           10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_34-59_Layout 1  18-07-19  7:05 PM  Page 2































































































                                                                                                                          11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_34-59_Layout 1  18-07-19  7:05 PM  Page 3































































































           12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_34-59_Layout 1  18-07-19  7:06 PM  Page 4]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_34-59_Layout 1  18-07-19  7:06 PM  Page 5































































































           14]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_34-59_Layout 1  18-07-19  7:06 PM  Page 6]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_60-69_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:34 PM  Page 1































































































           16]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_60-69_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:34 PM  Page 2]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_60-69_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:34 PM  Page 3































































































           18]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_60-69_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:34 PM  Page 4































































































                                                                                                                          19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_60-69_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:34 PM  Page 5]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_60-69_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:34 PM  Page 6































































































                                                                                                                          #]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_60-69_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:34 PM  Page 7































































































           22]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_60-69_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:34 PM  Page 8































































































                                                                                                                          23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_60-69_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:34 PM  Page 9































































































           24]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_60-69_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:34 PM  Page 10































































































                                                                                                                          25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_60-69_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:34 PM  Page 11































































































           26]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Chip Shots_Layout 1  18-07-19  6:01 PM  Page 1





               ChipShots






                                                       What does a 161 get you? In 1974 a
                                                       36-hole score of 161 had you in the
                                                       Men’s Championship ﬂight yet in 2014
                                                       you would be playing in the fourth or
                                                       ﬁfth ﬂight.


                                                         “I'm just trying to grasp the whole
                                                         thing right now. Coming into the
                                                         tournament, maybe some people
                                                         expected me to make the
                                                         championship ﬂight and maybe win
                                                         a match or two. But I never thought
                                                         I'd be in the ﬁnals.” – Dave Scinocca,
                                                         Men's ﬁnalist



              Shot of the Day – Brandon’s Jim Nay
              smacked his tee shot on the par-3 6th
              hole into the basket of Bob Jenkins cart
              parked near the 7th tee box.

               There have been 18 multi-championship
               winners in the Men’s Division. Only 5 have
               more than 2 titles. These 18 have won 49
               of the 84 played.*


                                                       Barry McKenzie is the only man able to
                 “I’ve caddied to a lot of celebrities  string three consecutive wins together.
                 you know like Clint Eastwood and      Winning in ‘65, ‘66, & ’67. He added a 4th
                 Douglas Bader, who was a great        title in 1971.
                 Battle of Britain pilot who lost his
                 legs,” said Haxton, who quit
                 caddying three years ago. “Probably
                 Clint Eastwood was my favourite.
                 To be in his company was something
                 very special. Plus, he paid very well.”
                 Haxton makes it sound like fun, but
                 how would you like to be the guy                                               26 of the 84 Women’s
                 that gives Dirty Harry the wrong                                               winner’s names started
                 club?                                                                          with the letter “M”.  But
                                                                                                none since 1988 when the
                                                                                                Queen of the Tamarack,
                                                                                                Marg Patrick won her
                                                                                                record 7th.



                                                       The longest match we came across while
                                                       combing thousands of stories was 26 holes. It
                                                       took eight extras for Ken Newman to top Rod
                                                       Zenk in a 2002 3rd ﬂight tilt.

                                                                                                                          27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_70-79_Layout 1  18-07-20  1:39 PM  Page 1































































































           28]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_70-79_Layout 1  18-07-20  1:39 PM  Page 2































































































                                                                                                                          29]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_70-79_Layout 1  18-07-20  1:39 PM  Page 3































































































            #]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_70-79_Layout 1  18-07-20  1:39 PM  Page 4































































































                                                                                                                          31]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_70-79_Layout 1  18-07-20  1:39 PM  Page 5































































































           32]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_70-79_Layout 1  18-07-20  1:39 PM  Page 6































































































                                                                                                                          33]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_70-79_Layout 1  18-07-20  1:39 PM  Page 7































































































           34]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_70-79_Layout 1  18-07-20  1:40 PM  Page 8































































































                                                                                                                          35]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_70-79_Layout 1  18-07-20  1:40 PM  Page 9































































































           36]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_70-79_Layout 1  18-07-20  1:40 PM  Page 10































































































                                                                                                                          37]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[MensWinnersList_Layout 1  18-07-19  6:25 PM  Page 1






                                                               Tamarack






                                                 Men’s Winners






                                                 1934 – 2017



                                                                                        2017 – Kody Fawcett
                                                                                        2016 – Steven Young
                                                                                        2015 – Kody Fawcett
                                                                                        2014 – Jay Thiesen
                                                                                        2013 – Jarod Crane
                                                                                        2012 – Dave Unger
                                                                                        2011 – Jared Jacobson
                                                                                        2010 – Jared Jacobson
                                                                                        2009 – Walter Debets
                                                                                        2008 – Stephen Pointon
                                                                                        2007 – Matt Burman
                                                                                        2006 – Jared Jacobson
                                                                                       2005 – Brad Clement
                                                                                       2004 – Scott Davidson
                                                                                       2003 – Bruce North
              Bruce
              North                                                                    2002 – Rod Klassen
                                         Barry                                         2001 – Jared Jacobson
                                         McKenzie
                                                                                       2000 – Dave Haxton
                                                                                       1999 – Dave Scinocca
                                                                                       1998 – Bob Cornell
                                                                                       1997 – Ken Stadnek
                                                                                       1996 – Dave Scinocca
                                                                                       1995 – Brad Clement
                                                                                       1994 – Mike Jones
                                                                                       1993 – Bruce North
                                                                                       1992 – Grant Coulter
                                                                                       1991 – Jamie Stone
                                                                                       1990 – Bruce North
                                                                                       1989 – Bryan Letain
                                                                                       1988 – Grant Coulter
                                Roy
                                Kepron                                                 1987 – Jack McDiarmid
                                                                                       1986 – Jack Matheson
                                                                                       1985 – Bruce North
                                                                                       1984 – Phil Hall

           38]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[MensWinnersList_Layout 1  18-07-19  6:25 PM  Page 2





































                                                                                                  Jack
                   Jack                                                                           Matheson
                   McDiarmid




                  1983 – Jack McDiarmid               1958 – Don St. John
                  1982 – Dwight Kearns                1957 – Dick Howard
                  1981 – Jack McDiarmid               1956 – Ted Homenuik
                  1980 – Bruce North                  1955 – Harry Critchley
                  1979 – Jack McDiarmid               1954 – Harry Critchley
                  1978 – Bruce North                  1953 – Roy Kepron
                  1977 – Jim King                     1952 – Don Gardner
                  1976 – Don Murdoch                  1951 – Don Gardner
                  1975 – Bruce North                  1950 – Roy Kepron
                  1974 – Alex Sinclair                1949 – Roy Kepron
                  1973 – George Sigurdson             1948 – R.D. Garrett
                  1972 – Jack Matheson                1947 – H. Eidsvig
                  1971 – Barry McKenzie               1946 – O.C. Steele               Jared
                  1970 – Jack Matheson                1945 – D.D. Garrett              Jacobson
                  1969 – Bob Cornell                  1944 – Allan Boes
                  1968 – Ted Homenuik                 1943 – George Cotton
                  1967 – Barry McKenzie               1942 – Jack Porter
                  1966 – Barry McKenzie               1941 – Bob Osborne
                  1965 – Barry McKenzie               1940 – Eddie Wiseman
                  1964 – Gerry Clark                  1939 – Foster Wooley
                  1963 – Noel Dalzeil                 1938 – Robert Osborne
                  1962 – Bill Bell                    1937 – Foster Wooley
                  1961 – Stan Homenuik               1936 – A.W. Kay
                  1960 – Dick Howard                 1935 – Reg Unicume
                  1959 – Jerry Jerrett               1934 – J.E. Adamson


                                                                                                                          39]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 1































































































           40]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 2































































































                                                                                                                          41]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 3































































































           42]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-23  2:05 PM  Page 4































































































                                                                                                                          43]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 5































































































           44]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 6































































































                                                                                                                          45]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 7































































































           46]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 8]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 9































































































           48]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 10































































































                                                                                                                          49]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 11































































































           50]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[3708128_SuperThrifty_Layout 1  18-07-18  2:32 PM  Page 1]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 12































































































                                                                                                                          52]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 13































































































           53]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 14































































































                                                                                                                          54]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 15































































































           55]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_80-89_Layout 1  18-07-20  2:41 PM  Page 16































































































                                                                                                                          56]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Chip Shots_Layout 1  18-07-23  1:50 PM  Page 2
























                                                                                              Shawn Cook made Tamarack
                                                                                              history, recording two holes-
                                                                                              in-one in the 2002 event -
                                                                                              one at the 17th in medal play
                                                                                              and one on 16 in his match.
                                                                  Bruce North’s 7 Men’s
                                                                  Division titles is indeed
              When the “Men’s Night” scramble occurs
              anything can happen. Usually the scramble features  impressive. Most
                                                                  impressive is they were
              roughly a ﬁftysome – accompanied by beer cart –
              playing a 9-hole scramble one evening. Standard golf  won over 4 decades.  ‘75
                                                                  ’78  ’80 ’85 ’90 ‘95 ‘03
              decorum does not apply. Loud jeers, heckling and
              spilled beers are the norm. One particular night a
              couple years ago, Dr. Brent Young was a little tardy
              getting to the tee and was subject to the most raucous
              reception that continued as he hit his tee shot on the
              short par-4 8 th . Despite the distractions he put a
              good swing on it and rushed to his cart without
              watching the shot and muttered “that’s a good one”.
              He never had to watch. It ended in the hole for his ﬁrst  Bob Cornell won his ﬁrst title
              career ace. And being the gentleman he is and     in 1969 and 29 years later
              tradition being what it is, the good doctor was the  (1998) won his second.
              supplier of drinks for his entire ﬁftysome.                                       Much has been made by
                                                                                                followers of the Tamarack
                                                                                                about Bruce North’s
                                                                                                length off the tee.
                                                                                                He put that on display
                                                                                                again in his quarter-ﬁnal
                                                                                                victory over Mike Jones.
                                                                                                North’s tee shot from the
                                                                                                back of the tee on the 433
                                                                                                yard 7th left him with less
                                                                                                than 80 yards to the
                                                                                                centre – a mere 350 plus
                                                                                                yards.




                                                                 ChipShots








                                                                                                                          57]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[LaidesWinnersList_Layout 1  18-07-19  6:16 PM  Page 1










                                                                           Tamarack







                                                                               Ladies






                                                                          Winners








                                                                                 1934 – 2017




                 Pam
                 Burneski





                                                   2017 – Bobbi Uhl                        1996 – Shelley Muir
                                                   2016 – Kaitlin Troop                    1995 – Shelley Muir
                                                   2015 – Kaitlin Troop                    1994 – Shelley Muir
                                                   2014 – Julie Card                       1993 – Gerri Cooke
                                                   2013 – Kaitlin Troop                    1992 – Shelley Muir
                                                   2012 – Sarah Stebeleski                 1991 – Shelley Muir
                                                   2011 – Pam Burneski                     1990 – Traci Poole
                                                   2010 – Pam Burneski                     1989 – Traci Poole
                                                   2009 – Pam Burneski                     1988 – Marg Patrick
                                                   2008 – Kaitlin Troop                    1987 – Marg Patrick
                                                   2007 – Kaitlin Troop                    1986 – Polly Ann Weday
                                                   2006 – Pam Burneski                     1985 – Marg Patrick
                                                   2005 – Pam Burneski                     1984 – Marg Patrick
                                                   2004 – Raegan Wilkie                    1983 – Marian Essele
                                                   2003 – Kaitlin Troop                    Cownsville
                                                   2002 – Rhonda Beatty                    1982 – Mabel Mitchell
                                                   2001 – Kathy Spalding                  1981 – Mona Pump
                                   Muriel          2000 – Shelley Dee Bridgett            1980 – Muriel Clark
                                   Clark
                                                   1999 – Shelley Dee Bridgett            1979 – Mona Pump
                                                   1998 – Donna Brownridge                1978 – Muriel Clark
                                                   1997 – Betty Couling                   1977 – Muriel Clark



           58]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[LaidesWinnersList_Layout 1  18-07-19  6:16 PM  Page 2








                    1976 – Muriel Clark
                    1975 – Marg Patrick
                    1974 – Donna Lawrence
                    1973 – Sue Thompson
                    1972 – Marg Homenik
                    1971 – Muriel Clark
                    1970 – Sue Thompson
                    1969 – Marian Lawrence
                    1968 – Betty Hall
                    1967 – Marg Patrick
                    1966 – Marg Patrick                               Shelley
                    1965 – Marian Lawrence                            Muir
                   1964 – Marian Lawrence
                   1963 – Merlene Wach
                   1962 – Mrs. Ted Homenuik
                   1961 – Merlene Wach
                   1960 – Mrs. T. Homenuik
                   1959 – Lynne MacDonald
                   1958 – Joann Percy
                   1957 – Ann Tachan
                   1956 – Merlene Wach
                   1955 – Carolyn Cameron
                   1954 – Merlene Wach
                   1953 – Merlene Wach
                   1952 – Ruth Thorvaldson
                   1951 – L.P. Mason
                   1950 – Mrs. E.M. Hodson        Marian Lawrence (left)
                                                  & Heather Lawrence (middle)
                   1949 – Mrs. H. Bowman                                                 Marg
                   1948 – L.P. Mason                                                     Patrick
                   1947 – J.L. Peterson
                   1946 – J.L. Peterson
                   1945 – A.R. Hurst
                   1944 – H. Bowman
                   1943 – L.P. Mason
                   1942 – L.P. Mason
                   1941 – Mrs. B. Polenz
                   1940 – L.P. Mason
                   1939 – Mrs. W.L. Taylor
                   1938 – Mrs. H. Bowman
                   1937 – Mrs. H.P. Pellenz
                   1936 – Mrs. Mary McDonald
                   1935 – Mrs. Chas. McLachlin
                   1934 – Mrs. J. Russell Smith

                                                                Kaitlin                                                   59
                                                                Troop]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[Article_MargPatrick_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:35 PM  Page 1




                          Queen







                                         of the
                       Tamarack











               By Bruce Penton

                       arg Patrick works occasionally in a dental ofﬁce in Calgary, where
                       extractions are commonplace, but trying to extract any words
              Mresembling braggadocio from her about her golf career is like trying to
              beat her at match play at Clear Lake during her prime — very difﬁcult.    Marg Patrick at the Tamarack circa 1988.
                Patrick — Margaret McDiarmid of Brandon growing up — is a seven-time
              winner of the women’s championship at Clear Lake but she’s quick to add a dose
              of self-deprecation: ”I’ve lost a lot of ﬁnals.”
                Those lost ﬁnals and seven titles means one thing: Patrick won a lot of matches
              — a lot! — and made it to a lot of ﬁnals from 1966, when she captured her ﬁrst
              championship, to 1995, when she played in the tournament for the ﬁnal time.
                “I was a basket case before every match,” said the affable Patrick over the phone
              in June from her cabin at Wasagaming, where she spends every May through
              September. “A little of that (nervousness) is good, because it makes you
              concentrate.”
                Patrick, whose titles came in 1966, ’67, ’75, 84, ’86, ’87 and ’88, said her
              matches were rarely easy because her opponents would bear down against a
              player with such a strong reputation. “They’re all gunning for you,” she said. “They
              bring their ‘A’ game.”
                Growing up in Brandon as one of the ‘golﬁng McDiarmids’ meant Marg’s sport
              of choice was almost guaranteed to be golf. She started taking lessons from
              Johnnie Lawrence at Clear Lake when she was eight and remembers that
              Lawrence wouldn’t let her hit a ball until he was satisﬁed that she had her swing
              down pat. “He was a wonderful teacher,” she said.
                Marg’s golﬁng friends called her “Pipeline Patrick” during her early days at
              Calgary’s Willow Park, due to her accuracy off the tee. She won her ﬁrst Clear
              Lake women’s crown at age 25 in 1966, when she was already the mother of two
              sons, Brad and Chris, born in 1964 and 1965. A third son, Tom, arrived in 1967.
              Marg celebrated by winning her second Tamarack title that year. “Mom and Dad
              were babysitters,” she said. “My mom (Anne) was the best,” she said. “She and my
              dad were very supportive. She was so good at being a mom and a grandmother.”
                Anne passed away in 1991 while her father, Dr. Bud McDiarmid, died in 1999.
                The Tamarack holds a special place in her memory bank because of all the
              friends and family who gathered annually once a week. “I just loved it,” she said.
                One of those ‘basket case’ moments referenced earlier came in a match against
              Brandon’s Grace Lindenberg. “I was four down after nine,” recalled Patrick. “My
              dad got me a hot chocolate on the 10th tee and said ‘You’ve got her right where
              you want her … you just have to win one hole.”                            “I’m so grateful that my
                No. 10 went into the Patrick folder, and she was three down. Patrick thinks  parents introduced me
              losing a hole puts a little stress on a golfer, and it has the chance to mushroom,
              and it certainly did that day. Before long, Patrick had evened the match, and  to golf. It’s been a huge
              eventually won.                                                           part of my life.”
           60]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[Article_MargPatrick_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:35 PM  Page 2





                “I do like match play,” she said. “Johnnie Lawrence’s daughters were always
              strong players. I remember beating Donna Lawrence one year and losing to
              Marion (Lawrence) one year.”
                She likes to avoid bad weather, though: “I’m a fair-weather golfer,” she said. “I
              remember in 1991, when Mom was sick with cancer, I played the ﬁnal against
              Gerri Cooke and it rained the whole match. I was miserable. And I lost.”
                She played one more Tamarack, 1995, primarily to help ﬁll out the ﬁeld, and
              wound up as medallist. “But I think that was it,” she said.  “I don’t think I played
              again.”
                One of the reasons she doesn’t play in the Tamarack anymore is because she’s
              not thrilled about playing bright and early in the morning, or when the
              weather’s cold. “If you enter the tournament, you take whatever time they give
              you. If it’s 7 a.m., come hell or high water, you gotta go. I just didn't want to do
              that anymore.”
                Patrick, now 77, still plays a pretty good game, carrying a handicap of about
              18, and shooting in the 80s and 90s two or three times a week. She’s grateful
              that Jack Matheson and her brother Jack McDiarmid “both know my swing”
              and can offer corrective advice when things go a little sour. “I was never very
              long, but I was a pretty good putter, like my mom.”
                In the past couple of years she has accompanied her son Chris on golf
              excursions to South Africa, where they played courses designed by Nicklaus,
              Els and Player, and to Malaysia/Borneo, where they played spectacular courses
              in extreme heat and humidity. Next winter’s planned trip is to New Zealand,
              but Patrick isn’t sure she’ll go. “I might just spend some time in Arizona instead,”
              she said.
                Wherever she goes, whatever she does, golf is usually not too far away from  1983 (Left to right): Marion Lawrence, Helen
              Marg Patrick’s world. “I’m so grateful that my parents introduced me to golf.  Hickling, Marg Patrick and Lynne Little.
              It’s been a huge part of my life.”                                       (Submitted)]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:37 PM  Page 1































































































           62]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:37 PM  Page 2































































































                                                                                                                          63]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:37 PM  Page 3































































































           64]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:37 PM  Page 4































































































                                                                                                                          65]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:38 PM  Page 5































































































           66]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:38 PM  Page 6































































































                                                                                                                          67]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:38 PM  Page 7































































































           68]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:38 PM  Page 8































































































                                                                                                                          69]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:38 PM  Page 9































































































           70]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:38 PM  Page 10































































































                                                                                                                          71]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:38 PM  Page 11































































































           72]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:38 PM  Page 12































































































                                                                                                                          73]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:38 PM  Page 13































































































           74]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:38 PM  Page 14































































































                                                                                                                          75]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_90-99_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:38 PM  Page 15































































































           76]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[3708693_ClearLakeGolfCourse_Layout 1  18-07-20  4:55 PM  Page 1






                          Proud host


                of the Tamarack

                        for the past


                              85 years










































































                                                                                 1 Johnnie Lawrence Drive, Wasagaming, MB
                                                                                204-848-4653  |  www.clearlakegolfcourse.com]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[Article_PhilHall_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:50 PM  Page 1














              Never count out











              By Bruce Penton



                    crucial business decision in 1974 resulted in Phil Hall abandoning
                    an idea of becoming a golf course operator and instead becoming,
              Aessentially, a trailer park boy.
                It turned out to be a great decision for his golf game, because running a
              golf course might have required hours and hours of sitting on mowers
              cutting grass, applying fertilizer, dealing with suppliers and the public and
              myriad other aspects of such a business.
                Not that buying the Brentwood Village Mobile Home Park didn’t mean
              long hours of work, but it gave Hall the flexibility to work on his golf game
              and the results are in the record book to be examined: A stellar amateur
              career and for many years a regular contender in the championship flight
              at the Tamarack.
                “Myself and a business partner came very close to buying Sunnyside Golf
              Course from Cam Williamson,” said Hall. “We were only a few thousand
              dollars apart on a couple of things, but one thing led to another, and the
              deal fell apart. The next year, we bought Brentwood, and that turned out
              to be a wise decision.”
                In an era of young bombers winning the men’s title at the Tamarack —
              long-hitters like Bruce North of Carman, Dwight Kearns and Grant
              Coulter of Brandon and Jack McDiarmid of Calgary —  the 43-year-old
              Hall surprised more than a few people in 1984 by taking the
              championship. It was a popular victory, for Hall not only struck a blow for
              the older set, but he was one of Western Manitoba’s most well-liked
              shotsmiths.
                Hall and the Tamarack go back a long way. In 1968, Hall was a travelling
              salesman whose territory took him to the Clear Lake golf course. “I was
              talking to Johnnie Lawrence one day in August and he said, ‘you know,
              we’ve got this match play tournament starting tomorrow and we’ve got
              one spot left.’”
                Hall took that one spot and it was the beginning of a beautiful lifelong
              relationship.
                He posted three appearances in the championship flight final, but
              managed only that one victory, over the late Mike Jones, The Brandon Sun
              sports editor, in 1984.
                Thirty-four years later, details are a little hazy, but “I think I closed him
              out on the 14th hole,” said Hall. “I was cheering for Mike all day to hit it
              close,” said Hall, “because I was confident that I could get inside him.”
                His first loss in the final came in 1971 against Winnipegger Barry
              McKenzie. One of seven titles by Carman’s Bruce North came in a final
              victory over Hall, too.
           78]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[Article_PhilHall_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:50 PM  Page 2





                           Phill Hall concentrating
                           on putting at the
                           Tamarack in 1984 (left)
                           and in 2012 (below).

                                                       Fabulous Phil


















                                                         “That loss to North went extra holes,” said Hall. “We tied the ﬁrst (extra)
                                                       hole, and then we went over to eight. I hit my drive a little left and had a
                                                       restricted backswing. I couldn’t make a par and Bruce did.”
                                                         Some of Hall’s favourite Tamarack memories involve other people, which
                                                       is not surprising since “Fabulous Phil” was never one to seek out the
                                                       personal spotlight.
                                                         One of his favourites involves his son, Rob, also a perennial contender for
                                                       the men’s championship. Rob, who now runs Brentwood Village, was playing
                                                       fellow Brandonite Rick Gudz in a championship ﬂight match, and eagled the
                                                       par-4 16th hole to go one up. “On the 17th tee, Rick’s caddie said ‘We’ll get
                                                       it back here’ and then Robbie stepped up and put his tee shot into the hole,”
                                                       said Phil. “Two eagles in a row to win the match.”
                                                         After Rob’s ball disappeared into the 17th hole cup, “Rick’s caddie said
                                                       ‘Maybe not.’ “
                                                         It was almost inevitable that the two Halls would meet face to face one
                                                       year and when it did (Phil couldn’t remember the year), youth won out.
                                                       “Yeah, Rob beat me,” said Phil, with a tone of pride.
                                                         Oddities? Hall’s seen a few. Like the time Gerry MacKay of Brandon was
                                                       in mid-downswing, a split second away from making contact with his ball
                                                       when a squirrel zipped in front of MacKay’s ball and became a dead squirrel
                                                       in a fatal blink of an eye.
                                                         Hall chuckles when talking about the 1984 calcutta, held prior to the
                                                       matches, when he went on the auction block and was ‘sold’ for a mere $70.
                                                       “Al Hunt got me in the calcutta and I’m sure he was joking later, but he said
                                                       ‘I didn’t want to buy you … I was just scratching my head’ and they said ‘sold!”
                                                       I won him a few dollars, though,” said Hall.
                                                         Laughs, a relaxed atmosphere and a chance to renew acquaintances with
                                                       friends and family are what makes the Tamarack week so special, said Hall.
                                                       “It’s been good times,” he said. “It’s a family event that’s so memorable. For
                                                       instance, we have good friends Dave and Betty Ann Mulholland of
                                                       Tilsonburg, Ont., share a cabin with us every year.”
                                                         Hall will be back in action at the Tamarack this year, competing on his
                                                       favourite course as he goes for more silverware. At 77, he’s not as long off
                                                       the tee as he used to be, and says he often depends on his hybrids for
                                                       second shots into par-4s. But he can still get it done, as evidenced by not
                                                       only shooting his age last year, but beating it by four shots in shooting 73
                                                       at Shilo. He almost did it again this spring in Shilo, but he bogied his ﬁnal
                                                       four holes to shoot 78.
                                                         It’s been the same story forever when it comes to golf and Phil Hall: It’s
                                                       never wise to count him out.
                                                                                                                          79]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[JuniorsWinnersList_Layout 1  18-07-19  6:17 PM  Page 1






                                                              Tamarack





                                                      Senior Men’s




                                                               Winners





                                                                     1982 – 2017



                                                   1982 John Hazelgrove                   2000 Phil Hall
                                                   1983 Barry Sanders                     2001 Clay Wyborn
                                                   1984 Marty Malcovish                   2002 Harvey Ebner
                                                   1985 John Lawrence                     2003 Harvey Ebner
           Bill                                    1986 Marty Malcovish                   2004 Harvey Ebner
           Crossman
                                                   1987 Cec Durnin                        2005 Harvey Ebner
                                                   1988 John Lawrence                     2006 Clay Wyborn
                                                   1989 Gerry McKay                       2007 Dan LeBarron
                                                   1990 Gerry McKay                       2008 Keith Fawcett
                                                   1991 Dick Garrett                      2009 Clay Wyborn
                                                   1992 Gerry McKay                       2010 Keith Fawcett

                                                   1993 John Kelly                        2011 Jay Myhre
                                                   1994 Reg Lang                          2012 Paul Solon
                                                   1995 Gerry Mckay                       2013 Mark Starodub
                                                   1996 Alex Peters                       2014 Cliff Lenz

         Clay                                      1997 Gerry McKay                       2015 Cliff Lenz
         Wyborn                                   1998 Reg Lang                           2016 Larrie Kidd
                                                  1999 Clay Wyborn                        2017 Bill Crossman



                                                          Champion





                                               Men’s Winners





                                                                   2014 – 2017

                                     Grant
                                     McPhail       2014 Ken Stadnek                       2016 Darren Graves
                                                   2015 Darren Graves                     2017 Grant McPhail


           80]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[JuniorsWinnersList_Layout 1  18-07-19  6:14 PM  Page 2





                                                               Tamarack





                                                         Junior Men’s




                                                                  Winners





                                                                        1956 – 2017



                                                    1956 – William Percy                   1987 – Jeff Howatt
                                                    1957 – Peter Herrndorf                 1988 – Chris Worley
                                                    1958 – Gill Dutteen                    1989 – Jody Chudley
              Jody                                  1959 – Peter Herrndorf                 1990 – Dean Oakden
              Chudley
                                                    1960 – Kit Leitch                      1991 – Shawn Cook
                                                    1961 – David Kruck                     1992 – David Scinocca
              Stephen                               1962 – Cliff Corman
              Pointon                                                                      1993 – David Scinocca
                                                    1963 – Brian Johnston                  1994 – Chris Isaac
                                                    1964 – Larry LaFleur                   1995 – Robert Elves
                                                    1965 – Lasey LowesJr.                  1996 – Jared Jacobsen
                                                    1966 – Johnny Erickson                 1997 – Jamie Scott
                                                    1967 – Johnny Erickson                 1998 – Jared Jacobsen
                                                    1968 – Tim Dinsdale                    1999 – Chanse Robertson
                                                    1969– Gordon Stewart                   2000 – Kevin McLeod
                                                    1970 – Kelvin Snell                    2001 – Garry Hargreaves
                                                   1971 – Rob Erickson                     2002 – Brad Palmer
                                                   1972 – Doug Murray                      2003 – Kyle Troschuk
                                                   1973 – Bruce North                      2004 – Stephen Pointon
                                                   1974 – Marlow Kirton                    2005 – Geoff Lang

                                                   1975 – Chris Craddock                   2006 – Brock Helgeson
                                                   1976 – Chris Craddock                   2007 – Aaron Stevens
                                                   1977 – John Nordien                     2008 – Josh Wytinck
                                                   1978 – Michael Allen                    2009 – Josh Wytinck
                                                   1979 – Mark Baynton                     2010 – Regan Headley
                                                   1980 – Kerry Janke                      2011 – Steven Young
                                                   1981 – Alan Scott                       2012 – Steven Young
                                                   1982 – Duncan Ridley                    2013 – Steven Young
                                                   1983 – Dean Goodbrandson                2014 – Colton Willms
                                                   1984 – Ian Lorimer                      2015 – Kolby Day
                                                   1985 – Tom Relf                         2016 – Braxton Kuntz

                                                   1986 – Paul Rudy
               Colton                                                                     2017 – Riese Gaber
               Willms
                                                                                                                          81]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[Article_TroopsBiebers_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:56 PM  Page 1































          Jayne Troop                                                      Jody Bieber


                       TheTroops  Biebers

                                                                   &






              Triumphs, Glory & Tears; Steaks, Burgers & Beers




              By Bruce Penton



                    or the Troops of Brandon and the Biebers of Winnipeg  And between the golf and the planned tournament
                    — a family which grew from the marriage of Doug and  activities, there will be social events galore in and around
              FMyrna Graham of Brandon — the Tamarack is all          the Bieber cabin. “When we were growing up, we had a
              about family.                                           whole social circle of friends who would be at the lake —
                Golf is the raison d’etre, of course, but the once-a-year  McPhails, the Dunns, the Murrays and a few others,” said
              family-and-friends gatherings are what make the third week  Troop.
              of August such a special one for the family that has had its  Jayne said the visiting and socializing are among her
              share of triumphs, glory and tears.                     favourite Tamarack week memories, but she has plenty of
                And plenty of steaks, burgers and beer, too.          golf stories, too
                “We’ll plan supper for 10 and by the time everyone gets  The Cubs, for 7-12-year-olds, is where most family
              there, it’s 10 squared,” said Jayne Troop, whose daughter  members got their start. Parents accompany the
              Kaitlyn, now 30, has won the women’s title six times.   youngsters around the course and Jayne said there were
                Jayne is the younger of Doug and Myrna Graham’s two   plenty of humorous moments during the Cubs era as
              daughters; the other being Jody Bieber of Winnipeg, who  parents tried to accurately count their young golfers’
              along with her husband Guy, a native Brandonite, have   strokes — “whether it was a 10 or a 15,” she said. “So many
              produced a couple of talented female golfers, too — Stacey,  happy memories over the years,” she said. “They might cry
              a former pro, and Reghan.                               over their score but then they’d all get a prize, so they’d
                Jody and Guy own a large cabin behind the Grahams’, and  be happy and couldn’t wait for the next year.”
              that’s usually get-together headquarters for the two     As their children grew up and became championship
              families. “Now we’re getting grandchildren added to the mix,  contenders, Jayne recalls some tense matches.
              so it’s a bit of a zoo sometimes,” said Jayne.           “(Cousins) Kaitlyn played Stacey in a championship flight
                “We’ll have a houseful again this year,” Troop continued.  match five or six years ago and it was really hard to watch.
              “The bedrooms will all be packed. In fact, Guy is borrowing  Stacey was kicking Kait’s butt all the way around, but she
              somebody’s trailer to put in the yard to handle any overﬂow.”  scratched back and tied it on the 18th. They went to an
           82]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[Article_TroopsBiebers_Layout 1  18-07-20  3:34 PM  Page 2





                                                                      ladies tournament – a 139,” she said. “I almost hit (the
              “It’s a great tournament.                               late) Don Campbell with  a drive, and he was standing
                                                                      almost behind me. Bless his heart. He was so nice about
              There’s a ﬂight for                                     it. He promised to buy me a beer after the round.”
                                                                       Jayne said she kept a tight smile on her face the whole
              everyone.”                                              round, but “bawled all the way home” once she got into
                                                                      her car.
                                                                       “I was working at the hospital then, and I was hoping to
                                                                      just skulk into work the next day, but an elderly patient
                                                                      saw me and said ‘tough round, eh?’ He’d seen it in the
              extra hole and Stacey’s drive went into the trees on the  paper.
              right and stayed up in one of the fir trees.”            “But it’s a great tournament,” she said. “There’s a flight
                Another memorable match featured mother (Jayne) vs.   for everyone.”
              daughter (Kaitlyn), at a time when Kaitlyn was an        While Mryna gave up playing in the Tamarack a few
              overwhelming favourite and Jayne said she landed in the  years ago when she was in her early 80s, her children and
              championship flight by more good luck than good         grandchildren carry on the tournament torch. Jayne and
              management. “I (jokingly) told Kait she had to go to    her husband Doug will both play, as will Kaitlyn, now a
              Southgate the night before the match,” the idea being that  physiotherapist in Calgary. Jayne and Doug’s son Adam
              a more talented but possibly hungover golfer might be   has become an avid golfer lately, but can’t get time off
              vulnerable against a less-talented mother who went to   work from his pharmacy job in Brandon to play.
              bed early the night before. “People were laying bets that  Jody and Guy Bieber will both play. Neither of their
              it would be over in nine holes,” said Jayne. “I spent the day  daughters, young mothers Stacy Sledge and Reghan
              before bargaining with her, telling her I’d buy her this or  Langston, will be playing, but Jayne’s nephews Brock
              that if she went easy on me.”                           Bieber and Brendan Graham are expected to play.
                Kaitlyn won the match on the 14th hole, but Jayne said  It’s a golf tournament, sure, but it’s a week for laughs
              there was a lot of hype and a lot of pressure.”         with family members and old friends and to renew
                Pressure also enveloped Jayne in one of her first years  acquaintances with some new ones, said Jayne. “It’s a
              playing in the Tamarack. “I had the highest score in the  lifelong event. We just love the Tamarack.”]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:41 AM  Page 1
































































































          84]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:41 AM  Page 2
































































































                                                                                                                           85]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:41 AM  Page 3
































































































          86]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:41 AM  Page 4
































































































                                                                                                                           87]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:41 AM  Page 5
































































































          88]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:41 AM  Page 6
































































































                                                                                                                           89]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:41 AM  Page 7
































































































          90]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:41 AM  Page 8
































































































                                                                                                                           91]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 9
































































































          92]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 10
































































































                                                                                                                           93]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 11]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 12

































































































                                                                                                                           #]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 13
































































































          96]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 14
































































































                                                                                                                           97]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 15
































































































          98]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 16]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 17
































































































        100]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 18
































































































                                                                                                                           101]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 19
































































































        102]]></page><page Index="103"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2000-09_Layout 1  18-07-23  10:42 AM  Page 20
































































































                                                                                                                           103]]></page><page Index="104"><![CDATA[Article_DaveHaxton_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:18 PM  Page 1










































              A
                 Great









                                     Scot                             Dave Haxton makes an approach shot from the rough on the

                                                                      second hole at the Tamarack in 2004.



                                                                      team, was introduced to Bill and, with a lot of free time
              By Bruce Penton                                         thanks to his job as a mailman, Haxton and Moody, Jr.,
                                                                      became regular golf buddies. “We played a lot of golf
                     olf fans around the ﬁrst tee of the Clear Lake Golf  around Fife,” he said.
                     Course during Tamarack week in 2000 might have    Bill, Jr.’s parents, Bill, Sr. and Linda, visited their son in
              Gthought a Brier had broken out when the bagpipe-       Scotland in 1999, met the Haxtons, and invited the Scot
              playing Ian Dickson and his son Scott celebrated Dave   and his wife to Clear Lake the following August. The
              Haxton’s championship with the ultimate Scottish tribute.  Tamarack was part of the deal, of course.
                Haxton, a Scot and playing in the Tamarack during his ﬁrst  And what a debut! First trip to Canada; ﬁrst Tamarack;
              visit to North America, said being piped to the ﬁrst tee  ﬁrst place!
              from the pro shop for the trophy presentation “was very  Haxton, who uses an unorthodox baseball grip, eventually
              special, with everyone clapping. It gave me goosebumps  played in four Tamarack tournaments, and he says in an
              and made me very proud. Yeah, that was a very proud     email interview from his home that “the competition was
              moment,” he said.                                       nothing like I had ever played in before. It was so organized
                Haxton, whose connection to Clear Lake came through   and everyone was so nice and friendly.”
              Brandonite Bill Moody via his son, Bill, Jr., came close to  “To be in another country and feel like you’re at home is
              winning back-to-back titles, but lost the 2001  ﬁnal to  something really special,” said Haxton. “Had it not been for
              Brandon’s Jared Jacobson.                               Bill Moody, Sr., on my bag with his knowledge on the
                The Haxton-Moody connection began in Kirkcaldy,       greens, I don't think I would have done so well. “
              Scotland, where Moody, Jr., was playing hockey with the   There is a stark difference between the Clear Lake
              local team. Haxton, friends with some of the players on the  course and the Scottish links Haxton was accustomed to,
          104]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[Article_DaveHaxton_Layout 1  18-07-20  3:21 PM  Page 2







                                                                       Another intercontinental friendship developed was
                                                                      between Haxton and Brandon’s Brent Little. The Scot
                  “To be in another country                           recalls playing a great sand wedge shot in one of his
                                                                      matches from the “cabbage patch” left of the 17th green —
                  and feel like you’re at home                        one that Haxton regards as one of his “most memorable”
                  is something really special.”                       Clear Lake shots. Later, Little presented him with a bag of
                                                                      the cabbage as a gag gift. “He's another great friend and a
                                                                      great guy,” said Haxton.
                                                                       Haxton also has a fond memory of the late Tom Betz,
              he said. Scottish links are much tougher with all the bumps  head pro at the Clear Lake course during Haxton’s ﬁrst
              and hollows and “we also have the weather to contend    Tamarack. “He gave me VIP treatment and treated me like
              with,” said Haxton. “You have to learn very early in your golf  royalty,” said Haxton. “He will be sadly missed. God bless
              career in Scotland to keep the ball low in the wind.”   him. That was a great shock to both my wife and I to hear
                As for Clear Lake at Riding Mountain National Park, “it is  of his (2016) passing.”
              manicured to a very high standard and also very          Haxton also had special mention for Jack McDiarmid,
              picturesque.”                                           Brad Clement, Don Taylor — “who knew more about
                While the golf competition was exciting and memorable,  Scottish history than I did … very impressive” — and Mel
              it was the lasting friendships generated around         (Bomber) Beatty, who kept him fed on the golf course with
              Wasagaming that Haxton says he will always revere. “I   homemade syrup tarts.
              recall playing against Brad Clement and making a friend for  At the top of the list of Canadian friends, of course, are
              life. It was an honour to play with him as he is a gentleman  the Moodys, Bill and Linda, “who will always remain like
              of the game.”                                           family to my wife Liz and I.”
                In another year, Haxton caddied for Clement in a ﬁnal and  Will he return one day for a future Tamarack? Haxton
              Clement told him “I have never been given as much       wasn’t speciﬁc, other than to say it would not be in 2018,
              information from a caddy in my life.”                   but “the Flying Scotsman will be back.”
                “Of course he won!” said Haxton.]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[Article_BillJohnston_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:09 PM  Page 1











              By‐law author,



                storyteller                                  ,








              Tamarack ﬁxture





              By Bruce Penton







                      ne of Bill Johnston’s earliest recollections is of his big  of 102-93, putting him into a ﬂight with some fairly high
                      brother Brian winning the junior championship at  handicappers.
              Othe Tamarack in 1960.                                   “As the week went on, and I played more, my game naturally
                Bill was three at the time.                           came around,” said Johnston. “So I’m playing John Braendle
                Now 61, the former Brandonite is known around the     late in the week and on the (par-5) fourth hole, I hit driver, 5-
              Winnipeg legal community as The Honourable Mr. Justice  wood onto the green and I’ve got 10 feet for eagle. John’s not
              William Johnston (Family Division). Apropos that he be  a very long hitter so he hit driver, 3-wood, 3-wood right into
              afﬁliated with the ‘Family’ division, because this is a story  the hole. for a three. Of course I missed my eagle putt. Gotta
              about the Tamarack, which has no prairie peer as a ‘family’  love match play.”
              golf tournament.                                         Another time, Johnston was playing Garry Hargreaves of
                “I was three, brother Brian was 16 and he beat Dave Hill (of  Brandon and was 1-up teeing off No. 17, the picturesque
              Winnipeg) in the ﬁnal,” said Judge Johnston. “Which is kind  downhill, 110-yard par-3 signature hole at Clear Lake.
              of neat, because Dave (a Winnipeg lawyer) and I are pretty  Johnston hit his tee shot 10 feet from the cup while
              good friends now.”                                      Hargreaves hit a fat shot that landed in the vicinity of the
                Summer, Bill Johnston, and Clear Lake are synonymous. He  creek that runs in front of the green. “I was looking around
              spends as much time as possible in his Wasagaming cabin and  at him to shake hands, but he didn’t realize he was in the
              when he’s not at the cabin, chances are he’s on the Clear Lake  water, so I marked my ball. He found his ball in a mud pile in
              golf course. A good chunk of that time has been Tamarack-  the middle of the creek, which was a little low. He whacked
              connected.                                              it, mud ﬂying everywhere, and it went right into the hole. I’m
                He served on the tournament board for 10 years, was chair  pretty rattled, and I miss my putt and then drive it wildly on
              for two, served a long spell as bar chair, ran the calcutta for  18 and he wins the hole and the match.”
              about 10 years, wrote the  ﬁrst set of bylaws for the    Long-time Tamarack competitors will never forget the
              tournament and incorporated the tournament in the late  tornado of 1985 or 1986 that ripped through the golf course
              1980s, and won and lost more than a few memorable       on a Friday night and rendered the course unplayable
              matches. “In 40 years, every possible stupid thing has  Saturday for that year’s scheduled opening day of qualifying.
              happened,” said Johnston.                               Thanks to golf course staff and a small army of volunteers,
                “Let me tell you about John Braendle, a gravedigger from  “there were 17 holes playable” by the end of Saturday, said
              Binscarth,” he said.                                    Johnston. Qualifying, now only one round, went ahead on
                It’s a good story.                                    Sunday — on a 17-hole golf course.”No. 10 was unplayable,”
                Johnston was in his early 20s, attending university and  he said. “So everybody was given a bogey on that hole — and
              working construction in the summer, leaving little or no time  nobody complained.”
              for golf. But he booked time off to compete in the Tamarack  The tournament went on, with a few emergency local rules
              and his very rusty golf game resulted in ugly qualifying scores  in effect to account for storm damage.
          106]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[Article_BillJohnston_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:09 PM  Page 2





                                                                       A number of changes were made to the tournament during
                                                                      Johnsgon’s time on the executive, including the addition of a
                                                                      second qualifying round for the men, and the interwoven
                                                                      match-play schedules. Men’s play used to feature qualifying
                                                                      Saturday and Sunday and then matches Monday through
                                                                      Thursday, culminating in the championship. The juniors and
                                                                      women would start Thursday and end on the weekend. Now,
                                                                      days off are provided to everyone, and every championship
                                                                      match in every section takes place on Saturday. “It was a
                                                                      tremendous change,” said Johnston. “A lot of guys would
                                                                      complain about having to play six days in a row.”
                                                                       Johnston credits that scheduling change to Barry Diller,
                                                                      who was tournament director for about 20 years. Diller is
                                                                      also responsible for helping to speed up play by establishing
                                                                      white chalk lines on the left and right of No. 10, requiring
                                                                      golfers to go to a drop zone on the fairway if their tee shot
                                                                      landed beyond the chalk. He did something similar on No. 15,
                                                                      too, drawing a chalk line in the middle of the fairway and
                                                                      having golfers who hit stray tee shots to take a one-shot
                                                                      penalty and hit their third shot from the centre line. “It really
                                                                      speeded up play and was a great innovation,” said Johnston.
                                                                       The experiment about 25 years ago with two shotgun starts
                                                                      had one major drawback, said Johnston. “The ﬁrst wave (of
                                                                      golfers) took up all the spots in the parking lot and the second
                                                                      wave would arrive and have to park at Onanole,” he said, the
                                                                      words dripping with hyperbole. “We were trying to maximize
              The Honourable Mr. Justice William Johnston.            the number of competitors, but we’ve come to the conclusion
                (Ken Gigliotti / Winnipeg Free Press)                 that 224 (men) is the comfortable number.”]]></page><page Index="108"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:09 PM  Page 1































































































          108]]></page><page Index="109"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:09 PM  Page 2































































































                                                                                                                          109]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:09 PM  Page 3]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:09 PM  Page 4]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:09 PM  Page 5































































































          112]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:09 PM  Page 6































































































                                                                                                                          113]]></page><page Index="114"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:09 PM  Page 7































































































          114]]></page><page Index="115"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:18 PM  Page 8































































































                                                                                                                          115]]></page><page Index="116"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:10 PM  Page 9































































































          116]]></page><page Index="117"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:10 PM  Page 10]]></page><page Index="118"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:10 PM  Page 11































































































          118]]></page><page Index="119"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:10 PM  Page 12































































































                                                                                                                          119]]></page><page Index="120"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:10 PM  Page 13]]></page><page Index="121"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:10 PM  Page 14































































































                                                                                                                          121]]></page><page Index="122"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:10 PM  Page 15]]></page><page Index="123"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:10 PM  Page 16































































































                                                                                                                          123]]></page><page Index="124"><![CDATA[TAMARACK_2010-17_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:10 PM  Page 17































































































          124]]></page><page Index="125"><![CDATA[Chip Shots_Layout 1  18-07-20  10:23 AM  Page 3





                                            Father – Son matchups are always a special time.
                                            This 2012 10th ﬂight battle was no different.
                                            Colin Kehler faced his Dad Reg.  After halving the
                                            17th, Colin, thinking he had won, went to shake his
                                            Dad’s hand. Reg laughed and chirped “I’m not dead
                                            yet”.  He then proceeded to win 18 and force an
                                            extra. Alas the younger Kehler would win the 19th
                                            and secure family bragging rights, albeit always
                                            with a pause for laughter.




                                                     Three women have won three
              “I shot 75, it probably looked              consecutive titles.
              like 80. I know it felt like 85.”        Muriel Clark ’76,’77 & ‘78
              Jack Matheson after topping              Shelly Muir ’94, ’95 & ’96
              Bob Cornell in the 1986                 Pam Burneski ’09, ‘10 & ‘11
              quarter ﬁnals.
                                                  All coincidentally have ﬁve wins each.
              Kurt Martin’s take on his 1-up
              win over Jack McDiarmid in
              the championship ﬂight?
              “We did not hit very many
              good golf shots. I was a little
              less ugly than Jack.”









                                             Chip







                                                             Shots






                                                                                              In 1956 Sam Gibney
                                            In 2012 Barry Hooke had driven up to the lake     established what must be
                                            on Friday night and was unloading his cart as his  a record – 10 putts through
                                            wife Kathy had gone to look at Deep Bay. The      11 holes! Not conﬁrmed,
                                            next thing he knew he was on the ground and the   but to put this in
                                            cart had run over him. Luckily no severe damage   perspective, a pretty
                                            but a cut arm from the rocks and gravel. No       decent player – Ken
                                            problem though as Hooke made every tee time.
              After missing a one foot putt  We said it was a family affair. Barry Hooke’s    Collyer – once took 5 on
              on 9 to lose a playoff: “Well  most memorable Tamarack was when he hurt his     the 9th hole alone.
              there's no gimmies on that    back the morning of the ﬁrst day of the
              green, but it was a pretty basic  tournament. I was going to drop out but Kathy  Also in 1956, Roy Kepron hit his
              putt. I was actually thinking  said just try it, if you have to, you can quit. I  tee shot on the 5th 325 yds.
              about my tee shot on the next  played 6 rounds that year and Kathy, my best  That’s pretty crazy if you’ve ever
              hole, if you can believe that.”   caddie, teed up my ball for every hole. She  hit a persimmon driver or balata
              – Paul Murray                 gained quite a reputation that week.           ball.

                                                                                                                          125]]></page><page Index="126"><![CDATA[Article_MikeGodfrey_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:46 PM  Page 1



































                 6 up, 6 to go –

                no problem

















              By Bruce Penton                                         Mike Godfrey tees off during a round at the  2011 Tamarack.


                       ike Godfrey has an unofﬁcial Tamarack record    “I remember thinking all I have to do is tie one hole,” said
                       that most people wearing spikes would like to  Godfrey.
              Mforget.                                                 Meanwhile, his caddie, Selkirk buddy Mark Starodub,
                On the other hand, if it was forgotten, Godfrey and his  departed after No. 11. “He said ‘you’ve got things under
              family members wouldn’t have the great six-up-with-six-  control’ and he had to go caddy for his wife,” said Godfrey.
              to-go-and-lost-the-match story to laugh about through the  “Later that night, either with a text or email, he said ‘what
              years.                                                  hole did you win it on?’
                “We’ve laughed about it ever since,” says Godfrey, a   The vanquished golfer sent back the bad news. “I didn't
              Selkirk native who moved to Brandon when he was in      win,” he said.
              Grade 12, and through golf met the girl of his dreams,   McDonald won 13 and 14, then 15 and 16 against a
              Trista Hall, and eventually married into the Phil-Carole Hall  fading Godfrey, who was now only two up with two to go.
              family.                                                 “By the 17th tee, I could hardly see the ball,” said Godfrey,
                “I’m an easy-going guy. It’s a great story, and I don't mind  laughing easily at the sordid memory. McDonald then
              talking about it,” said Godfrey.                        made Tamarack history by completing the comeback,
                It was in the early 2000s, competing in a lesser (ﬁrst or  winning 17 and 18 and then the extra hole (No. 8). “I hit it
              second) ﬂight, and Godfrey was in the process of crushing  into the trees on the left (on the extra hole) and couldn’t
              former Brandonite Cam McDonald, now of Edmonton.        make par,” said Godfrey. “Cam got a four to my ﬁve.”
              Godfrey holed a bunker shot on No. 11 to take a six-up   A similar match-play collapse almost happened later in
              lead, and after the duo halved the par-3 12th, the match  Godfrey’s career when he played his brother-in-law, Rob
              was virtually over — Godfrey was six up with six to go.  Hall, in a nine-hole match at a tournament in Melita. “I won
                But it wasn't.                                        the ﬁrst four holes and he won the next four.” But this story
          126]]></page><page Index="127"><![CDATA[Article_MikeGodfrey_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:46 PM  Page 2





              had a different ending from that of the Tamarack ﬁasco:
              Godfrey won the match on No. 9.                         “I remember thinking all I have
                Rob Hall also plays a major role in Godfrey’s favourite
              Tamarack match.                                         to do is tie one hole”
                The brothers-in-law tangled in 2009, in the second ﬂight.
              The match started on No. 10 and was close all the way. On
              the second nine (Clear Lake’s front), “we were trading
              birdies back and forth but in the end Rob came out
              victorious 1-up.
                “I believe we had at least eight or nine birdies between us
              so was a great match to watch for the many family and
              friends that were following us.”
                It wasn’t so exciting for Carole Hall, Rob’s mother and
              Mike’s mother-in-law. “She couldn’t bring herself to watch
              the match in person with the stress of not wanting either
              one of us to lose,” said Godfrey.
                Friends with Rob Hall through junior golf competitions,
              Godfrey renewed acquaintances with him after moving to
              Brandon. He met his future father-in-law, Phil Hall, at a
              Rural Amateur at Minnewasta in 1994, where Godfrey
              was the winner and, in fact, played in the last group with
              Hall the elder and Bruce North of Carman. It’s a Hall family
              fact that the trio of low-handicappers in the clan — Phil and
              Rob Hall, and Godfrey — all have Rural Amateur titles to
              their name.
                But Godfrey is the only one who has the six-up-with-six-
              to-go-and-lost-the-match story. The other two are quite  Mike Godfrey chips during day two of the Tamarack Golf
              content in knowing he has sole ownership of such a tale.  Tournament in 2008.]]></page><page Index="128"><![CDATA[ColourfulGame_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:42 PM  Page 1]]></page><page Index="129"><![CDATA[ColourfulGame_Layout 1  18-07-20  5:42 PM  Page 2































































































                                                                                                                          129]]></page><page Index="130"><![CDATA[Article_MemorableMoments_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:42 PM  Page 1







                          Great                           shots,









                                      greater                  memories






              By Bruce Penton

















                                                          Bruce     Dwight
                                                          North     Kearns


                 n Jack McDiarmid’s eyes, Bruce North of Carmen has   marvelled McDiarmid. North went on to defeat Clark in
                 nearly legendary status when it comes to the annual  the the playoff for medallist honours.
              ITamarack golf tournament.                               “It was the second-best shot I’ve ever seen in my life.”
                “He hit shots I’d never seen before,” said McDiarmid, a  Second-best? North had the best shot, too, said
              regular rival of North’s in the championship ﬂight, and a  McDiarmid, detailing a miraculous second shot from the
              good friend.                                            right rough on the 13th hole. His ball went through the
                “And without a doubt, he’s the most gentlemanly player I  fairway, landed on a downslope on some dried and packed
              ever played against,” said McDiarmid. “He’s out there   mud, with the ball about six or eight inches below his feet.
              cheering for you. The only guy I ever saw, other than Garth  “I was convinced he was going to hit a long iron and play to
              Collings, who was actually cheering for you while playing  hit the green in three but when I looked back, he’d taken
              against him in a match.”                                his three-wood out,” said McDiarmid. “He went over two
                One round — one hole, in particular— will never leave  sets of trees with that three-wood. His ball mark was about
              McDiarmid’s memory when it comes to North lore.         three feet over the (greenside) trap and he made eagle.”
                “It was the late ’80s or early ’90s and we were playing  While North may have been the author of two
              together in the second qualifying round,” McDiarmid recalls.  memorable shots, McDiarmid says the Tamarack’s best
              “Bruce was 74 in the ﬁrst round and even (par) in the second  match-play golfer ever, in his mind, is Brandon’s Bob
              as we teed off 18. Somebody came back and told us that  Cornell.
              Brian Clark had ﬁnished at 144, even par, and looked like he  A two-time Tamarack champ, ‘Plumber’ was never out of
              was going to win the medal.”                            a match, said McDiarmid.
                The steely determination  of North took over. “I gotta make  “I remember one match I was three up with ﬁve to go
              a two, Jack,” said North. “Gotta make a two.”           against Bob,” said McDiarmid. “I thought I had things under
                McDiarmid said North took such a vicious swing at the tee  control, but …”
              ball on the par-4 18th that “the trees were moving,” but  Cornell rattled off a birdie-par-birdie-birdie run on the
              overswinging led to a relatively short drive that landed  next four holes to tie the match on the 17th green.
              about 110 yards from the green on the 335-yard hole.    McDiarmid, somewhat rattled, popped up his drive on 18
                “He got up to his ball, walked all the way up to the green,  and had a full nine-iron into the green. Cornell’s drive,
              took a good look at the pin, and walked back. He hit a sand  meanwhile, landed on the fringe of the green. But match
              wedge and, unbelievably, it took two bounces and went in,”  play being match play, McDiarmid knocked his nine-iron to
          130]]></page><page Index="131"><![CDATA[Article_MemorableMoments_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:42 PM  Page 2





              within two feet and made the putt for birdie while Cornell  Cornell, meanwhile, said he loved “the competitiveness” of
              took three to get down from the fringe.                 the Tamarack.
                Brandon’s Dwight Kearns also has a Cornell story.      “I liked competition of all kinds,” he said. “Whether it was
                Kearns and Cornell were battling in the men’s         match play golf, or business, or running a hockey team.
              championship ﬂight ﬁnal and were on the 13th hole when  Competition’s the spice of life.”
              a torrential Saturday downpour stopped play.             Cornell, Tamarack champion at the age of 31 in 1969 and
                “I was one up at the time and somebody from the       again in 1998 when he was 60, plays infrequently these
              committee came out and said, ‘match is over. Who’s      days. At the age of 80, arthritis is winning the battle of his
              ahead?’”                                                back, he says, and an occasional nine holes with his buddy
                Kearns objected to the premature victory suggestion and  Jack Matheson is usually enough. A serious trafﬁc accident
              told the ofﬁcial that he and Cornell would return to the  about a decade ago seriously injured Cornell, and says it has
              course Sunday to ﬁnish things off.                      affected his memory.
                Which they did. In the end, Cornell tied the match by the  But he can’t forget the great times at the annual August
              end of the 17th hole and then won the title with a 20-foot  event at Clear Lake. “I loved the Tamarack,” he said. “A lot of
              birdie putt on No. 18.                                  great times. Great matches.”
















                                                           Bob          Jack
                                                        Cornell         McDiarmid]]></page><page Index="132"><![CDATA[0000000_BrandonSun_Layout 1  18-07-18  11:00 AM  Page 1

























































                                                                Proudly teeing it up at Tamarack for all 85 years.




                                                                                See you at the 100 !
                                                                                                   th


                                                                           Friends and family can view

                                                                              Tamarack 85 online at

                                                                     brandonsun.com/sports/golf/tamarack]]></page><page Index="133"><![CDATA[Filler_page_Layout 1  18-07-23  9:54 AM  Page 1]]></page><page Index="134"><![CDATA[Article_Coleman_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:11 PM  Page 1









              Nothing like a


               good stretch






              before playing




              the back






              By Bruce Penton


                Holes-in-one are unforgettable moments for golfers, but
              while Brandon’s Ken Coleman had an unforgettable
              Tamarack memory from the late 1970s, it didn’t include an
              ace.
                Out of the blue, Coleman brieﬂy conquered golf, making
              things look so easy for a four-hole stretch during the
              second round of 36-hole qualifying. But as quickly as the
              hot streak arrived, it went away.
                Carrying a handicap of around 10 and not usually a threat
              to challenge for the championship ﬂight, Coleman shot a
              rather pedestrian 79 on the ﬁrst day of qualifying and
              appeared headed for ﬁrst- or  second-ﬂight competition.
                Suddenly, however, he started playing like Jack Nicklaus
              for a four-hole stretch beginning on No. 6.
                He was two over par after ﬁve, a decent beginning, and
              then sunk a long birdie putt on No. 6 to start his
              remarkable run. On the long par-4 seventh, a hole on
              which many golfers are happy to make four, Coleman
              parred. On the shortish eighth hole, he chipped in from the
              fringe for an eagle two, and then almost did the same on
              No. 9, settling for a tap-in birdie.
                So, after being two over after ﬁve, Coleman suddenly
              made the turn at two-under-par 34.
                “A friend of mine started caddying for me on the sixth
              hole, when all this good stuff started to happen, but he
              abandoned me after nine, coming up with some lame
              excuse that he had to be somewhere,” he said.
                Coleman shot 43 on the back nine, posted a 77 and his
              two-day score of 156 was good enough for the ﬁnal spot
              in the championship ﬂight. “I played a Goodbrandson in the
              ﬁrst match and got my butt handed to me on a platter,” said
              Coleman. “I think the match was over after 12 holes.”
                But that four-hole stretch in the second round of the
              qualifying tournament — birdie, par, eagle, birdie — was
              unforgettable, and a great Tamarack memory.                 Ken Coleman (submitted).
          134]]></page><page Index="135"><![CDATA[Cubs_JuniorWomens_Layout 1  18-07-19  6:05 PM  Page 1
































         Cubs



















                                     Tamarack




              Junior Women’s Winners



                                        1990 – 2017



               1990 – Not Played                      2004 – Not Played
               1991 – Kathleen Spalding               2005 – Ashley Wells
               1992 – Not Played                      2006 – Cassie Ferguson                      Cassie
               1993 – Not Played                      2007 – Cassie Ferguson                      Ferguson
               1994 – Lindsay Wells                   2008 – Cassie Ferguson
               1995 – Tiann O’Carroll                 2009 – Cassie Ferguson
               1996 – Tricia Meadows                  2010 – Brandi Clayton
               1997 – Rhonda Beatty                   2011 – Brandi Clayton
              1998 – Brianna Souter                   2012 – Bobbi Uhl
              1999 – Not Played                       2013 – Bobbi Uhl
              2000 – Not Played                       2014 – Bobbi Uhl
              2001 – Not Played                       2015 – Bobbi Uhl
              2002 – Not Played                       2016 – Haley Shanks
              2003 – Pam Burneski                     2017 – Not Played                  Bobbi                            135
                                                                                         Uhl]]></page><page Index="136"><![CDATA[3708834_MyITSource_Layout 1  18-07-19  4:55 PM  Page 1






                                                                                   Celebrating


                                                                                   20 Years



                                                                                   in Business















                 First-Class Business IT Support

               Network Security

               Disaster Data Recovery

               Off-Site Cloud Backup Solutions                            Your most trusted

               Microsoft Office 365 Solutions                             IT support specialists













































                      1535 Pacific Ave, Brandon   |   204-728-1040   |   www.myITsource.com]]></page><page Index="137"><![CDATA[Article_Jerrett_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:27 PM  Page 1







             Drums up win in









              By Bruce Penton

              W        hen the sad day ﬁnally comes, Jerry                       fairway on No 9 with balls ﬂying back toward

                       Jerrett will die a happy man.
                                                                                 the tee. “If one of Johnny’s lessons didn’t show
                “My only ambition in life was to win that                        up, he’d give me the lesson,” said Jerrett.
                                                                                 Shagging balls for the pro was more lucrative,
              tournament,” said Jerrett, now 88, talking                         said Jerrett. It paid 50 cents an hour “and I liked
              about the annual Clear Lake golf tournament                        it better because I didn’t have to carry a bag.”
              that’s now known as the Tamarack. “I ﬁnally did                     Jerrett, who was a YMCA director in
              it in 1959.”                                                       Winnipeg and later an employee of Child and
                Jerrett grew up in Brandon but said the Clear                    Family Services during his working years, spent
              Lake track “was my home course” because his                        his ﬁrst 23 years in Brandon. His father was a
              parents owned a photo store at Wasagaming                          professional photographer whose shop was a
              and the family spent its summers there. “My life                   downtown staple. He recalls travelling to
              revolved around that course,” he said.                             Winnipeg with former Brandon pro Bill
                Jerrett, who plays a few rounds these days at                    Thompson for the Manitoba Open one year
              Wildwood in Winnipeg, played in his ﬁrst Clear                     and on the way home, after not scoring very
              Lake men’s open at the age of 14. “They had                        well, he told Thompson one thing that would
              only men’s and women’s then,” he said, “but                        cheer him up would be to win the Kinsmen Car
              they let juniors play, too. I remember I shot 99                   Draw at the Brandon Summer Fair. “Well,
              and was in the ﬁfth or sixth ﬂight. The next year,                 wouldn’t you know it, we had the radio on and
              I shot 89 and was overjoyed. But I played in that                  they announced the winner of the car draw was
              tournament every year and just loved it.”                          Jerry Jerrett of Brandon. That sure brightened
                Jerrett’s strong suit was his accuracy off the                   my day.”
              tee and his short game. Long-time Clear Lake                        Jerrett drove his prize, a 1952 Chevrolet
              pro Johnnie Lawrence  told Jerrett the key to                      DeLuxe, for one year, and then sold it for
              putting was to use a pendulum stroke on the                        $2,000.
              greens and it paid off. He shot a medal score of                    He was also somewhat of a musician, playing
              73 in the 1959  ﬁnal against Bob Gray, a                           drums in a band, the Jerry Jerrett Quartet, and
              Willingdon Cupper from Winnipeg, and won                           recalls that he was given free admission to
              the match on the 16th hole.                                        Danceland at Clear Lake if he promised the
                The men’s  ﬁnal was a major event, recalls                       doorman he’d sing with that night’s band.
              Jerrett. Spectators numbering in the hundreds                       These days, Jerrett says he plays golf only
              would follow the championship match and                            occasionally and usually shoots in the 90s (not
              newspaper coverage of the tournament in                            bad for an 88-year-old) and still hits it straight.
              Brandon and Winnipeg treated the Tamarack                          His short game — “a little shaky these days” —
              as they would a major sports event. “I                             has let him down. He remains close with the
              remember in the ﬁnal against Gray, we were on                      Lawrence family, and talks to Johnnie’s
              the 15th green and I looked back and the top                       daughter, Heather (a golf pro, too), every week
              of the hill was just jammed with carts. It was a  Jerry Jerrett in 1965 (top),  when they analyze the results of the weekly
              big deal to win the Tamarack.”            and 1966 (bottom).       PGA Tour event.
                Jerrett qualiﬁed in the the championship                          Jerrett doesn’t get up to Clear Lake often
              ﬂight a few more times but was unable to nab                       anymore, although he hopes to visit the
              a second title.                                         Lawrences when the family gets together this summer for a
                Lawrence was a major inﬂuence on Jerrett’s love for the  couple of weeks in August.
              game. When the young Jerrett wasn’t playing, he was      And for eternity, Jerrett will remain in Clear Lake. “I’ve told
              caddying for 75 cents a round, or shagging balls for Lawrence  my kids to spread my ashes in the creek on 17,” he said. “Then
              during his private lessons, staged at the bottom of the  I can spend my time laughing at everybody hitting the water.”
          137]]></page><page Index="138"><![CDATA[Blast_Layout 1  18-07-19  5:58 PM  Page 1
















                     Thanks Tamarack





















































                                   it ’ s been a blast]]></page><page Index="139"><![CDATA[3708737_Crane_Layout 1  18-07-19  4:50 PM  Page 1]]></page><page Index="140"><![CDATA[3708658_SandhillsCasino_Layout 1  18-07-20  12:43 PM  Page 1]]></page></pages></Search>