<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="48"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[2016 SPECIAL SUPPLEMENT]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[“Talk to the                                            The desire to “get the look you want” has more men
Doctor to                                               and women seeking quick and safe in-office
                                                        procedures to help maintain or reverse the effects
Get the Look                                            of time, sun and living. Dr. Kelleher’s Laser, Skin and
You Want”                                               Vein Clinic provides effective non-surgical cosmetic
                                                        treatments for both men and women. Patients are
                                                        assured of receiving high quality, professional
                                                        treatments performed by Dr. Barb Kelleher, BSc, MD
                                                        and her qualified staff.

Left to right, back row:
Lori – Laser & Esthetics Technician
Emmy – Laser & Esthetics Technician
Laurie – RN

Left to right, front row:
Susan – LPN
Dr. Barbara Kelleher, BSc, MD
Britta – Reception

CALL TODAY TO BOOK YOUR FREE CONFIDENTIAL CONSULTATION

150–1300–18th Street, Brandon, MB • 204-727-1920         NEW!                    • Botox Cosmetic      • Acne & Rosacea
                               • www.laserskinvein.com  • CoolSculpting          • Juvederm             Management
                                                        • FemiLift               • Microdermabrasion   • Latisse Eyelash
                                                        • Fractional Laser Skin  • Hydradermabrasion    Treatment
                                                         Resurfacing             • Laser Hair Removal  • Glo Mineral Makeup
                                                        • Sculptra               • Chemical Peels      • Skin TX & Vivier
                                                        • Dysport                • Photofacials         skincare lines
                                                        • Emervel                • Body Contouring     • Vein Treatments
                                                                                 • Skin Tightening     • Dermapen]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

Good year on the farm means good year for city

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                       we’re going to be at or above the national GDP           the economic engine that it is,” said Burgess.
                                                        numbers,” said Burgess.                                    “This year isn’t going to be any different. It seems
  Business owners will often keep a close eye on
what’s happening with the economy, not just on a          “The Conference Board of Canada just released          as though it’s going to be a relatively good year for
local level, but on a provincial, national and even     some information that indicated a 2.2. or 2.3 per        ag receipts, which will continue to have a positive
global viewpoint. The fact of the matter is, the many   cent improvement. It’s not where we’ve been, but         impact on our community. We’re in a pretty good
factors that drive or slow down the economy             considering what’s happened in the local economy         position to build on. If things continue the way they
generally have a strong impact on a business’s          with the oil and gas industry, we’re pretty              are, I think we’ll be in pretty good shape in a year’s
bottom line no matter where they operate in the         optimistic.”                                             time.”
world.
                                                          And while there’s optimism, there’s also still a bit     As an economics instructor at Assiniboine
  Brandon Chamber of Commerce president Terry           of risk. Burgess said that if the Canadian dollar        Community College, Rich Little encourages his
Burgess said that while there are many aspects to       doesn’t continue to be at the level it’s expected to be  students to also consider the multitude of factors
consider on what the economic outlook is for our        at, if oil prices happen to drop, or if something        that might affect the economy. One area they’ve
city and region, there seems to be a fairly consistent  happens in terms of world affairs, the economy will      recently been focusing on is interest rates.
message when it comes to what’s expected in the         be effected at all levels.
coming months.                                                                                                     “I often remind my students that there were times
                                                          In our region, however, the impact of the              when interest rates were pushing 18 to 20 per cent
  “Nationally I don’t think we’re looking for a return  agricultural industry is what many people will be        back in the ’70s and ’80s. Something to be mindful
to the high levels of GDP growth and economic           focusing on.                                             of is that we’ve had a historic period of low interest
growth that we’ve experienced in the last couple                                                                 rates and that’s created some interesting things in
years, but in Manitoba or the broader Brandon             “We’ve been on such a high that we’re probably         the economy,” said Little.
economic zone, we’re feeling pretty optimistic that     turning to more normal levels of economic activity.
                                                        Brandon has seen the benefit ever since our existence                                                 » Continued on Page 6
                                                        from the strength of our agricultural community and]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Because your pet is family too!                                                 Our Resort                     • Paw Spaw
                                                       Built to the highest standards of pet care facilities.  • A Bone to Pick
                                                      A calm, peaceful, healthy, and hygienic environment.      Boutique
                                                       Green design, recycled materials, top equipment.        • Wellness Room
                                                                                                               • Luxury suites
                                                                       A family-owned business.                • Cat Jungle Room
                                                                                                               • Focus Forward
                                                                                Our Services                    Training Centre
                                                         Boarding: Home-like comforts for dogs and cats.       • Play Care
                                                      Grooming: Tailored packages and no-stress approach
                                                      Play Care: Exercise, social time, and fun for your dog.
                                                        Dog Training Classes: Puppy life skills, competitive

                                                                  obedience, conformation and rally

                    GROOMING                                       TRAINING CLASSES                                    PLAY CARE
                                                      Evening group and private training classes are    Pets can join our supervised Play Care
Our Paw Spaw boasts accomplished friendly Pet                                                           groups for an afternoon, full day or play
Sylists, state of the art equipment in a calm, clean     offered from young puppies to advanced
                                                      levels. Classes are taught in a positive manner                  while they stay.
                       environment.
                                                                   rewarding and fun for all.

                    BOARDING                                             BOUTIQUE                                     PARTY TIME!
Accomodations are private suites, complete with       Our Bone to Pick retail area always has a great    Sign up for our fantastic parties go for
                                                                                                        country walks make some new friends we
    exceptional care and pampering, from our            selection of fine leashes and collars, healthy
                       attendants.                      training treats, toys and lovely clothing too!             love your VIP pets too.

“Committed to high standards that you expect and your pet deserves.”

                         CALL 204-729-9943 EMAIL: THEPAW@RFNOW.COM

                                         THEPAWRESORTANDWELLNESSCENTRE.COM

                                               Lobby Hours: Monday to Saturday, 8:00 am – 6:30 pm; Sunday, 10:30 am – 8:00 pm

                                       Directions: 3 miles West on the Grand Valley Road, turn North on Gray Road,
                                                    we’re at the top of hill – 2 storey, rust-coloured building]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[6 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

Incoming Chamber of Commerce president Terry Burgess smiles while being introduced by outgoing president Jordan Ludwig during the C o C’s changeover luncheon at the Royal Oak Inn and Suites. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)

« Continued from Page 4          Canada more often.                                                          “When we look at job growth in Canada, a high
                                 “I think there’s an opportunity to make a more percentage is coming from small businesses. What we
“So many people are attracted to low variable rates aggressive stand to promoting local tourism to areas promote to our students through our Capstone
and they’ve been so low for so long, there’s a lot of close to the Canadian border. We want to entice them Entrepreneurship course is that as a university or
talk about the interest rates going up. If that happens to come up here and spend some of their tourism college graduate, there’s a chance that you might have
and people haven’t budgeted properly, that could be dollars and buy consumable goods as well. There’s to make your own job, especially when we’re in a
a rude awakening. At some point, we’re going to face often payback as a result of investing in tourism. I volatile situation like we are now,” said Little.
that reality and that’s going to cause some issues for would encourage folks to think about that when “I consider things like the exchange rate, the price
some folks because we’re certainly supporting the they’re creating their own marketing plans,” said of oil to all be quite cyclical. I expect we’ll see that
economy on low interest rates.”  Burgess.                                                                    time again where economic activity, especially in the
In terms of the Canadian dollar and the rate that it Along with a focus on tourism, Little said there’s oil industry, is going to return. Hopefully, we’ll be well
is at, Burgess indicated that it may be the right time also renewed interest in entrepreneurship and the need situated to capture that opportunity,” said Burgess.
to promote the city and invest in more tourism dollars to support business start-ups, but it’s important to
and invite our friends south of the border to visit invest in retention of these businesses as well.
                                                                                                             » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[DO YOU OR SOMEONE YOU LOVE SUFFER FROM

 Arthritis • Migraines • Anxiety • Insomnia • Cancer • PMS
                        or other painful conditions?

WE OFFER A SAFE, HOLISTIC ALTERNATIVE
          to traditional medications

                                 with information and resources to assist you in this
                                      Natural Approach to Healing and Pain Relief.

                                                         • Books on Medicinal Marijuana
                                                         • Grow Tents
                                                         • Drying Racks
                                                         • Baking Ovens
                                                         • Advanced Nutrients
                                                         • General Hydroponics
                                                         • Rotary Evaporators
                                                         • and much more!

Owner Darrin  Kellsey & Butters                                                                                         Before

Here is what local customers have to say:                                                                                       After

Arthritis patient – Ann from Brandon

"I was seeing a local specialist for my painful, debilitating arthritis, and taking expensive prescription medications
that weren't effective. I now take one medical cannabis capsule at bedtime, and can't believe the change in my
condition! I can cook, climb stairs and enjoy life again. It's changed my life, and I have nothing but praise for this
product. My specialist told me to continue to take it because it's working. I no longer need to see him."

Migraine sufferer – Elsie from Brandon

"I was bedridden for 3 days at a time, with horrible migraines. Since I've been taking medicinal marijuana, I haven't had a migraine in 2
years! It's a wonderful natural approach to pain relief without side effects! It's like a God send!"

              THE HEALING POT

              Medicinal Marijuana Supplies

              204-596-8323 • 719 - 10th Street, Brandon]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

   A happy customer is extremely important

  For 14 years Extreme Electronics has been the            But it’s not just cars. Extreme Electronics has       knowing Extreme Electronics used only the best
most trusted name in home audio, televisions,            many satisfied customers who have had their trucks,     brands in the business, including Klipsch, Paradigm,
portable audio, marine audio and mobile electronics      buses, tractors, semis, boats and even golf carts       LG, Samsung, Yamaha, Panasonic, Control4,
in Brandon and Westman.                                  customized they way they want it.                       Pioneer, Alpine, Sharp, Hisense, Anthem and many
                                                                                                                 more.
  Locally owned and operated, Extreme Electronics          “You name it, and we’ll find a way to get it done
offers the best brand names, selection, price and        in a way that exceeds your expectations,” Johnson         “We want the best equipment in the most qualified
service. What really sets them apart, however, is        said.                                                   hands to ensure the customer is happy at the end
their attention to the customer, many who have been                                                              of the day,” Johnson said. “You wouldn’t just let
supporting the company since the beginning.                If vehicles aren’t your passion, Extreme              anyone work in your home, business or vehicle and
                                                         Electronics can give you that home experience that      we treat them all like they were our own. Think
  Extreme Electronics’ mandate says it all: “We will     will make all of your friends jealous.                  about it, if we don’t install your car starter or stereo
earn the loyalty and trust of our customers by                                                                   system, you might not want to look under the dash
consistently satisfying their individual needs and         With a the tap of a screen, you can now control       of your vehicle.”
exceeding their expectations in a comfortable and        your stereo, TV, lights, thermostat, security cameras,
supportive environment,” owner Brian Johnson             door locks, pool, hot tub, sprinklers and appliances      Integrity and honesty are the cornerstones of
said.                                                    — all from your computer, tablet or smartphone          Extreme Electronics success, with an emphasis on
                                                         from anywhere in the world.                             being a responsible corporate citizen that works to
  Extreme Electronics expert staff can walk you                                                                  make a positive contribution to the community.
through solutions for any of your home, business           And the customer will have the added comfort of
or vehicle needs.                                                                                                  “We are committed to retaining long-term,
                                                                                                                 professional relationships with our customers that
  “It’s important to us that we not just sell you the                                                            are mutually rewarding and are based on loyalty
product, but help you find the proper solution to                                                                and trust,” Johnson said. “Many of our customers
what you’re looking for,” Johnson said. “We want                                                                 have become great friends and have shown us great
to custom tailor it to your needs, then, if they would                                                           support, something that has allowed us to build at
like, deliver it, install it and show you how it works.                                                          our new location to hopefully serve them better. Our
We’ll even clean up the mess before we leave.”                                                                   customers are what makes us. And we won’t ever
                                                                                                                 forget that.”
  Extreme Electronics, located at 121 17th Street
North, can customize your car the way you’ve                                                                       Extreme Electronics invites everyone to visit their
always dreamed. From audio installations, GPS                                                                    new website extremeelectronics.ca
tracking systems, LED lighting, heated seats, cruise                                                             » The Brandon Sun
controls, starters and alarms, there is no job too big
or too small.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Guillermo Rocha MD, FRCSC

                                                                                                 Eye Physician & Surgeon
                                                                                            Local Surgeon, Local Care!

                    Specializing In Your Vision Needs

CORNEA • CATARACT • REFRACTIVE SURGERY

Achieve surgical vision correction better than ever before!
                 Free Complimentary Assessments

  Financing Available Book An Appointment Today!

              Suite 20 • 144 – 6th Street | Brandon, MB • R7A 3N2
 Tel: (204) 727-1954 | Fax: (204) 728-5248 | www.ocularcentre.com]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

Welcome to carefree comfort, companionship

BY WANDA KURCHABA                              try to make that decision as easy as         parents find a place that is comfortable   our own community within Rotary
                                               possible.”                                   and safe,” said Brown.                     Villas,” said Brown.
  As we move through the phases of our
life, it’s important to feel safe, secure and    Rotary Villas is geared to those who         “It’s important to consider places         While there are many benefits to living
comfortable in our homes.                      are 55+ and literally offers an array of     where you know they’ll get wonderful       in a retirement home, the added features
                                               services and amenities to ensure residents   meals, where they’ll have easy access to   for socializing and taking part in other
  While it is often a difficult decision to    can enjoy a carefree and independent         a doctor and a pharmacy or a place         activities at Rotary Villas only make it
move from a single family dwelling to          lifestyle.                                   where they’ll be able to develop           that much more welcoming. They have
another type of accommodation, it’s                                                         friendships and be active.”                a healthy living centre, games and sitting
important to realize that alternative living     With tantalizing and delicious meals                                                  room, billiard lounge, plus a library that
arrangements can improve your lifestyle        carefully prepared with a local flair by a     The three-storey Rotary Villas building  is supported by the Rotary Club of
tremendously.                                  Red Seal Chef, residents look forward to     has 12 different layouts within the 108    Brandon No. 1344.
                                               meeting their friends for breakfast, lunch   suites, including studio, one-bedroom
  And that’s certainly the case with           and dinner in the beautiful on-site dining   and two-bedroom apartments, as well as       They also have a full-time, convenient
Rotary Villas at Crocus Gardens, which         room. There is also light housekeeping,      two-bedroom villas that have an            shuttle service that allows residents to get
is Brandon’s newest retirement complex.        weekly linen service, 24-hour on-site staff  additional three-season room.              to their next bridge game, to medical
                                               and a la carte healthcare services.                                                     appointments or to meet their friends for
  “We do what we can to make all of                                                           It is 100 per cent locally owned and     coffee.
our residents feel comfortable. I think          In addition, Rotary Villas is home to      operated and is an integral part of the
many of them will agree that this really       Flatland Drugs, Dr. Meredith’s Medical       community.                                   Without a doubt, Rotary Villas offers
is a special place that they can call          Clinic and Camelot Personal Care.                                                       a carefree, convenient and comfortable
home,” said general manager Debbie                                                            “We are proud to be locally owned and    environment so that residents can enjoy
Brown.                                           “For someone who is getting close to       operated, our staff and our residents are  retirement living the way it’s meant to be
                                               retirement or is a son or daughter, you      from Brandon and surrounding areas,        enjoyed.
  “It’s a huge decision for families to        think of your parents and what would         we buy all of our products locally.        » The Brandon Sun
move and make their home in a new              be best for them as they move into           Supporting the community that we live
community and we understand that. We           retirement. We all want to help our          and work in is as important as developing]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[12 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

  High-tech eye clinic provides ‘vision for life’

We live in the 21st century,                                                                                                             followed by training in
and it is possible to achieve                                                                                                            cornea and external diseases
surgical vision correction                                                                                                               at the University of South
better than ever before, with                                                                                                            Florida in Tampa.
modern, high quality                                                                                                                               He resides in Brandon
technology.                                                                                                                              serving the Westman region
The Ocular Microsurgery                                                                                                                  as medical director of Ocular
& Laser Centre in Brandon                                                                                                                Microsurgery and Laser
was founded by eye physician                                                                                                             Centre, and in public, private
and surgeon Guillermo                                                                                                                    and academic facilities in the
Rocha, MD, FRCSC, FACS                                                                                                                   province.
as a tertiary care facility in                                                                                                                     Dr. Rocha currently is
ophthalmology. It specializes                                                                                                            president of the Canadian
in the diagnosis and                                                                                                                     Ophthalmological Society,
management of surgical and                                                                                                               past president of the
medical conditions of the eye                                                                                                            Canadian Cornea, External
through the collaboration                                                                                                                Diseases and Refractive
with public, private,                                                                                                                    Surgery Society and associate
academic, and research                                                                                                                   professor in the faculty of
entities.                                                                                                                                medicine at the University of
The centre provides “vision                                                                                                              Manitoba.
for life” by providing care for                                                                                                                    He is a past associate editor
medical, surgical, or                                                                                                                    and cornea section editor for
emergency situations to all                                                                                                              the international journal
age groups by a full-time                                                                                                                Techniques         in
ophthalmologist, two part-                                                                                                               Ophthalmology and past
time optometrists, and six                                                                                                               editor-in-chief of Online
certified     ophthalmic                                                                                                                 Clinical Communications for
technicians.                                                                                                                             Ophthalmologists. He has
Assessments, most surgical                                                                                                               also co-edited four books:
procedures and followup care                                                                                                             “Advanced Technology IOLs
are provided locally in                                                                                                                  in Cataract Surgery: Pearls
Brandon.                                                                                                                                 for Success,” “Bringing You
Modern technologies allow                                                                                                                the Future in
patients to experience                                                                                                                   Ophthalmology,” “Advances
improved quality of life                                                                                                                 in Refractive and Corneal
through more freedom from                                                                                                                Surgery,” and “Surgical
glasses or contact lenses.                                                                                                               Correction of Astigmatism.”
Patients can receive                                                                                                                               In addition, he has more
cataract surgery using laser-                                                                                                            than 60 published citations in
assisted techniques and                                                                                                                  book chapters, medical
advanced technology lenses                                                                                                               reviews and articles, and
to correct astigmatism and                                                                                                               study abstracts presented at
reduce the need for reading glasses. Laser surgery            In addition, Refractive Lens Exchange (RLE) or           international meetings. Many of his authored papers
choices include LASIK, PRK (photorefractive                 Visian ICL (implantable contact lens) surgeries are        and public presentations have received awards for the
keratectomy), Intacs, and Kamra inlays. These laser         performed locally on a routine basis for high              high quality of research, and in May of 2014 he
techniques are provided in partnership with Image           prescriptions. Cataracts can now be removed using          received the iCARE Award for his contribution to
Plus Laser Eye Centre in Winnipeg.                          Femtosecond Laser-assisted Cataract Surgery and            eye care from the lieutenant-governor of Manitoba.
Dr. Rocha has had the opportunity to bring many             Ultrasonic Phacoemulsification. Advanced                   Research activities at the centre are co-ordinated
firsts to Manitoba: the first LASIK procedure, the          technology lenses are available for astigmatism and        by a full-time clinical research associate. More
first Intacs to reshape the cornea and the first selective  presbyopia.                                                recently, the centre has established a Dry Eye Centre
layer corneal transplant (DSEK) along with the                                                                         of Excellence within its facility to address this chronic
artificial cornea (Boston keratoprosthesis). In               The centre has access to virtually all lenses available  and common health issue.
addition, he was the first in the province to use the       worldwide, and is able to custom order implants            Further information about the clinic and the
femtosecond laser to assist in cataract surgery.            depending on the needs. In essence, the centre aims        treatments available can be found on the website.
Refractive surgeries are used to reduce dependence          at identifying the patient’s needs, and providing the      There are occasionally informational seminars that
on glasses or contact lenses.                               service to achieve that goal with quality care.            the public can attend for more information about
“Often, the misconception that certain conditions                                                                      certain eye care subjects.
like astigmatism or the need for readers cannot be            Dr. Rocha received his medical degree from the           Contact information: The Ocular Microsurgery &
treated, have prevented individuals from achieving          Universidad Anáhuac in Mexico City where he                Laser Centre, Suite 20, 144 Sixth Street, Brandon,
their lifestyle goals,” said Dr. Rocha. In fact,            received honourable mention for the highest grade in       MB, R7A 3N2 Phone 204-727-1954;
conditions such as myopia, hyperopia, astigmatism,          his graduating class. He then completed a research         ocularcentre.com
and presbyopia can be treated by the centre’s team          fellowship in microvascular surgery in Mexico City
using lasers and other techniques.                          and Houston, Texas.
                                                                                                                       » Submitted
                                                              He trained in ophthalmology at McGill University
                                                            in Montréal where he also completed subspecialty
                                                            training in ocular immunology and inflammation,]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[When You Make the Keystone Your Keystone,
You Make it Everyone’s Keystone

  To book your next meeting,               YOU’RE THE KEY
 party or conference or inquire
about our arena ads, sponsorship

      and naming rights
  contact us at 204-726-3500.]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

Elite Safety’s Darren Brick and Marc Watt outside their new training facility on 17th Street East. (File)

Elite’s safety training aims to prevent accidents

BY WANDA KURCHABA                            further expand their courses and             services. With the training and the       we can to actually prevent accidents
                                                                                          services that we provide, we try to       from happening,” said Brick.
                                             services. A Facility Management              mitigate all the hazards. It’s rewarding  » The Brandon Sun
They’ve moved, they’ve grown and             division allows clients to access            when we know that we’ve done what
they’ve expanded their services. It’s truly  Confined Space Management and Rope
been an exciting year for Elite Safety       Access teams. Rope Access Technicians
Services Inc. of Brandon.                    work on jobs done that would normally
Safety is at the heart of this company       require the use of cranes or scaffolding.
that started just 13 years ago from          The results are reduced costs and less
personal vehicles and home offices.          time, all the while completing the job
Owners Marc Watt and Darren Brick            safely.
said because of their experience as          Their new location is nearly four
former firefighters, they knew there was     times the size of their former building
a need for safety training and prevention    and has ample space in a large shop for
— but even they were a little surprised      on-site, hands-on training — plus they
by the demand.                               have regular classroom space and stand-
“It really started growing in 2007-08        alone drug and alcohol testing facilities.
and started to become something that         The partners noted that one of the
wasn’t manageable by just Marc and           most important aspects of their business
myself, so we began to hire staff. It was    is their employees. Although they’ve
at that point that we started to realize     grown in the last few years, it is still a
that this could grow into something          family-run,      community-minded
much bigger. We went from four staff         business. They are invested in the
to 22 full-time staff, plus 50 to 60 part-   community and the people that they
time employees. When we’re working           work with.
on larger projects, we’ve had over 100       “We feel our instructors are the best
employees,” said Brick.                      in the business. We have a really good
The safety training programs and             group of people facilitating our
services that are offered by Elite Safety    programs. They are very current and
Services Inc. are customized to meet the     still involved in field operations when
standards and needs in a variety of          they aren’t in the classroom. Our
sectors,  including        energy,           employees are definitely our biggest and
manufacturing, construction and              our best assets,” said Watt.
agricultural. Some of the programs           A main focus with Elite Safety
offered include confined space entry, fall   Services Inc. is to work with their clients
protection, H2S Alive, first aid,            to identify problem areas or issues that
WHMIS, tower climbing and rescue             could potentially prevent an accident
and defensive driving.                       from happening.
The recent move to their newly built         “That is the basis of what we do. We
facility at 1850-17th Street East, has       do everything in our power to make sure
allowed Elite Safety Services Inc. to        that you don’t have to call emergency]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Grow Your Businessat Sunrise Credit Union!

                           · BUSINESS MASTERCARD · BUYER PROTECTION & EXTENDED WARRANTY
                         · CANADA SMALL BUSINESS FINANCING PROGRAM · CHEQUING ACCOUNTS
       · COMMERCIAL LEASING · COMMERCIAL MORTGAGES · CUSTOMER AUTOMATED FUNDS TR ANSFER
             · DEPOSIT ANY WHERE® · DING FREE® ATMS · FINANCIAL PL ANNERS · FOREIGN EXCHANGE
                  · FRAUD PREVENTION · INTERAC E-TRANSFERS · INTERAC FL ASH® · LINES OF CREDIT
                 · LOAN & LINE OF CREDIT INSUR ANCE · MERCHANT SERVICES & PAYMENT SOLUTIONS
               · MOBILE APP: SUNRISE LITE · ONLINE TRADING · RECEIVE A WIRE · SAVINGS ACCOUNTS

                                                        · TERM DEPOSITS/GICS · TERM LOANS]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[16 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

Many facets to city’s economic development

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                  identify constraints or opportunities that our      here,” said Trudel.
                                                   local business have. And, depending on what           Another project that has been a focus for
  When it comes to economic development            is required, we may connect them with
for any city, region or town, there are often      resources or to other opportunities.                Trudel and her team is the development of
a lot of activities in various forms taking place  Sometimes it may be a matter of connecting          an industrial land marketing study, which
all at the same time. It is like juggling, but     them with other businesses that have a              includes property profiles and an online
with 12 balls, not just three.                     synergistic relationship. It’s important to help    presence, as well as an industrial land
                                                   existing businesses remain strong if we can,”       analysis.
  Sandy Trudel, director of economic               said Trudel.
development with the City of Brandon, said                                                               “In order to attract the type of industries
it’s important to invest time and effort in          Local businesses have also identified that        that bring new wealth to the city, you need
multiple areas of economic growth and to           it is sometimes difficult to attract skilled        industrial land. So, we did an analysis that
not just focus on one stream of activity.          professionals to the City of Brandon. Trudel        included supply and demand projections and
                                                   said that they’ve carefully planned some new        the identification of growth nodes. Most of
  “Economic growth isn’t just about                strategies to market the city as not only a         the industrial land in Brandon is privately
attracting new businesses to the region,           place of opportunity, but a place where             owned so we’re working to establish and
although that certainly is a big part of it. We    families can enjoy an excellent quality of life.    strengthen existing relationships with
like to keep a rounded pulse on what’s                                                                 landowners to determine how ready the land
happening in the economy. We tend to have            “Despite the unemployment rate being              is for development, availability timelines and
multiple ongoing projects in the works             higher than it historically is, we still regularly  to ensure there exists a mechanism to connect
whether that be working towards retention,         hear that businesses are struggling to fill         land options with those seeking a site,” said
attracting skilled workers, marketing, drawing     skilled professional positions. We have really      Trudel.
large events to the city, economic incentives      worked to enhance our community tours for
or something as simple as maintaining              perspective employees, partnered with                 “Attracting investment to a city is a very
relationships and developing advisory              companies to delve in and understand what           competitive process and in the business
groups,” said Trudel.                              their labour constraints are and we launched        world, time means money. Our goal is to
                                                   a new online job portal, which is                   centralize as many land options as possible
  An ongoing focus for Economic                    jobsinbrandon.ca. To go along with the job          to simplify marketing and to ensure investors
Development Brandon has been working on            portal, we’ve created an online lifestyle           don’t overlook the city simply because the
the retention of existing businesses that help     marketing campaign. We’re hoping that with          information wasn’t readily available. We want
to bring new wealth and have an overall            this new marketing initiative we’ve increased       them to know that we’re open for business.”
positive impact on the community.                  the chances of people choosing to move              » The Brandon Sun

  “With the work that we do in this area, we]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2016 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                       17

          Eight signs you need to take

a break from your business

BY BONI AND JOHN WAGNER-STAFFORD                             entrepreneurs for nearly 30 years. And she often warns       Barlow says there are two approaches to taking
                                                             about the business perils of not taking breaks.            breaks.
  Big ideas and small pockets, long to-do lists and short
of help.                                                       “When you’re on at work too long for too often, you      BUILDING THEM INTO YOUR DAY
                                                             drain your energy reserves — like a battery — and need
  It’s a recipe that can take 12 to 18 hours a day on full-  to recharge,” says Barlow, president of C3                   Do walk-and-talk meetings. Get out of the office.
throttle as you juggle the demands of human resources,       Communications. “The brain becomes fuzzy, unable           Move your body. The brain works better.
accounting and budgeting, sales, customer service,           to focus, the body becomes lethargic and the soul
webmaster and marketing.                                     becomes numb.”                                               Desk yoga: Every hour or so, stand up and stretch
                                                                                                                        your arms to the ceiling. Bend down and touch your
  If you’re one of those small business entrepreneurs          Operating a business while your brain and body are       toes. Turn side to side in your chair and twist your spine.
who feels the pressure of time and you don’t take breaks     in this suppressed state will affect your ability to make
for yourself, you are on a slippery slope toward             sound decisions. You won’t be able to step back out of       Take five-minute breaks — no calls, no email — and
ineffectiveness or, worse, a health crisis.                  the day-to-day minutiae to think about the big picture,    just breathe: inhale to count of four, hold for two, exhale
                                                             to set your vision and strategy or plan for the future.    for six.
  We’ve been there. When John owned his sound
production studio, Montage Multi-piste, in Montreal,           Here are a few signs you’re in this no-grow zone,        TAKING AN ACTUAL VACATION
he was responsible for sales, production, mixing,            simultaneously doing too much (at work) and doing
maintenance and money. Working 18 hours a day was            too little (no breaks):                                      It doesn’t have to be costly, try a staycation.
absolutely normal — until he ended up in hospital with                                                                    Put your email and phone away.
stress-related health issues and he saw the damage he          • Anxiety                                                  Read books, watch movies.
was doing.                                                     • Waking up in the wee hours of the night with worry       Let your right brain play: pull out your guitar or your
                                                             or stress                                                  paints.
  When Boni was a cub reporter and television anchor           • Loss of joy                                              Barlow stresses (no pun intended) the importance of
at a small station in Prince George, B.C., producing           • Loss of sense of humour                                leaving your work behind if you do take the family
and hosting a daily live talk show at 9:30 a.m., then          • Losing track of the status of projects                 away for a vacation.
anchoring live newscasts at noon, 3 and 5 p.m., her            • Making decisions that turn out poorly or that            If you take your work with you, “It’s no break at all,
boss would tell her she needed to get out of the             backfire                                                   in fact has counter effects. The smartphone negates the
newsroom for a break mid-day. She rarely did. Years            • Require several shots of espresso throughout the day   break, the family resents your absence, you feed your
later, Boni was diagnosed with fibromyalgia, a stress-         • You’re too busy to take a break.                       guilt machine, which further exacerbates the stress
related autoimmune disorder.                                   “Taking a break, a real break with no iPhone, emails     cycle.”
                                                             or laptop allows space for the right brain to emerge,        So add another important job to your long list of
  But you’re strong as an ox, right? Your health and         which is the creative, feeling part of you,” explains      responsibilities: director of self-care. Your body and
your immune system can hold up to that constant              Barlow. “Entering this space is what replenishes your      your business will love you for it.
pounding and self-driven pressure, right?                    battery.”                                                  » Troy Media

  That may be, but by not taking a break, you’re
harming your business, too.

  Cynthia Barlow has been coaching leaders and]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[18 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

  Sunrise cooks up perfect fundraising recipe

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                                                                     The end result is a     “Being locally owned and managed means the values
                                                                                                    beautiful 182-page      of the credit union reflect the values of its members.
Volunteering,                                                                                      cookbook with 357        It also means an emphasis on service. Our strength
sponsoring and                                                                                     tried and true recipes   and growth has allowed us to provide greater service
donating is all part                                                                               including everything     at a lower cost. Plus, the more we grow, the more we
of the culture at                                                                                 from appetizers and       can give back to the communities,” said marketing
Sunrise        Credit                                                                             salads to main dishes     manager Terri Roulette McCartney.
Union.                                                                                           and desserts.
In fact, since                                                                                       “A lot of care went      In addition to being strong community supporters,
forming in October                                                                               into this book. Prior to   Sunrise Credit Union continues to make technological
2008, the organization                                                                          publishing, some of our     advancements to strengthen their business. From being
has contributed more                                                                            staff held a potluck style  able to deposit a cheque anywhere simply by taking a
than $1 million in                                                                              lunch to give colleagues    photo of it, to paying for purchases using Interac Flash
sponsorships and                                                                               a chance to sample some      technology, Sunrise is making banking easier and more
donations to hundreds                                                                          of their recipes. Not only   secure than ever before.
of organizations. In                                                                          did this help get everyone
addition,      they’ve                                                                        excited about the project,      They are confident in the strength of their members
granted scholarships to                                                                       but trying out some of the    in each of the communities in which they serve and
more than 70 youth                                                                           dishes was a great way to      are committed to providing the best service, while
pursuing post-secondary                                                                      kick off the project,” said    giving back when they can.
education and provided                                                                       Lori Taylor, deposit and
more than 45,000 hours of employee volunteer time.         member service support at the Hartney branch.                      To purchase a cookbook, contact any of the 14
                                                               Last year alone, Sunrise Credit Union staff                  Sunrise Credit Union branches.
                                                           volunteered well over 7,500 hours of their personal              » The Brandon Sun
                                                           time helping communities and community
However, that is only the beginning.                       organizations deliver services that benefit their
Just recently Sunrise Credit Union announced that          members.
their staff from the 14 locations in southern Manitoba       Sunrise serves more than 20,000 members,
communities have published a cookbook to raise funds       providing personalized, competitive financial
for local organizations.                                   services with their 180 employees, coming
“From Our Family To Yours: Sunrise Staff Favourite         into existence after the
Recipes” is now available for purchase at all the Sunrise  amalgamation of
Credit Union branch offices.                               five credit
“Each Sunrise branch chose its own local project or        unions in
charitable organization to donate the proceeds to. It      2008. 
was important to our staff to keep all the money raised
from the sale of each book, working in and for each of
the local communities that Sunrise is a part of,” said
Tammy Gillis Waldon, office supervisor of the Cypress
River branch.
The concept for a cookbook was developed at a team-
building event where staff representing each Sunrise
community were asked to come up with an idea to
create something unique and to add value
and benefit to the communities in
which they live and work. ]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[TOP BRANDS

                                                                                  AND MORE!

         TRY BEFORE YOU BUY            LARGEST SELECTION OF PROJECTORS!

IN OUR STATE OF THE ART THEATRE ROOMS        UHD, SUHD, OLED, 4K, CURVED
                                                       AND FLAT TV'S!

 FREE PROFESSIONAL IN-STORE OR         BEST MOBILE, MARINE AUDIO & VIDEO!
ON-SITE CONSULTATIONS FOR HOME         ALPINE, JL AUDIO, WETSOUND, KICKER,

             OR BUSINESS!                  POWERBASS AND MUCH MORE!

             SHOP ONLINE 24/7 AT                                                                   FIRE HALL                                                    Maple Avenue
                                                                                                         19th Street N
    extremeelectronics.ca                                                                                         BRIDGE 18th Street N                        121-17th Street N
            or visit us at 121–17th Street North, Brandon                                                                  17th Street N                      Stickney Avenue
             204-728-7743 | Toll Free 1-855-623-2995
                                                                                                                                        Proudly 100% Canadian
HOURS: Monday to Wednesday 10am – 7pm, Thursday & Friday 10am – 9pm, Saturday & Sunday 10am – 6pm                                       Locally Owned & Operated]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[20 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

Ownership in company inspires Cando staff

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                          corporate shareholders.                                        internal motto — Cando is more than a job.
                                                             The Employee Ownership Program began in 1996                 Think career. Think ownership. — has truly
  Cando Rail Services, a local business                                                                                   inspired staff commitment and involvement.
established by Gord Peters and Rick Hammond                and is offered to all employees. Cando matches their
in 1978, has earned a reputation as industry               share purchases up to a certain amount each year. The             Cando’s charitable philosophy is also very
leaders in providing railway services over the             program aims to engage employees in the work they              evident in every community in which they are
last 39 years.                                             are doing and provides an opportunity to reward them           located. The company’s Cando Cares Fund is
                                                           for their hard work.                                           targeted at handing out one to 1.5 per cent of its
  What started out as a railway abandonment                                                                               pre-tax profits every year.
salvage and demolition company has diversified               As a result, when Cando employees from coast to
over the years to incorporate more services,               coast are asked the question, ‘Who owns Cando Rail                Taking an extra step to enhance employee
including Engineering and Track Services,                  Services?’, they can truly respond by saying, ‘We do’.         engagement, Cando asked its employees to rank
Industrial Rail Switching and Material                     With the success and growth of this program, Cando’s           the causes, local charities and community
Handling, Terminal and Transload Services,                                                                                initiatives they hold dearest. In addition,
Mechanical Services, Short Line Railway                                                                                   employee donations or fundraising campaigns
Operation, and Railcar Storage.                                                                                           are often matched by the company.

  Although Brandon is where the main office                                                                                  And in spite of the fact that virtually none of
is located, the company has more than 20                                                                                  its rail service work is conducted in Brandon,
locations across Canada and the United States.                                                                            Cando and its ownership remain fiercely loyal
Clients of the railway, oil and gas, manufacturing,                                                                       to its home base, a community which continues
agricultural, mining, forestry, and intermodal industries                                                          to offer an attractive work-life balance to entice and
look to them for their expertise and experience.                                                                   retain staff.
                                                                                                                     “Operating out of Brandon has become part of the
  With a staff of up to 500 in peak season, Cando                                                                  company’s story and culture,” said marketing and
employees range from rail line labourers, locomotive                                                               communications manager Julie Pomehichuk. “As we
engineers, welders, truck drivers to corporate office                                                              continue to grow and add to our committed team of
staff.                                                                                                             employee-owners, we will make sure they know where
                                                                                                                   the company’s roots are.”
  Part of the success of every business is its employees                                                           » The Brandon Sun
and that’s certainly the case with Cando. They take
pride in the fact that half of their employees are also]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[22 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

Hassle-free Elite sunroom ideal ‘staycation resort’

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                      20 years that they’ve been in the industry, and most lasting sunrooms that are virtually maintenance free.

                                                       of them say the only thing they would change is “they Plus, you can custom design your space so that it is
In today’s real estate market, it is important to      wish they built their sunroom sooner.”     tailored to the needs of you and your family.
maintain your home and it is also a good idea to take  “Everyone has their own reason for wanting to add As with many renovation projects, homeowners are
on home renovation projects that will increase the     an addition to their home. Some people are looking often reluctant to get started because of the time and
value. Adding a three-season sunroom not only          for a cozy place to relax, others a bigger space to energy involved to get the job done. With Elite
increases the value, it also gives you more space and  entertain, but whatever the reason a                                        Sunrooms, they try to minimize the
years of enjoyment.                                    sunroom offers families so much more than                                   hassle for the homeowner.
Peter Behrens and Keith Bourgeois are co-owners        just the additional space,” Behrens said.  “Adding a sunroom is a             “Keith and I do it all. We get the

                     of Elite Sunrooms.                Sunrooms can provide homeowners                                             permit, we do the foundation and we
                     They  have                        with more privacy and allow them to                                         do the entire installation. We don’t
                     worked with                       spend more time in their backyards         lot less expensive than          have crews working for us and that’s

                           many                        without pesky mosquitoes and other bugs,   buying or building a             on purpose. We’re hands-on guys and
                           clients                     while at the same time enjoying the great                                   homeowners often don’t want a
                           over                        outdoors — even if it’s raining, windy or                                   bunch of tradespeople coming
                           the                         scorching hot. Behrens said some of their                                   through. Our clients are quite happy
                                                       customers have referred to their sunrooms  cabin or travelling.”            when they hear that we’ll personally
                                                       as their staycation resort.                                                 be handling the project,” Behrens
                                                                                                                  » Peter Behrens

                                                       “Adding a sunroom is a lot less                                             said.
                                                       expensive than buying or building a cabin or Installation of a custom sunroom generally takes
                                                       travelling. People are so busy these days, they one week. Add the furniture and within no time at
                                                       don’t even have time for a vacation and all, your living space is enhanced, and you’ve added
                                                       that’s why so many have found the functionality and beauty to your home.
                                                       option of a sunroom to be the best “Things are so different now. Twenty years ago, not
                                                       bang for their buck,” Behrens said. many people had sunrooms, so we spent a lot more
                                                       Elite Sunrooms has been a time on promotions, going to trades shows and
                                                       proud dealer for Sunspace, a educating people on the benefits. Now you see so
                                                       Canadian manufacturing many, people are familiar with them and once they
                                                       company, for as long as decide that it’s the right option for their family, it’s just
                                                       they’ve been in a matter of design,” Behrens said.
                                                       business. They Elite Sunrooms is conveniently located at 1840-18th
                                                       provide high Street, right within Windsor Plywood. Visit
                                                                                               quality, long- sunspacesunrooms.com for more information.

                                                                                                                                          » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2016 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                                              23

How small businesses can compete in a world of giants

  Small businesses are often seen        the potential to create a connection with  2. NICHE MARKET FOCUS                                larger counterparts. You have the
to be at a disadvantage when             each customer, providing an                                                                     opportunity to work directly
compared to their big box                unmatchable service experience to keep       When small businesses focus their                  with customers to meet their
competitors – but Industry Canada        customers coming back again and            efforts on a specific niche, they can offer          individual needs.
statistics show that small               again.                                     a high-quality product superior to their
businesses make up over 80 per                                                                                                         3. QUICK ADAPTATION
cent of Canadian exporters, and
almost half of private sector GDP.                                                                                                          Less red tape and a smaller
                                                                                                                                         team makes room for
  “Small businesses are the                                                                                                              innovation. Small businesses can
backbone of the Canadian                                                                                                                 quickly change direction in
economy,” explains Paul                                                                                                                  response to adversity or
Brousseau, vice-president of brand                                                                                                       opportunity, giving you a leg up
communications at Yellow Pages.                                                                                                          in areas like new media and
“Supporting small business                                                                                                               customer demand.
benefits all of us and an easy way
to do just that is to make local                                                                                                       4. OFFER PROMOTIONS
purchases and keep dollars close
to home.”                                                                                                                                   Deals aren't just for the big
                                                                                                                                         guys and small business
  Brousseau shares four ways                                                                                                             promotions don't have to
small businesses can compete in a                                                                                                        undercut chain stores.
world of giants and attract local                                                                                                        Sometimes a gift with purchase
shoppers:                                                                                                                                or a 2 for 1 can go a long way.
                                                                                                                                         Apps like YP Shopwise can be a
1. UNBEATABLE CUSTOMER                                                                                                                   great way to promote local deals.
SERVICE                                                                                                                          » News Canada

  Big box stores can often be
impersonal, but smaller businesses have

                108 – 18th Street                                                   Eleanor McCallum  Daryl Martens              Brian Canart    Michele Clouthier
                                                                                      204-726-9851     204-725-6288              204-724-2779      204-573-5120
                                                                                          Broker                                                     Residential
                                                                                                        Residential               Residential

Jared Jacobson  Donna Fletcher            Vonda Bos       Rebecca Ellchuk           Grant McKelvy     Murray Melnyk              Mike Kufflick   Jim McLachlan
204-761-0028     204-522-0826            204-648-7785       204-730-0987             204-476-6260      204-725-5858               204-721-1347    204-724-7753
                Waskada/Melita                                Residential                                Residential             Cottage & Lake   Farm & Rural
  Residential                               Dauphin                                     Neepawa

Anko Sweep      Rick Taylor              Wayne Robertson  Lloyd Carruthers          Terri Cosens      Glen Kirkland              Robin Lussier   Amanda Day
204-761-0554    204-867-7551                204-534-8177    204-851-0525            204-748-7699       204-720-1235              204-720-1494    204-721-2728
Farm & Rural    Farm & Rural                  Boissevain         Virden                                Residential
                                                                                        Virden                                     Residential    Residential

www.homelifepro.com No one treats you like the folks at Home!
                                                                                                            Residential, Condos, Farms, Commercial, Lake Properties]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Thank You Westman!

                     PROUDLY SERVING YOU

             --- Since 1979 ---

                                                                                                 Start Earning Today!

                                                                                                 Dealer#1597

                               FOR MORE INFORMATION VISIT OUR WEBSITE AT WWW.PRECISIONTOYOTA.CA

404 – 18th Street North, Brandon • 204-725-0508 • 1-888-725-0508 • sales@precisiontoyota.ca

  204 -727-8585

    1807 Pacific Avenue, Brandon
Email: trevor@advanceautobody.net]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[204.727.2727 (ASAP)

360 - 10th Street • Open 4pm-Midnight Daily

Thank you Westman         @pizzaexpressbdn

  for 34 years of    ✁
  loyal patronage.
                      Customer
                    Appreciation

                    COUPON

                    $5OFFONFOODORDERS
                                  OF $30 OR MORE
                                            PICK UP OR DELIVERY ONLY

                          Mention coupon when ordering. Not valid with any
                          other promotion. One coupon per customer per visit.

                                        Offer expires November 6, 2016

ORDER ONLINE www.pizzaexpress.biz]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2016 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                  27

The Vasilarakis family (L-R): Gus, Antoinette, Popi, Ayla, Brittany, Tony, Christos. (Submitted)

 Family business thrives thanks to quality, service

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                           “We have people of different ages, different           Brandon University, Assiniboine Community College,
                                                          nationalities, different cultures and different          Westman Immigrant Services, Westman Dreams for
  Pizza Express has been in business since 1982. As       educational backgrounds all thrown together to make      Kids, the Brandon Music and Jazz Festival, several
we move into 2017, they will be celebrating 35 years      a dream team. It’s about as diverse as a group of        community after school programs and community
in business.                                              people as you’ll likely ever see and we love it,” Tony   centre programs, Brandon United Way, Canadian
                                                          said.                                                    Cancer Society Brandon and Area Division and
  The current management team is made up of Gus                                                                    countless other community initiatives.
and Antoinette Vasilarakis along with their son Tony        “Much like our amazing customer base, we would
and his wife Brittany. Gus’s other son, Christos, and     not be around if it were not for the our incredible        “Whether it be through donations or prizes,
his daughter Popi are also a part of the management       employees. We are grateful to the current Pizza          volunteering or showing young kids how to make
team.                                                     Express staff, but we would also like to thank to the    pizza, it’s always been important to us to be involved
                                                          hundreds of former employees who have helped make        in these kinds of programs,” said Gus.
  It has always been a family affair at Pizza Express     Pizza Express such a success.”
with all members of the Vasilarakis family being                                                                     “We’re also heavily involved in sporting
involved. In 1979, at the age of 14, Gus moved to           Although the restaurant sports a fresh new look, an    sponsorships. With three kids involved in multiple
Brandon from a small island in the southern part of       updated menu and plenty of new faces, things really      sports, it made it easy for us to get involved and
Greece with his family. A few years later his parents,    haven’t changed that much. With all the changes in       sponsor a wide variety of local youth and adult sports
Antonios and Kalliopi Vasilarakis and brother Nick,       the food service industry along with the changes in      teams, the Brandon Wheat Kings, Special Olympics,
opened Pizza Express in Brandon.                          the city of Brandon, Pizza Express has stayed deeply     as well as individual player sponsorship for
                                                          committed to its two simple founding principles: to      underprivileged children.”
  “Pizza Express has been in business for over three      provide consistent, unique, handmade, high quality
decades and is now into its third generation of original  food and excellent customer service.                       The thoughtful owners also make a point of catering
family owners. Considering today’s food service                                                                    to the many service workers in Brandon — those who
industry, with large corporate restaurants dominating       “We truly care about our customers, our employees      work at the hospital, fire department, police station
the marketplace, we’re very proud, happy and              and our product and strive to provide excellence,” said  and correctional centre. As a small token of their
humbled to keep the family business successfully          Tony.                                                    appreciation, they send complimentary pizzas to these
running for as long as we have,” said Tony Vasilarakis.                                                            places on a monthly basis.
                                                            Brandon has and always will be home for the
  The Vasilarakis family welcomed its newest addition     Vasilarakis family and as such Pizza Express has           “We can’t express how grateful we are that this
as Tony and Brittany had a baby July named Ayla.          always focused on community involvement.                 community has embraced our family and our business.
Although very young, Ayla is already calling all the                                                               We are very fortunate and would like to extend our
shots in the Vasilarakis family and has taken her spot      “Brandon has provided a safe, friendly and             thanks to our faithful and die-hard Pizza Express
at the top of Pizza Express management team. With         welcoming environment for us to raise our family. The    customers for their patronage and overwhelming
any luck she will become the fourth generation of         community has always been incredibly supportive of       support over the years.”
original family owners of the restaurant.                 Pizza Express and our family and we love this city, it
                                                          has given us so much,” said Gus Vasilarakis.               Look for their Customer Appreciation coupon in
  Pizza Express currently employs 40 full-time and                                                                 their advertisement found within this publication.
part-time staff and has a diverse group of employees        As such, Pizza Express has been involved with a        » The Brandon Sun
from many different walks of life.                        number of community programs and initiatives. They
                                                          have worked with the Brandon School Division,]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[28 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

From left Dr. Joe Gray DVM, Dr. Jennifer Beckwith DVM and Dr. Vicky Sempers DVM, MRCVS . (The Brandon Sun)

From cows to cats, clinic provides compassionate care

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                       a partnership to share the workload and responsibility    medical, surgical, orthopedic and dental services.
                                                        of running the clinic,” said Dr. Sempers.                 They have a surgical suite with all the latest
  The Grand Valley Animal Clinic has been part of                                                                 technology, as well as an in-house lab. With their
the Brandon business community for well over 20           “It really seemed like a natural progression. Both      advanced equipment, they are able to do digital and
years. In that time, they’ve treated and cared for      myself and Jenn have been here for quite some time        dental X-rays, perform endoscope procedures and
countless number of precious pets and farm animals.     and we’ve been involved in seeing it and helping it       do ultrasounds.
                                                        grow, so it seemed like a natural, logical step.”
  “Pets and, of course, livestock are so important to                                                               “We just recently invested in a new ultrasound
people. We pride ourselves on having not only             Dr. Sempers has been part of clinic since 2008 and      machine that Dr. Beckwith uses, which is so accurate
experienced and well-trained staff, but also people     Dr. Beckwith started a year earlier in 2007. By           and helpful. She’s able to do echocardiograms, as
who are passionate and considerate to animals,” said    sharing managerial and administrative duties, the         well as more routine tests like abdominal ones and
Dr. Vicky Sempers, owner and partner of Grand           partners will be able to offer even better service to     such,” said Dr. Sempers.
Valley Animal Clinic.                                   their clients.
                                                                                                                    In addition to all the services they provide, the
  The clinic at 304 Pacific Avenue has a significantly    “We all work very closely together, so it’s a positive  clinic also carries a wide range of regular and
sized team of 24 employees and is pleased to recently   change. Dr. Gray really wanted to get back to             specialty dog and cat food, plus an assortment of pet
welcome some new and returning staff to the clinic.     working with clients and doing what he wanted to          accessories.
                                                        do, which was being a vet and not be entirely focused
  The clinic has undergone other changes as well        on the management side of the business. We grew             With 24 hour a day, seven days a week on-call
this year. Dr. Joe Gray had been the sole owner for     quite quickly — I’m not sure how he’s managed it          services, extended hours during the week and
a number of years; however, he’s pleased to announce    on his own for all these years,” said Dr. Sempers.        weekend hours, it’s easy to see that the Grand Valley
that as of January 2016 he’s formed a partnership                                                                 Animal Clinic team is caring and compassionate and
with both Dr. Sempers and Dr. Jenn Beckwith.              The Grand Valley Animal Clinic is a full-service        that they do what they can to provide the best service
                                                        animal hospital. They treat all kinds of small and        possible.
  “We’ve expanded so much in the past few years.        large animals, including cows, horses, sheep, cats,       » The Brandon Sun
The clinic is three or four times the size from when    dogs, ferrets, guinea pigs and snakes.
I came here, so we thought it was a good idea to form
                                                          The clinic offers both emergency as well as routine]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[1850 – 17th Street East Brandon, MB                                   OWNERS,
                                                         DARREN BRICK & MARC WATT

CONFINED SPACE TRAINER          Protect your Company

                        Elite Safety Services Inc. regularly provides programs and services
                        across Western Canada. In addition to our safety programs, we
                        specialize in turnaround safety, technical rescue, onsite paramedic
                        services, and specialized staff. Our experience and our staff are
                        second to none!

      CLASSROOMS                 TRAINING                     FIELD SERVICES
ROPE ACCESS SERVICES
                        • Confined Space Entry & Rescue  • Confined Space Rescue
                        • Fall Protection & Rescue       • High Angle Rescue
                        • Confined Space NFPA 1006       • Rope Access Services
                        • Rope Rescue NFPA 1016          • Confined Space Management
                        • Spill Response                 • Company Safety Programs
                        • TDG & WHMIS                    • Safety Watch / Fire Watch
                        • Enform H2S Alive               • Air Monitoring / Air Trailers
                        • Global Ground Disturbance      • Construction Safety Officers
                        • Respiratory Protection         • Paramedics
                        • Red Cross First Aid & CPR      • Drug & Alcohol / Fit Testing
                        • Elevated Work Platforms        • Full Turnaround / Shutdown
                        • Scaffolding Awareness
                        • Forklift Training                 Safety Services

DRUG & ALCOHOL TESTING  Visit our website for more information on services and courses available.

877-726-9101 www.elitesafetyservices.ca]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[30 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

The Coolsculpting procedure permanently removes fat from a variety of areas on the face and body. (Submitted)

Services, treatment at Kelleher clinic state-of-the-art

BY WANDA KURCHABA                         results because it induces your own       gynecologist Dr. Bernie Helms to          lines, even out skin tone, treat acne or
                                          collagen into the treated areas, so the   provide laser ablation that can help      acne scarring), as well as for the
  Staying on top of industry trends and   results last longer,” said Dr. Kelleher.  restore gynecological health.             removal of moles, skin tags and warts
changes is a priority for Dr. Barb                                                                                            with minimal scarring.
Kelleher. It’s been 10 years since she      In addition, she and her team have        “This is an amazing machine
first opened her own clinic and she has   added Microblading to their list of       (FemiLift) that we use for women with       Dr. Kelleher’s Laser, Skin and Vein
continually found new and exciting        popular services. Microblading is a       stress urinary incontinence, recurring    Clinic also has a variety of other
services to offer her clients.            type of permanent makeup that helps       yeast infections, for vaginal dryness in  specialized services to help you look
                                          to jazz up or create new eyebrows for     menopause, or if they are experiencing    amazing. They also offer Botox,
  Just recently, Dr. Kelleher’s Laser,    those that have thin or non-existent      painful intercourse or bladder leakage.   Juvederm, hydradermabrasion, laser
Skin and Vein Clinic at 1300-18th         ones.                                     It’s a fast procedure that can help to    hair removal, photo skin rejuvenation,
Street, has introduced two new services                                             improve these problems without            microdermabrasion, sclerotherapy,
and re-introduced another procedure         “A lot of women start to lose their     surgery,” said Dr. Kelleher.              echosclerotherapy and permanent fat
called Sculptra.                          eyebrows or have very thin brows that                                               reduction using CoolSculpting.
                                          they colour in all the time. This tattoo    The FemiLift is a pixel CO2 laser
  Sculptra is a minimally invasive        fills in the eyebrows and makes it look   attachment that is safe, effective,         With years of experience and
treatment that targets the loss of        like individual hairs — it’s quite        minimally invasive and doesn’t require    expertise, Dr. Kelleher and her
collagen, which is one of the             impressive and it looks really quite      post-treatment downtime, which is one     professional team pride themselves in
underlying causes of facial aging.        natural,” said Dr. Kelleher.              of the biggest advantages.                offering exceptional service to all of
                                                                                                                              their clients by staying up-to-date and
  “It is an alternative to fillers and      As she began her career as a general      The machine also has a second           current in terms on industry trends,
almost like a non-surgical facelift. The  practitioner at the Western Medical       purpose. With a different wand, Dr.       technological advances and training.
targeted areas include the cheeks,        Clinic in 1991, Dr. Kelleher has close    Kelleher will also use the pixel CO2      » The Brandon Sun
nasolabial folds, the chin, lower jaw or  connections to the medical industry       laser attachment for laser resurfacing
temples. Our clients are loving the       and as such has partnered with local      of the face and neck (to help with fine]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[BRANDON HILLS                                       Brandon Hills Veterinary Clinic is a full-service veterinary
             VETERINARY CLINIC                                   facility serving Brandon for 50 years. Our professional and
                                                                 courteous team seeks to provide the best possible medical,
           Dr. Maria Fuchs, Dr. Jay Thrush & Dr. Colleen Fisher  surgical, and dental care for our patients.We are committed
                                                                 to responsible pet ownership, preventive health care,
                                                                 proper pet nutrition and educational opportunities for our
                                                                 staff.

                                                                 We are dedicated to providing our patients, clients, and
                                                                 community with exceptional care in a competent,
                                                                 compassionate environment.

                                                                 We provide:

                                                                   • Routine Wellness tailored to meet your
                                                                     pet’s individual needs

                                                                   • Surgical Services, including Laser
                                                                     Surgery

                                                                   • Companion Therapy Laser
                                                                   • Dentistry and Digital Dental X-ray
                                                                   • Diagnostic Services
                                                                   • Orthopedic Surgery
                                                                   • Endoscopy
                                                                   • We are Brandon’s only AAHA

                                                                     accredited clinic

Catherine  Trudy  Kaley Vanessa  Carol                           Samantha   Justine    Arla   Angela

Emily Alison Cadence Barb                                        Taylor F.  Taylor B.  Jenna  Amanda

733 – 17th Street, Brandon | 204-728-2292

bvhc.recp@wcgwave.ca | www.brandonhillsvetclinic.com]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[32 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

                    You’re ready for your video interview.
                       What could possibly go wrong?

A video interview is a professional conversation, so no pets, no babies,
no technical glitches — and no workmen sawing in the background

BY CAROL KINSEY GOMAN                                                                                                        • Be proactive. If your computer needs rebooting, make
                                                                                                                           sure you do that before the interview. Shutting down programs
  Don’t like being interviewed on video? Prefer an in-                                                                     you don’t need during the call avoids possible alerts or pop-
person meeting?                                                                                                            ups and keeps your computer from getting bogged down. A
                                                                                                                           wired connection is better than a wireless connection. Make
  Chris Brown, vice-president of human resources at                                                                        sure your audio quality is strong. A headset works best.
West Corp., says you’re out of luck — video
interviewing is here to stay. That means learning to                                                                         • Share large and important files beforehand. If you plan
avoid the pitfalls of virtual interaction.                                                                                 to share or go over big files with the interviewer, send them
                                                                                                                           in advance. Not only will this help you prepare, it will reduce
  So I asked Brown for some tips.                                                                                          the likelihood that pieces get lost while on the call.

  Question: Can you tell me how to best prepare for                                                                          • Skip the free conference call services. While free services
the technical glitches that can derail an interview.                                                                       can seem very appealing, free generally means low quality
                                                                                                                           and inconsistency, which can leave a bad impression. Trusted
  Brown: Here are a few basic steps:                                                                                       providers not only own the infrastructure they operate, they
  • Give yourself plenty of time to set up and test meeting                                                                operate at fractional capacity to ensure peak times are covered
equipment. To make sure your technology is compatible, do                                                                  and service delivery is consistent.
a dry run. Video call a friend and test out the clarity and
sound. Calling into the interview early also gives you the                                                                                                             » Continued on Page 33
chance to make sure all equipment is working properly. Giving
yourself an extra few minutes will help you feel more calm
and confident.

The Wood That Made                                                                                  Buying a
       Us Famous                                                                                    Home?

                                                                                                           Purchase any MLS listed property                                             CASH BACK
                                                                                                      (LISTED WITH ANY REAL ESTATE COMPANY)                                              REWARD
                                                                                                                                                                                        PROGRAM
                                                                                                       and receive 20% of our co-operating

                                                                                                        agent commission after closing and our
                                                                                                            commission has been received.
                                                                                                             NO STRINGS ATTACHED

                                                                                                    EXAMPLE:

                                                                                                    * Using our services, purchase a home for $260,000.00.
                                                                                                    * The listing agents pays us a commission rate of 2.5%.
                                                                                                    * 2.5% of $260,000.00 = $6,500.00 our commission.
                                                                                                    * 20% of $6,500.00 = $1,300.00 your

                                                                                                     Cash Back Reward.

                                                                                                    ***Purchase a house worth $400,000 or more and receive 25% of our earned
                                                                                                    co-operating agent commission after closing and our commission has been received.
                                                                                                    *** The CASH BACK REWARD PROGRAM is not intended to solicit clients under
                                                                                                    contract.
                                                                                                    NOTE: Cash back amounts will vary as it is indicative of the commission rate being
                                                                                                    offered by the listing agent. Commission rates being offered to selling agents in
                                                                                                    Brandon typically range from 1.5% to 3.5%. Our Cash Back Program does not require
                                                                                                    any fee be paid by a prospective buyer.

1840 – 18TH STREET NORTH, BRANDON • 204-728-4243                                                    SCOTT ROUIRE           BRETT MCDOUGALL

Fax: 204-727-2619 • Toll-Free: 1-800-224-7506 • www.windsorplywood.com                              OWNER/BROKER/REALTOR®                  REALTOR®
sales@windsorplywood.net
                                                                                                     204.724.0469              204.724.7278
Store Hours: Mon. – Fri. 7:30 am – 6:00 pm; Sat. 8:00 am – 5:00 pm
                                                                                                    SELLING? CALL FOR YOUR FREE HOME EVALUATION
Some items may be cash & carry and we reserve the right to limit quantities. All items may not             www.commission-rebate-realty.com
be exactly as illustrated. At Windsor, we strive for accuracy, however if a print error occurs, it
will be corrected through notification to our stores. Rainchecks may be issued depending on
stock availability.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2016 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                            33

« Continued from Page 32                                                questions, you need to think about what other people in the hiring
  • Work through glitches. If glitches are minor, try to ignore them    process might want to hear from you. And if you are asked back
                                                                        for a second round, don’t be surprised if you are asked to expand
and keep moving forward. However, if technology problems are            on something you said previously. So be prepared.
blatant and preventing effective communication, acknowledge and
apologize for the issue. If video is giving you trouble, try switching    Question: I understand the importance of impression
to audio only. And make sure you have the number for tech support       management in any interview. How is this different in
at hand. Do your best to keep talking while they work to fix problems.  a virtual setting?

  • Always have an alternative way to connect. Share your contact         Brown: Just as in a face-to-face interview, first impressions
info with your interviewer beforehand. That way, your interviewer       matter. A lot. That’s why you need to be technically connected
can reach you in case technical glitches prevent the interview from     early. If you are late, the interviewer’s perception is that you are
going as planned.                                                       not prepared - or you simply don’t care. And an interviewer is
                                                                        impressed when it is apparent that you have done your homework
  Question: What’s the most annoying technical mistake                  and can subtly display your knowledge of the company’s history,
an applicant has made in an interview with you?                         value proposition or recent product announcement. Remember
                                                                        to speak to the camera and not the picture so that you’ll give the
  Brown: One applicant scheduled the interview while his house          impression of making eye contact. Smile. HR professionals want
was being renovated and we had to pause several times due to the        prospective employees to be upbeat and display good, positive
noise of workman cutting drywall. Although he apologized, it was        energy.
irritating because I felt as though he thought so little of my time
that he couldn’t be bothered to make other arrangements.                  Question: Is there anything you want to add?
                                                                          Brown: Just because you’re conducting the interview in your
  Question: Where should we set up our computer for the                 home, don’t treat it lightly. Be genuine, be yourself, but don’t get
interview?                                                              sloppy. This is a business meeting. Look like a professional. Dress
                                                                        and conduct yourself as you would if the setting were more
  Brown: A plain background works best. Also be aware of the            corporate.
lighting — and how it may change during the day. And no pets or
babies, please.                                                         » Carol Kinsey Goman, PhD, is an executive coach, consultant, and in-
                                                                        ternational keynote speaker at corporate, government, and associa-
  Question: What else should a candidate prepare for?                   tion events.
  Brown: I think the No. 1 thing to keep in mind is that unlike an      » Troy Media
in-person interview, where a hand-written note is all the evidence
of what you said, this is being recorded. You need to anticipate that
your interview will be shared with others. When you answer

             Got
           Big Plans?

                                  Call us!

                               FARM, RESIDENTIAL & COMMERCIAL
                                        PROPERTY APPRAISERS

                                                                           SINCE 1977

Roland Weir Appraisal Associates

                     Suite 30A, 1015 – 26th Street, Brandon
                      204-727-7100 Fax: 204-727-1563

                                    weir1@mts.net]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[34 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

When furry friend is ailing, run for the Brandon Hills

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                              In addition, there is a full team of medical             pet owners on preventative health care so as to avoid
                                                             receptionists, veterinary assistants and registered        problems in the future.
  We love our pets. In fact, according to 2014 statistics    animal health technicians to help care for and treat the
from the Canadian Pet Market Outlook, almost 60 per          animals. For farm animal care, Dr. Trevor Shamanski          As such, they offer food and nutrition counselling,
cent of the Canadian population own pets. At a local         operates Rover T. Mobile Vet out of the clinic as well.    wellness exams, have puppy and kitten packages that
level, Dr. Jay Thrush says that statistic is likely similar                                                             include important information for new pet owners and
in this part of the country as well.                           In terms of small animal care, the clinic offers a full  they strongly encourage proper dental care.
                                                             range of medical and surgical services, including laser
  “There do seem to be a lot of pet owners in Brandon.       surgery, ultrasound, dentistry and laser therapy. While      “About 80 per cent of pets over three years of age
Certainly, the people that we come into contact with         the majority of their patients tend to be dogs and cats,   have some sort of dental issue and this is simply
have a very high regard for their pets. The majority of      they also have a lot of experience working with other      because they don’t brush their teeth every day like we
our clients view their pets as a member of their family      pets such birds, rabbits, ferrets, hamsters and other      do. There’s a strong correlation between dental health
and want to make sure they are properly looked after,”       more exotic species.                                       and other health issues, just like there is with humans,”
said Dr. Thrush.                                                                                                        said Dr. Thrush.
                                                               “We do get a little bit of wildlife through our doors
  Since our furry and feathered friends are so near and      as well. It’s mostly birds, but we have had things like      As a locally owned clinic, Dr. Thrush is involved
dear to our hearts, it is important that they do get the     squirrels and raccoons, and even porcupines. It’s often    with community events and organizations related to
proper care that they need and that’s where the              animals that Manitoba Conservation brings in or ones       animals and does what he can to give back to the
Brandon Hills Veterinary Clinic at 733-17th Street can       that we get other calls on. They get triaged and treated   community. He’s proud to support the Brandon
help.                                                        as necessary and then we send them to a wildlife rehab     Humane Society, Strays That Can’t Pay and other
                                                             centre near Winnipeg,” said Dr. Thrush.                    rescue type organizations that are in this part of the
  Dr. Thrush has been with the clinic for 23 years, but                                                                 province. As well, when requested, they will do school
just recently became the sole owner. He’s pleased to           While they do spend time dealing with emergencies        visits and host clinic tours.
have two other veterinarians, Dr. Maria Fuchs and Dr.        and existing health issues, Dr. Thrush and his             » The Brandon Sun
Colleen Fisher, also working alongside him.                  experienced team also believe it’s important to guide]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[2 FULL-SIZE

SUNROOMS ON DISPLAY!

  The Weather Master®                      We specialize in building quality
     Window System                      sunrooms and patios designed to fit

        We can supply 3-season              your budget and your lifestyle.
   Do-It-Yourself windows for your      Your sunroom will be custom built for you.
   existing outdoor patio, verandah,
                                            Please allow 4-6 weeks for delivery.
            sunroom or cabin.            Foundations to finishing – we do it all!

         We carry the exclusive         Peter Behrens
      Weather Master® Vertical        & Keith Bourgeois
    Four Track Window System
   which opens from top or bottom              www.sunspacesunrooms.com
                                                    www.elitesunrooms.ca
       & allows 75% ventillation.

  • FREE ESTIMATES •

      1840 - 18th St N

  in the Windsor Plywood building

   204-726-8488

email : sales@elitesunrooms.ca]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[36 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

 Crocus beefs up business buying insurance agency

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                       this locally owned insurance agency when they are         on new debt, especially if your cash flow is tight.
                                                        in looking to get a mortgage, a car loan or opening       With any new payments, they will likely rise if and
  When it comes to banking and insurance, you can       a new business. Phillips Insurance Agency Ltd. is         when the interest rates do go up,” said Guist.
count on Crocus Credit Union to find the right          located at B-510 First Street, they are open Monday
solutions for your personal and business needs.         through Friday from 8:30 a.m. until 5 p.m.                  For more information on their services or to talk
                                                                                                                  with an account representative, visit their website at
  This local credit union has recently made an            “It is crucial for our credit union to find ways to     crocuscu.mb.ca or call 204-729-4800.
advantageous purchase in July and acquired 70 per       increase and diversify our revenue streams away           » The Brandon Sun
cent of Phillips Insurance Agency Ltd. in Brandon,      from just loan interest. The purchase of this
with the remaining 30 per cent to be purchased in       insurance agency will go some distance towards
stages beginning in January 2017. This additional       allowing Crocus to achieve both of these goals,” said
service goes hand-in-hand with the personalized         Guist.
service that they offer their 3,800 members.
                                                          The company prides itself on providing excellent
  Arnie Guist, the company’s chief executive officer,   service to their membership and one of their guiding
has worked in the financial industry for more than      principles is to give back. For their members
35 years. While his experience in the early years of    this comes in the form of competitive loans,
his career was with chartered banks, he’s spent the     investment rates and service charges; for the
last 22 years in the credit union system.               community it involves donations
                                                        and volunteer hours.
  The acquisition of Phillips Insurance Agency Ltd.
is part of a planned business growth plan.                Crocus Credit Union employs a
                                                        staff of 25 within its two branches at 1016
  “With interest rates at an all time low, many credit  Rosser Avenue and 742 18th Street in the Thomas
unions are looking for new business lines,              Mall, with an ATM available at both locations. They
streamlining operations or looking for alternative      have been serving Brandon and surrounding
ways to increase profitability. Crocus Credit Union     communities since 1952 and are committed to
is excited about this new venture and we’re pleased     helping you meet your financial goals.
to expand our service offerings to our membership,
as well increase and diversify our net income,” said      “With interest rates being so low at the present
Guist.                                                  time, it is likely that they will increase over the next
                                                        few years. People should take caution when taking
  Crocus Credit Union members can be referred to

  WE DRY CLEAN
            SUITS

          SHIRTS
         BLAZERS
        BLOUSES
        DRESSES

  AND WE CLEAN
   COMFORTERS
 SLEEPING BAGS
JACKETS/COATS

      SWEATERS
       CURTAINS

     WE ALSO DO
       MENDING!

BRANDON CLEANERS OPEN
                                                               MON. – FRI.

349 – 9th Street | 204-571-3033 7:00AM – 5:30PM]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2016 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                                                             37

       Five tips for launching a business
               in the digital age

  Today there are more opportunities        2. WRITE A BUSINESS PLAN                  5. CONNECT ON SOCIAL MEDIA              which social media channels your
than ever for people to start a business.                                                                                     customers are most likely to use and
While many entrepreneurs still open           Studies have shown that owners who        Social media is a great way to reach  connect with them.
businesses in fixed locations, more         create a business plan have a better      your target audience while saving       » News Canada
people are launching businesses that        chance of success. By developing a        money on advertising. Think about
operate entirely online.                    business plan you ensure everyone
                                            involved is on the same page to set
  “While the traditional tips for           priorities, establish goals and create a
starting a business still apply,            strategy for execution.
entrepreneurs can't ignore how
important having an online presence is      3. DETERMINE YOUR FINANCIAL
to the success of their business,” says     NEEDS
Sarah Adams, vice-president of Small
Business at RBC.                              Assess your start-up costs, calculate
                                            your cash flow needs, and figure out
  Adams offers five tips for launching      how long it will take to break-even.
a business in a digitally connected         Create scenarios to find out if you have
world:                                      the funds you need.

1. RESEARCH YOUR MARKET                     4. BUILD YOUR WEB SITE

  While it may be tempting to ask             To continue to find new customers,
family and friends for input on your        grow your business and remain
product or service, to truly understand     competitive your business needs to be
if your idea is viable, it is best to talk  online, and that means creating a web
to your target audience.                    site.

                                                                         UNDER NEW OWNERSHIP

                                                                         Chris and Carla Simard of Kemnay MB,               assembly line chain stores to meet peoples
                                                                                                                            fast paced needs, however the foundation of
                                                                         both born and raised in rural Manitoba. Chris      Superior Auto has always been friendly
                                                                                                                            personal service and trust. The shop is setup
                                                                         is from St.Lazare and Carla from Plumas.           in such a way that Chris or Carla will answer
                                                                                                                            your call, book the appointment, order the
                                                                         They both attended ACC with Chris taking           parts, price out the estimates, and collect
                                                                                                                            payment for service. No need to talk to
                                                                         the Automotive Technologies course and Carla       several different people in the process. Nothing
                                                                                                                            gets lost in the translation and the guy on
                                                                         taking the Medical Transcription course. They      the phone has his finger on what’s going on
                                                                                                                            with your vehicle at all times. What you can
                                                                         were married in 1998 and moved to Melita           expect is one of four Journeyman Technicians
                                                                                                                            to do your vehicles repair from a simple bulb
                                                                         to start a family. Chris worked as an automotive   change, tire plug, to a large complicated
                                                                                                                            repair procedure. When the time crunch is
                                                                         mechanic at Southwest Pontiac training as a        on everyone pitches in together and gets it
                                                                                                                            done. This is what you get in a healthy
                                                                         factory GM technician. After having two boys       environment where people get along and are
                                                                                                                            happy in the workplace. They have the ability
                                                                         Evan and Matthew they moved to Brandon             and certifications to do glass repair, air
                                                                                                                            conditioning, install complex remote start
                                                                         for more opportunities. Chris settled in at        systems, wheel alignments, MPI certified
                                                                                                                            accident repair, extended warranty repairs,
                                                                         Superior Auto in mid- 2003. Then came a            tires, MB safeties, the list goes on. Let’s not
                                                                                                                            forget that they have a detailing staff that
                                                                         daughter Avery in 2005.                            will give your vehicle a complimentary wash
                                                                                                                            and vacuum while it’s in. Chris, Carla and
                                                                         Superior Auto was founded in 1996 by               staff look forward to helping you soon!

                                                                         Grant Stanton and has grown to be a familiar

                                                                         well grounded business in Brandon. Chris

Left to Right: Doug Derouin, Jordan Dellanoy, Ted Hughes, Gavin Deacon,  worked for Grant Stanton for 13 years, gaining

Carla Simard, Justin Van Mackelbergh, Chris Simard & Clyde McCallum      valuable experience working on all makes

                                                                                      and models of vehicles. Through

SUPERIOR                                                                              Grant and Ramona’s guidance
                                                                                      Chris and Carla were able to

Auto & Glass                                                                          purchase Superior Auto and make
                                                                                      a smooth transition from employee

                                                                                      to owner. Working in the shop for

204-726-1333                                                                          many years helped Chris get to
                                                                                      know the customers and develop a

1919 Brandon Avenue, Brandon MB             Simard Family                             relationship of trust.
 www.superiorautobrandon.com                                                             The automotive industry has

                                                                                      leaned towards large dealerships and]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[38 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

Cancer survivor launches medical pot business

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                          What happened after that?                                 What are you currently doing to treat the cancer?
                                                           It’s really been an ongoing battle for the last 12        I had the option to undergo chemotherapy/radiation
  The Healing Pot is a new business in Brandon at        years, but I did find out after an exploratory surgery    treatments, plus undergo a major surgery to remove
719-10th Street. Owner Darrin Stewart opened a retail    last September that I was cancer-free or in remission.    the upper part of my right lung. I’m choosing instead
location this past February and wants to share his       This was without chemotherapy or radiation. I was         to juice and get back on medicinal marijuana oil.
story on how the business came to be.                    mainly juicing with marijuana, exercising and eating        I’m already feeling much better. It’s an amazing
                                                         really healthy. My doctors were pretty astounded.         plant that is mentioned in the Bible. If it is left in its
  What exactly is The Healing Pot?                                                                                 own natural state and used as needed, it can do
  We’re a resource centre for people who are wanting       In what form do you use medicinal marijuana?            amazing things.
to grow their own meds in terms of medical                 I eat the leaves of the plant and I juice them. I use     Did you use drugs prior to getting sick?
marijuana so that they know exactly what they are        the leaves, plus fresh fruit and vegetables to make my      No, I did not. I drank socially, but was never into
getting. We legally carry all the supplies that are      daily juice. The plant is highly acidic, so the juice is  drugs.
needed, but most importantly we have the knowledge       helpful to balance it out. I also use cannabis capsules     Are juicing and oil capsules the only options?
and experience of the medicinal values of the entire     and oil, which are both high in THC and CBD and             This is what I found that works for me. Others
plant.                                                   have been proven to kill cancer cells.                    might find that it’s better to smoke marijuana. I have
                                                                                                                   seen and helped people with post-traumatic stress
  How did you come up with the name?                       How long after you were first diagnosed with            disorder and various other anxieties where juicing
  I was on a business trip with my cousin Rod and        cancer in 2004 did you start using medicinal              didn’t help, but smoking would. It calms people with
we somehow just came up with the name; we thought        marijuana?                                                no side effects such as liver or kidney failure.
that it was great play on words.                                                                                     What drives you to be successful?
                                                           I started using medicinal marijuana a few months          I really want people to start to recognize The
  What made you decide to start a business of this       after I was initially diagnosed and faithfully continued  Healing Pot as a how-to centre. I’m passionate about
nature?                                                  until I was told that I was cancer free in 2015.          what I do because I believe it saved my life. I care
                                                                                                                   about people and I want to share my knowledge and
  Starting the business was really a result of my own      How are you feeling today?                              help others if I can — that’s what drives me.
health problems. In 2004, I was diagnosed with             I could be better. Earlier this year, I was told that   » The Brandon Sun
metastatic lung disease, otherwise known as lung         I have a new kind of cancer in my lungs called
cancer. I was given six months to a year to live. After  Ground Glass Nodules. The sad part is, when I went
many visits to the doctor, test after test and a number  into remission, I quit juicing. Had I been smart, I
of surgeries, I started using medicinal marijuana.       would have continued and I may still be been cancer-
                                                         free today.]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[40 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

Speedy oil change just one of Great Canadian’s services

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                           keeping current and up-to-date is a critical component      Great Canadian Oil Change opened in Brandon in
                                                            of the Great Canadian Oil Change.                         2011, and they launched their second location in
  Fast and reliable. This is what you can come to trust                                                               Portage la Prairie in February 2015. The franchise, with
at Great Canadian Oil Change.                                 “Customers today are pretty well-informed and           60 locations across Canada, originated in the late 1970s
                                                            recognize how important it is to get regular oil changes  in Saskatchewan.
  Local franchise owner Mike Blair and his team of          on your vehicle. However, we still get people that come   » The Brandon Sun
professionals ensure that your vehicle is maintained as     in thinking they need 10w30 for summer and 5w30 for
though it was one of their own.                             winter, which isn’t really the case anymore. A lot of
                                                            the viscosity changes and a lot of the new oils
  “We’re fast, we don’t waste time. The guys all know       are synthetic. We keep up on all of that and pass
what they are doing and we don’t cut corners. We make       that knowledge on to our customers,” said Blair.
sure the job is done right,” said Blair.
                                                              According to suppliers like Valvoline and the
  This drive-thru oil change facility at 827-18th Street    original equipment manufacturers (OEM), the
offers convenient oil change services, but also             day is coming very soon where there won’t be
transmission, differential and radiator services as well.   any conventional oils available and that
They also carry quality product lines in terms of oil,      manufacturers will only produce synthetic oils.
air filters, fuel filters and any other products that they
work with.                                                    In addition to the latest oils, the Great
                                                            Canadian Oil Change also has a range of quality
  With their 21-point inspection, they can identify if      products that meet or exceed current industry
your wiper blades need to be replaced or if a bulb is       standards.
burned out on your vehicle. In fact, they’ll even replace
it for you.                                                   “Our filters are manufactured by the same
                                                            manufactures as the OEMs. Lots of times it’s
  “Basically, we take care of anything that has to do       usually the exact same filter, but with just a
with maintenance. We want to ensure your vehicle runs       different paint job. People sometimes wonder
smoothly and that you are safe on the road. As well,        if our products are good enough — the fact
we are warranty approved, which means we can work           is everything that we have either
with pretty much any vehicle out there,” said Blair.        meets warranty specs or
                                                            is better,” said
  “We also let our customers know that regardless of        Blair.
what your dealer tells you, they cannot void your
warranty for not getting your vehicle serviced with
them. It’s not even legal for them to imply such, but we
still hear from customers on a daily basis
that they believe they have to return to
the dealer for service.”

  As with most industries,
research and new
technology usually results
in product changes or new
systems for how things are
done. In the oil change
industry, there are always
new oils and related
products entering the
market, so for Blair,]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[Locally Owned & Operated

                                                              • No Appointments • Warranty Approved

                                               Open 7 Days a Week for your Convenience!

                                                                                       Monday - Friday, 8 am – 8 pm; Saturday, 8 am – 6 pm; Sunday, Noon – 4 pm

      DRIVE UP - DRIVE IN - DRIVE OUT

Oil Change Package Includes:

Up to 5L warranty approved oil
New warranty approved oil ﬁlter,
Lube to manufacturer speciﬁcations
And a great cup of coffee!

Mike  Braiden  Ben         Desmond  Jason  Matt  Glenn  Paul

      CAA Recommended                       204-727-5823
      CAA Approved                  827 – 18th Street, Brandon
      CAA Member Discount
                                      www.greatcanadianoilchange.com]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2016 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                      41

New lumber store beckons pro, do-it-yourselfer

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                             They carry all the products you’d expect to find at a    build from here, whether it’s for an addition on your
                                                            lumber store, including a large supply of lumber,          house or a garage package. As part of the member-
  A high level of service, excellent product knowledge,     drywall, insulation, hardware, tools, flooring and paint.  owned Castle Building Centres Group, we have access
vast industry experience and a good understanding of        The store has a variety of product lines, some of which    to a vast supply of products that allow us to be
current practices and trends. This is what the owners       include Valspar Paint, James Hardie building products      competitive in our pricing. They’ve been very supportive
of Westman Lumber Supply Ltd. want to offer their           and Johns Manville insulation. They are also dealers       and are very member-driven; they’ve really impressed
customers.                                                  for the Frigidaire Gallery series, Electrolux and          us and have been great to deal with,” said Keller.
                                                            Norsman Structures.
  This new lumber and hardware store at 1875                                                                             The new company is pleased to have Vince Kramer
Middleton Avenue (along the Trans-Canada Highway)             “Our goal is to make it a one-stop shop so you can       on board as their store manager, who has 25 years of
is set to open in the coming weeks.                         pretty much source anything for your renovation or         experience in the building industry, and Theresa Dunn
                                                                                                                       as their assistant manager. Everyone is working hard
  This particular location and the name was chosen                                                                     to get the centre ready and they’re excited for the official
specifically to ensure that rural customers, along with                                                                opening.
those from within the city of Brandon, felt welcome
and had easy access off a major throughway.                                                                              “We wanted to be able to provide our affiliated
                                                                                                                       companies and other contractors with a higher level of
  Evan Keller, majority owner, said they’ve undertaken                                                                 service, better pricing and more product knowledge.
extensive renovations of the building that was formerly                                                                Product knowledge is probably the biggest component
the CanPro Gator Centre.                                                                                               of this, thus far,” said Keller.

  “We basically stripped it all down on the inside and                                                                   “There’s so much information and the building
have completely rebuilt it from scratch. We’re refacing                                                                industry is changing so fast right now that there’s new
the exterior and adding stone features. It’s going to look                                                             products, there’s new requirements and there’s new
fantastic when we’re all finished,” said Keller.                                                                       ways of doing things to meet those requirements. We
                                                                                                                       all pride ourselves on keeping up-to-date on what’s
  Westman Lumber Supply Ltd. is a full-service                                                                         happening in our industry and we want to pass that on
building and material centre. They look forward to                                                                     to our customers, whether they’re contractors or do-it-
dealing with contractors, as well as do-it-yourself                                                                    yourself homeowners.”
builders. They will deliver packages and material within                                                               » The Brandon Sun
the city, as well as to close neighbouring communities,
including Virden, Oak Lake, Souris, Carberry and
Minnedosa.

                                                                               The Keystone Motor Inn is under

                                                                              NEW MANAGEMENT!

                          HAIR DESIGNS & NAILS

  We offer looks for the whole family:                                                              Guy Lobreau has been with our company
           • Cuts • Perms • Colours • Foils                                                            for over 15 years and now brings his
                                                                                                      experience to the manager position.
• Manicures • Pedicures • Waxing • Ear & Nose Piercing                                                     Our company includes the
                                                                                                     Keystone Motor Inn, Georgie’s, Gondola
ANNIVERSARY PERM SALE                                                                                    Pizza and the Keystone Vendor.

$4995 $5995 $6995 $7995                                                       GUY LOBREAU
Reg. $59.95  Reg. $69.95  Reg. $79.95                            Reg. $89.95
                                                                                     KEYSTONE
             Includes cut & style. Long hair extra.                                  MOTOR INN

             Book your appointment today! Gift cards available!                            1050 18th Street, across from the Keystone Centre

16TH & COLLEGE • 204-726-4293                                                         204-728-6620 | www.keystonemotorinn.ca

  WALK-INS WELCOME • FREE PARKING]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[42 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

Team at Advance takes worry out of auto repair

BY WANDA KURCHABA

  Why take a chance when you can take your car or          informed on the status of your vehicle repairs. They      a full paint job or paint matching, you can look to
truck to Advance Auto Body & Glass? Their                  will also assist with insurance claims to ensure timely   Advance Auto Body & Glass for quality workmanship
experienced autobody technicians, mechanics and            repairs and payments. Complimentary courtesy cars         and service.
office staff will take care of your vehicle like they own  are available to alleviate the stress of an accident and
it!                                                        being without a vehicle.                                    They are located just under the 18th Street bridge at
                                                                                                                     1807 Pacific Avenue. For more information or to book
  For 32 years, this locally owned business has been a       Community involvement is an important part of their     an appointment, visit their website at
full-service automotive repair shop for all makes and      business and they continue to work with local charities,  advanceautobody.ca or contact them at 204-727-8585.
models. As a part of the Auto Precision Group, they        including Westman Dreams for Kids and Big Brothers        You can also connect with them find them on
specialize in providing quality service, products and      Big Sisters of Brandon, as a way of giving back.          Facebook.
technologies to meet market demands and industry                                                                     » The Brandon Sun
standards.                                                   Whether you are looking for glass repair or
                                                           replacement, dent or hail repair, frame straightening,
  Employees are highly trained professionals who are
certified with I-Car Gold status and continue to keep
up with the latest technologies and equipment. Advance
Auto Body & Glass is proud to take on apprentices
from the automotive program at Crocus Plains Regional
Secondary School, which allows high school students
to gain valuable experience in the industry even before
they graduate.

  “Over the last few years, vehicles have become more
sophisticated,” said Trevor Kindrat, general manager
of Advance Auto Body & Glass. “We are constantly
staying up-to-date with the latest training and equipment
in order to provide our clients with the best service.”

  The team at Advance Auto Body & Glass wants to
make your experience worry-free and will keep you

                                                           Interior Design Service

                                                           RESIDENTIAL & COMMERCIAL

                                                           REMODELING ALL SPACES, NEW OR OLD

                                                                           Colleen Sigurdson

                                                                                 Certified Interior Designer with a
                                                                                 Bachelor of Science, Interior Design,
                                                                                 CIDA Accredited, NTHS - Honors

                                                           Space Planning, Elevations
                                                           Drawings, Window Coverings,
                                                           Ceiling Design & Lighting

                                                           Interior Art and Textured Walls

                                                           Colleen looks forward to
                                                           hearing from you with
                                                           all your design projects!

                                                           204-726-8282 | 1440 Rosser Ave., Brandon | www.interior-images.ca]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[THERE’S NO BETTER PLACE TO CALL HOME   ySoeuersfeolrf!

    MEREDITH                            HSOAOT1-U4PRUpEDmASNYES
MEDICAL CLINIC
                                         until October 31

                  LOCALLY OWNED AND MANAGED

1340 - 10th Street • 204 .725 .1340 • info@rotaryvillas.ca • www.rotaryvillas.ca]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[44 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

Keystone Centre hub and heart of Westman community

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                               arena advertising and sponsorship to operate on a year-                        for foundation grants and sponsorships
                                                                round basis.                                                                   and to fundraise to pay for emergency
  The Keystone Centre has been the                                                                                                             capital projects and potential operating
heart of Brandon and surrounding                                  “Revenue earned from rentals, catering, concessions,                         revenue-enhancing projects for the
communities for nearly half a century.                          arena ads and sponsorship needs to cover around $6                             facility.
Home to countless sporting and                                  million in operating costs every year,” said Thomson.
entertainment events, fairs, and                                “If extra revenue is generated throughout the year, it is                         This non-profit corporation is
agricultural exhibitions and                                    put into a capital fund or is used for improvements for                        managed by a small management
conferences, it connects our                                    securing the facility’s future.”                                               team and their employees.
community and visitors alike.                                                                                                                  Management is accountable to a
                                                                  Until recently, the Keystone Centre has never had                            Leadership Group made up of
  This exceptional 90 acres of property                         ongoing capital funding. With a 40-year-old building,                          representatives from the community
and all of its buildings are operated by                        it requires a minimum of $2 million per year to remain                         and the three entities that originally
a non-profit corporation called the                             fully functional. The centre has just received the first                       joined forces to create the first stage of
Keystone Agricultural and                                       of a $500,000 per year capital contribution from the                           buildings known as the Keystone
Recreational Centre Inc. that prides                            City of Brandon, as approved by council, and remains                           Centre in 1971 — the city, the province
itself on bringing to the community a                           hopeful that the Province of Manitoba may soon also                            and the Provincial Exhibition of
variety of events that contribute to the                        see the importance of matching this funding.                                   Manitoba.
quality of life throughout the Westman
area.                                                             The corporation will still need to continue to apply                            The Provincial Exhibition, which
                                                                                                                           hosts the three fairs, the Brandon Wheat Kings and the
  “The Keystone Centre exists for community use but                                                                        Brandon Curling Club are separate organizations and
also to facilitate the hundreds and hundreds of events                                                                     tenants within the centre. They play an important role
that grow our community’s economy by millions of                                                                           toward the centre’s goal of breaking even, as a
dollars every single year,” said Keystone general                                                                          percentage of some of these events’ food and beverage
manager Neil Thomson. “At 540,000 square feet, it is                                                                       sales and tickets sold through the Keystone Centre Box
the largest indoor recreational and event facility in                                                                      Office, along with their rental of facility space, are
Manitoba and one of very few similar facilities in all                                                                     earned operating revenue for the facility.
of North America.”
                                                                                                                             Community support, business support and users are
  Each year, there are approximately 1,500 events                                                                          the key to the success and the future of the Keystone
booked at the facility, which provides an annual                                                                           Centre, and its impact on the region’s economy and
economic impact of more than $62 million for local                                                                         quality of life.

   businesses. This is, of course, a major contribution                                                                      Visit their website at www.keystonecentre.com
         to the local community and the local economy.                                                                     or find them on Facebook
                 With annual operating expenses totalling                                                                  @KeystoneCentreBrandon or
                   approximately $6.75 million, and only                                                                   Twitter @Keystone_Centre for
                         11 per cent of that coming from                                                                   upcoming news and events.
                              all levels of government, the                                                                » The Brandon Sun
                                    centre relies on facility
                                         rentals, food and
                                               beverage sales,]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[CROCUS CREDIT UNION
                      PURCHASES LOCAL
                     INSURANCE AGENCY!

                     Crocus Credit Union is pleased to
                     announce that as of July 1st
                     it has purchased a majority interest
                     in Phillips Insurance Agency Ltd.
                     This exciting new venture means
                     new expanded services are now
                     available to members.

                                      www.crocuscu.mb.ca

   Count on us to find the right solutions for your
personal and business insurance and banking needs!

Downtown Branch      Thomas Mall Branch      Phillips Insurance
 1016 Rosser Ave.       742-18th Street          Agency Ltd.
                         204-729-4820
   204-729-4800                               B-510 1st Street
                               ATM ON SITE!     204-727-0709
       ATM ON SITE!]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[46 THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2016

 Printing survives, thrives under Leech dynasty

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                                                                                                            on a printing press or a

                                                                                                                                             copier. But, beyond that
For the vast majority                                                                                                                        we’ve developed and
of us, there likely isn’t a                                                                                                                  transitioned ourselves
time that we would                                                                                                                           into a full service online
remember what it was                                                                                                                         and content provider for
like not to have home                                                                                                                        websites and social
refrigeration, a pop-up                                                                                                                      media,” said Meredyth.
toaster, penicillin, Band-                                                                                                                   “With       this
Aids or a cheeseburger.                                                                                                                      combination we’re able
That’s because these                                                                                                                         to provide our clients
were all inventions of                                                                                                                       with full marketing
the Roaring Twenties —                                                                                                                       services,   which
a time, as they say, that                                                                                                                    consolidates everything
set us into the modern                                                                                                                       we do. We’ve become
age. quite unique in terms of
Those were the days                                                                                                                          the print industry and
when Cecil Leech                                                                                                                             have created a true one-
published the ‘Leech                                                                                                                         stop-shop with complete
Letter’ on letterpress                                                                                                                       graphic communication
equipment and started a                                                                                                                      services.”
printing business.                                                                                                                           Leech       Printing
As this family-run                                                                                                                           currently has 46
business enters its 90th                                                                                                                     employees, which has
year in operation,                                                                                                                           remained consistent over
looking back at where                                                                                                                        the years. They are proud
they’ve come from is                                                                                                                         of the fact that they have
important. However, as                                                                                                                       many        long-term
fourth generation family                                                                                                                     employees and believe
members are welcomed                                                                                                                         that this has contributed,
into the business, they                                                                                                                      in part, to the longevity
are looking at the                                                                                                                           and success of the
possibilities of the                                                                                                                         business.
future.                                                                                                                                      “In the 90 years that
Third generation                                                                                                                             we’ve been in business, it
president and owner                                                                                                                          is the quality of the
Michael Leech said that                                                                                                                      people that we’ve had
they’ve continued to                                                                                                                         working here and the
expand and explore new                                                                                                                       longevity of our
services and products                                                                                                                        employees that have
that they’re offering                                                                                                                        made the difference. The
today, and that printing                                                                                                                     core group is still here,
remains at the core of                                                                                                                       which makes it nice for
their business.                                                                                                                              me as the owner to see
That progress has been                                                                                                                       how capable the staff is
a continuation of second                                                                                                                     to help the fourth
generation owners and                                                                                                                        generation come on
management led by                                                                                                                            board. Without good
Michael’s father Don                                                                                                                         staff, we wouldn’t be
Leech, and his uncle                                                                                                                         where we are today,” said
Bud Leech.                                                                                                                                   Michael.
“Leech Printing is                                                                                                                           It is expected that
recognized for printing                                                                                                                      Gillian Leech, who is
and that’s still our                                                                                                                         finishing her business
primary          business.                                                                                                                   administration degree at
Printing has seen a                                                                                                                          Brandon University, will
significant resurgence ‘Third and Fourth Generation Leaders’from left David and Meredyth Leech, Matt DeGagne and Michael Leech. (Submitted)  also join the company in
and has strengthened                                                                                                                                      the next couple of years.
with the maturing of the online world. Printing has         With Meredyth Leech, Mike’s daughter, joining the           So, as these millennials embrace the benefits of a
found a very solid place as a partner in terms of online  company a couple of years ago, it was an ideal time to      family-run, community-minded business, they’ll be able
promotion, and more importantly in direct mail            take the business beyond printing and introduce new         to help grow the company and take it to its 100th
marketing. It has recaptured its spot in the minds of     innovative services.                                        anniversary and beyond.
business owners and is still hugely relevant,” said                                                                   » The Brandon Sun
Michael.                                                    “We’ve expanded our large format business with
                                                          banners, decals and products that aren’t typically printed]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2016 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                         47

Relish vacation as your pet laps up life at the Paw

BY WANDA KURCHABA                                            The Nichols family. (Submitted)                              through Facebook that helps to establish solid
                                                               “We’re getting busier and busier each year. We’ve          relationships. We really enjoy getting to know our regular
  The Paw Resort and Wellness Centre has much to                                                                          visitors and they become part of our extended family,”
celebrate as they enter their fifth year of business. Frank  gone from one or two employees to 19. We’re humbled          said Nichols.
and Joanne Nichols, along with their family, own this        that so many people trust us to care for their animals.
luxury pet resort, which is situated just west of Brandon    It’s a huge responsibility especially when we’re a little      In addition to boarding, The Paw Resort also offers
along Grand Valley Road.                                     more specialized in that we’ll take in animals with special  training classes for puppies through to advanced levels.
                                                             needs,” said Nichols.                                        They’ve added fun classes like Rally and Dancing as
  The centre provides splendid accommodations for                                                                         part of the birthday celebrations for the dogs, as well as
dogs and cats in their 7,000-square-foot facility. While       The Paw Resort will house senior dogs and cats, those      offering grooming services.
there are many features that make this the ideal home-       on medication or others that may have special
away-from-home for beloved pets, much of the design          requirements. And while the main aspect of the business        “We have one part-time and three full-time groomers
was based on the health and safety of the animals. They      is boarding, it’s not simply just putting a roof over their  that use excellent products and modern equipment. It’s
have noise reduction, ventilation and air filtering, an      head — it’s about caring for them and making sure they       a nice environment for the dogs with a lot of natural
indoor and outdoor play park, calming music, and             are healthy, happy and content.                              light, plus we have tools and products available if the
natural lighting with lots of windows for the pets to see                                                                 dogs do happen to be under stress,” said Nichol.
outside.                                                       “We try to go that extra mile to ease our clients’
                                                             anxiety as well. We’ll email updates and photographs           With spa services and a luxury hotel in a fantastic
  “One of our most recent expansions was the addition        of their pets, plus we have a strong social media presence   rural setting, The Paw Resort truly is unique. With clients
of an exercise pen for large dogs, which is 30 feet by 90                                                                 from all over Manitoba, the message has spread how
feet,” said owner and general manager Joanne Nichols.                                                                     satisfied customers are with their professional and caring
“The fence is seven feet above ground and three feet                                                                      team, which means it’s important to book well in
below, so that no one can escape. We tried to make it                                                                     advance as some dates, especially holidays, are filling
as safe as possible. The health and safety of the animals                                                                 up quickly.
that we have in our care is our first priority.”
                                                                                                                            “We work hard and love hearing from our customers
  In addition to the new exercise pen, a large agility                                                                    on how they don’t have to worry about their pets when
field (160 x 220) was also built. While hand walking the                                                                  they are in our care or how grateful they were that we
dogs is still part of the great service that The Paw Resort                                                               were able to accommodate their schedules. Pets are
provides, having additional space for exercise has made                                                                   members of the family and really important. We feel
some dogs so comfortable they aren’t always that eager                                                                    good knowing that we’re able to help,” said Nichols.
to go home.                                                                                                               » The Brandon Sun

NOW OPEN IN BRANDON!                                            CheeseMAorGnoinodg
                                                                   To Say
           Residential or Commercial
       We’ve got all your needs covered!                                                  Cheddar Ciabatta Breakfast
                                                                                          Sandwich & Medium Coffee
           • All installations done by Journeyman Carpenters •
                      • We offer In-House Financing •                   T$595(6am-11am)

             • Our products come with a Lifetime Warranty •                                          Artisan Cheddar

  1126 Rosser Avenue, Brandon                                         Farm
204-212-0749 | www.luxvue.ca                                       Fresh Egg

                                                                510 – 1st Street, Brandon, MB
                                                                           204-717-9100]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Grand Valley Animal Clinic is a mixed veterinary practice, treating both small and large
     animals. We provide loving care for your pet, as well as 24 hour emergency care.

   We offer medical, surgical, orthopedic and dental procedures. Our veterinarians are
                   experienced and highly qualified for the best care available.

At Grand Valley Animal Clinic,   304 Pacific Ave., Brandon
we treat your pets like the               Tel: 204.728.0033
valued family members they are!
                                   39 Preston St. N, Souris
                                          Tel: 204.483.2193
                                                www.gvac.ca

Ultrasound  Grooming             Dental]]></page></pages></Search>