<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="36"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[SUMMER                                                                                   FREE ISSUE 03











                                                                                     And the living is easy



























































             Sweet                            camp                            Business is
                                                   the

                                                 COME BACK
             & FROSTY                                                         BUZZING




                                                                                                              1]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[3703947_BU_Layout 1  18-03-16  2:20 PM  Page 1























































































       2]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Editor’s Note


                                                                       Our  Manitoba  summer  has  finally
                        501 Rosser Ave., Brandon, MB
                     Email: trending@brandonsun.com                    arrived, and with the bright sunshine and
                           brandonsun.com/trending                     warm breezes, come all the trappings of
                                                                       what makes this season so enjoyable.
                                                                       From  backyard barbecues,  outings  at
                                    PUBLISHER                          summer  camp  and swimming at  the
                                     Jim Mihaly                        lake to  an  afternoon  at  the  ballpark,
                                      EDITOR                           and warm sultry nights  around a
                                  Matt Goerzen                         bonfire  under  a  wide-open  starry  sky
                                    WRITERS        —  summertime is  pretty  fantastic  in  this  province.  (Just  don’t
                                  Erin DeBooy      mention the mosquitos).
                       edebooy@brandonsun.com     However brief our summers are, they provide us with a welcome
                                 Jillian Austin   respite from the cold winters we are so infamous for. It’s almost
                       jaustin@brandonsun.com    like a reward for having lived through the ice and snow that remains
                                 Tyler Clarke    on the ground for six months of the year.
                      tclarke@brandonsun.com     Ironically  enough,  with  the summer  months  comes a renewed
                                Michael Lee     longing for frosty offerings from our favourite ice cream and gelato
                       mlee@brandonsun.com      shops. Sales of ice cream soar come June and July — especially during
                         PHOTOGRAPHERS         those  infrequent  summer  heatwaves that  leave city  streets feeling
                     Tim Smith, Matt Goerzen,    like an oven.
                    Jillian Austin, Michael Lee,    In truth,  ice  cream  is  always in  fashion,  both  here,  and  around the
                   Tyler Clarke, Melissa Verge  world. Doesn’t matter what size of community, you can find a unique
                 GRAPHIC DESIGN LAYOUT        frozen treat to beat the heat in all four corners of Westman. So Trending
                           Jane Chartrand    scribe Jillian  Austin  got on  the road for  this edition  to detail some
                                             sweet summer offerings around the region. Tag a note and picture to
                    SALES & MARKETING
                             DIRECTOR       @TrendingBdnMB so we can see your favourites!
                            Glen Parker     We’ve also got a honey of a business story out of Roblin featuring a family-
                                            owned company making  it  big in  the  Asian  marketplace.  Another  great
                        DISTRIBUTION       global trend coming out of our province — it seems that Manitoba honey is
                            Lori Timms
                                           prized around the world for its light colour and fine taste.
                             INTERN       And business is just buzzing — check out Tyler Clarke’s story on Wendell
                         Ashlyn Pearce    Estate Honey.
                         On the cover:    Now’s a good time to start looking at your local u-picks and market gardens
                  Two-year-old Martial   for  fresh  fruit  and  produce  as  well.  With  July  in  the  offing,  tables  will  be
            Cabernel from Chater nurses   packed with goodness from the gardens of many Westman producers. It’s a
              a chocolate ice cream cone   natural fit for the summer months. Trending scribe Michael Lee headed out to
            at the Velvet Dip in Brandon   Holland, Man. to chat with one of the farmers who supplies the local Brandon
                 on a warm and sunny    Farmers Market.
              Tuesday evening in June.   Continuing on with our summer theme, Jillian Austin looks at the ongoing plans
             (Matt Goerzen/Trending)
                                       for the Assiniboine River, and this city’s changing relationship with our iconic and
                Advertising Inquiries:  tempermental waterway. The ongoing Festival Park project promises a new and
                    204-571-7424      necessary relationship with the Assiniboine, as we work to reclaim our riverbank.
                       TRENDING      I hope you enjoy our summer edition of Trending Magazine, preferably somewhere
                   is a production of    on a patio with a cool drink in one hand and a warm breeze in your pocket.
                  The Brandon Sun.
                                     Enjoy the summer while it lasts!
                 Made in Manitoba.






                                                                             Matt Goerzen
                                                                             Editor

                                                                                                              3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[CONTENTS



                                                                        03 EDITOR’S NOTE


                                                                        06 GOOD EATS
                                                                             Sweet & Frosty

                                                                        12 WELLBEING

                                                                             From the Ground Up

                                                                        16 BUSINESS

                                                                             Business is Buzzing in Roblin
                                                      06                20 QUIRKS
                                                          GOOD EATS
                                                                             Pampering Pets with Pizzazz

                            20                                          24 TRANSFORMATIONS
                                QUIRKS
                                                                             Going with the Flow


                                                                        30 DESTINATIONS
                                                                             The Come Back Camp






















                                                08
                                                    WELLBEING













                                      24
                                          TRANSFORMATIONS

       4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[3707397_BirchwoodNissan_Layout 1  18-06-12  3:48 PM  Page 1





                                                          My  name  is  Cierra  Waddell-Hodgson  and  I’m  a  Sales
                                                          Professional/Financial Services Manager here at Birchwood
                                                          Nissan Brandon. I’ve been helping customers find their perfect
                                                          vehicle for over 2 years and absolutely love what I do. The best
                                                          part of my job is making new friends and watching them fall in
                                                          love with their new or pre-owned vehicle. I’m a strong believer
                                                          that the sale doesn’t end at the sale. Not only will I help you
                                                          make the best decision possible, but I’ll also continue to look
                                                          after you for all your service related needs. The great thing
                                                          about being apart of the Birchwood Automotive Group is
                                                          we’re not only one brand. We can provide you with whatever
                                                          make or model you want. Although my love is for Nissan, I can
                                                          assist you with whichever brand you’re needing information
                                                          on. I personally invite you to come by 3620 Victoria Avenue
                                                          at anytime to stop and say “Hi” over a cup of coffee. I look
                                                          forward to meeting you!
                                                               Cierra Waddell-Hodgson
                                                               Sales Professional/Financial Services Manager
                                                               Birchwood Nissan Brandon
                                                               cierra.waddell-hodgson@birchwood.ca









































                                                                                    BIRCHWOOD
                                                                                    NISSAN BRANDON
                                                                                    3620 VICTO   RIA AVENUE
                                                                                    TEL: (204) 727-6418
                                                                                    www.BrandonNissan.ca
                                                                                                              5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Sweet
















                               &         frosty

















           Morgan Ahmed and
           her daughter Zaara,
           4, look out from their
           popular ice-cream spot,                    YOUR SUMMERTIME
           Mad Dog Ice Cream, in
           Forrest, Manitoba.                               ICE CREAM GUIDE
           (Tim Smith/Trending)




       6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[By Jillian Austin
                      s Manitoba’s temperatures soar, there’s   stuff in there that you have no idea what it is.”
                      no better way to  cool  off than with  a   The  Batchery  often  has  classic  flavours  like
               A delicious frozen treat. Ice cream is the    chocolate and vanilla, but it’s Trinda’s creative
               quintessential  summer  indulgence,  bringing   combinations that tend to sell out quickly. Some
               people together after a baseball game, on the   flavours to look for this year include chocolate-
               way to the lake or simply a way to enjoy a warm   covered pistachio  gelato,  and  peanut  butter
               summer evening.                               pretzel ice cream.
                 Trending  magazine   scoured  Western        “It sounds strange, but it’s very good,” she said.
               Manitoba  for the  best ice cream  parlours,  so   “I dream. I wake up in the middle of the night
               take note and head out on the highway for your   and say, ‘that sounds good!’ I also do requested
               next road trip!                               flavours — if you have a flavour that you would
                                                             find interesting, I’m willing to try it.”
               Mad Dog Ice Cream — Forrest                    The menu includes gelato, which is made with
                 For more than  two decades,  Mad Dog Ice    a lighter milk fat than ice cream; sorbetto, made
               Cream has been a popular stop for travellers          with juices and fruits (no dairy), and
               on Highway 10.  The  old  Brandon                       they also  started  making  dairy-
 Sweet
               city bus has been converted into a                         free ice  cream,  lactose-free
               colourful ice cream shop.                                     ice cream and gluten-free
                 It  was  previously  located  on                             ice cream.
               the  east  side  of the  highway,                                The Batchery is located
               but was moved when  the                                         off of 18th Street,  in
               now owner,  Morgan  Ahmed,                                     the parking  lot  of the
               purchased it  four years ago.  It                              Healthy Living  Centre
               is now located on the west side                                at  Brandon  University.
               of  the highway, just south of                                  They also attend special
               Forrest Elementary School. “It’s              Igenimus, illorerum sit quidenim es con ellessita is
                                                                                events
                                                                                           throughout
                                                             ea solupta dus que et rem. Periostrunt volorum is ma
               just a part of the community …                volorat quatur, odist ipsusa et utem. Accaessimet ex
                                                                                the summer,  such as
               we wanted to see it continue,”                eos doluptatusda sapiene natatio vollacc
                                                                                 Music in the Park,
     & frosty  Chapmans,” Ahmed said. “This year                       cream  shop at  820 Victoria  Ave.
               she said.  Hard ice  cream  is  a
                                                                                 Cruise  Nights,  Global
               favourite, as well as milkshakes.
                                                                                Market  and  Canada
               “We have Dairy Chef and
                                                                               Day at the Riverbank
                                                                             Discovery Centre.
               our Flurries are pretty popular.”
                                                                          Velvet Dip — Brandon
               The Batchery — Brandon
                                                                           Owners Jackie  Kamann-Oke
                 Built  from a 1977  Airstream  van,
                                                                        and Sam Oke are proud to keep
                                                                       the Velvet Dip legacy alive. The ice
               The  Batchery  has  a  definite  retro  vibe.
               Trinda  and Darren Collister  completely
               modernized  the interior  with stainless
                                                                       opened in  1965,  and  has  been in
               steel and new appliances, and opened the
                                                                       the Kamann family for the past 35
                                                                      years. Jackie and Sam purchased the
               food truck in 2015.
                 Since then, it’s been a popular spot to find         business from her father in 2005.
               top quality and unique flavours of ice cream           “It’s  wonderful. It feels kind of
               — all made right on the truck.                   special,” Jackie said. “It’s nice to just have it
                 “What I make today, I serve tomorrow,” Trinda   still  going  because  so many people  just  know
               said. “Super fresh. I know everything that goes   and remember it from when they were kids.”
               into that ice cream, where as when you buy the   Along with the nostalgia, Velvet Dip is best-
               stuff out of the freezers at  the store,  there’s   known for its soft-serve ice cream, made from
                                                                                                              7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[“You can’t buy happiness, but you can buy ice cream

                    and that is pretty much the same thing.”                            located in Virden. Right:
                                                                                            Ice Cream Island is
                                                                                          Tiffany Cameron, who
                                                                                            works at Ice Cream
                                                                                       Island, shows off a flavour
                                                                                        burst cotton candy cone
                                                                                           that she’s just made.
                                                                                        (Melissa Verge/Trending)

















            real  cream.  All  their  cakes and novelties  are made   The Camerons relocated the business to 272 King
            in house.                                        St. E and are now in their second season. One of the
              The old saying, “if it ain’t broke don’t fix it” rings   most popular items is the Flavorburst, which mixes
            true here, as one of the best sellers continues to be a   in your favourite topping. There are more than 20
            plain vanilla cone.                              flavours of hard ice cream, but time and again, the
              “People just love  the vanilla  ice cream,  so  it’s   soft ice cream takes the top spot.
            probably  the No. 1 seller,” Jackie  said,  adding  hot   “We hear over and over again … it’s good quality,
            fudge sundaes, banana splits and parfaits are always   always creamy,” Tiffany said. “So our soft ice cream is
            popular choices.                                 by far the biggest portion of our business.”
              “Your good old classics  are still  some of the
            big ones.”                                       Dari Isle Drive-In — Minnedosa
              To keep things interesting, the staff creates new,   Shannon Alexander always had a dream of owning
            specialty  sundaes  with  unique  flavours.  Recently   her own restaurant,  so when the  historic  Dari  Isle
            they started  offering  the  “Miss Piggy,”  which   Drive-In went up for sale 11 years ago, she jumped
            features bacon.                                  at the chance. The ice cream parlour opened back in
              “Bacon is such a trending item these days on donuts   1965 and is located at the corner of Main Street and
            and everything else,  so we have that  incorporated   Sixth Avenue NE.
            into a sundae now too,” Jackie said. “It’s always fun   The seasonal  business serves up all  the classics,
            just to try new things.”                         such  as  sundaes,  floats,  ice  cream  cones  and
                                                             banana splits.
            Ice Cream Island — Virden                          “Our most popular would probably be the good old
              New owners Tiffany and Kent Cameron are thrilled   chocolate milkshake,” Alexander said.
            with their new business venture, after moving back   A quote posted on the Dari  Isle’s social  media,
            to Virden from Alberta.                          sums it up best:
              “My husband is originally  from Virden  and we   “You  can’t buy  happiness,  but you  can buy  ice
            moved away for 10 years,” Tiffany said. “We owned   cream and that is pretty much the same thing.”
            a business in Alberta, and we sold everything… and
            moved back to Virden.”                           Busy B Drive-In — Boissevain
              When they saw Ice Cream Island up for sale, it was   Busy B Drive-In is a well-known stop for travellers
            the perfect fit.                                 on their way to Lake Medigoshe and other southern
              “It’s  wonderful. We love it,” Tiffany said.  “Great   Manitoba lakes.
            community  support.  It’s  a  fun business  and    Located at the corner of Highway 10 and Highway
            great staff.”                                    348 in  Boissevain,  the  seasonal  ice  cream  parlour


       8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Michelle Foot serves
                                                                 up a colourful waffle
                                                                 cone at The Beach
                                                                 Hut in Killarney.
                                                                 (Jillian Austin/
                                                                 Trending)



            and restaurant is now in its 49th season.
              After living in Winnipeg, Keri Sawatzky wanted
            to come back to Boissevain where she was born and
            raised. She purchased the business six years ago.
              “We’ve had people stop and specifically say its the
            best ice cream they’ve had, which is always nice to
            hear,” she said.
              Busy B offers sundaes, banana splits, twisters, as
            well  as eight  varieties  of hard ice cream.  A unique
            item to try is their coffee milkshake.
              “It’s kind of like a latte flavour, not bitter but it’s
            not horribly  sweet either. It’s  just  that  nice coffee                        Trinda Collister and her
            flavour,” Sawatzky said.                                                        husband Darren own The
              Busy B also  makes homemade  ice  cream                                         Batchery, which makes
            sandwiches and custom ice cream cakes.                                          delicious home-made ice
                                                                                              cream creations. (Tim
                                                                                                  Smith/Trending)
            The Beach Hut — Killarney
              After retiring from their jobs in northern Manitoba
            11 years ago,  Dennis  and  Judy Pearce  purchased
            The Beach Hut.
              “That  was  our retirement  plan,”  Judy said.  “We
            decided to just do this for the summer so we could go
            south for the winter… I love it.”
              The popular restaurant  and ice cream  shop has
            been a part  of the community  since the 1950s,
            located  a stone’s throw from Killarney Beach (44
            Water St).
              It may be the Pearce’s last season, as they have put
            the business up for sale.
              “We’re getting  ready to leave it  because it’s  just
            time,  we’re  getting  on,”  Judy said.  “It’s  a  fun place
            to be.”                                                                      Customers have a variety of
              The  hut  offers  16  flavours  of  hard  ice  cream,  as                  toppings to choose from for
                                                                                           Busy B’s popular Twisters.
                                                                                            (Jillian Austin/Trending)
                                                                                                              9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[well  as  the  soft  ice  cream  favourites,  such as  cones,
            Twisters and sundaes.
              Be sure to try the “Beachie,” which is a refreshing
            combination of slush and soft vanilla ice cream. If you
            get the orange option, it tastes just like a creamsicle.

            The Boardwalk on Clear Lake —
            Wasagaming
              If you can’t decide between soft and hard ice cream,
            The Boardwalk has the solution. The “Stellar” (named
            after longtime employee Stella), lets customers choose







                                     Busy B owner Keri Sawatzky
                                       took over the business six
                                        years ago. (Jillian Austin/
                                                  Trending)











                                                                From top: Look for the boat at the corner
            a scoop of their favourite hard ice cream flavour and it   of Main Street and Sixth Ave. NE in
            is topped with soft ice cream — the best of both worlds.  Minnedosa; The Dari Isle Drive-In has
              Owner Sandra Shwetz said quality is the top priority,   been serving customers since 1965.
            sourcing from seven different creameries in Canada.   Above:The Beach Hut has been part of
                                                                the community since the 1950s; The
            They also have a  Manitoba  focus,  including  Prairie   Boardwalk on Clear Lake has been serving
            West Creamery and Dairy Chef.                       customers in Riding Mountain National
              “I’m a Manitoba girl, I did grow up here and so it’s   Park for 65 years. (Jillian Austin/Trending)
            important to me to put back into the community,” she
            said. “There’s lots of other independent businesses like
            mine that want to make a go of it. They’re Manitoba
            people and  they’re happy to  be here,  so its  great  to
            support each other.”
              The Boardwalk has been open for 65 years, and is in
            an ideal location at 138 Wasagaming Dr., across from
            Clear Lake Beach.
              “As we’re scooping, the sun is setting just on the lake
            across from us,” she said. “We have rainbow-coloured
            chairs that sit right across the viewing line that face
            the lake.”
              Shwetz grew up going to Clear Lake, and took over
            the operation 14 years ago.
              “It is the best job in the world, but it’s also crazy and
            very busy,” she said.
              Best sellers are chocolate chip cookie dough, along
            with  peanut  butter  chocolate and the New York
            cherry cheesecake.  ❚


       10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[3706324_Leons_Layout 1  18-06-11  11:16 AM  Page 1





















































































                                                  3635 VICTORIA AVENUE, BRANDON • 204-727-4444 • Toll Free 1-800-267-4441
                                                                                                             11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Terry Durham inside of his greenhouse where he is
                currently grows tomatoes and chili peppers. Left:
                Durham holds a pair of newly-hatched Narragansett
                turkeys at his hobby farm near Holland.
                (Michael Lee/Trending)


























            From the ground up











            By Michael Lee
                or as long as he has been in the business, Terry   Mother Nature works and I try to follow her lead,”
                Durham  has always wanted  to do things  the   he said.
           Fway nature intended it.                            Durham  is  one of the  more than  two-dozen
              Hidden away on his 10-acre  plot  of land  just   vendors who will take part in the Brandon Farmer’s
            north of Holland, Durham,  the owner of Sandy    Market this year, which beginning June 10 will have
            Hills  Chicken Run, doesn’t  spray any chemical  on   migrated from its winter abode in the Town Centre’s
            his  vegetables,  or give his  free-range  chickens and   main  concourse to the mall  parkade,  marking  the
            turkeys any antibiotics or growth hormones.      official start to the summer season.
              This  stands out  as  a  point  of pride  for the  self-  The year-round market has been around for more
            described hobby farmer, who has set aside a quarter   than  40  years  since  it  first  took  off  in  1977.  With
            of his property to grow everything from asparagus,   between 25 to 28 tables registered for the market,
            radishes, peas, carrots, beans, garlic, potatoes, corn,   president Jeanette Ens was happy with the variety
            chili  peppers, strawberries,  or anything  else he   of vendors she has for the year.
            decides to try his hand at throughout the year.    “Like we say, rain or shine, we’ve got you covered,”
              Over the next several  months, Durham  hopes   she said.
            his  all-natural  methods  will  serve him  well  as  he   Some  vendors have been around  for some  time,
            gets ready for the summer season at the Brandon   including Brenda Newton, Ens’s sister, who has been
            Farmer’s Market.                                 coming to the market for 17 years to showcase the
              “Call  me a bird brain,  I just  kind of like the way   thousands of perennials she grows in her garden.


                                                                                                             13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[“What makes a table (is a) variety of things not   who  have been  involved with it for  some time,
             just one, at least for me,” she said.           especially with an unpredictable growing season.
              Others  like Sharlotte  Neufeld and her husband   One year, Durham may not have any beans to sell.
             Darcy are relatively new players to the farmer’s   Another year, he may not have any corn.
             market game.                                      This  year,  Durham  started  the spring  with  a
              Last  year, the two bought  a home in Lake     healthy supply of asparagus. But on top of all that,
             Metigoshe that came with its very own a meat shop.  he has to keep an eye out for wildlife and jokes that
              The  Neufelds  had some  experience making     his neighbours are a coyote, cougar and a bear.
             farmer’s  sausage and decided later  that  summer   “I take my licks,” he said. “Some years I do good,
             to see how well they could do selling it at various   some years I don’t.”
             markets, including the one in Brandon.            And  even though  his  methods may be harder
              Since  starting  their  business  Bar  Y  Meats,   work, Durham wouldn’t change a thing. “Everything
             the  couple  has tried  their  hands  at  a  number  of   (is) done the way it should be,” he said.
             different  products,  from pork chops, ribs,  bacon   Moving  into  her 19th year  with  the farmer’s
             and hamburgers.                                 market, Ens knows it’s not easy work getting your
              “We really  liked the family  dynamic,” Sharlotte   products ready and bringing them to market each
             said. “So we thought we’d give it a try.”       week, but in some ways it’s a good problem to have.
              Zelda Kinniburgh started her jewelry wholesale   “We always say if we’re tired and we’ve had three
             company Oooh! Shiny  Things  in Brandon back in   hours of sleep prior to a market day, we tend to
             May 2016, with the goal of making her products as   blame our customers,” Ens said. “Because if you’re
             affordable as possible                          busy, the customers make us do this ... That means
              Today, she carries products from approximately   we have great customers.”
             200 jewelers across Canada and the U.S., with the   Since it does take time to establish yourself, Ens
             average ring or necklace selling for $33, she said.  said she hopes vendors don’t give up after two or
              The market is an almost guaranteed source of   three days. But after 40 years worth of markets, if
             income for her, but one of the things Kinniburgh   there is one thing vendors can rely on, it’s a solid
             said she enjoys most about the market is getting   customer base.
             to  know  the  other  vendors and the customers   “Whether  it  is  that  one lady who loves baby
             they serve.                                     carrots,  or little  tiny baby tomatoes,  or someone
              “The traffic and flow of the crowd here, it’s a small   who likes huge parsnips in the fall, everybody has
             trickle, but I’m always busy,” she said.        their favourite vegetables, but it’s rewarding to see
              But getting a good foothold at a farmer’s market   people appreciating the work that you have put into
             takes time and effort, even for those like Durham   it,” Ens said.  ❚


       14]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[“Call me a bird brain,

                                                                        I just kind of like the

                                                                          way mother nature

                                                                             works and I try to


                                                                              follow her lead...”



                                                                                  Terry Durham recently started raising
                                                                           Narragansett turkeys at his home near Holland,
                                                                           a breed the hobby farmer described as “hardier”
                                                                                than your average turkey. Left: Chickens
                                                                            drink from a water fountain drawn from Terry
                                                                           Durham’s well. (Michael Lee/Trending) Far left:
                                                                              Patrons line up at Brown Sugar’s booth the
                                                                            outdoor Brandon Farmers Market at the Town
                                                                             Centre parkade. The offeringof local produce
                                                                             and products moves from inside the shopping
                                                                                centre to outdoors each Saturday for the
                                                                                             summer season. (FILE)
  3707299_SobeysExtra_3707299_Sobeys  18-06-13  12:34 PM  Page 1






























         If you’re looking for dinner ideas, pick up a ready meal from our kitchen.










                                                            1570 18 Street
                                                                      th
                                                            Shoppers Mall              (204) 725-1134        15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Business is








           BUZZING IN ROBLIN





























































           Wendell Honey employee Edwin Villanueva
           shows off a hive of bees between Roblin and
           Russell. (Tyler Clarke/Trending)


       16]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Story by Tyler Clarke


                  global  enterprise  with  direct links  to  the
                  Asian  marketplace  and a new packaging
           A facility  slated  to  open in  Roblin,  Wendell
           Estate Honey is keeping up with the times.
             The  company is comprised  of more  than  4,000
           hives  spread between approximately  120  locations
           between Manitoba and Saskatchewan, which require   Wendell Honey.
           owner Tim  Wendell  to work some  long  hours;      His father, John, started
           particularly during this time of year.            keeping  bees in  Saskatchewan
             The days might  be long,  but Wendell  said  that  it   during the mid-’30s kick-starting
           doesn’t feel like work most of time time, particularly   a raw honey operation that would
           the hours he spends with his tiny little buzzing bosses.  later  be called  Wendell  Honey and
             “I’m not the boss, the girls are the bosses,” he said of   much later  encompass the value-
           his bees, after capping off another 12-plus hour work   added Wendell Estate Honey enterprise.
           day in late May, during which he took care of both the   Initially made up of approximately 50 hives, by the
           business side of things as well as his bees.      time Wendell bought his father out in 1974 it was
             “That’s who we work for, because they’re the ones   made up of 400.
           that  pay us.  If they don’t  pay me,  I don’t  pay (my   Expanding  beyond a raw honey exporter  and
           employees), so these are the bosses, without a doubt.”  packaging their own product since that time — and
             His  day began by checking  emails  at  5:30  a.m.,   bringing the Asian marketplace into the fold — it has
           after  which he hosted a meeting  in Roblin  where   since grown to its current 4,000 hives.
           he hopes to open up a packaging  facility. Their    Wendell Honey’s story highlights what Manitoba
           honey packaging operations currently take place in   Beekeepers’ Association president Mark Friesen said
           MacNutt, Sask., a village located on the eastern edge   is becoming a reality of the times.
           of the Saskatchewan border near Roblin.             “Like all farming, we’re seeing that same situation
             While the ever-expanding  company  extends      where beekeepers tend to get  very large-sized
           Wendell’s workdays, chipping away at the time he’s   operations,” he said, adding that it all comes down to
           able to spend with his “girls,” it’s the time he spends   the economies of scale, not that current prices are
           tending to his buzzing business partners’ needs when   doing them any favours.
           he’s in truly in his element.                       With the majority of exports going to the United
             On-site  earlier  in the  day at  properties  located   States,  whose president’s  protectionist  rhetoric
           between  Roblin  and  Russell,  Wendell  appeared  at   Friesen said has carried a trickle  down impact  via
           peace with  his bees, joining  several  employees in   “buy local” initiatives, the finances behind producing
           shifting them from their smaller winterized hives into   raw honey for export have been increasingly tight.
           regular-sized hives for the summer months.          “Last year when the price really crashed, I talked
             “This is a piece of heaven on earth in a way, because   to three new commercial  beekeepers who’d never
           there’s not a lot of noise, there’s not a lot of chemicals,   done packaged  honey and they were moving  into
           there’s not a lot of people and we get to be here with   that market, where they could put their product on
           nature,” he said as bees buzzed around him in every   the nearby shelves,” he said.
           which direction.                                    Although prices weren’t as harsh in 2011 as they
             “There’s probably no better place that I’d rather be   are  now,  Wendell  said  that  riding  the  commodity
           at this time of year than a bee yard … It’s work, it’s got   market’s ebbs and flows for decades led him to finally
           to be done and I work hard, but if you like what you do   take the plunge at  the time  and produce a value-
           it’s not so much work, no matter what it is … I’m in it.”  added product for local and overseas sales.
             Wendell has been “in it” since was a kid, and is the   Selling raw product below the cost of production
           second generation of his family to take the helm of   back  in  2005  provided  a  significant  enough  blow

                                                                                                             17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Left: Tim Wendell, of Wendell
                                                                                   Honey, adds some smoke to the
                                                                                    hives in order to make his bees
                                                                                   more docile while shifting them
                                                                                   from winter accommodations to
                                                                                   summer. Below: Wendell Honey
                                                                                  bees are seen on the exterior of a
                                                                                 stack between Roblin and Russell.
                                                                                         (Tyler Clarke/Trending)






            that  Wendell  said  that  making                             said,  adding  that  he  has  also  flown
            an  investment  toward  value-                                 out to the  Asian  country to attend
            added products during a more       “This is a piece of          trade shows.
            prosperous time to help them     heaven on earth in a               Although  much    of   the
            survive  the next  market                                          enjoyment  he gets  out  of his
            dip is a decision he’s now     way, because there’s not              professional  life  comes out
            looking  back  on with         a lot of noise, there’s not           of caring  for his  bees in  the
            gratitude.                     a lot of chemicals, there’s           prairie  fields,  Wendell  said
              He said  that  it  also          not a lot of people              that  the satisfaction  that
            helped  that  a  business                                          comes with  sharing  their  high
            partner   presented    the       and we get to be here           quality  product with  others
            product to a receptive panel of      with nature...”            provides a decent icing on the cake.
            entrepreneurs on the  television                                With  “so much fake honey in the
            show Dragon’s Den in 2013, and                               world”  supplemented  by things  like
            although it resulted in an a business                       rice syrup, he  said that  being  a purist
            offer at the time, Wendell said that                         in the “gong  show” that  makes up
            things don’t always turn out like                              a  significant  portion  of  the  honey
            they appear on television.                                      industry as it  currently exists can
              Certain   strings  were                                         be satisfying.
            attached  to  the  deal  that                                        Friesen  said  that  Canadian
            affected  its  viability,                                           honey, largely fuelled by bees’
            though   Wendell  said                                               pollination  of canola  crops,
            that  he still  gives the                                            is a near-white  honey that’s
            show  credit  for  getting                                          sought around the world, and
            their name out there, which                                       that few other marketplaces can
            opened some doors for them.                                      rival it.
              With  interest  in their  high-                                “You can always heat up the white
            grade  prairie  Canadian  honey on                            honey that Canadians have and make
            the rise, Wendell  said  that  he also                       it a golden colour, but you can’t make
            credits  his son Jeremy, a medical                         darker honey from  foreign  countries
            doctor who lives in China with his wife                   lighter,”  he said, adding  that Canadian
            Carol, with helping him market his product overseas.   honey is oftentimes used to enrich the other honeys.
              “They’re  busy with  their  own lives,  but they’ve   This, Wendell said, is why his sale of raw product,
            been helping  out since they are there,” Wendell   which he still  engages  in to a degree,  is a far less


       18]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Wendell Honey staff work at getting bees ready
                                                                       for summer, at one of their locations between
                                                                         Roblin and Russell. (Tyler Clarke/Trending)




            rewarding endeavour than exposing people to their   are temporary foreign workers alongside a number
            pure, value-added  packaged  product,  which he   of longstanding employees, such as Jake Dingman,
            considers the “Mercedes” of the honey market.    who joined Wendell Honey while he was growing up
              On the company’s website, wendellestate.ca, a 1kg   in MacNutt and has kept at it ever since.
            jar of their honey retails for $44.                Dan Margarit  emigrated  from Romania  to join
              When they sell it in bulk, others down the line use   Wendell Honey, keen on tackling a new way of doing
            it in the manner that Friesen described, wherein it’s   things after beginning his beekeeping career in his
            used to used to enrich cheaper product.          native country.
              “They just wreck it,” Wendell said. “They take my   While playing soccer in Grade 7, he chased a ball
            nice honey and mix it with ugly honey, so it’s kind of   into a field where he came upon a swarm.
            a generic colour, looks like honey and kind of tastes   Returning with a box, he managed to capture it and
            like honey, but they kind of wreck it.”          was not stung.
              Increasing  their production  capacity  to meet   Drawing  experience  from  his  grandfather,  who
            the  demand  they’re  uncovering,  Wendell  Estates   was a  beekeeper,  he set out to do the same,  later
            Honey is currently looking to expand their packaging   relocating to Canada to see how Canadians do it.
            operations into Roblin, an effort of which Wendell is   Pointing to these and other long-time beekeepers,
            currently finalizing the specifics.              Wendell  said  that  there’s something  special  about
              With Wendell’s skillset best utilized in the fields, he   honey producers that  keeps them  in  the  game  for
            said that he has always tried to get the right people   so long.
            on  board to help the company reach its potential,   Part of it’s an affection for the bees, he said — a
            including his sons Jeremy and Nathan.            point  that  he makes abundantly  clear  through  the
              Despite breaking ground on unique careers of   pride he exudes in describing the “gentle” buck fast
            their own — Jeremy as a medical doctor and Nathan   strain of bees that he works with, which is a Denmark
            as a psychologist  — both have opted to help the   variety he gets through the University of Guelph.
            family business.                                   Placing his flattened hand on a comb crawling with
              They echo their father’s experience, with the elder   bees, he gently pet the swarm to illustrate his point,
            Wendell  having started  a  teaching  career  in  the   resulting in zero stings.
            United States prior to returning home to take over   Another explanation  might  be  the venom in the
            the family business a few decades ago.           bees’ stings, he said with a chuckle, adding, “We get
              Joining the Wendell family with beekeeping duties   stung too much and we can’t do without it.”  ❚


                                                                                                             19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Kayla Knowles, a groomer
              at Grassroots Grooming on
              Rosser Avenue, grooms a
              dog for a client alongside
              co-workers. (Tim Smith/
              Trending)



































               Pampering pets with




               PIZZAZZ




















       20]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[By Erin DeBooy

                    f anyone ever calls Crystal Smitzniuk a crazy cat lady, she said
                    she takes it as a compliment.
                I A mom of two “fur babies” — a female cat named Misty and a male
                 named Stormy — Smitzniuk said the nickname is kind of accurate
                 since she loves them both like crazy.
                   “We love having cats  in our house … both of them  have their
                 own unique personalities. They’re funny at times, they’re annoying
                 at times, but they’re always around, and you miss them if they’re
                 not,” Smitzniuk said. “They’re part of our family. My husband and I
                 don’t have kids, so we have two fur babies that are our cats and our
                 kids, in a way. I do believe pets become family — you love them just
                 as much.”
                   Misty came into Smitzniuk’s life approximately 12 years ago, she
                 said, when her and her husband took Misty in from a family member.
                   They adopted Stormy a few years later after his mother, a farm
                 cat, abandoned him when he was only three weeks old.
                   “I used to have to mix him formula, so he was like a little baby and
                 he still is,” Smitzniuk said. “He’ll sit in my lap and he’s a good cat. He’ll
                 follow me around the house … I can still wrap him up in a blanket and
                 he’ll just fall asleep.”
                   Like any pet  mom,  Smitzniuk  likes to  make sure her cats  are
                 living their best life, and recent trends in pet care have made that
                 a little easier.
                   Smitzniuk has a nanny camera set up beside the cat’s automatic
                 feeders, she said, so when they go out of town they have peace of
                 mind in knowing their cats are doing okay while they’re gone.
                   The feeders also have Smitzniuk’s voice programmed into them
 Pampering pets with   the cats seem to find comfort in as well.
                 so they can call the cats for dinner by name, Smitzniuk said, which
                   Smitzniuk  even has  a  pet  stroller  she bought  from  PetSmart,
                 which allows her to take Stormy on summer walks.
                   “(Stormy) likes to kind of go anywhere with me … so I got this cat
 PIZZAZZ         stroller and he doesn’t mind it,” Smitzniuk said. “Once we get outside
                 he talks to me the whole way … there’s a little flap at the back of the
                 stroller so he’ll face front and then turn around a give a little, ‘meow’,
                 so I’ll assure him I’m right there and he’ll turn back around and face
                 the front again.”
                   For Alyssa Fletcher, owner of Grassroots Grooming in Brandon,
                 pet owners that go the extra mile for their best friends — as she likes
                 to refer to her pets — is nothing new.
                   Business  has  been steady  since Grassroots  Grooming  opened
                 their  doors, Fletcher said,  with programs  like their  deshedding
                 program growing more and more popular among dog owners and
                 creative grooming requests on the rise.


                                                                                                             21]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Alyssa Fletcher, owner of Grassroots Grooming
                                                                       on Rosser Avenue, grooms a dog for a client. Left:
                                                                       Crystal Smitzniuk at her home with Stormie, one
                                                                               of her two cats. (Tim Smith/Trending)




              “(Grooming)  has  always been in  really  high   pampered with a manicure, too.
            demand,”  Fletcher  said.  “I  think people  are  caring   “Kyle (a groomer at Grassroots Grooming) has a
            for their dogs more all around … they’re coming out   bulldog that comes in every month and every time
            from the backyards and they’re in our beds and on   he paints  that  bulldog’s  nails  pink,” Fletcher  said,
            our couches … it is a body and you want it taken care   laughing. “It’s pretty great.”
            of, it’s dog hygiene, really.”                     The  shop has  also  recently  introduced  mineral
              But taking care of your pet’s hygiene doesn’t have   mud baths, which help exfoliate, purify and detoxify
            to be boring.                                    the dog’s coat and skin, as well as blueberry facials,
              They’ve started doing  airbrush  tattoos,  Fletcher   which are ideal for white dogs looking to prevent or
            said, where dogs can get a little paw print airbrushed   clean up tear stains.
            onto their backside.                               “It’s  been surprisingly  popular  … It’s  not  for
              And just like their owners, dogs can enjoy getting   everybody but the people who like it, like it,” Fletcher


       22]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[PET





                 TRENDS                            SPACE CAPSULE                   MATCHING HUMAN PJS
                                                   BACKPACK PET CARRIER
                                                                                   shop.fabdog.com,
                                                                                   $25 to $35
                                                   Amazon.ca, ranging from
                                                   $39.99 to $99.99
                                                                                   The real question is, why wouldn’t
                 IN 2018                           These breathable carriers fit for cats and   you wear matching pyjamas with
                                                                                   your dog?
                                                   small dogs are ideal for convenient travel
                                                   and giving your little buddy a view. Most
                                                   brands are also airline approved.
















                  FURBO DOG CAMERA                 PORTABLE PET TENTS              CAT GARDENS
                  Amazon.ca, $249.00               AND HOUSES                      A beautiful array of cat-friendly plants
                  This full HD, wifi pet camera designed   Amazon.ca, $24.99 to $69  that look good, smell pretty and are safe
                  for dogs has two-way audio and can   Cozy hideaways for your fur baby that   for your cat to snack on should they feel
                  connect with Amazon Alexa so you can   fit effortlessly into your living space.   like grazing. Cat gardens are the perfect
                  interact with your pooch while you’re   It’s a win-win.          DIY project, with catnip, cat grass, mint,
                  away. Not only can it toss treats on your                        cat thyme, lemongrass and valerian
                  command, but it also has a barking alert,                        being cat-friendly additions.
                  which sends you a push notification
                  when it detects barking.





            said. “I think dogs like any extra bit of attention …   have run of the shop all day without having to be
            they know when they’ve got that little extra bit   rotated out to accommodate large dogs at play.
            of pizazz.”                                      “We were once taught you had to be alpha and
              Overall,  Fletcher  said  there was been a   dogs needed to mind. I’m so glad this has been
            “massive shift” toward kindness and mindfulness   disproved and will  be in our rear view mirror
            in dog owning, including training.             soon,” Fletcher said. “Now it’s all about slowing
              People  are  working  harder  to  socialize  their   down, teaching dogs in tiny approximations what
            pets, taking them to doggie daycares around the   is expected, and leading with kindness …Welcome
            city  and letting  them  mingle  with  other dogs,   to  2018 and  the  shift  toward  a  balanced  life
            Fletcher said.                                 for  families,  including  our  pets… seeing pets as
              Grassroots  has  a  daycare  that  is  small  dog   individual beings to be respected and the friends
            specific, Fletcher added, which allows the dogs to   they are.”  ❚


                                                                                                             23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Going




                        flow








                with the












            BRANDON’S NEW PARTNERSHIP

            WITH THE ASSINIBOINE RIVER



            By Jillian Austin

                      hen  developing  the Back to the   Mayor Rick Chrest recalled how the high
                      River master  plan,  the  notion   waters wiped out some of the amenities and
            W that  “Mother  Nature  always            improvements that had been built over the
            wins” was a central focus.                 years, such as Eleanor Kidd Park and popular
              Working  with  the river, rather than    walking trails.
            against  it,  was top-of-mind  and shaped the   “That was very unfortunate but undaunted
            entire  20-year vision  for the Assiniboine   the Riverbank Inc. organization,” he said.
            River corridor.                            “Lots of people in the community have circled
              “Sometimes  we forget  … that  the       back around and … are now working with the
            Assiniboine  River now is  just  a  tiny ribbon   river.  I think  it’s  just  very symbolic  … that
            of  water  through  the  huge  flood  plain…  we are wanting to embrace this sometimes
            and it used to be a (much wider),” said Lois   powerful, natural phenomenon … and realize
            MacDonald,  former general  manager  of    that  we have to just  work with  it,  and the
            Brandon Riverbank Inc. “It’s  just  been   river will be the boss.”
            reduced down to this tiny channel — but it   To re-evaluate the space and plan for the
            reminds us every now and again, that it’s still   future, Brandon Riverbank Inc. hired HTFC
            in charge.”                                Planning  +  Design to help develop the
              Brandon  experienced  historic  flooding  in   master  plan.  It was an 18-month  process,
            2011 and again in 2014. While most of the   which included many public consultations.
            city was protected, one area that sustained   City council approved the master plan in
            major  damage was the river corridor       June 2016. The total price tag is estimated
            and the area  surrounding  the Riverbank   at  $30 million,  and  the  projects  will  be
            Discovery Centre.                          completed as funding becomes available.


       24]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[The sun sets on the horizon over the
             swollen Assiniboine River at First Street
             North on a warm Thursday evening.
             (Tim Smith/Trending)



                                                                                                             25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[“It feels fantastic to
                                                                         have a plan, to have

                                                                         something to be working
                                                                         towards that we know
                                                                         we have the entire
                                                                         community’s support.”


                                                                         Lois MacDonald, former general
                                                                         manager of Brandon Riverbank Inc.
                                                                         (Tim Smith/Trending)






































       26]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[From left: Extensive gardens are planned near the Riverbank Discovery Centre, which will
                         include a venue for small weddings and other events. “Back to the River” Master Plan is a 20-year
                         vision for the Assiniboine River corridor. The Riverbank master plan includes a trail system, and
                         a Peter Sawatzky Sculpture Garden. (All images courtesy of HTFC Planning & Design)

                           Phase 1 is Festival Park, and is slated for   After going through some difficult years,
                         completion by the end of the summer. Key   MacDonald and others close to the project
                         features include a permanent,  covered     are thrilled to see construction underway.
                         stage,  as  well  as  an  amphitheatre  with   “From 2011 to 2016, it was five years of a
                         terraced seating for up to 3,000 people.   lot of damage, a lot of loss, a lot of uncertainty,”
                           Monica Giesbrecht, partner with HTFC     MacDonald said. “And now it feels fantastic
                         Planning  + Design,  said  the company     to have a plan, to have something  to be
                         prides  itself  on  understanding  the     working towards that we know we have the
                         biophysical conditions.                    entire community’s support.”
                           “We don’t  tend to design  anything  that   A  loan  agreement  of up to  $1 million
                         sort  of goes  against  nature,”  she said.  “It’s   between Brandon Riverbank Inc. and the city
                         super important  with  climate change  and   allows the accelerated completion of Phase
                         just the volatility and the expected changes   1. In addition to the amphitheatre, it will also
                         in  our weather patterns…to design  all    include two new picnic shelters,  as well as
                         projects now so that they are fairly resilient.”  establishment of native prairie grasses.
                           In some spots along  the river, more       “I feel really good about the fact that this is
                         naturalized areas will be developed, to allow   going to get done and the community will get
                         flood waters to move in and out.           to start enjoying it before too long,” Chrest
                           “Let it  come  and go,  rather  than trying   said.  “When potential  donors are now
                         to  engineer  something  that  would  try  to   starting  to see the project  come together,
                         withstand it,” she said.                   they’ll be more apt to want to get on board
                           Discovery  Gardens   will  eventually    to help fund it when they can see what the
                         surround the Riverbank Discovery Centre,   finished product is going to look like.”
                         creating  a horticultural  oasis  that  features   There are many  ways  the public can
                         a variety of gardens, outdoor programming   lend support to the Festival  Park project,
                         space,  as well  as an arbor for outdoor   including a seat sale campaign. For $2,500,
                         weddings.  This  will  replace  Eleanor  Kidd   an individual, family or business can sponsor
                         Gardens,  as it  was not feasible  to try and   an  amphitheatre  limestone seat.  For
                         restore  it.  The  plans  for the  entire  project   $500, a tree can be planted in your name.
                         have  been  designed  with  flooding  in  mind,   Sponsorship opportunities are also available
                         and are above the flood-of-record elevation   to name the stage and amphitheatre.
                         in an effort to keep it safe from high water in   “We’ve received some real good corporate
                         the future.                                support and we look forward to businesses


                                                                                                             27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[being involved,” said  Bernie Chrisp,  president of   Giesbrecht said this particular project has been a
            Brandon Riverbank Inc. “We want to thank the folks   special one for her, and she has been struck by the
            that have donated already, the businesses and also   community partnerships and support.
            the local people in Brandon and Westman, it’s nice to   “It’s by working together and continuing to work
            see that its happening and moving along.”        together  that  you guys are going  to really  achieve
              The long-term  vision for  the area is to create a   this,”  she said.  “It  was  really a  pleasure  to  have
            robust green space, which will become the heart of   committed leadership and city buy-in of the project,
            the community.                                   and I hope that continues.”
              “It will create reconnection to nature, for members   Other  components planned include Assiniboine
            of our community and people throughout the entire   Cove, which will transform existing wetlands into an
            region,”  MacDonald  said.  “I  just  see that  it  would   interactive outdoor classroom. There are plans for a
            create  a space that  everyone can access.  The   new safe, area to launch canoes and kayaks.
            riverbank to me, is an equalizer … regardless of your   The master plan also includes the creation of Peter
            age, your background, your socioeconomic status or   Sawatzky  Sculpture  Park near the corner of 18th
            where you live in our community, you can come here   Street and Kirkcaldy Drive.
            and enjoy the space.”                              “There  will  be lots  of changes,  lots  of


       28]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Construction work on the new stage at the Riverbank
                        Discovery Centre. (Tim Smith/Trending)






            transformations,  but we’re kind of earmarking
            the  big projects that  will  be moving  ahead,”
            MacDonald said. “As funding becomes available
            and partners become available, then definitely
            there’s  no shortage  of other  projects  that  we
            can get moving on as well.”  ❚



            Top right: Kaelan Huibers releases his
            catch, a large white sucker, back into the
            Assiniboine River while fishing with his father,
            Leo Huibers, at Dinsdale Park. (FILE)
            Right: The brush and bush found between the
            Assiniboine River and the Riverbank Discovery Centre’s
            nature trail is home to several red-winged blackbirds
            that fill the air with song.
            (Matt Goerzen/Trending)


                                                                                                             29]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[camp


              the





            COME BACK





























            By Tyler Clarke
               mmersed   in   nature  year-round,  Camp       deep as Mitch’s, they’re nonetheless passionate.
               Wannakumbac’s  new leadership  is only a few    The  two  have taken over as  managers  of the
           I months  in,  but they already  consider their  new   Riding  Mountain  Conference Centre  and its
            roles as being  a culmination  of their  life’s journey   Camp  Wannakumbac  summer program,  situated
            to now.                                           at  the southwestern edge of Riding  Mountain
              Mitch  Gustal  grew up at  the camp,  which his   National Park.
            parents Darren and Janet managed from 1992  to     Although the couple has bonded over their shared
            Darren’s death in 2014 and Janet passing the torch   love of nature, the two met as city residents, through
            to her son and daughter-in-law on Jan. 1.         mutual friends outside of a bar in Winnipeg.
              This daughter-in-law, Sarah-Anne, married Mitch   Both reflect on their time in the province’s capital
            during a ceremony held at the camp site two years   city  as positive, and at  one time  even considered
            ago. While her Camp Wannakumbac roots aren’t as   purchasing a house there, but now look at their city


       30]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[camp


      the





    COME BACK
















                                                         Above: A music lesson
                                                         takes place at Camp
                                                         Wannakumbac. Members
                    The campfire circle is pictured at Camp   of Camp Wannakumbac
                      Wannakumbac. Managers Mitch and    take part in a fishing
                       Sarah-Anne Gustal said that it is the   expedition off the west
                     summer camp’s most popular feature.    shore of Clear Lake.
                               (Tyler Clarke/Trending)   (Submitted)





            years as a phase they’ve moved past.             dates back to Mitch’s childhood, during which he said
              It’s in nature,  where  they can walk out of  their   that his time at the camp — particularly, bonding with
            backyard  to a network of trails,  where the lake is   camp counsellors — stuck with him.
            a short stroll  away and where the aurora borealis   “The  counsellors  were always my role models,”
            shines bright, that they have found their happy place.  he said. “From the beginning, camp felt like a place
              It’s  an  environment  they’re  intent  on sharing   where I was accepted no matter what.”
            with as many other people as possible, through the   A  camper  from  the  ages  of nine  through  15,  a
            efforts of the Riding Mountain Conference Centre   counsellor in training  at  16 and then a counsellor
            and its Camp Wannakumbac summer program they     for three summers,  Mitch  said  that  he was
            now manage.                                      “taught  the  value of community,  leadership,  public
              Their  journey  to  the  70-year-old  not-for-profit   speaking … compassion and patience,” among other
            camp,  situated  at  the  western  edge  of Clear  Lake,   valuable skills.


                                                                                                             31]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Camp Wannakumbac
                                                                                       managers Mitch and
                                                                                      Sarah-Anne Gustal are
                                                                                      seen on the Clear Lake
                                                                                      beach, which abuts the
                                                                                        164-acre non-profit
                                                                                      summer campgrounds.
                                                                                      They are pictured with
                                                                                         Penny, a mutt who
                                                                                     serves as camp mascot.
                                                                                      (Tyler Clarke/Trending)




















              Helping his parents and other staff throughout this time,
            Mitch said that he also remembers working hard, but rarely
            feeling put upon to do the work.
              Sarah-Anne said  that  she experienced  a similar  such
            feeling whenever she’d pop by the summer camp while they
            were dating, in that there was always plenty of work to go
            around, which she always eager to assist with.
              “You feel guilty just sitting  down,” she said, adding that
            there always seemed to be something to do.
              Meanwhile,  both Mitch  and Sarah-Anne were heading
            down life paths that  was leading  them away  from the
            summer camp and conference venue.
              Mitch trained as a graphic designer, landing  work  in   Riding Mountain Conference Centre and
            Victoria, BC, where Sarah-Anne joined him.              Camp Wannakumbac manager Mitch Gusdal,
              Unable  to work in the western  province as a massage   is seen with his father and past manager
            therapist due to a licensing disconnect between Manitoba   Darren Gustal enjoying Clear Lake in this
                                                                    undated photo from the ’90s. (Submitted)
            and BC, she spent her year in Victoria employed as a nanny.


       32]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Although  Victoria  is  a  city,  it’s  one that  remains   appreciate things more and value using your money
            well connected to nature, with parks and the ocean   as a vote instead of spending it because it’s there.”
            remaining a short walk way from their residence.   Mitch said that whereas when he was bored in the
              At a “crossroads,” they realized that their next step   city he’d likely head out somewhere to spend money,
            would have to be closer to nature. Continuing to live   now he’ll  head out into  the wilderness  to engage
            in a city would have felt like taking a step backward,   in a recreational  activity  like cross-country  skiing
            Mitch said.                                       or hiking.
              With  his  mother  firing  on  all  cylinders  running   “We’re doing  something  physical  and releasing
            the conference centre and summer camp following   endorphins because of it,  and feeling  better,” he
            her husband’s death, he said that filling the centre’s   said. “It’s a little bit like a spiritual thing for me, being
            management role felt like it would be the right fit.  outside in nature.”
              The  not-for-profit  organization’s  board  of   It’s  this love for nature  that  they aspire  to  help
            directors agreed, with Mitch and Sarah-Anne taking   bring out in people as a result of their management
            over effective Jan. 1, and Janet remaining on board   of the Riding Mountain Conference Centre.
            as a financial manager and mentor.                 Camp  Wannakumbac  appears  good  to  go,  Mitch
              Having  lived in  cities  for the  past  several  years,   said,  adding  that  they already  have about  400 of
            it’s been a bit of a culture shock, but one that both   their 500 available spots filled out.
            of them  consider a forward progression  that  has   Maintaining  their  tradition  as  a  general  nature-
            helped them inch toward becoming the people they   themed summer camp, he said that there’s enough
            wish to more closely resemble.                    inverted interest from past years to carry it forward
              “I’m  not going  to say it  was all  rainbows  and   for some time.  Even so, he said that  the hopes to
            butterflies, because I’m used to living in a city where   improve upon its  marketing,  and  like anything  else
            you walk block to get groceries, and here it’s a trip   continue to allow the summer camp to evolve with
            into Brandon to get groceries,” Sarah-Anne said.   the times.
              “I think the lack of  convenience makes  you     On this front, he clarified that technology would












































                                                                                                             33]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Clockwise from above: A leap of faith into the chilly waters
            of Clear Lake takes place during Camp Wannakumbac’s
            activities, while a canoe class operates in the background.
            (Submitted) Camp Wannakumbac members take part in
            supper cookout. (Submitted) Camp Wannakumbac’s pavilion
            building is pictured. Built in the 50s, the building is one of the
            property’s older structures. (Tyler Clarke/Trending)


            remain off-limits to those attending the camp, since
            the camp’s intention is to have participants connect
            with “actual human beings.”
              It’s the off-season — the 10 months outside of the
            summer camp season — that the new management
            duo  hopes  to  better  fill  out  for  the  not-for-
            profit organization.
              They’ve already put  the  nurse’s  cabin  available
            for rent on Airbnb.ca,  and have plans  to improve
            upon another space to make it available during the
            off season.
              They’re  also  hosting  the  centre’s  first-ever  adult
            summer camp during the September long weekend,
            called “Adults Wanna Come Back.”
              Similar  to  a  condensed summer camp  program,   centre,  which  the  young  couple,  both  in  their  late
            they’re incorporating live music and other activities   20s, are energized to do. Inspired by their love for
            for adults to enjoy during their time in the area.   nature,  they’re both  intent  on breathing  new life
              “Our generation; it’s hard to meet people in person   into the centre, and while some ideas might fall flat,
            anymore,  so it  was an opportunity  to help people   others might take off.
            our age,  who aren’t  in university  anymore,  not in   Mitch  said that  it’s  innovation  that  will  keep  the
            high school where you’re constantly being put into   camp running into the long term.
            social  situations,” Sarah-Anne said.  “This  gives you   With  overnight  school  groups  becoming
            a situation where you can meet people face to face   increasingly  difficult  to  book,  ebbing  away  at  their
            instead of on an app or Facebook.”               bottom  line,  it’s  booking  retreats,  field  trips  and
              Another effort, a Mother’s Day Wellness Weekend,   efforts such as their Airbnb.ca effort that will allow
            failed to gain traction, but rather than look at is as a   them to keep  efforts such  as  their summer camp
            failure they’re striving to learn why it didn’t take off,   program alive.
            and how they might make a similar such effort in the   Maintaining their traditions while moving forward
            future a success.                                remains a challenge, he said, but is one fuelled by the
              It’s all about adding new ideas to the 70-year-old   Gustal couple’s passion and creativity.  ❚


       34]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[3707398_BrightsideDental_Layout 1  18-06-11  3:35 PM  Page 1













          Brightsidedentalcare.com














          Brightside Dental Care


          @brightsidedentalcare                        Great locations to choose from!


                                                                          #25-144 6th St. -204-727-7136

   Here t Brightsie we tke  “rel-people”                                                      Bad
   pproch to entistry.  ur prctices were

   built on personl reltionships n the                  44 upper St. 
   hppy helthy smiles of stisfie ptients.         PaG a Pa
   We wnt you to know, from the moment you
   wlk through the oor, tht this is going to                24 Mill Street
   be  ifferent kin of entl experience.                   GadS
                                                                Cnex Mll
   - Call to book your New patient exam today!                       SH








                                                            Let’s talk about Cerec Crowns


                                                            l Cerecs Cad-CaM technology shortens the time it
                                                                tkes to get  crown from weeks to hours.

                                                            l o bulky uncomfortble impressions
                                                            l o temporry crown for severl weeks while the per-
                                                                mnent crown is being me in  lbortory
                                                            l o nee for  secon ppointment!





                                                                                                             35]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[3706535_KelleherCosmetic_Layout 1  18-06-12  4:17 PM  Page 1


           “Talk to the Doctor


             to Get the Look You Want”





             The desire to “get the look you want” has more men and women seeking
             quick and safe in-office procedures to help maintain or reverse the effects of
             time, sun and living. Dr. Kelleher’s Laser, Skin and Vein Clinic provides effective
             non-surgical cosmetic treatments for both men and women. Patients are
             assured of receiving high quality, professional treatments performed by
             Dr. Barb Kelleher, BSc, MD and her qualified staff.



             CoolSculpting         Juvederm             Acne & Rosacea
             FemiLift              SilkPeel              Management
             Fractional Laser Skin   JetPeel            Latisse Eyelash Treatment
              Resurfacing          Laser Hair Removal   Glo Mineral Makeup
             Sculptra              Chemical Peels       Skin TX & Vivier Skincare
             Dysport               Photofacials          & Anti-aging Skincare
             Restylane             Body Contouring      Vein Treatments

             Botox Cosmetic        Skin Tightening      Dermapen



             Call today to book your free confidential consultation





















             Emmy, Technician – Lori, Office Manager/Technician – Laurie, RN – Dalelene, Technician – Heather, LPN – Britta, Reception  Dr. Barbara Kelleher, BSc, MD













                        th
             150–1300–18 Street  |  Brandon, MB  | 204-727-1920  |  www.laserskinvein.com
       36]]></page></pages></Search>