<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="16"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[TO AGRICULTURE









































































































































                            NEW GARDENERS



                            HEAD TO MARKET




                            Story on B14]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[B2     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                                                        THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  MARCH 25  2021
            n
        Provincial Ex planning fundraisers








        BY TYLER CLARKE
          One year into the pandem-
        ic, community support has
        allowed the Provincial Exhibi-
        tion of Manitoba to persevere.
          That’s despite the past year’s
        worth — and running — of
        major events being cancelled.
          “We’d be telling a different
        story without that support, for
        sure,” chair Greg Crisanti said.
          “We still have a good mara-
        thon to go before we are out of
        our worry stage, but definitely
        moving  forward  to  the  new
        normal.”
          Around this time, the Royal
        Manitoba  Winter Fair would
        normally be taking place, but
        the  COVID-19 pandemic  has
        again forced the cancellation
        of this flagship annual event.
          Looking forward to the
        Manitoba Summer Fair and
        this autumn’s AgEx with cau-
        tious   optimism,  Crisanti
        points to health regulations
        as the main determinant for
        which form these events take.
          It all depends on what’s al-
        lowed.
          “The moment we’re able to
        put on events in person, we’ll
        be ready to go cross that start
        line,” he said, adding they’re
        still planning to host some
        incarnation of these future
        events, as well as organizing
        next year’s re-introduction to
        the Royal Manitoba  Winter
        Fair after a two-year absence.
          Alongside  planning   for
        these uncertain events, the or-
        ganization is hosting a num-
        ber  of  fundraisers  to  keep
        themselves in the financial
        black.
          Running a large operation   Provincial Exhibition of Manitoba chair Greg Crisanti stands outside of the Dome Building. (Tyler Clarke/The Brandon Sun)
        such as theirs is expensive,
        even with minimal staff, with  “just get us around the cor- in partnership with DeNardi/  • Love A Fair online auction   • Planted in History — a tree  display in the Dome Building.
        status quo building and op- ner.”                       La Boutique.                from 10 a.m. March 29 to 5  is purchased to be planted on   With  a  dedicated  board,
        erating expenses estimated at   Less than three months into   • Meat Cute sales in partner- p.m. April 3, at charityauction. the Provincial Exhibition of  staff and supportive commu-
        $350,000.                   the year, Crisanti said they  ship  with  To-le-do  and  Heri- bid/loveafair.       Manitoba grounds.           nity, Crisanti said he’s opti-
          This,  Crisanti  said,  is  why  were already  approximately  tage Co-op.           •  Your Name in Stone at    •  Personal  pledges  of  bi- mistic looking forward to the
        this  year’s  fundraising  goal  25 per cent of the way toward   • Safe the Fairs Donut Week  the Dome, where people can  weekly,  monthly,  quarterly,  balance of 2021.
        is $250,000 —  a figure being  earning the $100,000 required  with Tim Hortons      purchase a brick to have their  annual or one-time dona-  “We’ve seen some great
        topped up with a matching  to  top  out  the  Kinsmen’s   • A #SaveTheFairs clothing  name or their loved one’s  tions, with options and details  results so far,” he said.  “The
        pledge of up to $100,000 from  matching pledge.         line in partnership with  Tri- name engraved along a stone  coming in April.        Provincial Exhibition will cer-
        the  Kinsmen  Club  of  Winni-  Fundraisers that fell under  Star Screenprinting    walkway  at  the  Dome  Build-  • Community gifting via  tainly be  around for  years to
        peg.                        their “Love A Fair” campaign   Ongoing efforts include:  ing.                       corporate  donations  or  per- come.”
          “If we got to that $250,000,  to already take place have in-  • Sunrise Credit Union   • Love a Fair online-only  sonal pledges, which receive
        we’ll be  just  fine,” Crisanti  cluded:                drive-thru breakfast from 8-10  50/50 raffle with a guaranteed  additional recognition by way  » tclarke@brandonsun.com
        said, adding it’ll be enough to   • Wine and food basket sales  a.m. at the Dome Building.  pot of $1,000       of social media and a digital  » Twitter: @TylerClarkeMB
































                                                                                              HEAD TO TAIL




                                                                                              VETERINARY CARE








                                                                                                       Offering complete medical, surgical


                                                                                                              and consulting services for

                                                       AgriInsurance provides you with
                                              production and quality guarantees against                       small and large animals
                                         losses on over 80 grain, oilseed, and forage crops.
                                                                                                                           since 1996.

                                                                    NEW FOR 2021
                                    • Expanded seeding dates for winter wheat and fall rye.
                                         • Individual productivity indexing for silage corn.
               • Contract Price Option on canola, including specialty oil canola, and ﬁeld peas.               Dr. Jeff Gervin B. Sc., D.V.M.
                      • Forage Yield Cushioning to stabilize yield coverages for some forages.



                                    Contact your MASC oce by March 31, 2021 to apply                                  204-534-3212
                                          for or change your coverage or crop selections.
                                                                                                           Located at the North end of Boissevain on

                                                                                                           Hwy. 10 – Just 40 minutes from Brandon!






                                                                           @MASC_MB
                                                                  www.masc.mb.ca]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  MARCH 25  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                                WESTMAN THIS WEEK     B3
                                                                                                                                                                          n





























                            Canadian  a gri C ultural  S afety  WeeK




                 how to prevent common                      Safety inspections: a key tool                            12 fire safety practices for farms
                         farm injuries                        to prevent farm accidents
                                                                                                          If  you want  to  protect  the wor­  6.  Avoid placing flammable mate­
              Canadian Agricultural Safety Week will be     Farms have multi ple ha  zards that can lead   kers, animals, buildings and equip­  rials near welding areas. Com­
              held this year from March 14 to 20. In light   to serious accidents and significant health   ment on your farm, implementing   bustible  items should be kept
              of the occasion, here’s a look at some of the   pro blems. As an agri cultural producer, you   fire  prevention  strategies  is  a   at least nine metres away.
              main risks that farm workers are exposed      have a responsibility to protect the safety   must.  Here  are  12  tips  that  can
              to and how accidents can be prevented.        and well­being of your emplo yees. In fact, the   help you  protect your  as sets and  7.  Make sure you follow the sto­
                                                            Oc cu pational Health and Safety Act requi res   potentially save lives.         rage  standards for hazardous
              • Chemical contamination. Make sure you       that you identify, control and eliminate va­                                     products  including lime and
                read and understand the labels on agri­     rious hazards.                                1.  Never  smoke  in  farm  buil­  nitrogen fertilizers.
                cultural chemicals such as pesticides and                                                    dings.  Among other things,
                fertilizers.  Wash  your  hands  with  soap   Inspections should therefore be an integral    this will  prevent  the  methane  8.  Clearly  identify  pesticides  and
                and water before drinking or eating.        part  of  your  prevention  plan.  Indeed,  by   gas that’s generated by manure   store them  in a separate  buil­
                                                            regularly conducting various checks, you’ll      from igniting.                  ding.
              • Falls from a height. Always maintain three   be able to identify risks and take the neces­
                points of contact when climbing on and      sary measures to eliminate hazards before     2.  Have  at  least  one  water  tank  9.  Make sure your grain dryer has
                off  stepladders  or  farm  machinery. This   an injury or accident occurs.                  available to assist firefighters.  a fail-safe switch that’ll turn off
                could mean keeping one hand and both                                                                                         the fans if they get too hot.
                feet or both hands and one foot on the      What to look for                              3.  Install smoke and carbon mono­  The motor should also be lubri­
                surface.                                    A  safety  inspection  involves  an  extensive   xide  alarms in areas  where    cated according to the manu­
                                                            checklist,  and  you’ll  need  to  examine  all   dust and moisture won’t com­   facturer’s recommendations.
              • Slips  and  trips.  Wear  properly  laced   buildings,  fields  and  equipment  used  on     promise their effectiveness.
                shoes or boots, adjust your walking speed   your  property. Road safety, methods of                                       10. Have  a  master  electrician  re­
                to suit the terrain and make sure your vi­  working and management practices should       4.  Keep  a  sufficient  quantity  of   place outdated  electrical  sys­
                sion  isn’t obstructed  when carrying a     likewise be revie wed. Emergency prepare­        porta ble ABC fire extinguishers   tems.
                load.                                       dness and fire prevention are also key.          on hand.                     11. Regularly  clean the electrical

              • Musculoskeletal injuries. Ask for help or   During  any  safety  inspection,  it’s  best  to   5.  Don’t use combustible mate­  panel, outlets and switches.
                use lifting aids such as a wheelbarrow to   avoid dispersing your efforts. Instead, you      rials such as sawdust to absorb
                move heavy or bulky loads.                  should concen trate  on one stage of pro­        oil from the ground.         12. Don’t apply paint or any other
                                                                                                                                             product on  electrical  installa­
              • Heat stroke. Wear light clothing and a      duction, one type of equipment or one lo-                                        tions.
                wide­brim med hat on hot summer days.       cation at a time.
                Be sure to drink water regularly and take   To learn more about farm safety, refer to
                                                                                                                                                If a fire breaks out in
                frequent breaks in the shade.               the  resour ces  provided  by  the  Canadian                                    an airtight silo, don’t open it.
                                                            Agricultural   Safety   Association   at                                           Doing so could cause
              For more tips on how to prevent injuries and   casa­acsa.ca.
              make  your  workplace  safer,  visit  agsa-                                                                                          an explosion.
              fetyweek.ca.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[B4     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                                                        THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  MARCH 25  2021
            n
        Shape Foods





        broadens scope








        BY TYLER CLARKE             straightforward —  vast in    Oil can be used for such
                                    scale, but “not in-depth.”  products as an ingredient in
          A  global  enterprise at  the   Sourcing cleaned product  non-dairy beverages for its
        east end of Brandon, Shape  from Zeghers Canada in Hol- omega 3 content, while flax
        Foods processes approximate- land  and  Vandaele  Seeds  in  meal can be used for various
        ly 4,000 to 6,000 metric tons of  Minto, their mainly automat- things, such as baking and pet
        flax in an average year.    ed plant gets to work as soon  food.
          At various stages of expand- as grain trucks’ contents pass   “Flax meal is also used as an
        ing to accommodate hemp,  an initial inspection.        egg replacement, if you want-
        sunflower seeds and their own   Product is  then  vacuumed  ed to have a truly vegan meal,”
        line of in-house products, the  into the plant’s largely auto- Snidal said.
        company has worked to diver- matic process, which begins   Shape Foods has been in
        sify its appeal in recent years.  with it being crushed into flax  Brandon for approximately 10
          Company president and  meal and flax oil.             years and employs 21 people,
        CEO Vernon Snidal walked the   The oil is still dark at this  with much of their product
        Sun through their operations  stage, so it’s filtered to get the  shipping out of the coun-
        recently, from pre-deposit in- sediment  out  and  packaged  try  —  mainly to the United
        spection to readying product  into totes for export.    States, though their exports
        for overseas shipment.        Flax meal is either refined or  stretch around the globe.
          By food-processing stan- exported as flax meal, depend-
        dards, he said it’s ultimately  ing on the client’s needs.    » See ‘In-house’ — Page B6









                  We involve ourselves in all things farming –

                       offering everything from tractor tires

                                to on-the-farm services.




























                   Brandon, MB        204-725-1523          fountaintire.com

                                                                                            Shape Foods lab technician Diogo Janiaski inspects yellow flax seed. (Tyler Clarke/The Brandon Sun)



















                                            WEST END                                                                                 Produce
                                                                                                                                       Fresh






                                         START YOUR




                         Spring                                                                                                            Scratch
                                                                                                                                           Freshly
                                                                                                                                            Baked
                                                                                                                                             From







                                      Fresh                                                        Designs
                        OFF                                                                        Custom
                                                                                                     Floral











                                                                                                                                                               More

                                                                                                                                 Deli                         Baked
                                                                                                                               & Wide                         Goods
                                                                                                                              Selection
                                                                                                                               of Meat



















             3409 VICTORIA AVENUE   |   BRANDON   |   204-727-3443                                                          bdnsobeyswest              bdnsobeyswest]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[B6     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                                                        THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  MARCH 25  2021
            n
              »In-house flax, hemp products set to hit shelves





        Continued from Page B4

          In many cases, value is added
        outside of Canada and exported
        back to the country by way of
        whatever end product it’s been
        used in the creation of.
          In addition to flax, the com-
        pany has expanded to accom-
        modate hemp and is in the pro-
        cess of incorporating sunflowers
        seeds into its operations.
          “All of those would have very
        similar properties to what we’re
        doing here, and all would be
        human-consumption     ready,”
        Snidal said, adding all three un-
        dertake the same exact process
        using the same equipment.
          Along the way, Shape Foods
        has also recently expanded to
        include their own in-house flax
        and hemp products, which they
        are currently in the process of
        marketing and distributing for
        sale in Canadian grocery stores.
          While many businesses have
        been negatively impacted by
        the COVID-19 pandemic, Snidal
        said theirs has pushed through.
          “As COVID came on, there was
        definitely  an  increase  in  busi-
        ness for us we’d typically not
        see at that time of year,” he said,
        adding he’s uncertain as to the
        source of this demand within a
        global marketplace, but that it
        was followed by a lull.
          Operationally, he said they
        overcompensated to  the  pan-
        demic at first and slowly eased
        back on certain overly cautious
        self-imposed restrictions as in-
        formation came forward.
          Ultimately, their existing sani-
        tary operations were of benefit,
        as not much had to change aside
        from wearing masks and signing
        people in with a health-related
        questionnaire upon their arrival.
          There’s great potential for flax
        moving forward, Snidal said, as
        plant-based proteins carry lon-
        gevity in a marketplace looking
        for environmentally minded al-
        ternatives.
          “There’s definitely a move-
        ment for healthy food, for sure,
        and flax would be in that catego-
        ry regardless of the pandemic,”
        he said, adding everything they
        strive toward builds upon this
        brand of “healthy items for peo-
        ple to eat.”
        » tclarke@brandonsun.com
        » Twitter: @TylerClarkeMB     Shape Foods shipper/receiver Rob Dufresne is seen hard at work recently. (Tyler Clarke/The Brandon Sun)]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  MARCH 25  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                                WESTMAN THIS WEEK     B7
                                                                                                                                                                          n
        Celebrating Manitoba’s farm families







          We are excited to be honour- VERWEY FAMILY —
        ing the 2020 BMO Farm Family   VERWEY FARMS
        Award recipients. Unfortunate-
        ly, when the 2020 Royal Mani-  Historical background: This
        toba Winter Fair was cancelled   third-generation  farm  was
        last March due to COVID-19,   started by Raymond’s parents.
        we were unable to move for-  Ray  and  Jill  encouraged  their
        ward  with  our  planned  in-  children to gain an education,
        person celebrations.  We are   then come back help grow the
        happy to be partnering with   farm.
        The  Brandon  Sun  and  BMO   They work together as a fam-
        to finally acknowledge these   ily, as everybody has the ability
        families and celebrate their ac-  to do “the job.”
        complishments and dedication   Jill is the vice-president of
        to agriculture in Manitoba.  Keystone Ag Producers (KAP).
                                      Type of farming operation:
                                    Grain, cattle and dairy farm.
        » The Provincial Exhibition of
        Manitoba                      Family participation:  Run-            Verwey Family — Verwey Farms                           Steppler Family — Steppler Farms
                                    ning a 6,000-acre farm requires
        Editor’s note: Look for stories   the family all work together.  the future:  The family has  voice in ag policy.   bandry is a priority.   STEPPLER FAMILY —
        about the Provincial Exhibi-  They promote equality among  maintained a mixed operation   The family has not been   Community involvement:   STEPPLER FARMS
        tion’s 2021 farm families in   cousins and siblings.    despite continued industry  afraid to try new crops and  In 2018, the family grew 40   Historical  background:
        upcoming editions of Westman   People involved include Ray  pressure to specialize. They en- cropping methods to improve  acres of soybeans to support   Steppler Farms is a multi-
        This Week.                  and  Jill,  their  children,  and  courage each other to get and  farm profitability.  STARS, raising $22,350.  They   generational farm and will cel-
                                    Ray’s brothers Gerry, Roger  stay educated with advances in   Land stewardship: Crop ro- open their farm on Open     ebrate its centennial in 2021.
                                    and Conrad.                 agriculture. With Jill’s presence  tations are maintained to im- Farm Day to promote ag edu-
                                      Combining the past and  in KAP, they are now pursuing a  prove soil health. Cattle hus- cation.
                                                                                                                                                                    » See Page B10

            Whether you need a wheel barrow tire, passenger
           tire, medium truck tire, farm or earthmover tire, we                                 Organic Producers Association of
                service and sell whatever your tire needs are!                                        Manitoba Co-operative Inc.

                                                                                                 Offering professional organic certification services
                                                                                                          to customers in Western Canada




                                                                                                •  Established in 1988
                                                                                                                                                         New members
                                                                                                •  Provides CFIA accredited certification system.           receive a

                                                                                                •  Distribute information to producers, processors,         10%
                                                                                                  and handlers regarding techniques, standards,           DISCOUNT
                                                                                                  and procedures.                                           off initial
                                                                                                                                                        application fees
                                                                                                •  Promote and provide education on orgainc systems.
                                                                                                                                                       SPECIAL RATES
                                                                                                •  Annual farm tours and member get-togethers.            FOR SMALL
                                                                                                                                                          PRODUCERS
                        24-hour after-hours on-site service
                                                                                                  MISSION STATEMENT
                                                       1 Mile West of Husky                       To promote organic food production and consumption
                                                       on #1 Hwy, Brandon
                                                  204-727-3323 | 888-727-3323
                                                                                              CONTACT US
                                                     490 Hwy 5 N., Neepawa                    204-567-3745                 123 North Railway Avenue, Box 279, Miniota, MB  R0M 1M0
                                                          204-476-5566                                                                  info@opam-mb.com  •  www.opam-mb.com]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[GERVIN STOCK FARM





                                                                         RETIREMENT FARM AUCTION








                                                                                      APRIL 21, 2021





                                                                          ONLINE BIDDING ONLY











                                     For more information, or to book viewing of sale items contact

                                        Curtis Gervin 204-522-6207 or broomhillcows@gmail.com











































































































            Fraser Auction Service P: 204-727-2001   TF:1-800-483-5856   Email: ofﬁce@fraserauction.com


                                  Like us            Fraser Auction Service Ltd.     Follow us                              @fraserauction








                                          fraserauction.com






                  For complete details & to sign up for online bidding.










               Brandon, MB      Auctioneer: Scott Campbell / Jesse Campbell      Licensed and bonded. P.L. License #918093. Member of M.A.A., S.A.A., A.A.A., A.A.C.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[2021









                                                                                                    MARCH & APRIL SALES





                                                                           Phone: 204-727-2001 or 1-800-483-5856                Like us    Fraser Auction Service Ltd.
                                                                                                  Fax: 204-729-9912                      Follow us     @fraserauction
                                                                                     Email: ofﬁce@fraserauction.com          www.fraserauction.com

                                                                        2021 DATES STILL AVAILABLE




















                         MARCH 28   TH
                 KILLARNEY CONSIGNMENT                            APRIL 8  TH                            APRIL 12  TH                            APRIL 14  TH
                                                                  MCPHAIL                                CALDWELL                                 PEARSON
                     JOHNSTON FARMS

















                          APRIL 15 TH                            APRIL 16  TH                            APRIL 17  TH                            APRIL 19  TH
                           AMENDT                                 MCBRIDE                               SCHWEITZER                              WOODHOUSE





                  fraserauction.com For complete details & to sign up for online bidding.





                  Brandon, MB      Auctioneer: Scott Campbell / Jesse Campbell      Licensed and bonded. P.L. License #918093. Member of M.A.A., S.A.A., A.A.A., A.A.C.









                                                                                                    2021








                                                                                                    MARCH & APRIL SALES





                                                                           Phone: 204-727-2001 or 1-800-483-5856                Like us     Fraser Auction Service Ltd.
                                                                                                  Fax: 204-729-9912                      Follow us     @fraserauction
                                                                                     Email: ofﬁce@fraserauction.com           www.fraserauction.com

                                                                         2021 DATES STILL AVAILABLE





















                          APRIL 20  TH                            APRIL 21 ST                            APRIL 22  ND                            APRIL 23  RD
                          MCGOWAN                                  GERVIN                                  COTTYN                                  PAWICH


















                          APRIL 24 TH                             APRIL 24 TH                            APRIL 28  TH                            APRIL 30  TH
                            LOCKE                                   MOIR                                   NETTLE                                 HALWAS





                      fraserauction.com For complete details & to sign up for online bidding.





                  Brandon, MB      Auctioneer: Scott Campbell / Jesse Campbell      Licensed and bonded. P.L. License #918093. Member of M.A.A., S.A.A., A.A.A., A.A.C.]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[B10     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                                                       THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  MARCH 25  2021
             n

        Continued from Page B7        Family participation: Dan  world as a keynote speaker.  Baseball. Andre is also a past
                                    and Pat’s four sons are all in-  Land  stewardship:  The director of both the Manitoba
          The farm began as a grain  volved in the farm. Ian is the   grain farm has implemented  Charolais Association and the
        and cream quote operation.  president of the farm. He and  zero tile and minimal till prac- National Charolais Associa-
        When the farm was transferred  his wife Sandy manage the bee  tices to effectively manage soil  tion. He sits on the foundation
        to  Dan  and  Pat  Steppler, the  operation. Geoff and Sarah are  health. Soils at risk are sowed  board for the Canadian Cha-
        grain farm continued, milk  directors. Adam and Amber  down for rotational grazing  rolais Association. Ian is vice-
        cows were sold, and a PB Cha- are managers of grain opera- with an increase of wild flow- president of the Manitoba Bee
        rolais operation was created in  tion. Andre and Katie manage  ers and forages to increase the  Keeping Association.
        1973. Dan and Pat’s sons all at- the cattle operation.  food needed for honey pro-    Awards and highlights: An-
        tained a post-secondary edu-  Combining the past and the  duction  and  bee  health.  The  dre and Katie were recently
        cation, and brought new ideas  future:  Use of Facebook and  cattle farm is committed to  selected for the Great  Tastes
        back to the farm. After Ian re- YouTube provide the farm with  riparian preservation and wa- of Manitoba.  The farm was
        ceived his diploma at the Uni- a large audience. Andre and  tersheds. They fence off these  awarded Purebred Breeder of
        versity of Manitoba, he started  Katie travel across Canada to  areas and use the water and  the Year in the past. Their cat-
        the honeybee operation.  This  judge and evaluate cattle. They  grazing sources responsibly.  tle are shown at provincial and
        was integral to the expansion  share their knowledge on cat-  Community involvement:  national shows and have won
        of the farm and allowed more  tle and help promote positive  The family recently  raised  several championship awards.
        family involvement.         messaging through keynote  more than $16,000 from a do- The farm was awarded with               Grossart Family — Howpark Farms
          Type of farming opera- speaking appearances at 4-H  nation heifer for a national  the 2018 Pembina Valley Con-
        tion:  The farm consists of  clubs.  They were recently se- youth event in Brandon. An- servation Award.        a fifth-generation farm this  for grazing and crop produc-
        4,000 acres of grain, 600 PB  lected as the face of the Mani- dre, Katie and Sandy are Mi-                      year. Ian’s great-grandfather  tion. They have taken on land
        Charolais cows, a commercial  toba Beef Producers through  ami  4-H  beef  club  leaders.   GROSSART FAMILY —   homesteaded the farm in  under Habitat Heritage agree-
        herd of 100 black cows and a  the Great  Tastes of Manitoba  Andre, Katie and Pat are direc-                    1879, naming it after his birth- ments to preserve the land on
        2,500-beehive operation. They  campaigns.  Ian  shares  the  tors on the Miami Agricultural  HOWPARK FARMS      place  in  Scotland.  The  farm  and  adjacent  to  the  Brandon
        grow cereals, oilseeds, pulses,  Steppler Bee operation with  society. Andre and Katie are in-  Historical  background:  has always operated with di- Hills. They have installed more
        grain corn, silage corn and  his  25,000  YouTube  channel  volved with the Miami Sports  Howpark Farms is a fourth- verse mix of crops and cattle.  than six miles of pasture pipe-
        sunflowers.                 subscribers and travels the  Complex and Miami Minor  generation farm, moving into    Type of farming operation:  line. They have been a part of
                                                                                                                        Organic mixed farm raising  the Habitat Heritage-support-
                                                                                                                        organic grains, grass-fed beef  ed Twice Over Grazing Project
                                                                                                                        and pasture chickens.       aimed at improving the native
                                                                                                                          Family participation:  Ian  pastures and protecting habi-
                           FARMS FOR SALE                                                                               son Zach are currently active  cies at risk.
                                                                                                                        and Linda, father Doug and  tat for native species and spe-
                                                                                                                                                     Community involvement:
                                                                                                                        and directly involved with
                                                                                                                        the farm, while children An- The Grossarts have opened
                                                                                                                        drew and  Avery are indirectly  their farm to university and
                                                                                                                        involved. Doug, Ian, Andrew,  college tours over the years.
                                                                                                                        Zach and Avery are all gradu- They have also been a part of
                WAWANESA                   DELORAINE                    NESBITT                   DUNREA                ates of the University of Mani- local film productions. Doug
                                                                                                                        toba, and Linda is a graduate  was a past-president of the
                   SOLD                  $ 2,300,000                $ 3,200,000                 $ 320,000               of  Brandon  University.  Avery  Brandon Co-op, a volunteer

            Located south of Wawanesa.     Great starter farm.         Eight quarters.       Located north or Dunrea.   will soon graduate from Life  with the Farm and Rural Stress
                                                                                                                        University in Marietta, Ga.,  line, chair of the local elevator
               Fourteen quarters of     Located adjacent to Hwy    Gently rolling productive   Quarter section of good   and plans to return to Bran- and has been a part of various
               productive grainland     #3 west of Boissevain with   grainland adjacent to   grainland seeded to fall rye.  don to work.            local committees. Doug, Ian
            complete with beautiful two    central yard site.          PR Raod 346.               SE-3-6-17W              Combining the past and the  and Linda have all been on var-
            storey home, excellent newer   Section 2-3-22W                                                              future: The Grossarts have ad- ious committees of the Bran-
            buildings, and hopper bottom                                                                                opted fully organic agronomy  don Hills Church and Commu-
                  grain storage.                                                                                        and husbandry to meet the  nity Club. Linda and Ian taught
                                                                                                                        growing consumer demand.  first  aid  and  lifeguarding  to
                SHOAL LAKE                   VIRDEN                    BRANDON                    NEEPAWA               Their regenerative and or- area residents for several years
                                                                                                                        ganic practices are aimed at  and Linda is a past-president
               $ 7,200,000                 $ 735,000                    SOLD                       SOLD                 building healthy soils, growing  of the Manitoba Lifesaving So-
                                                                                                                        nutrient-dense foods, preserv- ciety. Ian served eight years as
               Central yard site with     Ready to go livestock   Productive grainland for sale   Productive farmland for sale   ing the natural landscape and  a municipal councillor for the
               modern grain storage.   operation! Located north of   located three minutes west   located east of the thriving   native prairie habitat.  then RM of Oakland and has
              Twenty quarters of flat,   Oak Lake between Brandon   of Brandon, MB, adjacent to   town of Neepawa, MB.    Land stewardship: The fam- served and continues to serve
            productive grainland, with B     and Virden.                HWY 459.                  NE 16-15-14W          ily’s organically regenerative  on several ag-related commit-
            and C crop insurance ratings.  E 1/2 33-10-24W          B rated soil is great for                           practices include  long-term  tees.  The  farm  was a  World
                                                                   growing all types of crops                           crop rotations, cover cropping  Wide Opportunies on Organic
                                                                   including beans or corn.                             and high stock density grazing.  Farms host family for several
                                                                                                                        They purchased ecologically  years and hosted young people
                                                                                                                        sensitive lands adjacent the  from several countries from
            For more information contact:                                                                               farm  to  maintain  the  nature  around the world on their farm
            Henry Carels 204.573.5396                                                                                   ecology and help maintain  and more recently has host-
                                                                                                                        the local plant species.  The  ed and provided internship
            Catharina Carels 204.720.4779                                                                               Grossarts manage their land  training  to  ag  students  from

            Please call or text for additional available listings                                                       to build soil health and pro- France.
                                                                                                                        vide fully self-sufficient land             » See Page B11















                                                                                                                   “Our Buns Don’t Jiggle”




























                                                                                                               who work so tirelessly during
                                                                                                              harvest to provide us with the

                                                                                                            ingredients we use in the bakery,
                                                                                                                especially the amazing flour.



































                                                                                               1411–1  Street, Brandon
                                                                                                          st
                                                                                               204-728-3023]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  MARCH 25  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                                WESTMAN THIS WEEK     B11
                                                                                                                                                                         n















































                                 Berry Family — Under the Hill Farms                                                 Itzke Family — Itzke River Farm Ltd.


        Continued from Page B10           now managed by the third genera- Managing row crops with strip tilling  work ethic — all values which the  organism. Itzke River Farm has cho-
                                          tion — cousins Chad Berry and Kev- and cover crops minimizes soil loss.  family shares today.  The tight-knit  sen to nurture the life within the soil
          Awards and highlights: Previous  in Berry. Doug and Bruce continue to  They use micronutrients and bio-ad- Itzke family takes pride in serving as  to promote healthy plants and high
        Century Farm Award, designated a  be active in management and day- ditives to  maximize soil health and  role models and support systems for  yields rather than banking complete-
        heritage farm.                    to-day work.                     productivity.  Transition to organic  each other.                  ly on synthetic inputs. Some of these
                                           Combining the past and the fu- production and incorporating solar   Type of farming operation: Pro- practices include cover cropping,
        BERRY FAMILY —                    ture: All crops are grown under irriga- energy into the operation demon- duce.                      reduced tillage, fertilizer application
                                          tion. When Simplot facilitated condo  strates their commitment to main-
                                                                                                              Family participation: Hedwig Itz- efficiency, application of biological
        UNDER THE HILL FARMS              storage for potatoes at the Portage la  taining soil health sustainably.  ke, John D. Itzke, Uwe Itzke, Astrid  inoculants, soil and plant tissue
          Historical background:  Grandpa  Prairie plant, the Berrys bought in,   Community involvement: His- Itzke-Meilleur,  Gerry  Meilleur,  Mats  analysis.
        Berry operated the grain and cattle  and recently commissioned a wash  torically, the operation has support- Meilleur, Lars Meilleur, Jens Meilleur,   Community involvement: The
        farm  north  of  Cypress  River.  When  plant at their condo to improve the  ed local 4-H clubs. When the local  Meike Meilleur and Drew Itzke are all  family is very much part of their
        his sons Doug and Bruce took over,  quality of product going into the  Glenboro  4-H club recently reno- involved.                    community.  They donate many
        they expanded and changed the  Simplot Portage la Prairie potato  vated and built a new show ring, the   Combining the past and the fu- cases of vegetables annually to lo-
        operation to handle two  growing  plant. In 2018 and 2019, solar energy  Berrys donated and delivered all the  ture: Itzke River Farm has shown  cal fundraisers and events. They run
        families. Looking to manage crop  was brought in to power seven pivot  sand. The farm is a previous winner  outstanding sustainment and pro- tours to promote education in the
        rotations by the mid-1990s, Doug  sites. When not running a pivot, the  of the McCain Environmental award.  gressive agricultural management  vegetable industry from kindergar-
        and Bruce expanded the crop rota- solar sites feed renewable energy  The family chose to branch out and  practices in the past few years. They  ten classes to university students to
        tion to include edible beans, then  back into the grid for consumption  bought the Pleasant  Valley golf  have taken preliminary steps in the  government representatives. In past
        potatoes.  This brought the need to  by Manitobans. With potatoes as a  course to ensure there was a qual- direction  of  regenerative  farming,  years, the family has been involved
        manage the light soils north of Cy- key crop in the rotation, the Berrys  ity golf facility adjacent the Pleasant  working alongside natural laws, rath- in coaching and playing with local
        press River to minimize soil ero- are continually adopting techniques  Valley Tri-Lake system.       er than against them. As the climate  sports teams.  They donated funds
        sion. The family has chosen to grow,  to maintain soil health. Row crops                             and soil have changed, management  and contributed to the planning of
        diversify and evolve with every    are now strip-tilled to minimize soil   ITZKE FAMILY —            practices and paradigms have been  the artificial ice construction in the
        generation to maintain their rural  disturbance, and many row crops are                              altered as well. The Itzkes’ goal is to  local hockey arena.
        way of life.                      grown with cover crops. Some acres  ITZKE RIVER FARM LTD.          one day pass their land along to oth-  Awards and highlights: Itzke River
          Type of farming operation:  The  are being transitioned to organic   Historical background: The farm’s  ers in better condition than it was  Farm was the recipient of the Loblaw
        farm grows 2,000 acres of potatoes  production for all crops.      founder, Johannes Itzke, immigrat- primarily received.             Vendor Development Partnership
        along with corn, canola, sunflowers,   Land stewardship:  The Berrys  ed to Canada from northern Ger-  Land stewardship: For many years,  Award in recognition of leadership
        oats, barley, wheat, fall rye, rye grass,  were  early  adopters  of  the  Ducks  many in 1953. Along with his strong  soil has been seen solely as a medium  within the produce industry.
        flax, soybeans and edible beans.  Unlimited projects. Their motto for  knowledge of plants and passion for  to hold plants upright when, in real-
          Family participation: The farm is  crop production is “Keep all the dirt.”  growing, Johannes carried a resilient  ity it’s a crucial, living and breathing     » See Page B15]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  MARCH 25  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                                WESTMAN THIS WEEK     B13
                                                                                                                                                                         n
        Producers have moisture on their minds






        BY COLIN SLARK                                                                                                                              moving in the right direction
                                                                                                                                                    with rising commodity and
          It could be another dry year                                                                                                              stabilizing livestock prices.
        for Westman crop producers.                                                                                                                   “We  know  a  lot  more  than
          Though there was far too                                                                                                                  we did a year ago with regards
        much moisture for most peo-                                                                                                                 to  safety  protocols  and  PPE
        ple’s liking at the end of June                                                                                                             and that part,” he said about
        and beginning of July last year                                                                                                             farming during COVID-19.
        when excess rainfall caused                                                                                                                 “There still is that element of
        flooding, it has been fairly dry                                                                                                            uncertainty and we haven’t
        since August.                                                                                                                               mentioned the weather yet.”
          That lack of moisture com-                                                                                                                  He said there have been re-
        bined with a forecast that                                                                                                                  ports that the last winter was
        doesn’t predict a lot of rain                                                                                                               one of the driest on record in
        could be a bad combination.                                                                                                                 certain areas because of a lack
          Natalie Hasell, a warning                                                                                                                 of snowfall.
        preparedness  meteorologist                                                                                                                   “Not to complain about it
        with Environment and Cli-                                                                                                                   because it has made winter a
        mate Change Canada, told                                                                                                                    bit more tolerable other than
        the Sun that rainfall events                                                                                                                the two weeks of extremely
        over the next month are sup-                                                                                                                cold weather we had, it has
        posed to be small individually,                                                                                                             been  beneficial  in  some  as-
        though there is a chance that                                                                                                               pects,” said  Campbell.  “But
        collectively they could add to                                                                                                              moving forward, we realize
        to an above-average total.                                                                                                                  that we need subsoil moisture
          A seasonal forecast issued                                                                                                                and  subsoil  moisture  replen-
        at the end of last month un-                                                                                                                ishment to ensure a good crop
        fortunately doesn’t offer more                                                                                                              moving forward.”
        clarity.                                                                                                                                      Though the lack of sus-
          “Unfortunately for south-                                                                                                                 tained rain last year might
        ern Manitoba, it doesn’t actu-                                                                                                              have meant the subsoil mois-
        ally have a dominant trend for                                                                                                              ture reserves in Manitoba were
        precipitation,” said Hasell. “It                                                                                                            depleted, he said it also led to
        literally could go either way. It                                                                                                           an easier harvest than in 2019.
        could be near normal, it could                                                                                                                On KAP’s list of lobbying pri-
        above normal, it could be be-                                                                                                               orities for this year is the car-
        low normal.”                                                                                                                                bon tax, specifically the insti-
          However, she said that in                                                                                                                 tution of an exemption to the
        southeast     Saskatchewan,  Though there was far too much moisture for most people’s liking at the end of June and beginning of July last year when excess   tax for producers drying their
        the seasonal forecast shows  rainfall caused flooding, it has been fairly dry since August. That lack of moisture combined with a forecast that doesn’t predict   grain and heating and cooling
        a  trend  toward  below  nor-  a lot of rain could mean another dry year for Westman producers. (File)                                      farm buildings.
        mal precipitation.  That  could                                                                                                               “I know that’s been a topic
        mean Westman is in the same  in late summer 2020.       got more farmers to pick the  so that’s always encouraging.”  will be a better choice.”  of conversation at the federal
        boat as its neighbouring re-  The alliance was formed last  brains of and get some head-  Coming into the 2021 grow-  Luckily, Greig said farming  level and they’re talking about
        gion to the west.           year  when  members  of  the  space on them and get their  ing season, he says producers  has probably been one of the  a rebate program,” said Camp-
          Hasell speculated that the  Manitoba  Wheat and Barley  input  on  issues that affect  he  has talked to are worried  segments of the economy that  bell.
        dry conditions currently might  Growers Association, Manito- us all instead of individu- about the lack of precipitation  has continued to drive activity   “There’s also the whole issue
        be beneficial to farmers, let- ba Corn Growers Association,  ally,” Grieg said. “Some of the  and the potential depletion of  during  COVID-19. However,  of carbon sequestration and
        ting them sow their crops  Manitoba Flax Growers Asso- boards are smaller, so it can be  subsoil moisture.      repairs to equipment have  the whole issue of agriculture
        without having equipment get  ciation, Winter Cereals Mani- quite a daunting task some-  If conditions stay dry, Greig  been delayed if they’re com- getting acknowledged for the
        stuck in the mud.           toba and the National Sun- times. From a staff standpoint,  is guessing that most produc- ing out of the United States  benefit they provide to society.
          That  was  a  problem in  late  flower Association of Canada  it sure was nice to have some  ers will switch to crops that  and there have been some de- We take carbon dioxide from
        2019 when a dry spring and  voted to merge into a single  overlap in some positions.”  handle lack of moisture better.  lays along the industry’s value  the air and produce food and
        summer was capped off with  entity.                       He said that unlike in 2019,  Until then, they’re probably  chain.                release oxygen and store car-
        a wet fall that made it hard   Board chair Fred Grieg, who  most producers were probably  sticking with their rotations.  At Keystone Agricultural  bon in the soil and the prod-
        for producers to harvest their  operates  a  farm  near  Reston,  pleased with how 2020 treated   “That’s the most sustain- Producers,  president  Bill ucts we produce.”
        crops.                      said  COVID-19  prevented  the  them from a weather stand- able thing long term,” he said.  Campbell said that producers   On  his  own  farm  south  of
          “But  if  we  don’t  get  a  lot  of  organization from holding  point.           “There’ll  be  a  little  more  bar- always go into a new growing  Brandon,  Campbell  said  he’s
        precipitation at the right time,  in-person strategic planning   “For as little moisture as we  ley and oats this year at the  season with optimism but are  excited to see the grass start
        getting water to crops could be  meetings last year, but work  got throughout the growing  expense, probably, of spring  realistic about potential prob- to turn green, for seeds to start
        expensive,” said Hasell.    continues to get done based  season, I think the soil reserves  wheat.  It  looks  like  canola  lems that could arise.  going into the ground and for
          At the Manitoba Crop Alli- on the framework left behind  we were able to rely on a bit,”  might take some acres from   While he said there isn’t cer- cows to be let out to pasture.
        ance, work is getting ready to  by the constituent groups be- he  said.  “Timely  rains  made  soybeans again, especially if  tainly around the issue yet,
        prepare for its first full growing  fore the merger.    for a better than average crop,  guys think it’ll be a little drier.  Campbell said that there’s a  » cslark@brandonsun.com
        season after being established   “What’s really nice is we’ve  I think. Prices have snuck up,  Maybe peas and sunflowers  general sense that things are  » Twitter: @ColinSlark

            INCREASE THE ENJOYMENT



                            OF YOUR VIEW!                                                           YOUR CENTURY 21 WESTMAN
                                                                                                    FARM SALES AND MARKETING TEAM


                             YOU’VE EARNED IT!





                                                              FREE



                                                              ESTIMATES


                                                        SUPPORT LOCAL


               Serving Westman since 1997               BUSINESSES























                                                                                                           We are committed to providing a full
                                                                                                           Professional Service.




                                                                                                           You only market your property once...

                                                                                                           YOU DESERVE THE BEST.













                                                                                                                         2915 Victoria Avenue
                        RESERVE A SUMMER DATE FOR
                THE INSTALLATION OF YOUR SUNROOM.                                                                       Brandon, MB  R7B 2N6
                                                                                                                   century21westmanrealty.com

                204-726-8488  |  www.sunspacesunrooms.com                                                                    204-725-0555

          155 Prairie Crescent Brandon  |  sales@elitesunrooms.ca]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[B14     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                                                       THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  MARCH 25  2021
             n
        Market gardeners learning fast








        BY HEATHER REIMER                                                                                                                           boxes  containing  a  variety  of
                                                                                                                                                    fresh produce from their farm
          The year 2020 was a life-                                                                                                                 delivered weekly to subscrib-
        changing year for  Prairie                                                                                                                  ers.  The couple intends to
        Knight Farms  operators  Ash-                                                                                                               double their crop varieties this
        ley Heaman and Graeme                                                                                                                       season.
        Knight, and not just because                                                                                                                  Despite having done a lot
        of the COVID-19 pandemic.                                                                                                                   of  research  before  making
          The couple from  Winnipeg                                                                                                                 the move to rural Manitoba,
        moved with their two young                                                                                                                  Knight says he wishes he knew
        daughters out to the country-                                                                                                               sooner about things like suc-
        side near the small Westman                                                                                                                 cession planting, where grow-
        community of Margaret  to                                                                                                                   ers make produce available
        begin their new occupation as                                                                                                               to consumers throughout the
        market gardeners. Neither had                                                                                                               season with phased plantings
        ever farmed before the move.                                                                                                                and small, frequent harvests.
          Knight, 27, had spent his                                                                                                                   He also wishes they had
        entire working life from age                                                                                                                learned earlier about pest-
        14 onward in retail, and his                                                                                                                prevention tricks like row cov-
        wife Ashley, 30, worked as an                                                                                                               erings, and had planted more
        administrative assistant while                                                                                                              leafy vegetables to meet the
        they raised Iyla, 6, and Elise, 3.                                                                                                          demand.
          “I had the idea shortly after                                                                                                               Nevertheless, the satisfac-
        having Iyla,” said Heaman. “I                                                                                                               tion they feel in growing and
        wanted to do things to take                                                                                                                 selling food is only eclipsed by
        better care of the  planet,  be                                                                                                             the positive changes in their
        more   environmentally  re-                                                                                                                 quality of life on the land. They
        sponsible. That meant starting                                                                                                              eat better, spend more time
        to grow our own food.”                                                                                                                      together as a family, and Hea-
          Knight’s  initial  reaction  to                                                                                                           man says she’s enjoying home-
        her plan?                                                                                                                                   schooling Iyla.
          “I thought you were crazy,”                                                                                                                 “In the city, I wouldn’t have
        he said.  “No, I’m not moving                                                                                                               had that opportunity. Plus we
        to  the  middle  of  nowhere.  I                                                                                                            get to feed them healthy, deli-
        really enjoyed my job. But as                                                                                                               cious, home-grown food every
        time went on, it started mak-                                                                                                               day. In the city, we did takeout
        ing more sense.  We got into                                                                                                                a lot because we were exhaust-
        gardening, and lo and behold,                                                                                                               ed all the time.”
        here we are.”                                                                                                                                 Meaud and Burrell live in
          In March of 2020, the family                                                                                                              the nearby main house where
        left their life in Winnipeg just                                                                                                            both families come together
        as the first cases of COVID-19                                                                                                              daily to cook, eat and visit and
        were being announced by the  Ashley Heaman and Graeme Knight pose for a photo on their farm near Margaret. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)      where their kids can play safe-
        province. And while rural life                                                                                                              ly within their COVID bubble.
        provided a buffer from the  their relatives a guest cabin  was raging and heightened  shifted again in late August  help his cousin with the grain   Looking back at the past 12
        worst effects of the pandemic,  and three acres of land plus all  government regulations made  when even stricter COVID  harvest.  The  family  saved  on  months,  Knight and Heaman
        it also presented a plethora of  the free farming advice they  doing business more compli- rules were introduced. The trio  groceries  by eating their un- have no regrets about their de-
        challenges to the young family. could handle.           cated, requiring markets to  made the tough call to shut  sold produce through the au- cision to trade the city for the
          First,  the  bank wouldn’t   “Now we ask their advice on  enforce  mask-wearing,  social  down the market two weeks  tumn and winter.     country life.
        give them a mortgage to buy a  everything, probably to the  distancing and hand-washing.  earlier than scheduled.   Despite  an  unprofitable  “We’ve met some fantastic
        farm, even though they owned  point where it’s obnoxious,”  That prompted the sole op-  “That really put a damper   2020 (they broke even), Prairie  people at the Ninette market,”
        their home in the city. For a  Knight said with a laugh.   erator of the Ninette Farmers  on things,” said Knight. “A lot  Knight Farms is now blazing  said Knight. “The community
        while, it looked like the dream   The couple launched a Face- Market to cancel the season  of our produce was ready that  ahead into its second year with  is really, really wholesome.
        would have to be put on hold  book page announcing the ar- before it even started. Sudden- very week — spaghetti squash,  optimism. Seeds are sprouting  We’re lucky to be where we
        until they could save enough  rival of Prairie Knight Farms  ly, market gardeners in the re- butternut  and  acorn  squash  indoors,  plans are underway  are.”
        to buy a place.             and in May last year,  planted  gion had nowhere local to sell  and pumpkins. All of a sudden  to manage the Ninette Farm-  “I don’t want to sound
          But then help came in a  their first crop — mostly root  what they had grown.     we had all this food and no  ers Market again and to sell  cheesy,” said Heaman,  “But
        most unexpected way.        vegetables and flowers. Later   Knight, Heaman and Burrell  markets.”               produce at the Global Market  we’re trying to be good stew-
          Heaman’s cousin, Brian Me- came pumpkins, watermelon  joined forces to organize and   The couple had to dip into  in Brandon.             ards of the land and take care
        aud, and his wife Kara Burrell  and squash varieties, all grown  manage the market them- their savings in order to get by   They recently launched a  of the planet, and I feel we’re
        farm 25 minutes west of  using organic practices.       selves.  They kept it going all  that  fall.  Knight  learned  how  membership drive for a new  going  in  the  right  direction
        Ninette.  They offered to rent   Meanwhile, the pandemic  summer until the landscape  to drive a combine so he could  income generator —  veggie  with that.”






























                                               Bulk Hopper Service

                                      throughout WestMan and

                                              the Prairie Provinces


                                      Professional • Reliable • Reasonable



                                       280 Taylor Road, Rivers, MB • 204.724.6870 • alepp@redlinetransport.ca
                                                                       redlinetransport.ca





            BRED COWS DIRECT


                                                                                                               Serving Southwest Manitoba for 25+ years


                                         P. Quintaine & Son LTD would like                       Providing Small & Large Animal Veterinary Care to your Home!
                                         to introduce the newest member

                                         of our livestock team;                                        Surgery                    X-rays                   Lab Work
                                         Mark McDowell.                                               Dentistry          Health & Wellness Exams         Vaccinations

                                         Mark grew up on a livestock farm at                     In-Home Euthanasia               Equine                   Beef Cow
                                         Deleau, MB and has taken a keen interest
                                         in the livestock business.
                                         Mark’s main focus is helping producers
                                         trade bred cows direct from farm to farm.



                ONLY A $10 PER HEAD FINDER’S FEE.


                   If you are considering buying or selling bred cows call or text
               Mark at (204) 761-9246 and he will try to connect you with another
             producer who wants or has the type of bred cows that match your herd.


          NO BUYING, RESELLING, TRADING OR EXPENSIVE COMMISSIONS.                                         For an appointment or for information please call or text 204-305-0630
                                                                                                                     Boissevain, MB | www. adamsmobilevet.ca]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[n
        THURSDAY  MARCH 25  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                               WESTMAN THIS WEEK     B15
        Continued from Page B11     Manitoba Veterinary  Medi-
                                    cal Association and chairs
        HUEGING & PYLYPJUK          the Food Animal Commit-
        — CURRENT HOLSTEINS         tee and helped deliver pro-
          Historical   background:   ducer presentations on be-
                                    half  of  the  Dairy  Farmers  of
        Darren Hueging and Allison   Manitoba for ProAction Bios-
        Pylypjuk were both raised on   ecurity.
        dairy farms.  When they mar-  Land  stewardship:  Land
        ried in 2011, they took over   stewardship is very impor-
        Current Holsteins, a farm   tant to Current Holsteins,
        branching off of Darren’s par-  with approximately 850 acres
        ents’ dairy farm. Darren and   of hayland and 1,500 acres of
        Allison milk 72 Holstein cows   pastureland.  They leave bush
        in a tie-stall facility and raise   pastures native  and fence off
        125 beef cow-calf pairs. Allison   areas for wildlife. They practise
        and Darren raise their three   rotational grazing in an effort
        young children (Jocelyn, Myers   not to overgraze. A lot of for-
        and Madden) with the values   age crops are grown, and they
        their parents taught, including   try to improve alkaline areas
        hard work and dedication.   with  alfalfa  and  salt-tolerant
          Type of farming operation:   grasses.
        Dairy farm.                   Community involvement:
          Family participation: Dar- Darren and Allison volunteer
        ren runs the dairy full-time  with young children at their
        while Allison is also a licensed  church during Sunday service.
        veterinarian, working both on  Allison coaches a local ringette
        and off the farm.           team and gives presentations
          Combining the past and the  to both beef and dairy 4-H
        future: Darren has been presi- clubs. Darren sits as a panellist
        dent of the Interlake Dairy  at the University of Manitoba
        Club for more than 10 years.  for the agriculture diploma
        Allison is vice-president of the  oral presentations.                                         Hueging & Pylypjuk — Current Holsteins




                                                                                                                                                                                                    HOME




                                                                                                                                                                                                    IMPROVEMENTS


                                                                                                   IN STOCK

                                                                                                AND READY


                                                                                                  FOR YOU!



                                                                                                  Rough 2 x 6,

                                                                                                  2 x 8 & 6 x 6

                                                                                                16’ Fence Rails







                                                                                                1840 - 18th Street N., Brandon
                                                                                               204-728-4243 • 1-800-224-7506
                                                                                                 windsorplywood.com]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>