<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="16"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[»COMMUNITY LEADER OF THE YEAR, SPONSORED BY BDO
        Ramsey tops this year’s awards








        BY PERRY BERGSON

          There are a lot of ways to deﬁne
        success for a coach.
          Tyson Ramsey, the new head coach
        and general manager of the Manitoba
        Junior Hockey League’s Virden Oil
        Capitals, is well aware that he’ll ulti-
        mately be judged by wins and losses.
        But that’s not the only part of the
        equation for the veteran coach.
          “I think at the end of the day, if
        you’ve contributed to a player’s well-
        being and helped them become bet-
        ter at the sport that they’re involved
        in and helped them become better
        people, you can’t look at that as any-
        thing but success,” Ramsey said. “Ob-                            2019
        viously with some of the elite level
        sports, winning and the standings
        and the records are something you
        look at as success, but that’s only one
        part of it. Even at the elite level sports,
        not everyone is going to make a living
        playing a sport and have a career in it.
          “I think at the end of the day, if the
        kids have enjoyed what they’ve done
        and they’ve learned something both
        on the ice or on the ball ﬁeld or on
        the court, and they learned a pile of
        things off it, you can’t look at that as
        anything but successful.”
          Ramsey knows what he’s talking
        about.
          After playing in the MJHL with the
        Winkler Flyers, Ramsey came home
        to play with the Brandon University
        Bobcats, serving as captain in his ﬁ-
        nal season in 2000-01.
          Ramsey started coaching peewee
        hockey in 2002 with Brad Wells when
        he was still playing at Brandon Uni-
        versity. A year later, he joined Ken
        Schneider with the AAA bantam
        squad, and then spent a season with
        the under-18 team in 2005-06.
          He took a few seasons off to play
        senior hockey, rejoining Schneider’s
        U18 staff as an assistant coach with
        the Wheat Kings in 2011-12. He spent
        three seasons in that role before tak-
        ing the helm in 2014-15.          Riverview School coach Tyson Ramsey is this year’s Community Leader of the Year. (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)
          In four years as head coach, he
        compiled a record of 120-55-1-4 and was awarded the head job in May.  at every level he has coached,” he in February practices began for the triguing to me was the growth that
        the team played in the league ﬁnal  In nominating Ramsey for the wrote. “Tyson is dedicated and com- Magic fastball team which he was happens over the course of a season
        twice, while also serving as a scout for Community Leader Awards, Glen mitted to any team he puts his name coaching and his younger daughter and obviously the relationships that
        the Western Hockey League’s Moose Tosh said the coach is certainly dedi- forward to. For example, in the 2017- Avery was playing on.”  you develop with people along the
        Jaw Warriors.                     cated.                           18 season, he was the head coach of  Ramsey said the appeal of coaching way. It was something that I enjoyed
          In 2017-18, he began scouting for  “Tyson is the ultimate coach as he the Brandon AAA Wheat King midget is simple.                  and I had a real sense of pride in see-
        the Oil Capitals as well, and last winter is a terriﬁc communicator, runs an boys and the head coach of the West-  “It’s seeing a group of young people ing what you could accomplish with a
        joined the staff as an assistant coach extremely organized and efﬁcient man Wildcat AAA bantam female start at a certain spot and then kind group of kids from beginning to end.”
        to Troy Leslie, whose contract wasn’t practice and has strong game man- program, which his daughter Emma of grow as the season went along,”
        renewed in April. Ramsey eventually agement skills and has had success was playing on, and at the same time Ramsey said. “What was really in-  » See‘Developing’ — Page B2]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[B2  ■  COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2019                                                                                         THE BRANDON SUN ■ THURSDAY SEPTEMBER 26 2019

        » Developing better people as a coach







        Continued from Page B1
          Ramsey teaches half-time
        at Riverheights School, a job
        he will continue to hold next
        year. He has coached a num-
        ber of school sports there, and
        was involved in house league
        fastball in the past. This sum-
        mer, he coached the under-12
        Westman Magic softball team
        that won provincials.
          Over the years, he has
        worked with players of varying
        abilities and wants to have an
        impact on them all.
          “I think it’s just being able to
        develop a connection with all
        of them individually,” Ramsey
        said. “I think understanding
        where they’re coming from
        and where they’re at in their
        skill development and really
        helping them develop indi-
        vidually to help the group is
        something that is challenging
        with a lot of groups, but cer-
        tainly something that is very
        rewarding when you can take a  Ramsey with the Brandon Midget AAA Wheat Kings directs his team at the Sportsplex. (File)
        kid and help them individually
        increase their skill level so that to move to Virden when their ﬁts of it is just the relationships come together as a group and
        they become a member of the house sells.                and the connections and net- learning how to work together.
        group that succeeds is pretty  He faces a new challenge as working that you do through  “Really the resiliency that
        rewarding.                  the head coach and GM of the team sports,” Ramsey said. kids learn from team sport
          “Certainly having to make Oil Capitals, but the ultimate “There is just stuff that lasts a is amazing and is something
        an   individual  one-on-one lesson won’t be much different lifetime. I’m seeing it now with that helps them not only in
        connection with each kid is than it was for the U12 Magic my daughter being involved their sporting lives but will be
        something that’s important to team he coached in the sum- in team sports and the friend- beneﬁcial lessons for them to
        try to help them be successful mer.                     ships that she’s made, not only think back on and refer back
        from wherever they start to the  Ramsey wants good team- in her small group of friends to when they move into their
        end of the season.”         mates who work hard and from Brandon, but she’s got professional careers.”
          His family, which also in- compete because those are the friends from all over southern
        cludes wife Tracy and daugh- attributes that will last.  Manitoba. That to me is the » pbergson@brandonsun.com  Ramsey directs players during practice at the Sportsplex.
        ters Emma and Avery, plan     “I think one of the real bene- coolest part, kids having to » Twitter: @PerryBergson  (File)























                                      2019
























































        Nate Harrison and one of his plush sharks. (Drew May/The Brandon Sun)
        »ENVIRONMENTAL LEADER OF THE YEAR, SPONSORED BY KOCH FERTILIZER

        Environmental steward’s advocacy never ends





        BY DREW MAY                       cold get sick too,” Nate says while was two. The family visited a shark think we look like seals and seals from him and it gives me a lot of
                                          holding a plush shark and wearing conservation centre, where he had are their food.”                hope to see where our future is go-
          Nate Harrison has a passion for a shark-print Hawaiian shirt.    the chance to see the animals ﬁrst-  Jamie said it was a bit of an ad- ing to see kids doing such amaz-
        sharks.                            Jamie Harrison, Nate’s mom, hand.                                 justment for the family when Nate ing things. It makes us very proud
          On his ninth birthday — his most says her son has undertaken a wide  “All the creatures on the earth are ﬁrst started pushing them to be — even though he says it’s cheesy
        recent — he asked for donations variety of projects aimed at help- important, and if we didn’t have greener, but it has resulted in real when I tell him that,” Jamie said.
        and gave $565 to the Rod Stewart ing the environment. Nate and his them we wouldn’t be alive,” he said. changes. The family has a green  Nate also has an Instagram ac-
        Foundation, which works to pro- family do a garbage cleanup along    Nate is particularly passionate bin to compost food scraps and count (@natetheshark) where peo-
        tect sharks in the wild.          Victoria Avenue every spring and about banning shark ﬁnning, a doesn’t use chemical pesticides ple can follow along with his envi-
          Harrison’s love for the ocean- participate in larger community practice where sharks have their on the lawn, she said. The family ronmental projects.
        dwelling predator motivated the cleanups. He also recently started ﬁns cut off to make shark ﬁn soup. is also working to reduce plastic  Overall, Nate said one of the
        Grade 4 student to do his part to designing a rainwater collection When this happens, the sharks are waste and uses reusable bags be- goals of his young life is to make
        help the environment and encour- system for his family’s home.     thrown back into the ocean, where cause of Nate’s work.            Brandonites more conscious of
        age his family to lead a more envi-  On top of his other environmen- they inevitably die.             “He’s very vocal about it at their environmental impact and
        ronmentally friendly lifestyle. For tal activities, Nate is also encour-  He wrote letters to Brandon- home,” she said,               to help make the Earth a little bit
        his work, Harrison has won the aging the City of Brandon to ban Souris Conservative MP Larry Ma-      Nate’s work is inspiring, Jamie greener.
        Brandon Sun’s Community Leader single-use plastic bags.            guire to raise awareness about the said, even if he is shy about always  “I just want everyone in Brandon
        Award in the Environmental Lead-   “The plastic is affecting the ani- issue. Canada banned the import sharing it, saying he is somewhat of to know you should clean up after
        er category.                      mals in the ocean most, so if we get and export of shark ﬁns in June a reluctant leader. Nate said even yourself and not throw your gar-
          “I just want to help save my rid of those we can have a cleaner 2019, something Nate said made some of his friends don’t know bage wherever you want because
        friends. If you don’t have sharks environment,” he said.           him very happy to see.            about all the environmental work it’s affecting us.”
        — they eat the sick or injured ﬁsh  His love for sharks stems from   “Sharks are good creatures and he is doing.                      » dmay@brandonsun.com
        — and if we eat that ﬁsh then we a family trip to Hawaii when he the only time they bite is when they  “I love the empathy that I see » Twitter: @DrewMay_]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[B4  ■  COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2019                                                                                         THE BRANDON SUN ■ THURSDAY SEPTEMBER 26 2019





















                                    2019
















































        Community Leader Award Youth Volunteer winner Whitney Seib. (Chelsea Kemp/The Brandon Sun)
        »YOUTH VOLUNTEER OF THE YEAR, SPONSORED BY BRANDON UNIVERSITY

        Seib ﬁnds enjoyment in volunteerism






        BY CHELSEA KEMP                   past two years.                  business degree at Brandon Uni- with her commitment to helping to raise money.
                                           “It’s like a family,” she said, de- versity while working full time, but others.                     Hughson has been amazed at
          Whitney Seib’s smile is a welcom- scribing how tight club members are. always ensures she can volunteer in  “She has been working tirelessly her devotedness to volunteering in
        ing and familiar sight to many in They can often be found out in the the community.                  ever since volunteering in the com- Brandon, especially given that she
        Brandon.                          community helping out at as many   “When I’m not working or vol- munity.”                           has shown this dedication since she
          The 24-year-old has been volun- events as possible to the beneﬁt of unteering and not going to school I  Bright, bubbling and committed became involved with the Food for
        teering at various organizations in the Brandon community.         don’t really do much,” Seib said with to any project she takes on, Seib is Thought Program.
        the city for almost as long as she can  She ﬁrst dipped her toes into the a laugh.                   incredibly hard-working, Hughson   “She started working with them
        remember.                         world of volunteering with the Food  The commitment and time she said.                              when she was very young. When she
          “It makes me happy to make other For Thought Program, which helps spends working to make the com-   Her commitment inspires those was still going to school she would
        people happy — that’s why I do it,” prepare and serve breakfast in Bran- munity a better place is all the more around her, he said, especially given get up in the morning and go off to
        Seib said.                        don Schools for students who are un- commendable because she works the many leadership roles she has one of the elementary schools and
          Her glowing and cheerful personal- able to get a nutritious meal at home. and attends university,” Dayle Hugh- taken on to help projects in the com- help serve breakfast and then go to
        ity combined with her hard work has  “I’m part of a family that volunteers son said.                 munity ﬁnd success.              high school,” Hughson said.
        helped events and groups that in- — I’ve been doing it since I was a kid,”  Hughson nominated Seib for her  He cited Seib’s role as chair of the  He has been amazed at the energy
        clude the Food ForThought Program, Seib said. “However, I really got into a hard work in the community, de- Rotary Rib Fest for two years as a and tenacity she brings to everything
        Brandon Rotary Club, Swim Abilities lot when I ﬁnished high school.”  scribing her as full of energy and ea- showcase of her incredible commit- she touches.
        and Christmas Gift Wrapping with   One of her favourite times of the ger to help those who need a hand.  ment to volunteering. She lined up  “She is a very incredible young
        CNIB ﬁnd success in the community. week is Sundays when she gets to  “I think she really deserves it. She is numerous volunteers to help and lady,” Hughson said, explaining that
        She is this year’s Community Leader volunteer with the SwimAbility pro- a wonderful young lady who spends has taken on so many different com- Seib cares about causes and people
        Youth Volunteer award winner.     gram, working with physically and a lot of time volunteering and work- mittees that it is almost too much to and is willing to work hard to ensure
          Volunteering has proved to be a fun mentally disabled children as a swim ing for different causes,” Hughson count, he added.        things get done.
        experience and a great way to build coach. She hosts one-on-one swim said.                            She is happy to work behind the   “She doesn’t believe in leaving ev-
        relationships in the Brandon com- lessons for 30 minutes, working with  He wants to see her recognized for scenes or in front to ensure the com- erything to somebody else to do it.
        munity, she said, highlighting the op- three students over the course of the the impact she has had on Brandon.  munity is a better place, he said.  She jumps right in and drags other
        portunities and friendships she has night.                           Hughson belongs to the Brandon   “She’s very caring about people,” people with her,” he said. “She gets
        made through the Brandon Rotary    “They’re going to learn something Sunset Rotary Club and met Seib Hughson said. “She loves to raise it done.”
        Club. She serves as treasurer for the and they’re going to have fun. It’s when she joined the group a few money for different causes.”
        organization and has been the chair- awesome,” Seib said.          years ago.                         He highlighted her work with » ckemp@brandonsun.com
        person of the annual Rib Fest for the  She is currently ﬁnishing up her  He was immediately impressed SwimAbility as a coach and working » Twitter: @The_ChelseaKemp
        Students dedicated to environmental causes






                                                                                                                                                      “It’s  deﬁnitely  not  the
                                                                                                                                                    easiest thing to do, there’s a
                                                                                                                                                    number of different roadblocks
                                                                                                                                                    that come up along the way,”
                                                                                                                                                    she said.
                                                                                                                                                      “I think it’s tough that way for
                                                                                                                                                    students, it’s deﬁnitely a credit
                                                                                                                                                    to those who stay in the club
                                                                                                                                                    and stick it out and continue to
                        2019                                                                                                                        be the person who talks to their
                                                                                                                                                    friends about composting and
        BY DREW MAY                                                                                                                                 recycling and to really not get
                                                                                                                                                    too down about larger things
          Whether it’s starting a com-                                                                                                              that are happening that they
        posting program, using recy-                                                                                                                can’t control.”
        clable materials to wrap Christ-                                                                                                              Moving forward, Manko said
        mas presents or striking outside                                                                                                            she wants to start an eco club
        city hall for climate action, the                                                                                                           at Brandon University based on
        École secondaire Neelin High                                                                                                                her experience with the Neelin
        School Eco club knows the im-                                                                                                               high school Eco Club. Manko
        portance of taking a stand for                                                                                                              and other members from Nee-
        the environment.                                                                                                                            lin are also trying to start a
          The goal of the club, which is                                                                                                            broader    community-based
        the ﬁnalist in the Youth Volun-                                                                                                             club to do community clean-
        teer category, is to bring aware-                                                                                                           ups, helping in community
        ness to how students speciﬁcal-                                                                                                             gardens and possibly another
        ly can be more environmentally                                                                                                              climate strike.
        friendly, said Melissa Robinson,                                                                                                              Seeing a fresh group of stu-
        the club’s teacher-organizer.  École secondaire Neelin High School Eco Club teacher-advisor Melissa Robinson. (Drew May/The Brandon Sun)    dents in the club each year and
        Throughout the year the club                                                                                                                the work they do is motivating,
        sets up programs and initia- that her parents passed on to true to many things in our com- don climate strike by attending Colby Pilling, Samantha Cruz Robinson said. Each group of
        tives for students and their her. The club really came to- munity when we want to see a global climate strike with the Alvarado, Kayla Burt, and Olivia students brings fresh ideas to
        peers to take small actions to- gether during the strike.  change.”                 club in Winnipeg on Sept. 27.  Erickson.                the table through brainstorm-
        wards a greener future.       “With a club that it’s not just  While a member of the eco-  “Now it’s a global event and  While the students have ing meetings that can help
          Last year the club organized one person — each person had club, Manko said she learned it’s also general, where in the moved on they will continue have a real impact on climate
        a climate strike outside city hall such an involvement in every- the importance of teamwork past it was just youth who were to spread the message of sus- change.
        in May, where 50 students held thing we did … I brought the and how important the support striking from school — so this tainability and the small ac-  “It’s super inspiring, I love it,
        up signs with slogans like “Save idea to the group, but without of others can be in achieving one coming up is likely to be the tions people can take to leave it makes my days … just hear-
        our planet, save our future” and the help of my club members personal goals.        largest worldwide,” she said.  an improved natural world. It’s ing everyone’s ideas. It’s re-
        “The oceans are rising, now it’s and my peers it wouldn’t have  “That was one of the main  The club will be getting a a consistent battle to share in- ally wonderful to hear students
        our turn.”                  been possible,” she said.   things I’m grateful for and the fresh start this year, Robinson formation on being more envi- who feel passionate about the
          Cassidy Manko, a member of  “I felt like we really came to- camaraderie and friendship in said, as all ﬁve of the students ronmentally friendly and help- same climate issues that I feel
        the club who graduated from gether and worked hard on an that group,” she said.     from last year were in Grade 12 ing people change their habits, are so important today as well.”
        Neelin last year, said she has a issue that we were really pas-  Robinson said she wants to and have now graduated. Last Robinson said, but she believes » dmay@brandonsun.com
        passion for the environment sionate about and that rings follow up on last year’s Bran- year’s club included Manko, they’ll stick it out.   » Twitter: @DrewMay_]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[THURSDAY SEPTEMBER 26 2019 ■ THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                                               NEWS   ■  B5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[B6  ■  COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2019                                                                                         THE BRANDON SUN ■ THURSDAY SEPTEMBER 26 2019





















                                    2019


















































        Todd Bullee, one of six performers to play the part of the Man In Black, strums a guitar onstage at the Centennial Auditorium as he and troupe mates from Mecca Productions prepare for their
        showing of “Ring of Fire”, a musical about the life of Johnny Cash — in 2012. (File)
        »ABOVE AND BEYOND, SPONSORED BY GUILD INSURANCE BROKERS
        Community steward Bullee was a ‘go-to guy’






         BY DIANE NELSON                   Bullee was on the board of South gave directorial feedback, he was trea- treatment in Winnipeg.    was just himself.
                                          End Community Centre for several surer — he did everything,” Simard  “I met Todd through Korinne when  “That’s just who he was,” she said.
          “Our Hero.”                     years. He also spent many hours vol- said in a phone interview. “He was a they were ﬁrst dating,” Cristal said in “He just did it. He just helped out. He
          That’s what the late Todd Bullee’s unteering at Neelin High school. He member right ’til the end and involved a telephone interview. “He was a great was always lending a hand.”
        mother-in-law, Maureen Hunter, said helped with the building, setting right to the end.              guy — kind, helpful — he did a lot for  Korinne said she could imagine his
        he was to his family and friends.  up and transporting the sets for the  “He helped out wherever he could. the community and anybody around response to winning a Community
          Before his untimely death in June of school’s major productions. He volun- He was just that kind of guy.  him. He was always the ﬁrst to volun- Leader Award.
        this year, Bullee was the go-to guy for teered with Neelin’s choir group, going  A great friend — a family friend. teer.                “He’d probably have said something
        everyone lucky enough to know him, along on many choir tours and con- He was always there to help you if  “When they were living with us, he like, ‘I just do it because I’m a doer,’”
        Hunter said, in nominating him for certs. He was up early to board the bus you needed help in any way. He was was always trying to help us, from ﬁx- she said. “I don’t need any accolades
        the award. A partner with his brother with a smile and McDonald’s breakfast an amazing individual. A joy to be ing things around the house to tak- or credit.”
        Brent in H. Bullee & Sons Spring Ser- for all, Hunter said.        around. Always positive and kind.  ing my kids places, planning family  In other words, he did so much and
        vice, the siblings bought the company,  As well, Bullee was a regular volun-  “He was just a great guy. And we dinners — those were just things that expected nothing in return.
        a Brandon ﬁxture since 1958, from teer for the Cerebral Palsy bike race, loved him.”                 Todd always did.                   Hunter said she nominated Bullee
        their father 25 years ago. And while loading up the bikes, transporting  Bullee was diagnosed with a rare  “He was positive — he never wanted for the courage and bravery/above
        Bullee worked hard at his business — them to the venue, assembling and form of blood cancer in December to give up, he never complained, never andbeyondCommunityLeaderAward
        his motto was “if you’re going to do disassembling them, and then riding 2017. After aggressive chemotherapy, said anything about how bad he was not because of how gracefully he dealt
        something, do it RIGHT” — he was to collect donations. With a knack he received a stem cell transplant feeling. I wish I could be that way if I with his cancer, but because of his zest
        always available to his employees, his for drama and singing, Bullee’s love of from his sister Tammy. Unfortunately, was ever in that situation.” According for life and his constant commitment
        friends and his family, helping them music brought him to the men’s choir, it failed. But Bullee was not done ﬁght- to Hunter, Todd was a wonderful fa- to those he loved and the community
        with their vehicles during business Prairie Blend. He loved to perform ing. He agreed to be part of a drug trial. ther to his daughters Laura and Jenna at large.
        hours and after hours — even while he and in addition to working behind the  During the entire 18-month ordeal, and a fabulous partner to Korinne.The  “He did not leap into freezing water
        was on vacation at Clear Lake.    scenes, he took part in many Mecca Bullee remained strong.         family travelled together, tried most or into a burning building to save lives,
          Whether it was a boat, a car, some- productions.                   “Despite his discomfort, Todd … water sports, skied the mountains and butTodd (was) anything but ordinary,”
        thing to do with home, or even some-  “We will always remember him never complained, which is a rare spent many happy summers at their Hunter wrote. “He has experienced
        thing personal, people could always playing Johnny Cash,” Hunter said.  virtue in any person,” Hunter wrote. cottage in Clear Lake.   emotionally both the valleys and the
        count on him, Hunter said.         Bullee was one of the founding “Throughout all this, he continued to  Korinne appreciated the same qual- mountains of the real world.
          “His selﬂess ways and bright smile members of the Assiniboine Theatre help others and be a beacon of light.”  ities in her husband that everyone  “Todd has taught us to acknowl-
        rubbed off on all those around him,” Company, and ATC president Dave Si-  Kathy Cristal, a close friend of else did. And it’s perhaps predictable, edge what is already within us — the
        she continued. “Having Todd in your mard still misses his wise counsel and Bullee’s wife Korinne, agreed whole- then, that she feels he might have strength and the abilities we hold. His
        life was like knowing you’d never have his eagerness to assist in anything that heartedly with Hunter. The Bullees been humbled to receive the award. love of life and community never wa-
        to worry. He would always come run- needed doing.                  lived with Cristal and her husband Because  although  everyone  else vers. He is a hero to all his family and
        ning — he never stopped moving.”   “He built sets, he gathered props, he while Todd was undergoing his cancer thought he was special, to him, he friends.”
        McNish ﬁlled a need to help families







                                                                                                                        for something like this for our of attention that comes with be-
                                                                                                                        community,” Hrubeniuk con- ing nominated as a Community
                                                                                                                        tinued. “She’s done a great job Leader, she is grateful her work
                                                                                                                        for Brandon and Westman.”   has had an impact.
                                                                                                                          McNish said that creating  “It’s nice to be acknowl-
                                                                                                                        Baby Bump was “a leap of faith” edged,” McNish said. “It means
                                                                                                                        for her, but she had conﬁdence a lot — it really does. It makes
                                                                                                                        that the services she and her it all worth it. It makes me want
                                                                                                                        staff provide were much needed to cry!
                        2019                                                                                            in the region.               Stadler said she nominated
                                                                                                                          “I just went with it,” she said McNish for the Community
                                                                                                                        in a phone interview. “I love Leader Award because she be-
        BY DIANE NELSON                                                                                                 teaching, I love talking to peo- lieves McNish is a positive role
                                                                                                                        ple, and just doing what people model who goes above and be-
          She saw a need, so she set out                                                                                are asking for and what people yond to facilitate easier transi-
        to provide the service.                                                                                         are needing. I just keep being tions in the parenting journey
          And she has done that — and                                                                                   me.”                        and thus creates a healthier and
        a whole lot more.                                                                                                 Despite her success, McNish happier community.
          Adrienne McNish, a regis-                                                                                     was astonished when she heard  “She lights up any room with
        tered nurse who’s worked for                                                                                    she was nominated for a Com- her warm, authentic smile and
        more than 12 years with women                                                                                   munity Leader Award.        genuine, caring nature,” Stadler
        and their babies in Single Room                                                                                   “I was taken aback — it’s very said. “As Adrienne’s peer and
        Maternity Care, opened Baby                                                                                     overwhelming,” she said with teammate, I can say it is a plea-
        Bump at 728 — 18th St. four                                                                                     obvious delight. “It’s amazing. sure to work with her and call
        years ago. But in tandem with  Baby Bump owners Adrienne McNish and Stacy Nevill, from left, are seen with twins Wade and Rhett  I’m shocked. I feel very hon- her a friend. She always has
        the merchandise available in  Lewandoski, eight months old, whose mother Charlene received prenatal guidance from them. (File)  oured and it’s very exciting.”  space for others’ concerns and
        the store, she created a Family  Bump’s personally tailored pre- First Aid, Sleep Sanity and Baby respect from her colleagues and  McNish said her work on the is an excellent listener.
        Centre, which offers a vast array  natal and postnatal parenting and Me yoga are also offered patients.”        maternity ward and at Baby   “I have heard rave reviews
        of services for her clients.  support and wellness classes through Baby Bump.         Another nursing colleague Bump complement each other from patients who have attend-
          “Adrienne goes above and  provide a safe and accept-    “Adrienne’s leadership skills, and friend, Amber Hrubeniuk, beautifully. While she’s very ed prenatal classes with her or
        beyond to support, educate,  ing environment for new and high standard of patient care, couldn’t agree more heartily.  busy, she said it’s all extremely had the experience with Adri-
        and empower the women and   expanding families to grow, depth of knowledge and im-    “Adrienne’s an amazing per- rewarding.                enne as their nurse in the hos-
        families of Westman to make  learn and build relationships. peccable professionalism as a son,” Hrubeniuk said.“She does  “Both jobs complement each pital setting. A common theme
        informed   decisions  about  McNish’s conversational ap- Registered Nurse are inspiring,” so much for women in Brandon other,” she said. “I make con- is that she exceeded expecta-
        their wellbeing,” wrote nurse,  proach to learning addresses Stadler said. “She advocates and the Westman region. She’s nections teaching prenatal cli- tions and made parents feel
        co-worker and friend Jennifer  the individual needs of her cli- for patient safety, builds conﬁ- had this vision for a very long ents, and then seeing them at safe, supported and empow-
        Stadler in her missive nominat-  ents in prenatal classes that dence for couples to fulﬁll their time. She’s a very smart busi- the hospital and delivering ba- ered. Adrienne works hard and
        ing McNish for a Community  better prepare them for their birthing wishes and is an unpar- nesswoman and she’s got it — bies, and then following up af- is humble about her successes,
        Leader Award.               birthing experience. A variety alleled team player and leader. she’s got the clientele.  terward (at Baby Bump).  which makes her even more lik-
          According to Stadler, Baby  of classes including CPR and She works hard and earns great  “There was deﬁnitely a need  Whileshe’snotafanofthesort able.”]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[CONGRATULATIONS TO ALL THE



                                         COMMUNITY LEADERSHIP WINNERS!





                                             Thanks for everything you do to make our


                                                              community a better place.




                                          ENJOY

























                                                             THE

























                                           VIEW!












































                                       PROVIDING PEACE OF MIND THROUGH INSURANCE



                                                       AND RISK MANAGEMENT SOLUTIONS




                                   At Guild HMS, we take a panoramic view of your entire life and


                                     business to ensure you are properly covered. So you can sit


                                                                back, relax, and enjoy the view.







                                  GUILD INSURANCE BROKERS & HMS INSURANCE AGENCIES


                                                                 www.guildhmsinsurance.ca]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[B8  ■  COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2019                                                                                         THE BRANDON SUN ■ THURSDAY SEPTEMBER 26 2019
























                                      2019





























        Frank Crew is this year’s Community Leader Award winner in the “volunteer” category. (Colin Slark/The Brandon Sun)
        »VOLUNTEER OF THE YEAR, SPONSORED BY SUNRISE CREDIT UNION
        Crew led by example in Birtle









        BY COLIN SLARK                    family owned for more than a century, department, even bringing his own cord include concerts, hockey games, cipient of a Premier’s Volunteer Ser-
                                          divesting of the last portion in May farm’s water truck to help put out and even grain threshing.   vice Award, where he got to attend a
          In making a list of Frank Crew’s ac- 2018.                       blazes on more than one occasion.  His contribution to the historical gala and meet the premier.
        complishments volunteering in his  Other than just farming, Crew’s   Before it closed, the Birtle Bap- record also includes a history book he  He was also named a Melvin Jones
        home community of Birtle, it would land was a frequent location for Le- tist Church was the beneﬁciary of worked on and his father ﬁnanced ti- Fellow, the highest award that Lions
        probably easier to list the few things gion and Lions Club social events and his skills. Frank helped maintain the tled “Wandering Through Wattsview,” Club International bestows on its
        he didn’t volunteer for.          the occasional family reunion.   grounds and build an addition that which chronicled the history of the members.
          He technically lived in Wattsview,  As he started to transition from liv- added a washroom and entrance foy- community from 1879-1967.  When Crew’s wife Olive Perreault
        which was part of the old RM of Birtle, ing in Birtle to living in Brandon, Crew er.                  “People contributed their stories was dying of cancer, he had to back
        but he was an active member of both said that many of the townspeople  His skills weren’t just limited to ﬁx- and another neighbour and I were to out of a lot of his volunteer commit-
        communities.                      made sure his land was well taken ing, though. Some wood and metal type it all out,” Crew said.     ments. He recalls being asked around
          Until the 77-year old moved away a care of while he was away.    picnic tables he built are still in use at  The neighbour eventually moved that time how he’d gotten involved
        few years ago, Crew met the textbook  Not having kids of his own to pass it a park in Birtle.        away after being accepted into nurs- with all these projects and organiza-
        deﬁnition of “pillar of the communi- on to, Crew ended up selling the ﬁnal  “When we downsized the farm and ing school. “I kinda got stuck with it tions.
        ty.” He probably still does.      plot of land to a young family that he had to clean it out, we donated a pile all,” Crew said.        He said his parents Ken and Ella set
          Even though he has since relocated felt would make good use of the space. of stuff to neighbours and friends,”  After a slow start sales-wise, Crew an example by being heavily involved
        to Brandon, he and his partner May  “We just got some texts this morn- Crew said. “Feels good when you said universities came to appreciate in the community.
        Culbertson still keep tabs on the small ing from the young couple that phone these people and they say the book and he eventually sold out.  “If you don’t keep up this repair
        town he called home for more than bought Frank’s farm,” Culbertson they’ve used a certain thing they got “They’re a scarce commodity right work and help out, organize things,
        seven decades.                    said. “(They) sent us pictures this from you.”                     now,” he said.                   the community just dies,” Crew said.
          “It will always be home,” Crew said. morning of different scenes from the  Three centennial celebrations in  These are just some of the things “I always say it was a labour of love.”
        “It’s where I was born and raised.”  farm and that is so nice to see.”  Birtle were assisted by Crew’s skills: that Frank Crew did for his commu-  “He loves that community still, to
          He was a member of the Birtle Lions  Another part of his land was sold to the Canadian centennial in 1967, nity. A short list of his other work in- this day,” Culbertson said.
        Club for decades and even though the Manitoba Habitat Heritage Cor- Manitoba’s centennial in 1970 and cludes helping organize the annual  By following in his parents’ foot-
        he now attends the Wheat City Lions poration for use as a wildlife refuge.  Birtle’s centennial in 1984.  Lions Journey for Sight snowmobile steps, Frank Crew might just have in-
        Club since moving, the organization  Crew was the self-taught handyman  But Frank did more than just help fundraiser, giving rides to people who spired others to do the same.
        awarded him a lifetime membership who helped keep several organiza- put on events — he also helped docu- need kidney dialysis and serving on  “I think they’re doing a pretty great
        in honour of his service.         tions running. “Just learned it as you ment and broadcast them through the board of the local Co-op.  job,” Crew said about those who have
          The longtime grain farmer retired went,” he said.                doing camera work for the local pub-  What he did seems to have been ap- taken the reins from him.
        from that life in 2000 and slowly sold  He performed maintenance on lic access television station.   preciated.                       » cslark@brandonsun.com
        off pieces of the homestead that his the machines used by the local ﬁre  Some of the events he helped re-  Earlier this year, Frank was the re- » Twitter: @ColinSlark
        Elliott driven to help his community






        BY COLIN SLARK                SInce 2005, he has been in-
                                    volved with the Cornwallis
          Chuck Elliott has been help- Police Board, which oversees
        ing build communities for de- the one-person police force
        cades, whether it has been in in the municipality. Currently
        the RM of Cornwallis where the vice-chair, Elliott has also
        he lives, the City of Brandon spent time as the board’s chair.
        or the Murray GM dealership Then-reeve of Cornwallis and
        where he works.             former Brandon mayor Reg
          Now 54, Elliott is currently Atkinson recruited Elliott to
        in his 25th year of working at get involved.
        Murray GM. Starting as a regu-  Within Brandon, Elliott is
        lar salesperson, he has risen to the co-chair of the board of                2019
        become the sales manager.   Helping Hands soup kitchen
          The salesman grew up in and has been involved with
        Brandon and completed his that organization since he was
        undergraduate degree at Bran- recruited to help out 2015.
        don University with a major in  His workplace had already
        math and minors in business been involved with Helping
        administration and psychol- Hands since 2014, with Mur-
        ogy. He went on to work for the ray GM sending a dollar from
        local health authority for sev- every oil change to the soup
        eral years before leaving Bran- kitchen and Samaritan House.
        don in hopes of becoming an   Elliott speaks with pride
        air trafﬁc controller.      about the oil change program,
          A vision problem prevent- saying he recognizes that the
        ed him from achieving this beneﬁciaries need consistent
        dream, so he returned to Bran- support from the community
        don, eventually landing at to run their programs.
        Murray GM.                    As of a year ago, he said that
          Elliott ﬁrst met his wife more than $50,000 had been
        Carla, a nurse, when they raised for Helping Hands and  Chuck Elliott is the ﬁnalist in the volunteer category of the Community Leader Awards. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
        were both students at BU and Samaritan House through the
        they reconnected when they oil change donations.        said ‘That’s the best organiza- to help in this community.”  Brandon as a small city, but ac- year, doing things with differ-
        were both working for what is  Further to thse efforts, El- tion in the community that  Elliott’s past volunteer work tually the catch area for Bran- ent social clubs and events
        now called Prairie Mountain liott is also involved with run- makes the biggest impact’,” he has also included Crime Stop- don is very large and the com- that come to town.”
        Health.                     ning fundraiser barbecues and said.“Now being involved with pers, Habitat for Humanity merce from around us comes  Now Chuck is leading by ex-
          The letter sent to The Sun test drive events for service it for so long, it’s obvious it is and the Assiniboine Commu- into the city,” he said.  ample, at his workplace, in the
        nominating Elliott for a Com- clubs through his workplace.  when you’re close to it.  nity College Foundation.    Throughout the years, vari- community and for his kids.
        munity Leader Award in the    Another organization Elliott  “There’s so many social pro-  Though he doesn’t serve any ous organizations have con-  His younger son Lyndon
        “volunteer” category  called is involved with is the local grams that the government speciﬁc role for the organiza- tinued recruiting Elliott to be a is studying automotive busi-
        him the hardest-working per- United Way, which he assists funds, and you know we all tion, Elliott is also a supporter part of their team, which begs ness at a university in Barrie,
        son at the dealership — work in organizing the annual fun- pay taxes and et cetera, but of the local Chamber of Com- the question: why?     Ont. His older son Hewson is
        that extends beyond the busi- draising campaign for. He said you know the police and all the merce.               “I don’t know,” Elliott said. almost ﬁnished training to be-
        ness and into the broader that Murray employees are service industries and basical-   “The more we can keep “I think any time that I feel come a mechanical engineer.
        community at large. Often- encouraged to deduct a small ly the social working system Brandon local: buy local, sell there’s a need to do some-  Elliott doesn’t know if his
        times, Elliott helps out local portion of their paycheques would be totally overloaded if local, et cetera, it’s a great thing, I don’t mind ﬁnding the kids will return to the area
        organizations  through  his to be given to the United Way it weren’t for all the organiza- thing to keep this community time to help out.”  once their schooling is com-
        workplace.                  each month.                 tions that come to help with spinning,” he said.          “Growing up, my parents plete.
          Elliott told The Sun that he  Elliott gives credit to Mil- speciﬁc needs.           Elliott’s belief in the local were big on community sup-  If they end up settling else-
        doesn’t necessarily agree with lie Murray, mother of Murray  “The United Way actually Chamber also extends to busi- port and volunteering in this where, other communities will
        the characterization offered owner Doug Murray, for en- makes that happen in our ness in general throughout the area, in Brandon,” he added. ﬁnd out what it means to have
        by his nominator, but that he couraging him to support the community. ... It makes our Westman area.            “They led by example. My an Elliott leading by example.
        does believe in leading by ex- United Way.              community a better place      “We get talking to a lot of mother still is — she’s 90 years » cslark@brandonsun.com
        ample.                        “When I started here, she when there’s private initiative outside companies that look at old and still giving back every » Twitter: @ColinSlark]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[B10  ■  COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2019                                                                                        THE BRANDON SUN ■ THURSDAY SEPTEMBER 26 2019

        »EMERGENCY SERVICES,

        SPONSORED BY THE BRANDON SUN
        Life saver






        touched






        ‘countless’                                                                                                                                       2019






        lives in area








        BY DIANE NELSON                    High praise indeed. But the obvi-
                                          ous admiration his colleagues have
          “We would like to nominate Mr. for Duthie doesn’t just apply to his
        Jim Duthie, paramedic with Prairie work in EMS and ﬁreﬁghting. He has
        Mountain Health in Rivers, and cap- also hailed for his contributions to
        tain with Rivers/Daly Fire Depart- the community through activities
        ment.”                            such as refereeing hockey games
          So began the nomination letter in the winter and coaching soccer
        for the Emergency Service Com- in the summer. He’s coached youth
        munity Leader Award, penned by and high school soccer and contin-
        David Creighton, Duthie’s colleague ues to coach the ladies senior team
        in both Emergency Services and the in Rivers, women who became so
        Fire Department.                  enamoured with soccer in their high
          And while people in leadership school years that they just kept play-
        roles don’t often get credit for what ing.
        they do, Duthie’s co-workers, which  “And (he) still ﬁnds time to main-
        include Creighton, Randy King, Rob- tain the soccer and rugby ﬁelds
        bie Brown, and Richard Brown, have largely on his own!” Creighton wrote.
        so much respect for him that they “He does all of this for the commu-
        took the time to put his name for- nity, without asking for anything
        ward for this award.              in return! Jim is a highly respected
          Born in the Rivers area, Duthie has member of the community and we
        spent his entire life in that commu- are fortunate to have him!”
        nity. He started his EMS career as a  Duthie was amazed to hear he’d
        basic ﬁrst aid provider and worked been nominated for a Community
        hard over the years to achieve the Leader award when he was contact-
        designation of Intermediate Care ed by The Sun for comment.
        Paramedic (ICP).                   “I’m surprised,” he said quietly.
          “During Jim’s EMS career over “It’s pretty ﬂattering.”
        the past 26 years, he has touched  Duthie’s journey toward excelling
        countless numbers of lives in SW in his ﬁeld came about due to anoth-
        Manitoba,” Creighton wrote. “In er selﬂess act. After volunteering for
        their time of need, when a patient the ﬁre department for 25 years, he
        sees Jim walking in their door, they was approached to help with EMS.
        are immediately reassured that they  “I thought, ‘I probably can’t do
        are going to receive the best of care! that,’” he said. “But they needed
        Regardless of the situation, Jim has drivers. And it ended up I enjoyed it,
        a calming, professional demeanour and I enjoy helping people, so I took
        about him that immediately puts more training and more training,
        not only the patient at ease but also and then here we are.”
        those that are working alongside   He started as a full-time para-
        him.                              medic in 2001 and has never looked
          “Jim has also trained and tested back. And while his colleagues think
        numerous   paramedics  over  the he’s pretty special, it’s a sentiment
        years and continues to teach CPR/ Duthie returns to them in spades.  Jim Duthie of the Rivers EMS Station. (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)
        First Aid in the community. It is the  “Having the crew and the team —
        same with his 25-plus years with everybody’s always very supportive always had good family support with, “I thought you were the lead- support of his colleagues but, as he
        Rivers/Daly Fire Department. Jim to everyone else,” he said. “What through the years — a good back- er?,” Duthie replied, “I am in ﬁre. But expressed earlier, in helping others.
        has mentored many new ﬁreﬁghters we’ve seen and what we’ve experi- bone, I guess. And good leadership you can’t do it all yourself.”    “Being able to try to make a dif-
        and continues to be a leader both on enced — you have good support. helps.”                           Ultimately, Duthie ﬁnds the re- ference,” he said. “That’s the biggest
        a ﬁre scene and in training.”     And family support is big. We’ve   When this reporter countered ward for his work not only in the thing for me.”
        Newton a dedicated leader









                                                                                                                                                    agement and is the contact
                                                                                                                                                    person for the Ofﬁce of the
                                                                                                                                                    Fire Commissioner. She’s a
                                                                                                                                                    Senior Support Advocate, and
                                                                                                                                                    volunteers as a Handi-van
                                                                                                                                                    driver, volunteers for Meals
                                                                                                                                                    on Wheels, and assists seniors
                                                                                                                                                    daily with grocery shopping
                                                                                                                                                    and mail delivery. Addition-
                        2019                                                                                                                        ally, she accompanies seniors
                                                                                                                                                    to doctor’s appointments and
                                                                                                                                                    city hospital destinations and
        BY DIANE NELSON                                                                                                                             offers companionship, per-
                                                                                                                                                    haps one of the most impor-
          Linda Newton was born and                                                                                                                 tant things of all.
        raised and has lived 98 per                                                                                                                   “I like to keep busy,” New-
        cent of her life in Shoal Lake.                                                                                                             ton said with a laugh when
          And it’s probably safe to say                                                                                                             contacted by phone. “Basical-
        the town wouldn’t be the same                                                                                                               ly, I have a terrible time saying
        without her.                                                                                                                                ‘no’ — it’s my biggest ﬂaw.
          Her    nominator,   Cory                                                                                                                    “I like helping people — I
        Luhowy, said Newton became                                                                                                                  like to see that things keep
        involved in the community                                                                                                                   moving in a small commu-
        at a young age, and hasn’t                                                                                                                  nity.”
        stopped since.                                                                                                                                While she takes on a lot
          “Her dedication and passion                                                                                                               herself, as evidenced by the
        to help others began to de-                                                                                                                 activities noted above, she’s
        velop through Girl Guides and                                                                                                               learned the most important
        as a Sunday School teacher,”                                                                                                                lesson is teamwork.
        Luhowy wrote in her nomina-                                                                                                                   “I am a leader and I do del-
        tion form. “Linda entered the                                                                                                               egate,” she said. “You can get
        ﬁeld of nursing that saw many                                                                                                               a lot done if you have lots of
        changes through her 43-plus                                                                                                                 help. I’ve always had the com-
        years in this profession. This                                                                                                              munity behind me when I’m
        career has revealed many ave-                                                                                                               doing these jobs. I certainly
        nues of patient care for Linda.                                                                                                             don’t do it single-handed.”
        Her passion for helping people  Emergency Services Award ﬁnalist Linda Newton. (Drew May/The Brandon Sun)                                     When she heard she’d been
        led to a lifetime of mentorship                                                                                                             nominated for a Community
        and education.”             women to join her in this re- And even after retiring from someone’s hand as they took According to Luhowy, she was Leader Award, Newton, like
          Newton shared her knowl- warding profession.”         nursing, she couldn’t bear the their last breath, she knew instrumental in the develop- most nominees, was pleased,
        edge and skills with local    Newton   dedicated  many thought of sitting idle when she had made a difference in ment of the newly formed but modest as well. “Actually,
        health care providers, includ- hours to training and mentor- so many people needed as- someone’s life.”         Lakeside Golf Club Camp- I was quite thrilled with it, and
        ing those who perform First ing ambulance personnel in sistance. So, she joined the   Newton’s dedication is not ground and adjoining play very humbled by it,” she said.
        Aid and CPR. She spent more the region, and received the home-care team as a travelling limited to the medical ﬁeld. structure.             “It’s nice to know you’re ap-
        than 32 years teaching First Exemplary Service Medal for nurse because she still had She can frequently be seen at  As if all that weren’t enough, preciated.
        Responders and 10 years in- her efforts.                more to give.               Shoal Lake sporting venues Newton is an executive mem-    “But that’s not why I do this.
        structing Emergency Medical   She took 10 years off from  Even now, she volunteers guiding  sports  enthusiasts, ber of the Manitoba Clydes- I was born and raised here —
        Technician students.        nursing to work as a First Re- with the local Palliative Care particularly those in curling dale Club, has earned her Gold my mom was quite involved
          “During her role as station sponder and Emergency Med- group, assisting patients and and golf. She’s an executive Cord in Girl Guides and has here and she kind of built the
        supervisor for EMS, she would ical Technician, but after a family at the end of life.  member of the Curling Club, spent a lifetime involved in the staircase that I climbed. She
        go above and beyond the call decade, she felt the job would  “She’s a hands-on nurse and teaches the rules of the Anglican Church, where she’s was into community service
        of duty,” Luhowy said. “Linda be better done by someone with a passion to help the game and techniques to any- currently a churchwarden.    and instilled that in all of her
        was one of the ﬁrst women to younger. So she went back sick and injured,” Luhowy one who is interested in learn-  Newton is also currently children. But I’m basically the
        join the volunteer ambulance to nursing — helping people said. “Whether it was bathing ing. She also participates in the chairperson of Westman only one who stayed around
        and she encouraged other seems to be in her blood. a newborn baby or holding Ladies and Senior League play. Critical Incident Stress Man- here.”]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[THURSDAY SEPTEMBER 26 2019 ■ THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                    COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2019     ■  B11




















                                    2019

















































        Former Brandon Wheat Kings forward Jeff Hoad speaks to the young team he coaches during a practice at the Sportsplex last week. (Perry Bergson/The Brandon Sun)
        »COACH OF THE YEAR, SPONSORED BY BRANDON SOURCE FOR SPORTS

        Questions key to coach’s success: Hoad






        BY PERRY BERGSON                  make the NHL, it’s ingrained upon a of ﬁve seasons with the Wheat Kings, want to be able to pass on as much that’s AAA midget or the Wheat Kings
                                          player at a very young age. I think it’s ﬁnished up his professional hockey of the knowledge that I believe I re- or whatever.”
          Jeff Hoad deﬁnes success as a very important for coaches to recog- career in 2006 and moved home. tained through all my years playing.”  As a result, he put his focus on
        coach with a number of questions.  nize that about being a positive in- He helped out some friends who  Unfortunately for Brandon minor player development because every
          The former professional hockey ﬂuence on the kids on how to carry coached on the ice at different times, hockey, that knowledge won’t be as player could improve, regardless of
        player and current Brandon Police themselves when they win, and how and in 2009, began working in Tim- available this winter.         where they started the season.
        Service ofﬁcer has spent the last de- to carry themselves when they lose, bits hockey.                The police ofﬁcer went back on    In his 12-year pro career, Hoad
        cade coaching youngsters.         how to approach the game, and how  He has helped with soccer as well, patrol earlier this year, and the shift played in the North American mi-
          “Whether you break it down from to apply themselves to the sport that but is quick to add that’s not his work means he won’t be able to serve nors before a move to a Europe spent
        ice time to ice time or throughout they’re doing.”                 area of expertise. Hoad knew he had as a head coach this season. He has mainly in the British Ice Hockey Su-
        the whole year, have I developed the  He’s apparently succeeded.   something to offer, especially when offered his services to Curtis Brolund perleague. He knows ﬁrst-hand the
        players?” he asked. “Have I made   In nominating Hoad for the Com- his youngster began to play.      and the under-18 AAA Wheat Kings if value of teamwork, noting the old
        them better on the ice than they were munity Leader Awards, Kim Roziere  “I had a number of great experi- needed and will also tell the staff of saying that a chain is only as strong
        at the start of the year? Have I worked said he is the ideal coach.  ences with coaches, but having said whatever team his son plays on that as its weakest link.
        with them individually and as a    “Jeff Hoad has been an exemplary that, I also had experiences with he can lend a hand when necessary.  “What you learn in team sports is
        group to make them better individu- hockey coach in a world that needs what I would say are some not-so-  He said one of the most challeng- to be accountable and be depend-
        ally and as a group? On top of that, more like this guy!,” she wrote. “He great coaches,” Hoad said. “When I ing parts of coaching, especially at able,” Hoad said. “My job is to be
        through my experience in hockey, always maintains the utmost respect stepped away from the game … I al- the minor sport level, is ﬁnding a way there and be accountable to myself
        have I impacted those players, again for the sport, players, referees, all ways saw myself as a student of the to engage and develop players with and to my teammates, and you learn
        individually and as a group, in a posi- involved. Always behaving in an ad- game and understood the game. I wildly different skill levels.  to play within that group. Yes, there
        tive way?”                        mirable, positive manner maintain- wasn’t always the best player on the  “It’s a difﬁcult balance,” Hoad said. are still individual aspirations and
          He said the results can be seen ing perfect balance between com- ice, but I knew what my job was and “Not that you want to classify play- individual goals that you are looking
        when National Hockey League play- petitiveness, growing the athlete and I knew how to do it well, and that’s ers, but that’s just the nature of sport. to be the best that you can be, but it’s
        ers are interviewed and invariably their emotional and athletic develop- kind of what carried me through my You have the top players and want also in that team dynamic, which I
        defer to the team.                ment. Jeff brings a great balance to hockey career. If you asked my coach- to challenge them and push them think makes team sport such a differ-
          “Part of the world of hockey is the sport also in terms of the parents es, they would more than likely say to develop and reach their potential. ent avenue for learning because you
        good character people, and you and family lives involved in them. that Jeff Hoad was coachable. I took It’s the same thing with, if you want have all those different parts at play.
        learn that at a very early age,” Hoad Keeping dreams alive while also a lot of that stuff in from my playing to use the term, lower-end players or  “When it comes to working with
        said. “When you watch TV and you keeping age-appropriate perspec- days and it was the natural progres- someone who isn’t quite there yet.  people who have been involved in
        watch the NHL players getting inter- tive. Jeff is continuously giving of his sion for me as my son got involved in  “You don’t want to leave them be- team sports, it’s very evident very
        viewed, many are very humble and time, putting hundreds of hours into hockey and started bringing me back hind because at the end of the day, early on who has been involved in
        they speak about the importance of planning, training on and off the ice towards the rink.           it’s a game. It’s meant to be fun, re- team sports.”
        team, and that starts when they’re mentally and physically.”         “It just became one of those things gardless of every person’s aspirations » pbergson@brandonsun.com
        young. It doesn’t start when they  The Brandonite, who spent parts where if I’m going to be at the rink, I of making it to the next level, whether » Twitter: @PerryBergson
        Koscielny learned big lesson at hockey school




                                                                                            their team clothing, when that a challenge to have the high other and want to wear the
                                                                                            kid sends a message and asks achievers with some who may- team clothes and take pride in
                                                                                            ‘When are we starting again?’” be don’t achieve at the same the team. I think a little bit in
                                                                                            Koscielny said. “That for me level, but I think a lot of it is our situation is being rural and
                                                                                            is success and rewarding, that people. It’s a people profession, going into competitions in big-
                                                                                            you’re creating an environment it’s a people thing. You try and ger cities against bigger clubs
                                                                                            or impacting people. I have a treat everybody with respect and bigger teams. There’s may-
                                                                                            couple of former athletes who I and with manners and talk to be a little bit of the kids want-
                                                                                            still get messages from. To me, people and try to get to know ing to show that we can do it,
                        2019                                                                that’s success that they keep people. If you do those things, too.”
                                                                                            in touch and want me to write I think you can have great re-  His goals extend well beyond
        BY PERRY BERGSON                                                                    letters of recommendation or lationships  with  everybody, the track.
                                                                                            letters of reference and want regardless of what they accom-  He said the individual part of
          Bryce  Koscielny  learned                                                         me to know what they’re doing. plish.                   track magniﬁes people pushing
        a lasting lesson at a hockey                                                        That to me is success because  “I’m just as close with kids against their perceived limits,
        school he helped out at many                                                        you know you’ve connected who maybe weren’t as accom- and he has seen many kids who
        years ago. The result has him                                                       with someone.               plished as with past athletes said they couldn’t complete a
        still running in some fast com-                                                       “There are a lot of layers to it who were accomplished. I workout and willed their way
        pany more than two decades                                                          and it’s not just one thing.”  think at the end of the day, it’s through it.
        later.                                                                                He began coaching while he just people.”                Their conﬁdence and belief
          “I had great coaches as a kid,                                                    was in university, serving as  Another  challenge  with in themselves invariably grow
        and had great relationships  Prairie Storm Athletics coach Bryce Koscielny poses for a  an assistant with a high school coaching track is knitting to- as a result.
        with them,” Koscielny said. “I  photo at the UCT Athletic Field last year. (File)   hockey team in 2001. That gether a group of athletes who  “I think at the end of the
        loved being involved in sports,                                                     eventually turned into a head mainly compete in individu- day, it’s just about developing
        and it was always maybe just that’s not all.            is essential. He focuses on per- coaching job, and he has been al pursuits, aside from relay people and skills that they can
        a way to stay involved. Trevor  In nominating Koscielny for sonal bests in their progression active ever since.  events. Creating a team bond is use long term,” Koscielny said.
        Robins gave me a chance when the Community Leader Awards, to success. His commitment to  Over the years, he has also slightly tougher.      “It will be rare that we coach an
        I was a little kid to help out with Mark Perrett and Myrna Den- his athletes in his approach and coached track, cross-country  He said he doesn’t do any- athlete who makes millions of
        his hockey school once upon a bow noted that since coming encouragement has resulted in running and baseball, while thing in emphasizing the team dollars and wins Olympic med-
        time, and watching those guys to Neepawa in 2005, the track great rewards.”         supervising other high school concept or culture — other als. Hopefully one day they’ll
        working with kids and being coach has proven to be devoted  This  year,  he’s  coaching sports at NACI. Coaching pro- than keeping them together as be quality employees or maybe
        able to help sparked an interest and extremely resourceful.  cross-country and track with vides an opportunity for him much as he can, including dur- own their own businesses and
        and a passion in me.”         “Having limited resources, the high school and will serve to give back, and also to keep a ing warmups and cooldowns hopefully one day they coach,
          The  sporting  community he improvises places to train, as an assistant coach with his foothold in the sporting com- — but has seen it grow organi- too. I think sport teaches time
        in Neepawa clearly owes the like school hallways, under the son’s team in the Neepawa Mi- munity.               cally among the athletes.   management, it teaches orga-
        former Brandon Wheat Kings bleachers in the Yellowhead nor Hockey Association as well.  One of the challenges is ﬁnd-  “I think there is just a lot of nization, it teaches work ethic,
        goalie Robins a giant thank you: Centre, and unlike bigger cen-  Clearing a new bar, running a ing a way to provide a good ex- talk about supporting each it teaches dedication.
        Koscielny has since become an tres has no assistants and lim- faster time, throwing farther or perience to a group of athletes other and working together  “I think for a lot of them,
        invaluable resource.        ited equipment,” they wrote. jumping farther is nice, but he’s that may have vastly different for that common goal,” Kosci- it teaches them about them-
          The teacher at Neepawa Area “Not being deterred, since be- looking for more.      talent levels.              elny said. “Everyone is there to selves and what they can do
        Collegiate Institute is perhaps ginning the club he has helped  “For me, when that kid comes  “I think it’s just trying to be get better. I think it’s evolved and what they can’t do.”
        best known for coaching the athletes to develop speed no back,whenthatkidrefersteam- available for everyone,” Kosci- through the athletes that I’ve » pbergson@brandonsun.com
        Prairie Storm track club, but matter what sport where speed mates, when that kid wears elny said. “It certainly can be coached. They support each » Twitter: @PerryBergson]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[The Right Gear                                                  CUSTOMIZED APPAREL FOR TEAMS,


                                                                                    SCHOOLS & BUSINESSES

                    For Your Game





                    at the Right




                    Price!










                                                                              Uniforms, Jerseys, Golf Shirts, Head Wear,

                                                                              Sports Bags & More! Stop by the store and check out your options.









             Congratulations







             to all the


             Community Leader Award Recipients.


             Thanks for bringing your a-game to

             making Westman a great place to live


             and do business!







                                                                                                                    NEED TO UPGRADE


                                                                                                                    YOUR SKATES?



                                                                                                                     We are the only store in Brandon that

                                                                                                                     will take your old skates on trade


                                                                                                                     towards a new skate purchase!



































































             2025 Brandon Avenue                                                  Phone: 204-727-0756]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[THURSDAY SEPTEMBER 26 2019 ■ THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                    COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2019     ■  B13




















                                    2019










































        Chris and Kim Lowes are this year’s Community Builder Award recipients. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
        »COMMUNITY BUILDER, SPONSORED BY FUSION CREDIT UNION

        Couple selﬂess community builders






        BY DIANE NELSON                    “These two loving people are self- Kim said people have to want to par- a woman who was walking the streets than content with their family’s des-
                                          less in their pursuit to see women ticipate for the right reasons.  selling herself to try to pay for her ad- tiny.
          If their nominator’s testimonial is freed from their addictions and the  “The only ones who are saved are diction,” she added. “Addiction knows  “We have three kids and I was
        any indication, to say they’re selﬂess many issues they face when coming the ones who genuinely want to be no boundaries.”            pregnant with the ﬁrst one when we
        would probably be an understate- to Teen Challenge,” the nominator saved,” she said. “You can’t do it to  While reality dictates they can’t save started, so it’s all our kids have ever
        ment.  Kim and Chris Lowes have wrote. “They help these women de- please others. You have to have hit everybody, one might think this type known,” she said.
        dedicated their lives to helping people velop a strong and solid relationship rock bottom and want to ﬁnd a way of work would be depressing, and it  “And we believe this is what we’re
        of all ages get their lives back on track with God, and they have sacriﬁced back.                    does have those low moments, Kim supposed to do. It’s your job, but when
        from addiction, starting in Ontario much, moving here with their three  “We kind of try to train the whole said. But happily, the victories out- you feel it’s your calling, that just feels
        in 1998, continuing in Winnipeg in children from Winnipeg.”        person — we believe the addiction weigh the sadder outcomes.       different. I can’t imagine doing any-
        2010, and ﬁnally bringing their work  In fact, the couple is so dedicated is the surface, and we try to ﬁnd out  “There’s pain along the way, but thing else with my life.”
        to Brandon in 2012.               to their cause that when they became what’s the root of that addiction.”  often I would be the ﬁrst voice they  And in terms of being nominated as
          The husband-and-wife team runs frustrated by being limited by physi-  Not surprisingly, people come to would talk to,” she said. “And when a Community Leader, well, Kim says
        the Adult and Teen Challenge Cen- cal space in the Wheat City — they them from all walks of life. Kim said you go from utter hopelessness or ‘I she’s just thankful. And she feels espe-
        tre in Brandon, a ministry that helps could only accommodate ﬁve or six while some folks are referred through might as well be dead’ and then have cially grateful that their nominator is
        people cope with life-controlling ad- people at a time — they built, in 2016, the legal system, others just present them realize that there is hope and someone with whom they had a bond.
        dictions.                         a property about ten miles north of themselves because they don’t know they can be the person they want to  “She was in our program — she
          “It started out as drugs and alcohol, Brandon where they can now house what else to do — they can’t ﬁnd ways be or the mom they want to be, well, was one of our students, or clients as
        but now if it’s anything that someone’s 16 women at a time. Kim and Chris to cope on their own and know they that’s really gratifying.”  some people like to call them,” Kim
        addicted to, we’re here to help,” Kim and their family live on a bungalow need help.                  In addition to the centre, some said. “She came to our program to get
        said during a phone interview.    on the same property.              “It’s a pattern of living that they months ago the Loweses opened and help.
          According to their nominator, a  “It was frustrating before because don’t know how to get out of, and also operate, along with women from  “That she nominated us — that’s
        woman who was formerly in their with only being able to handle ﬁve that’s what we try and help them get the program and a few paid staff, the very humbling, I think. And I just
        program, the couple has helped save or six, it was a year’s wait, and some out of,” she said. “And the reality is Super Thrift Store at 127 Seventh St. in think back to when we started. We
        many lives. And while Kim knows people passed away during that time,” women who come to us with addic- Brandon. And while that means she don’t do it for this sort of thing.
        that’s the case, she said it’s nice to Kim said quietly.           tion issues are often in abusive rela- and Chris are both spread fairly thin,  “To be nominated by a sweet wom-
        hear that from someone they were   But now, they’re able to offer their tionships.                   Kim said they’re conﬁdent they’re do- an that we helped, that brings tears to
        able to assist.                   program to all those who want it. But  “I’ve had a woman with a PhD and ing what they should, and are more my eyes, to be honest.”
        Cowan ‘overwhelmed’ to get prestigious nod

















                        2019


        BY DIANE NELSON
          You could have knocked Lor-
        na Cowan over with a feather
        when she learned she’d been
        nominated for a Community
        Leader Award.
          “I’m a little overwhelmed,”
        Cowan said when informed
        she’d been given such a pres-
        tigious nod. “It is very much a
        surprise.”
           But like most nominees,
        Cowan was humble.
           “It’s lovely, but I don’t know
        if that would ﬁt me. But it’s very
        nice people think I am (a leader
        in the community).”
          While Cowan is modest, her
        track record speaks for itself.
        She turned 86 on Sept. 6, and
        has spent most of her life help-
        ing others, both as a career
        nurse and as a volunteer on
        the boards of several organi-  LEFT: Lorna Cowan in her home. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun) RIGHT: Cowan adds a handful of daffodils to her order of ﬂowers being delivered to local businesses
        zations. She was awarded the  for the Canadian Cancer Society. (File)
        Westman     Communications
        Group Lifetime Achievement and for years, before she met mother at that time, and I had  “It was very special to me,” organizations, including the always so interested — I still
        Award during the YWCA Bran- her second husband, she raised a son I thought was in real need Cowan said.         Brandon Regional Health Cen- see lots of things that I‘d like to
        don’s 32nd annual Women of her two young sons alone. It of a big brother. So it’s near and  After two years on the Big tre, Brandon Regional Health be involved in and then I say,
        Distinction Awards Gala earlier was at that time, in the early dear to my heart.”   Brothers board, a paid co-or- Authority (now Prairie Moun- ‘Don’t be silly.’
        this year.                  1970s, she became one of the  She was happy to be a volun- dinator was hired because the tain Health), Fairview Personal  “I’m limited. So I do what I
          “I think there is great satis- original board members of Big teer on the committee and en- demand became more than Care Home and the Imperial can, that’s all.”
        faction in knowing that you can Brothers. It was the ﬁrst time joyed interviewing the mothers the board — comprised solely Order Daughters of the Empire  And even though she’s done
        make a difference for some- she’d worked in such a major who felt their boys needed big of volunteers — could handle.  (IODE), a women’s charitable and still does so much, as far as
        one,” she said in an earlier in- capacity with a community or- brothers,aswellasthekidswho  Cowan retired from nurs- organization for which she is a the Community Leader Awards
        terview with The Brandon Sun.  ganization.              were applying for a big brother, ing in 1993 to spend more member of the national advi- go, Cowan reiterated her ﬁrst
          Cowan grew up in Dauphin    “I’d always been interested and those people wishing to be time with her husband, who sory committee.         response to hearing of the
        and became a registered nurse, in helping kids in whatever one. Then the committee had suffered from illness until his  “There’ve been many differ- nomination.
        working in hospitals in Souris, way you could,” she said. “But to decide who would match death nine years later.  ent things that have come up  “I’m very honoured,” she
        Dauphin and Brandon. She Big Brothers was of particular and which people might be a   Since then, Cowan has sat over the years that I have an said. “I’m completely surprised
        was widowed at the age of 28, interest because I was a single good ﬁt.              on the boards of numerous interest in,” Cowan said. “I’m by the whole thing.”]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[B14  ■  COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2019                                                                                        THE BRANDON SUN ■ THURSDAY SEPTEMBER 26 2019





















                                    2019
















































        Doris Pratt dedicated her life to preserving the Dakota language. (Doug Thomas Photography)
        »TEACHER OF THE YEAR, SPONSORED BY ASSINIBOINE COMMUNITY COLLEGE

        Pratt dedicated life to preserving Dakota language




        BY DIANE NELSON                   writing system for the Dakota lan- adviser for Sioux Valley Education cipal, director of education, and as a ours,” Hall said. “She didn’t like
                                          guage that provided an easier way to and Governance. Mrs. Pratt was a professor at the university level.  being the centre of attention. She
          It might be suggested that endur- read and write it.             respected mentor, an inspiration to  Pratt also spent ﬁve summers at would have shown up, but she didn’t
        ing the Residential School system  She created Dakota language — many Indigenous educators with the American Language Institute De- like the limelight.”
        motivated the late Doris Pratt to do related materials for both school her wealth of knowledge, experience velopment Program at the University  And that’s because, for Pratt, it was
        something to improve education for curricula and for those wishing to and wisdom.”                   of Arizona and achieved an educa- her work that was important, not be-
        her people.                       pursue an education at home. And   According to her daughter Marilyn tion, culture and language specialist ing acknowledged for it.
          And she certainly did that — and she didn’t restrict her teachings to a Hall, Pratt was always stressing the degree in 2004. As well, she served as  “She would have seen a need, and
        more. Hailed as a teacher by her particular age group. She developed importance of education.        an ofﬁcial translator for the federal she would have ﬁlled it,” Hall said.
        Sioux Valley Dakota Nation com- methods to instruct students right   “She encouraged us all (her chil- government and the Truth and Rec- “She kept learning her whole life.
        munity, Pratt took her strength, from the elementary school level dren) to go back to school,” Hall said. onciliation Commission.     She was always busy at something.
        her insight and her many abilities through to senior high school and “Education was an issue with her.  Pratt received many prestigious She was very driven.”
        to the community at large, then to beyond.                         And not just family — she encour- awards during her lifetime, but    Hall said that Pratt would tell peo-
        the province, and eventually, to the  At the time of her passing – March aged everybody to get educated. found her greatest satisfaction in ple that a teacher at the Residential
        country.                          10th of this year — at age 83, the She’d say,‘It’s never too late to learn.’” helping preserve and teach the lan- School used to call her and her In-
          An acclaimed Manitoba elder, chief and council of Sioux Valley Da-  In addition to earning bachelor’s guage of her people.          digenous classmates “trash.” Pratt
        Pratt dedicated her life to preserving kota Nation emailed the following degrees in teaching and education,  And while she was pleased her had no idea what that meant until
        the Dakota language. In addition to statement to The Brandon Sun’s Bud and a master’s degree in education contributions were appreciated, and years later. And while that wasn’t her
        writing two books — one published Robertson, who wrote the newspa- from Brandon University, Pratt co- would, according to Hall, have been motivation for all she accomplished,
        by the Truth and Reconciliation per’s original story of Pratt’s legacy.  ordinated the Brandon University honoured to receive a Community she did allow herself a small degree
        Commission in 2016 and another     “Elder Doris Pratt will be remem- Teacher Education Program (BUN- Leader Award, she would not have of satisfaction in all she’d achieved.
        published by the Manitoba First Na- bered for her lifetime commitment TEP) program to train teachers for been thrilled about the accompany-  “She’d say, ‘Not bad for trash,’”
        tions Education Resource Centre to education and the preservation work in northern Manitoba commu- ing publicity.                     Hall said. “She was not trash and she
        in 2018 – she developed a phonetic of our Dakota language. She was an nities. She worked as a teacher, prin-  “Truthfully, Mom didn’t like hon- proved that.”
        Piano teacher ‘ﬂabbergasted’ by nomination





        BY DIANE NELSON

          She was acknowledged last year with a
        tremendous honour — she was named a
        Teacher of Distinction by the prestigious
        Royal Conservatory of Music in Toronto.
        And now, piano teacher extraordinaire April
        Gibson has been acknowledged again as
        a ﬁnalist in the “Teacher” category of The
        Brandon Sun’s Community Leader Awards.
          “I’m completely ﬂabbergasted,” Gibson
        said when she heard she’d been nominated
        as a Community Leader.“It’s a real surprise!”
          Gibson, who has been teaching piano                         2019
        for 35 years, took her training at the Victo-
        ria Conservatory of Music and has taught
        in B.C., Alberta, and Manitoba. She’s lived
        in Killarney for more than six years, and ly good teaching and really good teachers.”
        while she teaches two days a week at the  And as an instructor, Gibson tries to instil
        Eckhardt-Gramatté Conservatory of Music that love of music in her students.
        at Brandon University, she has a full studio  “For all students, I would just want them
        of students in Killarney. Her pupils range in to have a lifelong passion for music,” she
        age from age three to adult.            said. “Some will go on and study in universi-
          As if that weren’t enough, Gibson is also ty, but that’s not my ultimate goal with every
        on the faculty for the Kick Start Piano En- student. It’s just simply that they would have
        semble Camp at BU, and is active as an ad- that passion for music, and that love for mu-
        judicator and workshop and master-class sic all their life.”
        clinician. She also has extensive training  One of the things Gibson insists on is ex-
        in pedagogy and andragogy, so she teaches posing her students to a variety of musical
        other teachers. But whatever their age or styles. She said when inquiring about her
        level of experience, she tries to engender teaching approach, parents often want to
        her readily evident passion for music in all put her in a box — they try to determine
        her students.                           what speciﬁc kind of music she teaches. But
          On its website, the Royal Conservatory of she makes it very clear that variety really is
        Music says those chosen as Music Teachers the spice of a musical life.
        of Distinction“are leaders in the ﬁeld of mu-  “I teach everything in every genre of mu-
        sic education, recognized for their contribu- sic,” Gibson said. “I teach jazz, whether they
        tions of creativity, dedication, innovation, like it or not, I do sacred stuff, popular mu-
        and passion.”                           sic, Canadian music. Highlighting Canadian
          And that describes Gibson — in spades.  composers is very important.”
          “I’m very passionate about students play-  Exposing students to all types of music
        ing by ear, improvising, using a lead sheet — can often spark a desire to pursue a path
        kids should be learning all of that,” she said they might not have considered or discov-
        during a phone interview. “It’s really impor- ered otherwise. Making musicians inde-
        tant for us to teach functional skills, and I pendent — able to play without full scores
        really try to foster creativity.”       in front of them and able to compose and
          As one of seven children in a musical fam- improvise when the situation calls for it – is
        ily — all the siblings played instruments one of her main objectives.
        and sang — music has been a constant for  And her enthusiasm for her craft is evident
        as long as she can remember.            at every turn, as was her delight in being
          “My grandmother taught me to play by nominated for a Community Leader Award.
        ear,” Gibson said. “At a very early age, I was  “I’m very honoured — it’s very exciting,” April Gibson is the ﬁnalist in the Teacher category of the Community Leader Awards.
        composing and playing by ear. So I had real- Gibson said. “I totally love my job.”  (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>