<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="36"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[2019 WESTMAN


                         BUSINESS













































                                                                                                                              2019 SPECIAL SUPPLEMENT]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Dr. Kelleher’s

                                                                                                                                   Skin & Vein

                                                                                                                               Centre is excited

                                                                                                                                  to be the first

                                                                                                                                   to bring this

                                                                                                                                    innovative

                                                                                                                                 technology to


                                                                                       Clear Skin                                   Manitoba!
                         Clear Lift                                                                                                 This multi-
                                                                                      Acne Scars
                      Pigmentation                                                    Photofacial                                  application
                      Skin Tone & Texture                                             Pigmented/Red Lesions                       platform can
                      Skin Remolding                                                                                           treat a full range

                      Wrinkles
                      Fine Lines                                                                                                   of aesthetic
                                                                                                                                 needs. Proven

                                                                                              More Treatments                        safe and


                                                                                             Tattoo Removal                          effective.
                                                                                             Hair Removal
                          Clear Vein                                                         Treatment for

                                                                                             Toenail Fungus
                        Varicose Veins
                        Spider Veins






                Does your feminine life need a lift?





















                Do you have vaginal laxity, vaginal dryness, stress urinary incontinence, recurring infections?
                   If you have answered, “yes” to any of these conditions, FemiLift may be right for you.
                This is a safe, minimally invasive, non-surgical procedure designed to help give you back your
                   femininity, For more information or for your complimentary consultation, call us today!

               150–1300–18th Street  |  Brandon, MB  | 204-727-1920  |  www.laserskinvein.com]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2019 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           3













































            Brandon’s business sector experienced a busy year in 2019, says Brandon Chamber of Commerce president Cathy Snelgrove. (File)
            Growth ‘keeps us fresh and exciting’






            BY COLIN SLARK                      rooms booked in Brandon has risen over  Street getting the building ready for a new  weight in some areas.
                                                the past few years. That figure may further  PetSmart location and the Community Fu-  It’s been slightly more than a year since
              Brandon’s business sector has had a busy  increase when the new Holiday Inn Ex- tures building downtown getting a facelift.  cannabis was legalized in Canada.
            year.                               press opens on 18th St. across from the   “I think that’s really great,” Snelgrove   Manitoba  as a whole might not have
              Much of that has to do with the big con- Keystone Centre next year.    said. “That keeps us fresh and exciting. It’s  fulfilled the provincial government’s
            struction projects in and around the city.  Harvey attributes this to two fac- good stuff.”                  goal of having a cannabis outlet within
              But for many of these construction proj- tors. The first is that Brandon is the eco-  Mayor Rick Chrest told the Sun that  a 30-minute drive of 90 per cent of resi-
            ects, the businesses involved have to believe  nomic hub for the region, attracting people  Brandon has never been a boom or bust  dents, but Brandon has more than fulfilled
            that Brandon is the right place to build.  from all over Westman.        town and is in solid shape right now busi- that goal on a local scale.
              To find out what the current business   The second is what Harvey said is from  ness-wise.                    Five cannabis retailers have opened
            climate in Brandon is, the Sun talked to  “the uptick in the number and quality of   “When you get a significant uptick in  in Brandon over the last year under four
            local business leaders to find out why they  events the city is hosting.”  private investment, then that does signal  different brands: Delta 9, Meta Cannabis
            think Brandon is a good place to do busi-  He called the Keystone Centre and the  confidence in your community,” Chrest  Supply Co., Tweed and Tokyo Smoke.
            ness.                               new amphitheatre at Festival Park “world  said. “Especially when you get a manufac-  One company, Canopy Growth, owns
              There have been some high-profile  class.”                             turer such as Koch Fertilizer spending $30  three of those locations: the Tweed retailer
            events in the city this year with more com-  The new amphitheatre has already been  million on an office complex.”  on Victoria Ave. and the two Tokyo Smoke
            ing up.                             put to good use, hosting several musical acts   The old Sobeys location in the South  locations, including the recently-opened
              Country stars Dean Brody and Dallas  during the summer and providing a stage  End next to Staples has remained vacant  location beside the Dairy Queen at the
            Smith came to town on their latest tour,  for Canada Day celebrations at the Riv- since the grocery store moved across 18th  Corral Centre.
            the Tim Hortons Brier thrilled curling fans  erbank Discovery Centre.  The Discovery  Street to Shoppers Mall. In July, develop-  “We’re seeing a few things,” Matt Ryan,
            earlier  in the year, Scott  Moir and  Tessa  Centre is still looking for a sponsor to ac- er Shindico told the Sun that Sobeys still  vice-president of marketing for Meta par-
            Virtue came to town as part of their retire- quire the naming rights for the stage.  holds the lease and they are looking for  ent company National Access Cannabis,
            ment tour with the Rock the Rink show   Brandon Chamber of Commerce pres- someone to sub-lease the space.    told the Sun. “The competition in Bran-
            and the Champions of Magic illusion show  ident Cathy Snelgrove said it has been a   One complication is that Sobeys does  don and the province alone is escalat-
            is coming soon.                     strong year for businesses, led by new con- not want another grocery store to move into  ing because more and more stores have
              The  Canadian  National  Arabian  &  struction and business expansion projects.  that space.               opened. I think competitions affect things,
            Half-Arabian Championship Horse Show   She mentioned that  there have been   Jonathan Alward of the Canadian Fed- but I think all the cannabis retailers are
            had another successful year only slightly  some strong retail and restaurant develop- eration of Independent Businesses told  noticing that there’s still room for more
            dimmed by a decreased number of compet- ments recently in the city.      the Sun that in his institution’s  “Entre- stores to come.”
            ing horses due to an outbreak in the United   One positive trend she has seen recent- preneurial Communities” report from last   Another company, Garden  Variety, is
            States that forced some animals to be quar- ly in local businesses is the revitalization of  year that Brandon outpaced Winnipeg in  aiming to open Brandon’s sixth cannabis
            antined.                            previously existing spaces.          areas like business establishment growth  retailer next to the KFC/Taco Bell restau-
              Brandon First executive director Gra-  Snelgrove pointed to renovations to  and business establishments per capita,  rant on 18th St.
            ham Harvey said that the number of hotel  the former Shoppers Drug Mart on 18th  showing that the city is punching above its       » Continued on Page 4]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019


            » Continued from Page 3                                                                                         Snelgrove was asked why she thought
                                                                                                                         American restaurant chains like Qdoba,
              The  Winnipeg Free Press recently re-                                                                      Applebee’s and Wayback Burgers have
            ported that Manitoba Liquor & Lotteries,                                                                     chosen to come to Brandon early in their
            which handles wholesale cannabis sales to                                                                    expansion into Canada.
            retailers,  lost  $2.4  million  on  cannabis  in                                                               “I think we are pretty representative,
            the 2018-19 fiscal year ending March 31.                                                                     we’re a pretty engaged community,” she
              Given that loss and the effect of can-                                                                     said.
            nabis derivative products, which recently                                                                       Because Brandon has hit the 50,000 to
            became legal on the one-year anniversary                                                                     60,000 population threshold, Snelgrove
            of legalization, the long-term health of the                                                                 says it makes the community more desir-
            market remains to be seen.                                                                                   able for new businesses.
              However, MLL said that some of their                                                                          “They’ve got a large enough draw area,”
            losses were due to one-time expenses in-                                                                     she said. “They can know how successful
            curred  during the  legalization  process.                                                                   they’re going to be and not get lost in, say, a
            Without  those expenses, the organization                                                                    million-person city.”
            told the Free Press that it would have re-                                                                      As for why businesses are staying in
            corded a $1.7 million profit.                                                                                Brandon after they arrive, Snelgrove be-
              Another problem the industry faced   LEFT: Brandon First executive director Graham Harvey, outside of Brandon’s historic Dome Building, which   lieves  that  it’s  due to  the  strength  of the
            during its infancy was supply shortages,   serves as their headquarters. RIGHT: Brandon Chamber of Commerce president Cathy Snelgrove listens to   local workforce. She believes Brandon is a
            though CEO John Arbuthnot of Delta 9   a fellow speaker at a past Chamber event. (Files)                     hard-working community due to its agri-
            recently told the Sun that those problems                                                                    cultural background.
            have  largely  been  resolved  at  this  point.  tion. Ryan said that Brandon’s Meta loca- over illnesses linked to vaping in the Unit-  When asked if she was worried about
            Ryan  concurred that  the supply  situation  tion was built with the derivative products  ed States and Canada, both Arbuthnot and  the potential economic effects on the city
            had improved.                       in mind for when they became legal.  Ritchot said that                   due to the agricultural sector having had
              Even though derivatives like edibles,   Robert Ritchot, the founder of local-  Brandon has seen a few restaurants open  such a rough year with a dry summer fol-
            topicals, and  concentrates  are now legal,  ly-based national cannabis accessories com- this year, like the Original Joe’s at Shoppers  lowed by an extremely wet fall, Snelgrove
            producers still have to sort out regulatory  pany humble + fume (formerly BOBHQ),  Mall as well as the Freshii and full-service  remained optimistic.
            issues like getting Health Canada approv- recently told the Sun that he expects the  Dairy Queen at the Corral Centre.   It would be naive, she said, to expect no
            als.                                products his company’s research and de-  Murray Fischer, the City of Brandon’s  effect from this difficult year, but suggested
              These products will take a while to hit  velopment branch is working on will most  acting building safety manager, said there  that Brandon has rebounded from previous
            store shelves and there may still be supply  likely hit shelves in the first quarter of next  are a few more restaurant chains looking to  bad years for agriculture.
            issues as the market waits for a full suite of  year.                    move into Brandon but did not have spe- » cslark@brandonsun.com
            products to become available for distribu-  Though there have been recent concerns  cifics.                  » Twitter: @ColinSlark

                                                A  Inclusive Retirement Living...


                                                                  because you deserve it!






















                                                                                                             • Suites & Villas designed with you in mind

                                                                                                              • Light housekeeping & laundry services included
                                                                                                               • Spacious common areas & recreation facilities
                                                                                                               • Varied & delicious meals created by our Red Seal chef

                                                                                                               • No buy-in fees or long term leases
                                                                                                              • On-site medical clinic, pharmacy, salon & shuttle services
                                                                                                            Book Your Tour Today!

                                                                                                                                         204-725-1340

                                                1340 - 10  Street, Brandon                 www.rotaryvillas.ca
                                                          th]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2019 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           5
            Big projects





            dominate






            Brandon





            construction






            in 2019






                                                                  Contractors lay the foundation for the rebuilt beer vendor next to the former Knights Inn on Rosser Ave. (Colin Slark/The Brandon Sun)
            BY COLIN SLARK                      compared to last year, but the dollar value of  cludes the RMs of Cornwallis and Elton.  ects this year in Brandon have represent-
                                                those projects have been much higher.  At the same time last year, 534 permits  ed $121,258,848 at the end of September.
              The City of Brandon’s monthly con-   At the end of September, 458 building  had been issued in Brandon and 599 per- That’s more than double the $58,714,868
            struction reports this year have shown a  permits had been issued in Brandon this  mits had been issued for the entire planning  construction projects represented at the
            clear trend.                        year and 506 permits had been issued for  area.                          same point in time last year.
              There have been fewer projects this year  the Brandon planning area, which also in-  However, the dollar value of those proj-    » Continued on Page 6


                                                                                                                               Daughter On Call  Traditional
                                                                                                                                Elder Homes    PCH Facility

                                                                                  Resident decides when to get up & when to go to bed.

                                                                                  Resident can custom order breakfast.
                                                                                  Resident helps choose the fresh, homemade menu items that are served.
                                                                                  Resident can request an alternate meal.
                                                                                  There are live-in pets to provide comfort.

                                                                                  Resident can help out with tasks such as meal making, baking, doing dishes,
                                                                                  gardening, walking the house dog.
                                                                                  All staff have received extensive dementia training following Teepa Snow’s
                                                                                  positive approach method.
                                                                                  Resident helps decide what activities & outings their home takes part in.
                                                                                  All staff have been trained as Eden Alternative Care providers.

                                                                                  Clothing is not labelled. Personal laundry is not washed with others clothing.
                       When your loved ones need some attention, personalized care &   Transparency of care – Family can access loved one’s daily care notes via
                                                                                  the internet.
                     nurturing, Daughter On Call Elder Homes are where they need to live!
                                                                                  Couples can stay together regardless of their different abilities.
                     Our homes are just that – HOMES – and not facilities. In a home they   Residents can move in when they are independent and stay until they die.
                     continue to have the ability to make all their own choices, while in a   All in the same familiar room.
                            facility those choices are generally made for them.   Resident can bathe as many times a week as they would like.

                                                                                  Resident directed plan of care.



                             2412B Victoria Avenue, Brandon  •  Brandon 204-725-6629 & Portage 204-872-5613  •  www.daughteroncall.com]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[6                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019


            » Continued from Page 5

              In September this year alone, 70 permits were is-
            sued, valued at $15.3 million.
              Contributing to that figure are two 15-unit apart-
            ment buildings being constructed by Youth for Christ,
            a new vehicle garage at Brandon Municipal Airport,
            the  renovation  of  the  old  Shoppers  Drug  Mart  on
            18th St. to accommodate a new PetSmart, and two
            new 12-unit apartment buildings being built on Brae-
            crest Drive.
              The former Shoppers Drug Mart building can
            now accommodate two tenants, and Colliers Canada
            is looking for a neighbour to occupy the space beside
            PetSmart.
              According  to  the  city,  a  few  major  projects  have
            represented a substantial amount of the value of proj-
            ects that have happened to date this year.
              Koch Fertilizer has spent $33 million on a new ad-
            ministration building at its Brandon site.
              The new Maryland Park School being built has
            represented tens of millions of dollars coming into the
            community.
              Murray Fischer, the city’s acting building safety
            manager, told the Sun that for residential construction
            there has been a trend toward large multiplexes and
            apartment buildings instead of single dwelling homes.
              That  explains part of  the reason why there  have
            been fewer permits issued for more money, as these
            multi-unit buildings represent a larger dollar value
            than single-occupancy residential units.
              “In the last two years, we’ve seen more of a trend
            toward multi-family (units),” Fischer said. “I think it
            has to do with the economy. We’re seeing more peo-
            ple trying to take advantage of a lower-income bracket
            and the need for housing in that area.”
              At the end of September this year, construction
            represented 211 new dwelling units in Brandon, where
            there had only been 139 by September of last year.

                                           » Continued on Page 8  Builders are aiming to have the new Holiday Inn Express on 18th Street finished by late spring. (Colin Slark/The Brandon Sun)









































            Construction equipment sits along Clare Avenue, adjacent to the future Gambler First Nation urban reserve. (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[ARE YOU AFRAID TO




                                  GO TO THE DENTIST?









                                                                            •  Do you find yourself on edge when going to the dentist,
                                                                              even for routine hygiene?

                                                                            •  Is the level of anxiety from anticipating dental procedures
                                                                              high enough to lead you to postpone or cancel visits?
                                                                            •  Have  you  been  living  with  pain  or  discomfort  in  your
                                                                              mouth, thinking about calling your dentist, but can’t bring

                                                                              yourself  to  pick  up  the  phone?  If  you  answered  yes  to
                                                                              any two of these  three questions, then you may be an
                                                                              ideal candidate for  sedation dentistry.

                                                                            Here  at  Princess  Dental  Centre  our  goal  is  to  help  you

                                                                            minimize the fear and tension associated with your dental
                                                                            care needs. Sedation dentistry can even be used for routine
                                                                            procedures such as teeth cleaning and check-ups.

























                 1202 Princess Avenue, Brandon, MB R7A 0R3 | Phone: 204-717-0249 | Toll Free: 1-866-563-1627

                                                              www.princessdental.com]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019


            » Continued from Page 6
              According to Fischer, the biggest residential project this
            year is the building going up at the corner of 18th and Brae-
            crest. He said the developers are halfway finished with that
            development.
              Another trend Fischer has seen this year is that compa-
            nies are looking to renovate existing buildings rather than
            starting from scratch.
              Fischer also noted that this year defied expectations when
            it came to construction.
              “To be honest with you, this year was a bit of an anoma-
            ly,” he said. “We were expecting a slower year than what we
            had. We didn’t expect the school or the Koch Fertilizer or
            the hotel, which really boosted our numbers.”
              Based on housing trends, he said that the city is not fore-
            casting a strong year for construction next year. However,
            if next year ends up being like this one, Fischer won’t com-
            plain.
              Other businesses are also in the process of expanding or
            upgrading their facilities. Precision Toyota recently finished
            building a new building and is in the process of tearing
            down its old one.
              TD Canada Trust is constructing a new building on 1108
            18th St. where the Shell station used to be. Back in July,
            a representative from the company told the Sun that once
            their new location is finished in spring 2020 that they will
            move operations from their current location on Rosser Ave.
              Next to the former Knights Inn, the beer vendor de-
            stroyed in last year’s downtown fire is currently being rebuilt.
            However, when completed it will only be one storey instead
            of the two in the previous building.
              The local RE/MAX branch finished building a new
            headquarters on Richmond Ave., which they moved into
            over the summer.
              The plot of land at First Street and Richmond Avenue is
            planned to be the new home of an Esso gas station and Tim
            Hortons location. Developers were permitted by the city to
            install underground fuel tanks earlier in the year.  A section of floor for the new TD Bank building at 1108 18th St. is lifted and moved into place during morning construction on Friday. The new
                                                              location will have longer hours, including being open on Sundays, additional parking and a range of financial advisors, including specialists
                                               » Continued on Page 9  from TD Wealth, TD Business Banking and TD Agriculture Services. (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)









































            A sign announces upcoming business development at the Gambler First Nation urban reserve in Brandon along Clare Avenue. (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2019 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           9

            » Continued from Page 8
              On 18th Street, the ongoing construction
            of a new Holiday Inn Express across from the
            Keystone Centre represents millions of dollars
            in spending. Construction of the hotel started in
            March of this year.
              Jeff Krivoshen, COO at P.R. Hotels, which is
            managing the hotel, told the Sun that it will be
            the second Holiday Inn Express in all of Mani-
            toba. There are already two regular Holiday Inns
            and a Holiday Inn Express in Winnipeg.
              When finished, the hotel will have 116 rooms.
            It won’t have a restaurant but will have an area
            where continental breakfast is served. There will
            also be two meeting rooms on the top floor, but
            no large conference space.
              Though rain in late summer and the recent
            heavy snowstorm have slowed down the build a
            little, a representative of the contractors building
            the hotel said that once they finish the roof and
            siding, they’ll be able to work through the winter.
              “They’re accustomed to working in winter
            conditions,” Krivoshen said. “It is Canada and
            anybody who’s building anything will have to
            contend with that.”
              The Sun had a look at the building and saw
            the early stages of certain amenities, such as the
            hotel’s pool and hot tub taking shape. Outside,
            the sidewalk was freshly poured and setting.
              Developers hope the hotel will be ready to
            welcome guests sometime in June.
            » cslark@brandonsun.com                  Construction crews work on a newly poured sidewalk on the south side of the Holiday Inn Express currently under construction on 18th Street. (Matt Goerzen/
            » Twitter: @ColinSlark
                                                     The Brandon Sun)

                Travelodge Brandon,


                Chicken Chef,



                Beer Vendor


                and The 40









                                All Under One Roof!
                                All Under One Roof!
                                All Under One Roof!














               210 - 18  Street North, Brandon • the40.ca Street North, Brandon   the40.ca
                        th
                        th
               Call: 204-727-3800 to reserve your room
               www.chickenchef.com • 204-727-2433]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019






































































            Brandon Delta 9 manager Taylor Bristow, centre, and employees Taylor McAvoy, left and TJ Blampied show off products at the store’s Sensory Bar. (Colin Slark/The Brandon Sun)
            » Delta 9


            Ready for Cannabis 2.0













              It’s been a year since cannabis was legal- have been unable to sell them directly to  ready for Health Canada to approve hun- Manitoba, with one right here in Brandon
            ized recreationally in Canada.      consumers.  Vaporizable cannabis oil and  dreds of new cannabis products in these  at Shoppers Mall.
              This first anniversary represents a mile- high-potency concentrates as well as topi- categories for sale.     CEO John Arbuthnot said that Delta
            stone, but it also represents the future of  cal products such as lotions have also been   One of these companies is Manitoba’s  9’s goal when it comes to both growing and
            cannabis.                           off-limits.                          own Delta 9, which grows cannabis for sale,  selling cannabis is to provide a craft prod-
              While cannabis edibles have been legal   However, all of that’s about to change  sells growing technology to other producers  uct at reasonable prices cheaper than their
            for people to make at home since medical  with Cannabis 2.0. These products are now  and runs a network of retail outlets.  competitors.
            cannabis was legalized years ago, retailers  legal and producers and retailers are getting   There are four Delta 9 retail locations in   » Continued on Page 12]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[12                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019


            » Continued from Page 10            ty if not all of these cases are involving   government’s goals of having cannabis   checking out a cannabis store.
                                                black market vape products where there   accessible within a 30-minute drive for   He said an older couple once came
              Arbuthnot said that some of the ed-  have been certain additives put into the   all Manitobans,” Arbuthnot said.  in looking for CBD products, saying “I
            ible products will take familiar forms   vaporizable oil, which can be potentially   Arbuthnot warned that a similar sup-  hope our pastor doesn’t see us” and look-
            like gummies, hard candies, baked goods   harmful for people’s lungs.    ply situation may occur with edibles as   ing around before entering the building.
            and chocolates. Also being developed are   “I’m confident that here in Canada be-  the market adjusts to accommodate the   “I think that the negative connotations
            cannabis drinks.                    cause of the regulatory structure where   new products. These derivative products   are still potentially there for some peo-
              Because of regulations on how much   we are prohibited from using any of those   are expected to hit stores beginning De-  ple, but realistically it’s gone to the way-
            THC edible cannabis products can con-  additives or stabilizers, on the front end   cember 16/19, just in time for the holi-  side a lot more,” Bristow said.
            tain, drinkables will be more compara-  we’ll have products that are much safer,”   days.                       The team at the Brandon store has
            ble to beer or coolers rather than harder   Arbuthnot said.                At Brandon’s Delta 9 store, manager   staff ranging from people in their twen-
            drinks like spirits or cocktails.     When  cannabis  was  first  legalized,   Taylor  Bristow  is  ready  to  sell  the  new   ties to their sixties. Bristow said that
              Some might be worried about vaping   there were some initial supply issues   products when they arrive. Bristow has   some customers enjoy having older, more
            cannabis given reports of vaping-related   with the availability of products. Arbuth-  managed the store since it opened in   experienced staff that can help them find
            illnesses in the United States in recent   not said that in the last six months, this   April but also worked for Delta 9 in   products to fulfill particular needs.
            months. However, Arbuthnot said the   problem has essentially been resolved,   Winnipeg in the lead up to legalization.  Bristow isn’t sure exactly which Can-
            situation here in Canada will likely be   and will continue to improve further as   Bristow said that some people still   nabis 2.0 products will arrive at Bran-
            different.                          we see cannabis stores moving into more   tentatively enter the store after decades   don’s Delta 9 outlet in mid- December,
              “What we’re seeing in those stories   rural communities across the province.  of prohibition, but people are becom-  but he and his team will be ready when
            out of the U.S. is that the vast majori-  “That’s the next phase of achieving the   ing more comfortable with the idea of   they do.































                  When entertaining at your home or office, Sobeys brings plenty to
                  the table. Our premium quality ingredients, better eating options
                  and  thrilling  selection  of  over  60  platters  and  trays  make  any
                  occasion extra special. Plus your order is made especially for you, so
                  it’s as fresh as can be. Hosting just got a whole lot easier.

                  Choose from a wide variety of freshly prepared trays, order and pay
                  online. Your order will be ready for pick up in-store in 24 hours.




                                                    1570 18  Street  |  Shoppers Mall  |  204-725-1134
                                                              th]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2019 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           13

              KOCH EXPANSION



                                                                                                                               Earlier this year, the Sun reported that Koch
                                                                                                                               Fertilizer Canada, ULC is in the process of
                                                                                                                               constructing a new headquarters in Bran-
                                                                                                                               don, which will reportedly bring together
                                                                                                                               operations, logistics, sales and marketing
                                                                                                                               under one roof, with office space for more
                                                                                                                               than 100 employees. The two-storey build-
                                                                                                                               ing, to be located on the northwest corner
                                                                                                                               of the property on 17th Street East, across
                                                                                                                               from Pfizer Canada, is scheduled to open
                                                                                                                               in the fourth quarter of 2020. The initial
                                                                                                                               $33-million headquarters project is one of
                                                                                                                               the largest investments ever made at the
                                                                                                                               site, according to a company news release.
                                                                                                                               In total, Koch Fertilizer Canada will be
                                                                                                                               investing nearly $130 million over the next
                                                                                                                               five years into its Brandon operations.
                                                                                                                               (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)


































                             2 FULL-SIZE

                  SUNROOMS ON DISPLAY!

                            • FREE ESTIMATES •




                            We specialize in building quality
                          sunrooms and patios designed to fit
                             your budget and your lifestyle.
                          Your sunroom will be custom built for you.
                           MAINTENANCE-FREE Sunspace Railings
                           Available In A Variety Of Styles & Colours.
                          Foundations to finishing – we do it all!



                          1840 - 18th St N                          204-726-8488                                www.sunspacesunrooms.com

                    in the Windsor Plywood building            email : sales@elitesunrooms.ca                       www.elitesunrooms.ca]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019


































































            Dr. Joe Gray of Grand Valley Animal Clinic examines a canine patient. (Colin Slark/The Brandon Sun)
            » Grand Valley Animal Clinic


            Providing the same great care amid changes






              In the past couple of years, the vet-  ment closely.                   ago, but it wasn’t until this spring that   local contractors and suppliers, many
            erinary industry has undergone a lot   Doctors Joe Gray,  Vicky Sem-     the veterinary community in Manitoba   of whom are clients of the clinic. Keep
            of changes, and Grand Valley Animal   pers and Jennifer Beckwith, owners   voted to ban declawing in cats, mak-  checking their Facebook page for the
            Clinic is working hard to ensure they   of Grand  Valley Animal Clinic, are   ing Manitoba the sixth province to ban   announcement of the grand reopening!
            stay up to date.                    pleased to report that they have de-  this inhumane procedure.              This  major  expansion  will  enable
              One major development in the      cided to remain independently owned     On the local level, clients and the   them to improve current services, as
            veterinary industry is the takeover of   with a strong emphasis on being a lo-  local community have no doubt won-  well as add several more! The addition
            small independently owned veterinary   cal business, employing local people,   dered about the construction vehicles   of a second surgery suite will enable
            clinics by large corporations. This is a   and practising high-quality veterinary   in the clinic parking lots over the last   the clinic to offer advanced surgeries
            global trend that has reached Manito-  medicine with patient care and patient   several months.               to the local community.
            ba.                                 well-being as their primary objective.  Grand Valley Animal Clinic is very   A new underwater treadmill will
              While it is not yet know what the    Another change in the industry    excited to report that the clinic has   also be installed before Christmas and
            implications of this will be for the   is the banning of certain procedures,   been undergoing major renovations   the clinic will be offering rehabilita-
            veterinary services in our community,   most recently the declawing of cats.   and an expansion in the past year.   tion services for patients once this is
            the owners of Grand  Valley Animal     Grand Valley Animal Clinic stopped   Because they believe in supporting   up and running.
            Clinic are monitoring the develop-  performing this procedure several years   local, the owners have focused on using            » Continued on Page 16]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[We Can Print Your Photos!



                                                                                             Order Online:

                                                                              lab@brandonphoto.com








                   Passports                                             Frames                         iPhone



                            &                      Photo                        &                       App &                       Film

                     Portraits                     Gifts                 Albums                        Online               Developing



                                                                                                   Ordering
                                                                                                   Ordering









                                NOW’S THE TIME TO BOOK YOUR HOLIDAY PORTRAIT SITTING!

                                              NOW TAKING ORDERS FOR CUSTOM GIFT GIVING ITEMS:

                                 • Calendars • Photo Books • Personalized Cards • Aluminum & Acrylic Panels
                                                    • Wood Block Photos • Mugs • Coasters & More!

















                 848–18  Street • 204.727.3263 • www.brandonphoto.com
                                  th]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[16                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019






































                                                                                                LEFT: Grand Valley Animal Clinic is constructing new additions to their building to
           Something for Everyone!                                                              improve services.  ABOVE: A vet at Grand Valley Animal Clinic vaccinates a pair of playful
                                          Something for Everyone!
                                                                                                kittens.
            » Continued from Page 14            winter weight!                       for adding comfort to their patients.  forms of cancer with chemotherapy, and
                                  Something for Everyone!                              Great advances in cancer care for our  the clinic will now have a dedicate space
                                                   The addition of more kennel space
              This service will also be available for  will allow the clinic to have separate  furry friends in the past few years means  for performing this.
            those pets needing to lose a bit of extra  kennel rooms for dogs and cats, essential  that it is now possible to treat different   » Continued on Page 17



                                                                                       Something for Everyone!



                                                                                                                 Weekly Entertainment & Daily Specials
                                                                                Something for Everyone!
 services                                                                              Weekly Entertainment & Daily Specials
 -Full auto service and repair                                                            Weekly Entertainment & Daily Specials
 -Glass repair and windshield replacement                                                 For every Wheat Kings home game get
                thank you to our customers                                                                       Great Selection
 -remote starters                                                                       50% OFF our Nachos between 5:30 - 7 PM
 -air conditioning
 -tires and wheel alignments                                                           Great Selection
 -used car sales


                                                                                          Great Selection
 204-726-1333                                                                          Gondola Pizza
 superiorautobrandon.com                                                                                        of Coolers & Cold Beverages in the
                                                                                                              Keystone Beer Store’s Well-Lit Location                         Weekly Entertainment & Daily Specials
                                                                                                                 Gondola Pizza


                                                                                          Gondola Pizza


                                                                                           Check out our new specials for delivery,
                                                                                            pick-up or dine-in at George’s Lounge                                              Weekly Entertainment & Daily Specials
                                                                                                                                                                              Great Selection
                                                                                            Order online at dashdelivers.ca



                                                                                                                  1050 - 18th Street
                                                                                                              across from the Keystone Centre
                                                                                                                   204-728-6620           204-727-2070
                                                                                                              www.keystonemotorinn.ca
                                                                                                                                                                               Great Selection
                           204-726-1333       superiorautobrandon.com                                             Please drink responsibly.                                   Gondola Pizza







                                                                                                                                                                               Gondola Pizza]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2019 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           17

            » Continued from Page 16
              The new expansion will
            also add a dedicated room
            for performing abdominal
            and heart ultrasounds in a
            quiet and peaceful setting.
            Additional exam rooms
            and a brand new receiving
            area is another feature of
            the expansion.
              The clinic is also adding
            a new online store, which
            will enable clients to shop
            for trusted, high-quality
            veterinary  products  from
            the comfort of their home,
            as well as collars,leashes,
            pet beds, treats, etc.
              While this is a lot of
            change, the clinic would
            like  to  assure  their  cli-
            ents that they will con-
            tinue to provide the same
            high-quality patient  care
            that they have become
            known for at Grand Valley
            Animal Clinic.




                 Grand Valley Animal Clinic’s
                    team of veterinarians.


















                                                                                                     We would like to welcome

                                                                                                          Michelle Jacobson &

                                                                                                        Amy Gies to our team.


                                                                                                      We would love to design


                                                                                                      cabinetry for your space!


                                                                                                            Come see us for a

                                                                                                   complimentary consultation.]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[18                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019

            » myITsource



            Offering your








            best choice







            for business








            IT support











              If you’re running a business that only re- America or even Europe if I wanted to,”
            acts to computer problems after they hap- Arndt said, adding that there is no business
            pen, you need to look into myITsource.  in Brandon that myITsource could not han-
              Founded in 1998, the Brandon-based  dle IT support for.
            company can help you with your IT prob-  Is it raining? Is it snowing? Are the roads
            lems, but they also aim to solve problems  terrible? That won’t stop myITsource from
            before they happen with their world-class  remotely solving your tech problems.
            service.                               “What it does is it minimizes down-
              By signing up for their full managed ser- time and doesn’t knock anybody out of
            vices, you can make sure that your compa- their chairs anymore,” Arndt said.  When
            ny’s technology needs are taken care of by  a technician is working on a problem, your
            western Manitoba’s largest IT support com- employee will likely still be able to do some
            pany.                               work on their computer.
              They can handle any IT needs for small   In the unlikely event that a problem
            and medium-sized businesses anywhere  needs to be solved in person, myITsource
            in western Manitoba. They cover an area as  can either dispatch a truck or contact a more
            far north as Dauphin and as far south as the  local technician and arm them with the in-
            U.S. border. They even have some customers  formation they need to solve your problem.
            in eastern Saskatchewan.               The company has been contracted to do
              Founder and owner Frank Arndt likens  repair and installation work for companies  myITsource offers complete managed IT service for small and medium businesses of any kind. (Robert Lovatt/
            myITsource’s full managed services to an  like Dell and BellMTS, so you know that  Keywest Photo image by design inc.)
            all-inclusive resort.               they know their stuff.
              “Once you pay your fee, that includes   Arndt also takes pride in being more ef- give businesses advice on what kind of hard- services, if your computers get hit with ran-
            your Office 365 subscription ... that also  ficient and useful to businesses than many  ware works best for them. Because of their  somware they can quickly restore from a re-
            includes an antivirus program and that in- in-house IT specialists. If a business’s single  21 years of experience, they know what kind  cent backup so you can keep your data and
            cludes our service desk remotely monitoring  IT person takes a two-week holiday, no one  of computers work best for all sorts of dif- minimize the amount of time your employ-
            your entire IT environment,” Arndt said.   is there to repair problems.   ferent situations.                 ees are prevented from working.
              “We see what’s going on a lot of times   If a member of the myITsource goes on   A recent problem for some companies   That is the difference between being
            before you even know what’s wrong with  vacation, there are still many other qualified  has been ransomware — malware that takes  reactive and proactive. By being reactive to
            your computer or your network,” he added.  technicians available to solve problems.  over your computer and keeps you from ac- IT problems, you can have your data taken
            “In a lot of cases, we can just remotely access   Another advantage of the remote service  cessing your files unless you pay a ransom.  from you forever with no solution.
            any of your computers or your network and  is that myITsource technicians can access   If your computer has been hit by ran-  By being proactive, myITsource sets up a
            repair what’s wrong.”               your network from anywhere, not just at the  somware, Arndt said that the only option  safety net so that any potential problems are
              That’s right, for most problems you don’t  home office in downtown Brandon.  is really to pay the ransom and hope the  only minor inconveniences.
            have to wait for a truck to be dispatched.   Their proactive approach to IT is com- hacker frees your data. Sometimes you get   To start being proactive and to sign up
            Most problems can be solved remotely by  bined with regular monthly reports on your  lucky and they honour the deal, sometimes  your business for complete managed IT ser-
            the 14-person myITsource business team.  network so you know everything that’s go- nothing happens at all and your data is gone  vices, contact myITsource at 204-728-1040
              “If I can solve problems remotely, then I  ing on.                     forever.                            or toll-free at 1-866-928-1040. You can also
            can have customers all over Canada, North   Additionally, myITsource is available to   However, with myITsource’s managed  email them at sales@myitsource.ca.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[LOCALLY OWNED!




                                And expanding to serve you better.

                                     Renovations to be completed
                                           early in the newyear.



























                            204-728-0033                                                                                204-483-2193

                        304 Pacific Avenue                                                                       39 Preston Street North
                             Brandon, MB                                                                                  Souris, MB



                                                                       www.gvac.ca]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[20                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019

            » The Skin and Vein Centre



            Clinic has new






            name, operates







            in same vein







              There’s plenty of change afoot at Dr.  ticular veins,” Dr. Barb said. “All we’ve been
            Barb Kelleher’s clinic.             able to offer for a number of years is mul-
              First of all, the name is changing to The  tiple injections for all those veins and we
            Skin and Vein Centre.               get good results. But that involves needles
              “The old name  was too long!” she ex- and not everyone tolerates so many needles.
            plained.                            The cooled 1064 Nd:YAG can treat red or
              Second, she has bought some new equip- blue spider veins up to three millimetres in
            ment.                               diameter, superficial to deep. Ten years ago,
              Third, the advanced treatments she’ll be  we couldn’t do blue veins with laser and the
            able to offer take less time, are usually less  treatments hurt like heck. With the cooled
            painful and less invasive.          head, it’s relatively comfortable.
              And the good doctor is extremely excited   “I’m really thrilled about that because I
            about all of it.                    think a lot of people shy away from treating
              “It complements what  we already do,  small veins because they’re needle phobic.”
            but does even more,” Dr. Barb said of the   Dr. Barb is positively jazzed about her
            new additions to her practice.  “The new  new acquisitions. You can tell by the smile
            machine is called the Alma Harmony XL  on her face and the enthusiasm in her voice
            Pro, a multi-platform device, and it is won- as she discusses the benefits of the addition-
            derful! The DYE:VL head combines pulsed  al services she’s now able to offer her clients.
            dye laser with Intense Pulsed Light (IPL)  But that’s what’s NOT new. The doctor has
            and will replace my old IPL, which was  been enthused about providing the best and
            very effective, but slow and uncomfortable.  most advanced care to her patients since she
            DYE:VL will allow us to treat more vascu- opened her practice several years ago.
            lar and pigmented lesions. For example, I   She’s  passionate  about  making  people
            could never treat port wine stains or large  feel better about themselves. She believes if
            hemangiomas and now I can.”         we look good, we feel good. Or if we think
              And her Harmony DYE-VL can  help  we look better after a procedure, we feel
            those who are troubled by red clusters of  better about ourselves, which is the whole
            veins that have previously been difficult to  point. And all that positive energy goes a   Dr. Barb Kellher showcases her clinic’s Pixel Co2 femilyft machine. (Chelsea Kemp/The Brandon Sun)
            treat.                              long way.
              “Not everybody has just spider veins,”   “Then there’s skin tightening with the   But as usual, the doctor is frank and  remove raised lesions, especially on the
            she said. “Sometimes they have redness —  ClearLift head for fine lines and wrinkles,”  honest about what people should and  face such as a mole you dislike but don’t
            these red clusters — we call it matting. And  Dr. Barb enthused. “And that’s pretty im- shouldn’t expect.    want to cut it out because of the scar.
            you can’t really get a needle into them and  pressive.  You can hardly feel it because it   “It’s super impressive,” she said. “But  The  CO2  laser  vaporizes  it  and  leaves
            IPL is quite painful. Now we can use the  creates microscopic holes under the skin by- all the colours don’t respond equally as  a little black mark, and then when that
            DYE-VL and, in a few treatments that are  passing the outer layer. We do the treatment  well. The red, dark blue and black tat- falls off after a few days, you just have
            really quick, get it done. Practically pain- and the patient thinks it won’t work because  toos respond really well. The tough ones  new pink skin underneath with minimal
            free with a cooled head and Alma’s propri- it  doesn’t  hurt.  Come  over  at  lunchtime  are the greens, yellows and the vibrant  if any scarring.
            etary IN-Motion technology, there is no  and rejuvenate your neck. I’m really excited  blues.”                  “I also offer Alma Femilift vaginal
            need for topical freezing and treatments are  about it. It also will work on stretch marks   And  while  cosmetic  procedures  are  laser treatments, which take care of vag-
            faster, and comfortable.”           and scars and it is safe for all skin types.”   frequently the focus, Dr. Barb’s other la- inal dryness, urinary stress incontinence,
              While many patients have seen Dr. Barb   Dr. Barb is also delighted about some- sers can address additional issues as well. vaginal laxity, and discomfort with inter-
            over the years for sclerotherapy, which is in- thing that’s new to her practice — tattoo   “The Alma Soprano Ice Platinum  course. It’s a virtually painless treatment
            jecting a solution into spider veins on the  removal with the Q-switched Nd:YAG  is the most advanced laser hair remov- that helps with all those problems.”
            surface of the legs to make the veins disap- treatment head.             al system and is safe for all skin types,”   So lots of new options and improved
            pear, her new 1064 Nd:YAG laser head will   “We’re fairly excited about that,” she said.  she said.  “The Alma Pixel CO2 laser  techniques are available at  The Skin
            treat those visible veins and others without  “Because the longer you leave it (between  does skin resurfacing for rough, irregu- and  Vein Centre. Call 204-727-1920
            using needles, and works for all skin colours.  treatments), the better the results. You do a  lar, wrinkled, pigmented, or scarred skin  to book a consultation or appointment,
              “The Nd:YAG does the small superficial  treatment and you wait three months before  on the face, so you can get a whole new  email info@laserskinvein.com or check
            spider veins as well as the deeper bluish re- you do the next.”          top layer of skin. It can also be used to  out the website — laserskinvein.com.]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[myITsource offers world class IT Support for your Business






                                  Trust Western Manitoba’s largest IT Support Company for all

                                 your Hardware, Network, Printer, Security & Backup Solutions






                                                   Full managed Services for your business
                                         Your Most Trusted IT Support Specialists since 1998

















































                                              Sales@myITsource.ca    |    www.myITsource.com]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[22                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019










































            » Princess Dental


            Changing people’s lives one smile at a time






              Princess Dental’s goal is to provide an   “We treat everybody like family,” said   One unique offering at Princess Dental  they waited so long to give it a try.
            exceptional quality of service and always  Jerilyn  Miscavish,  Princess  Dental’s  of- is intravenous sedation for restorative den-  Princess Dental is changing lives for pa-
            face life with a smile.             fice manager and treatment co-ordinator.  tal treatment.                 tients who have avoided the dentist due to
              Everything they do goes toward show- “That’s  one  of  the  things  that  makes  us   Sedation dentistry helps ease the stress  fears and anxiety one smile at a time.
            ing that the  business’s utmost  priority is  special.”                  associated with treatment.             Princess Dental gives back to the com-
            their patients.                        Part of the way they maintain the high-  “We see a lot of fears every day,” Miscav- munity by being the official dentist for the
              Owners Dr. Geoff and Adele McIntosh  est level of care is by offering world-class  ish said. “Some people are afraid of sounds,  Brandon Wheat Kings.
            took over the business in 2013 and have ex- training to their employees.    some people are afraid of injections, some   That’s right, when a Wheat Kings game
            panded the business from having a single   Sending them to industry leading con- people can’t walk through the door.”  is on at Westoba Place, the team at Princess
            dentist with two hygienists to having four  ferences and courses across North America   Instead of avoiding dental work because  Dental is on call in case of a dental emer-
            full-time dentists with a staff of 18.  has allowed everyone to stay up to date with  of anxiety, patients can use this alternative  gency.
              Rounding out the dentistry team are Dr.  the latest developments in oral health.    solution to make sure that they receive the   Players wear mouthguards for a reason,
            Jessica Carswell, Dr. Jill Gudmandson and   Many of these trips are done as a team  level of oral health they desire.  but when something goes wrong, one of
            Dr. Dustin Wurm.                    to ensure everyone at Princess Dental have   Where  some  practices  offer  sedation  Princess Dental’s dentists is there to help.
              Their treatments range from simple fill- a unified approach to patient care.  via inhalation or oral medication, Princess   Whether it’s a member of the  Wheat
            ings to complete smile makeovers, with the   Technology has also changed drastically  Dental  offers  IV sedation  in addition to  Kings, someone needing a filling or some-
            team  at  Princess  Dental  working  closely  over the past decade in dentistry.  those methods.             one getting sedation dentistry, everyone is
            with each patient to plan their comprehen-  Princess Dental has striven to stay cur-  They say that the IV sedation is a con- treated like family at Princess Dental.
            sive dental care.                   rent with 3D imaging (CT machine) to  scious  sedation  where  the  patient  can  re-  To become a patient or inquire about
              By regularly scheduling checkups, both  allow safe placement of dental implants, in- spond to  questions from the dentist, but  services, please visit their location at 1202
            patients and staff at Princess Dental can  traoral scanners to eliminate messy impres- typically don’t even remember their dental  Princess Ave. in person or give them a call
            be proactive, preventing or mitigating oral  sion materials, as well as intraoral cameras  visit.            at 204-717-0249. Patients outside of Bran-
            health issues before they become a major  to allow our patients to see exactly what   According to Miscavish, many people  don can call toll free at 1-866-563-1627 or
            problem.                            they are seeing in their mouths.     who try sedation dentistry wonder why  visit the website at princessdental.com]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Landscaping
                                                                                                                             Take your outdoor living experience to a
                                                                                                                            higher level with professional landscaping
                                                                                                                              design and installation services from
                                                                                                                           Alternative Landscaping has always been our
                                                                                                                            core business, locally owned and operated
                                                                                                                              since1998. Over 20 years experience
                                                                                                                             creating, and construction of innovative
                                                                                                                                       landscaping.

               Bringing Life to Your Landscape Since 1998


                Family-run and locally-owned,
                Alternative Landscaping Ltd. has
                grown to become a household name                                                                                       Excavation
                in landscaping and the Manitoba                                                                               Starting with site clearing, demolition,
                green industry throughout Westman.                                                                              site/lot preparation, digging for
                The business was opened in 1998 by                                                                           basements and pools, to Complete Sewer
                Chris and Karin Griffin with the goal                                                                        and water projects, grading, compacting,
                                                                                                                             and back-filling supply and installation of
                of providing superior workmanship by                                                                         all aggregate required for civil projects.
                people who care. It’s a philosophy that
                has served the business well over the
                past 21 years.
                Since the beginning, Alternative
                Landscaping has designed, built and
                maintained award winning residential
                and commercial projects throughout                                                                           Greenhouse & Nursery Westman’s
                Brandon and the Westman                                                                                           Gardening Destination
                area, stretching all the way into   line of professional retail landscape   34th Street and Patricia Avenue,          GET INSPIRED
                                                                                                                               Alternative Choice Garden Centre
                Saskatchewan.                      products in 2008 selling landscaping   Alternative Excavation and           is Western Manitoba’s largest one-
                In 2007, the operation expanded    hardscape and softscaping products   Alternative Choice Garden Centre      stop destination for unique gardening
                services to Clear Lake and all     bulk to contractors and DIY clients,   were launched to accommodate the     gifts, plants, trees and shrubs, and
                surrounding communities within three  the concept of bringing supplies and   growing needs of Alternative clients,   landscaping products and materials.
                hours of Brandon. It wasn’t long after   expertise under one roof is what   and offer Westman customers
                the company extended geographically   spurred the vision for the current   additional green industry products
                that they also grew and enhanced   operation and business model.       and services .
                their menu of product and services.  Just five years later in 2013 with an   In 2016, Opportunity to expand to
                The company introduced a complete   expansion to a brand new facility at   Brandon’s North hill arose and a
                                                                                       second retail location was leased ,
                                                                                       giving the company the opportunity   Yard Care, Fertilizer & Snow Clearing
                                                                                       to expand their growing needs         Worry free Lawn & garden maintenance
                                                                                                                                    YEAR-ROUND CARE
                                                                                       and operation while increasing the   Don’t spend your weekends maintaining your
                                                                                       retail presence and service in retail   yard and garden. Let the professionals make
                                                                                       gardening.                            your home the envy of your neighbours.
                                                                                       The most recent addition of services
                                                                                       to the company was in 2017 when
                                                                                       Heartland Fence, Deck & Rail was
                                                                                       acquired, further expanding the
                                                                                       company’s complimentary services to
                                                                                       the green industry.                         Fence, Deck & Rail
                                                                                       Today, Alternative Landscaping        Your no maintenance specialists have
                                                                                       continues to flourish, with a second   been serving Brandon and area since
                                                                                       generation of the Griffin family now   2003 and provides a full line of PVC
                                                                                       working in the business.              Fence, ornamental iron, PVC Decking,
                                                                                                                              aluminum railing, and their newest
                                                                                                                              product line, Duradek vinyl decking.
                2019 Award winning property from the Canadian National Landscape Association

                                       34th and Patricia Avenue                               alternativelandscapingltd.com
                Sales: 204-727-7289 • Fax: 204-727-7531 • Toll Free 1-866-727-7289          info@alternativelandscapingltd.com]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[24                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019
            » Super Thrift


            Thrift shop making positive impact







              It’s a store that’s doing well and doing                                                                   quired component for successful completion
            good at the same time.                                                                                       of their rehabilitation.
              Super Thrift at 127 Seventh St. has been                                                                      “The women’s home in Brandon — part
            in business for just over a year now, and has                                                                of the program is teaching the women work-
            enjoyed tremendous support from the com-                                                                     ing skills and coping skills so they can be
            munity. Folks are donating items for sale                                                                    employable after the (year-long) program,”
            and are shopping at the store. And by so                                                                     McKenzie said. “They could find farm jobs
            doing, they’re helping former addicts gain                                                                   because the home is sort of in the country,
            work experience and get their lives back on                                                                  but most of the girls came from the city.”
            track.                                                                                                          That meant they had no knowledge of
              Super Thrift was opened and is operated                                                                    or experience in what would be required of
            by Chris and Kim Lowes, a husband-and-                                                                       them in agricultural settings. So Kim sug-
            wife team who run the Adult and  Teen                                                                        gested they try opening a Super Thrift in
            Challenge Centre in Brandon, a ministry                                                                      Brandon. And as mentioned, it has been a
            that helps people cope with life-controlling                                                                 rousing  success.  In  addition  to  McKenzie,
            addictions. Approximately 16 kilometres                                                                      co-manager Aaron Murray and a handful of
            out of Brandon, they built a residence that                                                                  paid staff, the women from the residence all
            can accommodate 16 women from all walks                                                                      work in the store for no remuneration. But
            of life who are looking to shake their ad-                                                                   what they gain are social skills and employ-
            dictions, mostly to drugs and alcohol, but  Store manager Terrence McKenzie and development officer Aaron Murray stand between rows of clothing in   ability skills they can hopefully parlay into
            also to food, gambling and video games, and  the Adult & Teen Challenge Super Thrift at 127 Seventh St. in Brandon. (Photos by Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)  jobs when they graduate from the centre.
            move on to a future full of possibilities.                                                                      “It’s work experience, it’s training and
              And Super  Thrift store manager  Ter-  “It all stays within Manitoba and most  Bay, Ont., and Winkler. McKenzie said the  it kind of allows them to feel good about
            rence McKenzie said once expenses are  of it goes to the women’s home,” McKenzie  Loweses decided to open the Brandon shop  themselves because they are contributing to
            paid, all other monies go to the women’s  said.                          because they were having difficulty finding  their programs,” McKenzie said.
            residence and Adult and Teen Challenge.   There are Super Thrift stores in Thunder  jobs for their clients, and working is a re-   » Continued on Page 25
                                                                                       The Wood That Made
                                                                                       The Wood That Made
                                                                                                       Us Famous
                                                                                                       Us Famous



















                                              .










              PLUS, our gift to you! Get a free trunk organizer **                                    S i n c e   1 9 6 9
              for giving the gift of membership ($30 value).
                                                                                      1840 – 18  STREET NORTH, BRANDON • 204-728-4243
                                                                                                   TH
              Buy a CAA Gift Membership today!                                        Fax: 204-727-2619 • Toll-Free: 1-800-224-7506 • www.windsorplywood.com
              204-571-4100 • 305 18th St. North, Brandon                              sales@windsorplywood.net
              www.caamanitoba.com                                                     Store Hours: Mon. – Fri. 8:00 am – 5:30 pm; Sat. 8:00 am – 5:00 pm
              *Based on research results conducted by an external research company commissioned by CAA.**Valid on new Primary Gift Memberships only. (Excludes A La Carte and Associate Memberships,   Some items may be cash & carry and we reserve the right to limit quantities. All items may not
              and renewals.) While supplies last. Items inside trunk organizer not included. © 2019 CAA Club Group. All rights reserved. Serving Members in Southern and Central Ontario and Manitoba. ®   be exactly as illustrated.
              CAA trademarks are owned by, and use is authorized by, the Canadian Automobile Association.]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2019 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           25

            » Continued from Page 24           shops in town, McKenzie said, with jeans
                                               priced from $5 to $13, for example.
              Super Thrift is chock full of articles   “We have standardized pricing across
            that are acquired almost exclusively by  all of our Super Thrift stores,” he said.
            donation. While they have some brand-  “We think it’s really fair and accurate.
            new furniture and mattresses — beds are  Plus we have sales every day.”
            among their most popular items, so they   Open from 9:30 a.m. to 6 p.m. Mon-
            buy them from a supplier in Winnipeg  day to Saturday, Super Thrift accepts all
            just so they can provide that service to  forms of payment except cheques, McK-
            their customers — McKenzie said “99.99  enzie said. Even American Express and
            per cent” of what they have for sale is do-  Apple  Pay  can  be  used  for  purchases.
            nated.                             And if people would like to volunteer to
              Clothes are the main seller, and about  work in the store, their assistance would
            60 per cent of the goods for sale on the  be welcomed with open arms.
            main floor are articles of clothing. The   But back to the reason for the Super
            basement contains furniture, but they  Thrift’s existence in the first place. McK-
            also offer housewares, sporting goods,  enzie was surprisingly forthcoming and
            home improvement and seasonal items,  offered his and Murray’s life histories as
            toys and various other articles rounding  a reason why the store is so important.
            out their selection.               Both men are gainfully employed, help-
              “We try to have something for every-  ing others, and paying it forward. They’re
            one,” McKenzie said.               living proof that the Adult and  Teen
              So why are people so generous? McK-  Challenge program works.
            enzie thinks the answer is two-fold.    “Aaron and I manage the thrift store,”
              “A lot is donated because people have  he said. “But we’re not business tycoons.
            so much stuff,” McKenzie said frankly.  Both of us are graduates of the  Teen
            “So a part of it is convenience, but also  Challenge  program. Thirteen years  ago
            people do believe in the cause.  We do  in B.C., I was an addict. Six years ago,
            partner with the John Howard Society,  Aaron, who’s from Binscarth, was an ad-
            Seventh Street Access and Samaritan  dict. So we’ve been there and done that,
            House. If people who need help get a  and we’re giving back. And we’re hoping
            voucher from (one of those entities), we  that (Super Thrift) is something that’ll
            can give them stuff for free.”     benefit, or has become beneficial to, the   Development officer Aaron Murray and store manager Terrence McKenzie stand outside of Adult & Teen Challenge
              Pricing is competitive with similar  community.”                   Super Thrift at 127 Seventh St. in Brandon.]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[26                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019
























































            Lifestyle director Jillian Garbutt and executive director Claudia Nohr sit in Victoria Landing Retirement Residence’s second floor theatre, where residents can watch television programming and play recreational games.
            (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)
            » Victoria Landing Retirement Residence

            Community about aging in place









              Everyone experiences the natural pro-  Care is committed to ensuring the highest  and allow them to age in place graceful-  including fitness centre, games room,
            cess of aging in different ways. Some folks  quality of life for our residents. Designed  ly,” Nohr said. “We have created a secure  salon, a theatre and even private dining
            might remain active and independent, yet  to enhance daily enjoyment and well-be-  living area that exceeds expectations for  room for special family celebrations. Per-
            over time, they might find that they could  ing on a continuous basis, the exclusive  support. Whether helping new residents  haps best of all, couples with different care
            benefit from assisted living while remain-  QOLA program provides the All Seniors  adjust, assisting with personal grooming  needs can remain together in an environ-
            ing still very active in their community.  Care team with the ability to learn about  or going for a walk, staff members are  ment that allows them to age with grace.
            Others might find themselves needing  resident’s specific needs and individual  committed to providing a supportive fam-  “Victoria  Landing is  a safe, beauti-
            greater assistance within a secure living  preferences.                  ily environment.”                    ful neighbourhood that offers seniors
            space, particularly if their health or mem-  Prior to moving in each resident is   Adding to the  ease, dedicated  staff  gracious living while providing peace of
            ory is declining.                   consulted on dietary wishes, medical  members take care of light housekeeping  mind for families,” Nohr said. “We’ve seen
              “We are an Aging-In-Place commu-  needs, recreational, and physical activity  duties, provide emergency response and  many changes over the past year — new
            nity,” said Claudia Nohr the Executive  preferences. After all the information is  organize fun activities, both on site and  faces, new families and new interests. We
            Director of  Brandon’s  Victoria  Landing  consolidated a personal profile is creat-  off.                    continue to strive to stay current in pro-
            Retirement Residence.  “We supply our  ed and specific programming developed.   “Our  person-centred philosophy  al-  viding our residents with the best service
            residents with the daily support they need  Families can feel assured that their loved  lows us to identify each resident’s unique  and care.”
            to continue an active, healthy, indepen-  one’s needs are met daily in a holistic ap-  attributes, values and history,” Nohr said,   For  more  information,  call  204-271-
            dent lifestyle.”                    proach including mind, body, and soul.  “enabling us to create individualized lev-  6000 or drop by for coffee and a visit at 10
              Age-in-Place living is the philosophy   “Victoria Landing is all about taking  els of programming that are flexible to  Victoria Ave. E. (right beside the Bran-
            that allows residents to remain at this  care of seniors and providing them with a  changing health needs.”   don Regional Health Centre). Details are
            lovely residence throughout the years as  good quality of life in a setting that’s been   Enhancing the experience, residents  also posted on the All Seniors Care web-
            needs change.  The team at All Seniors  designed to adapt to their changing needs  can take advantage of on-site amenities,  site at allseniorscare.com.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[28                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019
            » Westman Communications Group

            Services connect communities








              It  might not  occur to  people living                                                                     BellMTS,” said Bud Keys, director of West-
            in Brandon, but not everyone in the West-                                                                    man Business services at Westman Commu-
            man region has the same access to telecom-                                                                   nications Group.
            munications services.                                                                                           WCG  offers  at  least  150  megabits  per
              Some rural communities still have old co-                                                                  second download speeds to their fibre-con-
            axial lines that aren’t set up for fast internet                                                             nected communities. In several communities
            speeds, feature-laden home phone service or                                                                  where WCG and BellMTS compete, Bell-
            access to a full variety of cable channels.                                                                  MTS offers as limited as 5 megabits per sec-
              That’s why  Westman Communications                                                                         ond.
            Group (WCG) is working to bring fibre-op-                                                                       When these four new communities are
            tic service to previously underserved commu-                                                                 brought into the WCG family, they will get
            nities.                                                                                                      fibre-optic service right to their door, just like
              Over the next few months,  WCG will                                                                        in Brandon. That means they’ll have access
            be bringing service to Rapid City, Inglis,                                                                   to speeds faster than previously mentioned.
            Oak River, and Minto for the first time.                                                                        There aren’t appropriate telecommunica-
              Expansion to those last three communi-                                                                     tions infrastructure in those places currently,
            ties represents the furthest east  WCG has                                                                   so WCG is making it available via new con-
            ever serviced. When they are connected to                                                                    struction directly to the residents and busi-
            WCG’s fibre-optic network, it will mean                                                                      nesses in these communities.
            that more than 40 communities are serviced   Westman Communications Group is expanding fibre service into seven new Westman communities.   For the first time, some of these commu-
            by the company.                     (Colin Slark/The Brandon Sun)                                            nities will get the option to choose between
              This means that customers, whether  viced by WCG don’t have fibre-optic service   Before fibre-optic, WCG provided service  different service providers. They can compare
            they’re individuals or businesses, will have  right to their home, connecting WCG’s fi- to smaller communities via satellite, which is  what they’ve always had with the new WCG
            access to the same reliable service that 35  bre-optic network to previously existing co- not as fast.       service options and see what they prefer.
            Westman communities already enjoy.  axial infrastructure has brought a noticeable   “In many of these cases, we’re capable of
              While customers outside Brandon ser- improvement.                      being upwards of 20-30 times faster than                  » Continued on Page 29]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2019 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           29

            » Continued from Page 28
              As  everything  is  connected to  WCG’s  fibre-optic  LEECH PRINTING

            network, it means that all customers in communities
            serviced by WCG are offered the same services at the
            same prices that people in Brandon receive.
              The same television channel lineup, same phone ser-
            vice and same Internet capabilities.
              “They’re extremely enthusiastic when we arrive,”
            Keys said. He added that a lot of businesses are depen-
            dent on the Internet these days and it is difficult to grow
            a business without access to reliable high-speed Internet.
              Complete managed phone service can also be ar-
            ranged, with WCG taking care of everything.
              More than 90 per cent of businesses in communities
            WCG is moving in to sign up in advance for their ser-
            vices, according to Keys.
              When you sign up, a dedicated service team is avail-
            able 365 days a year to help you with your business ser-
            vice needs.
              Keys, a former employee of both Bell and MTS at
            different times, said that his company differentiates it-
            self from its bigger competition through customer ser-
            vice.
              “We like to think that we work for the customers,”
            Keys said. While many companies say that, WCG is a
            co-op, meaning that customers also have a stake in own-
            ership. That’s rare for a company in this industry.
              WCG isn’t beholden to shareholders in Toronto or
            Montreal, they report to people right here in Westman.
              If your community has WCG service or will be get-
            ting it soon, you can sign up online or call 204-725-
            4300. Callers outside Brandon can call toll-free at  Third-generation Leech Printing owner Michael Leech is seen with the fourth generation to pursue careers with the company, including daughters
            1-800-665-3337.                              Meredyth, left, and Gillian, right. (File)









              Sensus Chartered Professional Accountants Ltd. has grown and undergone many changes over the past 40 years. Since its beginning in 1979, our Firm has opened
              new locations, amalgamated with other Firms, changed our name and expanded our services to become the strong Firm we are today.

                                                        Today we are excited to announce another
                                                        milestone in our history.
                                                        Audra Nychuk, CPA, CA and Harold Reid, CPA, CA would like to
                                                        welcome their NEW PARTNERS to the Firm.
                                                        Their dedication and hard work, along with their commitment to excellence, has allowed
                                                        them to progress to this next step in their careers. Each of these new partners brings a
                                                        unique set of experiences, perspectives and ideas to help shape our Firm for the future.
               Audra Nychuk, CPA, CA  Harold Reid, CPA, CA  Please join us in congratulating Tiffany, Ian, Brett, and Kyle on this accomplishment.  Tiffany Bodnariuk, CPA, CA  Ian McMullan, CPA, CA
                  We would like to thank our clientele for their patronage over the past 40 years who have trusted us and allowed
                            us to provide our professional services. We attribute our success to all of our clients.

              We will continue to provide the following services to our clients in the Westman area and eastern Saskatchewan. These services include:
               • Personal tax planning & preparation  • Bookkeeping services      • Auditing of not-for-profit organizations
               • Municipal auditing          • Notice to reader & review engagement preparation  • Farm and business succession planning
               • Payroll services            • Estate tax planning                • Corporate tax planning & preparation
               • Incorporating your farm or business  • Auditing of public sector boards  • Retirement & financial planning
                                                                                                                    Brett Fordyce, CPA, CGA  Kyle Paul, CPA, CA
                       RUSSELL, MB               SHOAL LAKE, MB               BRANDON, MB                  VIRDEN, MB                 YORKTON, SK
                      209 Main Street N           426 Station Road            929 – 24th Street         275 Nelson Street W         15 – 1st Avenue N
                        204-773-2106               204-759-2240                204-727-5577                204-748-3135               306-782-4320
                       Visit our website www.sensuscpa.ca • Please contact any of our locations for a consultation or email us at sensusrsl@sensuscpa.ca]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[HELPING LOCAL BUSINESS




                                               GROW SINCE 1882












                                       To see how we can help you grow, call 204-571-7424]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[32                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019





















































            Karin and Chris Griffin stand in the greenhouse of Alternative Landscaping Ltd. (Chelsea Kemp/The Brandon Sun)
            » Alternative Landscaping

            Changing people’s lives












              It’s not just about adding features to  said. “And it generally makes them better.” bigger earthmoving landscaping projects,”  ada-wide level, that’s not their motivation
            yards or improving properties.         The couple has been in business almost  Chris said. “They’re the ones who’re mov- for what they do.
              It’s about changing people’s lives.  22 years, beginning as Alternative Land- ing all the material and putting it into place.   “We have been very fortunate to have
              So said co-owner Chris Griffin about  scaping and then adding more and more  And  then  there’s  the  latest  purchase  that  won a lot of awards over the years, which
            his and his wife Karin’s business, referred  elements as the business grew.  They of- we didn’t actually create from the ground  is nice, but we don’t do it to win awards,”
            to affectionately nowadays as simply ‘Alter- fer designing, building and installation of  up, which was Heartland Fence, Deck &  Chris said. “It’s extremely humbling when
            native.’                            residential and commercial landscaping,  Rail, so it’s decking, railing, fencing” and  things like this happen. And this was a real
              Although they do design and build  as well as the Alternative Choice Garden  all the specialized carpentry projects that  surprise.”
            landscaping, yard care, excavation, deck- Centre, which  not  only supplies  bedding  support the total landscape projects.  But Chris was quick to say that it’s not
            ing, building and growing plus a whole lot  plants and nursery stock for all your gar-  Just this year, Alternative won Land- he and Karin who are responsible for the
            more, their focus from the ground up is all  dening needs, but also offers bulk land- scape Manitoba’s provincial award for best  nationwide recognition.  They and their
            about people: those clients who hire them,  scape materials and block for the DIYs and  unique and innovative design for their work  teams of industry professionals work as a
            those who work with them and those who  for contractors. Then there’s their mainte- on Laurel and Charlie Clark’s property  close-knit team to achieve the best results.
            visit the on-site greenhouse and retail store. nance department, Alternative Total Yard  southeast of Brandon. But unbeknownst to   “It’s about our family of people and
              Their motto —  “Superior workman- Care, which offers year-round specialized  the Griffins, Landscape Manitoba entered  great  people  within  the  organization,”
            ship by people who care” — guides their  yard care maintenance services offering  the  photos  and  materials  from  the  Clark  Chris said. “And it’s not just the ones who
            every move and is in play on every project,  monthly contracts for both residential and  project to the Canadian National Land- are here today, but the ones who have been
            whether it’s a small residential revamping  commercial clients.          scape Association national competition.  here before.  We really believe that most
            or a large commercial endeavour.       “And then we have Alternative Excava- And Alternative became the first company  of the things that have allowed us to have
              “I think that’s the story that doesn’t get  tion, which looks after our aggregate, soils  in  Manitoba to  win a national landscap- some successes has been all because of
            told enough — we’re in an industry that  landscape materials trucking logistics — it  ing award.  While they were thrilled to  those individuals.
            absolutely changes people’s lives,” Chris  also does civil construction and handles our  have their work acknowledged on a Can-    » Continued on Page 33]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2019 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           33
            » Continued from Page 32            And execute on that decision.”       deserves to a certain degree,” Chris said.  something back to Mother Earth. We’re
                                                   As mentioned, the company has ex- “Because as I said before, it’s changing  giving back to what the earth has given
              “Our team  came up  with  ‘Superior  panded in terms of scope and acquisitions  people’s lives.            to us.”
            workmanship by people who care’ togeth- over the last few years, but their roster of   “And the beauty of it is, it’s going to   In order to maintain their high stan-
            er. And we’ve built our core values around  employees has grown as well. Rather than  grow with you, your family, your life. So  dards, Chris said they are “never not hir-
            it. My point is I believe that’s what allows  10 or 15 people, they now employ 75 to  if you’re doing an interior renovation,  ing”  — that  they’re  always  looking  for
            us to do the things we do.”         90 during their exceedingly busy summer  they’re not growing any further after the  great people.
              And while they’re pleased to have such  months.                        contractor leaves. Whereas when you do a   “We believe that if the people that
            a successful business, it’s more than that   “We’ve grown very quickly, and the  landscape renovation, if it’s done properly  work for a company are successful, then
            for them.                           growth trajectory hasn’t been about being  and it’s planned out properly, every year  the company will be successful. Surround
              “I think it’s a passion,” Karin said. “And  the biggest,” Chris said. “When we made  it’s growing and different. You get a dif- yourself with great people and great things
            when you’re passionate about something,  the decision to move out to this new lo- ferent feeling from a different perspective.  happen. It really is that simple. We focus
            you’re passionate! So, everything is done  cation six years ago (the southeast corner  And our goal has always been, on a de- on the little things so the big things can
            because you care, and you like it when you  of 34th Street and Patricia Avenue) and  sign/build side and the landscaping side,  happen!
            do it.”                             build this facility, it was about how we  whenever we’re doing a design and we’re   “We’re very high on safety,” Chris said.
              “Karin has always said if you love what  could add to the industry.”   doing an installation, if we’re looking  “We were one of the first landscape com-
            you do, it’s not work,” Chris added. “At   People  told  them  they  were  nuts  to  from one corner of the yard to the other  panies in Manitoba — the first one out-
            the end of the day, we’re a little bit of  expand from a contracting business to a  corner of the yard, it should all be consis- side Winnipeg — to be COR certified. So
            an anomaly to a certain degree, because  garden  centre  instead  of  the  other  way  tent and have continuity, but the goal is to  we’ve driven that through our whole orga-
            we’re partners at work and there are a lot  around, but for the Griffins, it just seemed  get a different approach. To get a different  nization. And every week we have a safety
            of things we agree on, and there’s certain  a logical move. And as far as integrating  look and the same feeling.”  meeting — we use those for communica-
            things we don’t. But we’re also partners in  different services and expertise, they’d al-  Alternative has made several contribu- tions, incentives — we have employee of
            our life, and I think that that passion does  ready done that in Alternative Landscap- tions to the community by offering their  the month, paid birthdays off, staff barbe-
            add. And I think when we have some- ing right from the beginning.        expertise on projects that are mostly fo- cues and family functions.
            thing that’s a challenge — if somebody   “We’d been doing gardening and yard  cused  on  kids  and  families  and  building   “We believe doing things like that, so
            has a complaint, let’s say, we go back to  maintenance for years,” within our land- communities.  They’ve also been recog- they understand how much they’re appre-
            that same mission statement and go back  scaping,” Karin said. “And I think this was  nized by the Indigenous community be- ciated, but also it’s part of building our
            to our teams and ask,  ‘Was it superior  just the right fit. We love what we do.”  cause of their sensitivity to the planet,  culture as well. And I can’t say it enough:
            workmanship?’ And it’s a pretty yes-or-no   And really, what they do by creating  something Chris thinks is pretty special.   We could not to do what we’re doing to-
            question.                           their living art and in some cases making   “They talk about Mother Earth,” he  day if it wasn’t for phenomenal people —
              “And if they say, ‘Well, maybe not, then  something out of nothing is make people  said.  “And I think that’s kind of a cool  phenomenal clients, and such a dynamic
            we say, ‘Well then, do we care?’ And the  happy.                         thing, because from that perspective and  community to support and to be support-
            answer is of course we care. So, then we   “I think the whole industry, the green  their elders’ perspective — I had never  ed by, we are truly thankful and very ap-
            figure out what we’re going to do about it.  industry, is not given the attention that it  looked  at  it  this  way  —  you  are  giving  preciative.”


                  GOT





                 BIG




                  PLANS?






                  Call us!







                  FARM,                                                                                                   Roland Weir


                  RESIDENTIAL                                                                       Appraisal Associates
                  & COMMERCIAL

                                                                                                                                th
                  PROPERTY APPRAISERS                                                                Suite 30A, 1015 – 26 Street, Brandon
                                                                                                       204-727-7100     Fax: 204-727-1563
                  SINCE 1977                                                                                                         weir1@mts.net]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[34                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2019
































































            Natalia, David and Cherrill. (Submitted)

            » Brandon Photographics


            Keeping up with developing industry







              Brandon Photographics is not housed  had to diversify. It started out just roll-  they’ve moved away from shooting wed- can hold their own head up, we have to
            in a large building, but it appears to do  developing, and the studio, and it’s  dings and sports teams, they’ve expand- book them into the studio.”
            a land-office business. On a weekday  branched out into photo books, calen- ed  their  business  in  other  areas  and   While a number of places shoot pass-
            afternoon, the space had plenty of cus- dars, cards and photo gifts.  There’s al- specialize in taking photos of infants,  port photos, Brandon Photographics is
            tomers – having passport pictures taken,  most nothing we can’t put your picture  families, and graduates.   hailed as one of the most reliable estab-
            purchasing photo gifts and getting por- on.”                               The business’s particular ability to  lishments in town to have that all-im-
            traits done in the on-site studio.    There used to be a lot more competi- photograph the youngest of customers  portant picture taken.
              A long-time fixture on the local com- tion  in  town,  so  Brandon  Photograph- also has a side benefit, one that per-  “We have a very low rejection rate,”
            mercial landscape, Brandon Photo- ics tried to offer things other establish- haps many people might not be aware  Hrabok said. “It’s not to say we don’t get
            graphics offers great customer service,  ments didn’t.  That approach – paying  of. If you’re travelling out of the country,  the odd one back, but we try to stay on
            delivers professional results, and has  close attention to what’s happening in  when it comes to passports, even the  top of it. I think we’ve earned ourselves
            modified itself to fit the changes that  the industry – has obviously worked.   youngest  of  infants  must  have  one  of  a good reputation in that area for know-
            now  happen  fast  and  furiously  in  the   Including  owner-manager  David their own.                      ing what we’re doing and producing the
            photographic world.                 Tschetter,  there  are  four  full-time  em-  “They need it right from birth,” Hrabok  photo that you need accurately and ef-
              “We offer a lot of products and a lot of  ployees at the shop and as mentioned,  said. “If they’re under three months and  ficiently.”
            services,” Cherrill Hrabok said.  “We’ve  all of them are kept hopping.  While  they’re not quite at the place where they         » Continued on Page 35]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2019 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           35

            » Continued from Page 34            er format rolls, we can send them out  ry for them, because they’ve got their  baggie full of 35 mm rolls of film. She
                                                for processing,” Hrabok said. “As far as  life on their (phone or computer), and  said they were of her daughter from
              In addition, Brandon Photographics  printing, we can print from just about  if it crashes, it’s heartbreaking to think  birth to age two and that she would
            is the only place in the Wheat City that  anything.”                     about – it could be gone in an instant,”  like them processed and printed. Every
            processes film in-house. Surprising-  The business enjoys a lot of patrons  she said.                        single roll was blank. They hadn’t been
            ly, given the ubiquitousness of phone  who are committed to having their   It’s been said that the current gener- loaded properly into the camera and
            cameras, the number of folks wanting  photos printed, something that Hrabok  ation is the most photographed in his- she had nothing. Worse yet, that child
            to have film processed is on the rise.    strongly advises. She’s a big believer in  tory, but there aren’t any actual pictures  had nothing. At that point there isn’t
              “There are a few different reasons  albums, because the photos are accessi- of them, because everything is in digital  anything you can do.”
            why people are shooting film,” Hrabok  ble and tangible and always at the ready.  format. Sometimes, printed photos are   When asked by customers what
            said. “Some may have a really nice film  While she acknowledged that prints can  very necessary.             she would recommend for archiving,
            camera and not want to switch unless  also be lost or burned or susceptible to   “At the beginning of September, I took  Hrabok says USB is likely the most re-
            something happens to it.  There are  other sorts of mishaps, they’re still one  note of how many parents came to the  liable format, given the changes in the
            some people who don’t have a camera  of the best ways to ensure your memo- store in a panic, or emailed us some- digital realm that take place on an al-
            and just need to take a few photos, so  ries are preserved.              thing quick from their phone because  most daily basis.
            they’ll purchase a disposable camera.   “We have a group of people who are  their kids were going back to school and       “If you think back to older com-
            Then there are the people who were  very dedicated to printing,” Hrabok  needed images for projects.”        puters, they had a USB port,” she said.
            born into digital, but think it’s pretty in- said. “You see them once a month. They   Hrabok said her unwavering belief in  “Computers are still made with these
            teresting to go back and shoot film.”  have everything they’ve shot, and it’s all  printed photos has only been under- ports. So as long as nothing happens to
              The shop can develop 35, 110 and 126  catalogued. They get (multiple copies),  lined by what she’s seen happen to peo- that stick, it seems to be a format that
            mm C-41 film.                       because one is for them, one is for their  ple who haven’t kept up with printing.  has hung around while others have
              “If  a  customer  brings  us  something  parents and one is for each of their kids.  “The worst thing I ever encountered  gone by the wayside.”
            odd, like black and white, slides or larg-  “The people who don’t print – I wor- was a lady who came in with a Ziplock
                                     GIANT SELECTION OF CURRENT FASHIONS













































                              GIANT TIGER                     300 - Mountain Avenue Neepawa
                              CANADA’S BEST-KEPT SECRET.        2626 Victoria Avenue Brandon
                              FOR YOU. FOR LESS.                        #seeyourselfsaving]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Offer ends Midnight                        1 bedroom
                                                        November 15    th                           suite
                                                        204.571.6000                           AVAILABLE]]></page></pages></Search>