<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="36"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Winter 05 CoverV2_Layout 1  18-12-05  10:46 AM  Page 1




                WINTER                                                                                   FREE  ISSUE 05












                                                                                                    brine that bird











































                  DELIVERING
                  CHOICE






                  aTwiston






                 MILLION


                 DOLLAR HOMES]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[3714297_BdnEconDev_Layout 1  18-11-29  9:57 AM  Page 1]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Masthead_Letter_Layout 1  18-12-05  10:42 AM  Page 1








                                                                Editor’s Note



                             501 Rosser Ave., Brandon, MB                       ast issue’s month-long Burger Brawl
                          Email: trending@brandonsun.com                        competition that pit some of Brandon
                                brandonsun.com/trending                    Land Westman’s top culinary minds
                                                                           burger to sandwich to burger this past fall
                                         PUBLISHER                         drew a lot of interest from the region’s burger-
                                          Jim Mihaly
                                                                           loving crowd.
                                           EDITOR                          Eight restaurants competed in our contest,
                                       Matt Goerzen                        which was sponsored by Assiniboine
                                                                           Community College. The Canad Inns Tavern
                                         WRITERS       United, Coffee Culture, Echo Restaurant, Prairie Firehouse, Sandhills
                                       Erin DeBooy     Casino’s Oasis Lounge, Smitty’s Restaurant’s Sportsline Lounge and VLT,
                            edebooy@brandonsun.com    Thunderbird Bowl & Huggy’s Sports Bar and Benny’s all participated. To
                                       Michael Lee    each of them, we thank you for your imagination and your spirit of friendly
                              mlee@brandonsun.com    competition.
                                    Melissa Verge    Ben Hernandez of Benny’s Restaurant in downtown Brandon and his
                           mverge@brandonsun.com     Chorizo Burger, was the popular winner. Ben told us that he was very
                                   Chelsea Kemp     pleased with the interest shown by his customers, and even more pleased
                           ckemp@brandonsun.com     that the contest brought in new customers who had never walked through
                                  Bud Robertson
                      brobertson@brandonsun.com    his doors before. Got any suggestions for what culinary creations you’d like
                                                   to see battle it out next? Pass them on to me at @MattGoerzen or
                             PHOTOGRAPHERS         @TrendingBdnMB and we’ll see what we can do.
                          Tim Smith, Michael Lee,   But I digress. Winter has once again taken hold of our attention. And as we
                      Bud Robertson, Erin DeBooy,   hunker down near the heat registers, wood stoves and ﬁreplaces, (some parts
                      Jeff de Booy, Chelsea Kemp,  of Canadian life really never go out of style — we all need heat), our minds
                                Melissa Verge    inevitably wander to how to spend the cold-weather holidays.
                            GRAPHIC DESIGN      Sure, you may dislike winter — especially when the temps dip to downright frigid.
                                Nadine Krahn    But huddling up in the blankets while awaiting the onset of cabin fever also seems
                            Christine Torrance  like a waste of a perfectly good winter season.
                          Lorraine Dillabough    So if you’re looking to get out and about, Trending writer Melissa Verge has you
                                               covered. From heading down the slopes of the Asessippi ski hill near Russell, and
                       SALES & MARKETING
                                DIRECTOR      ice ﬁshing upon one of any number of Manitoba’s frozen lakes, to snowshoeing,
                               Glen Parker    skating, tobogganing, or snowmobiling, there’s plenty of winter activities sure to
                                              please.
                           DISTRIBUTION      You might even want to try a new and growing winter sport called skjoring, where a
                               Lori Timms    person on cross-country skies is pulled by a dog — or a horse or a car or what have
                            On the cover:   you. Typically around Manitoba, dogs seem to be the favoured method for skijoring
                    Photo  by Chelsea Kemp  locomotion — but it takes all kinds I guess. Read all about it in Chelsea Kemp’s feature
                                            from our winter edition’s front page.
                     Advertising Inquiries:  If you’re like me, and you’re trying you’re trying your hand at brewing beer — one of my
                          204-571-7424     other winter activities this year —  check out Michael Lee’s feature on Prairie Mountain
                                          Hops in Boissevain. If you like Manitoba microbrews, chances are you’ve already tried
                         TRENDING is a
                       production of  The  their product.
                          Brandon Sun.    But if grumpy Old Man Winter even has you second guessing that trip to the grocery
                                         store that you’ve been putting off all week, read Erin DeBooy’s take on a few trending
                      Made in Manitoba.   alternatives that bring all the ingredients for tonight’s dinner right to your door.
                                        Enjoy our latest edition of Trending, and tell us what you think! Until then keep warm
                                        thoughts in mind, and remember Percy Bysshe Shelley’s thoughts about winter: “If Winter
                                        comes, can Spring be far behind?”

                                                                                                Matt Goerzen
                                                                                                Editor


                                                                                                                     3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[04 Contents_Layout 1  18-12-05  11:48 AM  Page 1







                                                                           CONTENTS


                                                                           03 EDITOR’S NOTE


                                                                           06 GOOD EATS

                                                                               Delivering Choice

                                                                           11 TRANSFORMATIONS

                                                                               More Than Just a Hoppy Farm

                                                                           14 GOOD EATS

                                                                               A Twist on Tradition
                                                             21
                                                                 OUTDOORS
                                                                           18 DESTINATIONS

                                                                               Staying Home for the Holidays

                                                                           21 OUTDOORS

                                                                               Dashing Through the Snow

                                                                           26 DESTINATIONS

                                                                               Come for the Snow, Stay for the Whoa!
                                                      06
                                                           GOOD EATS
                                                                           30 DWELLINGS

                                                                               Million Dollar Homes

                                                                           34 DESTINATIONS

                                                                               Hot Winter Escapes



                                            26
                                                 DESTINATIONS




















                                                      30                                              14
                                                                                                           GOOD EATS
                                                           DWELLINGS
              4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[3714330_SobeysExtra_Layout 1  18-11-29  9:58 AM  Page 1








                                                                     SEE THE DIFFERENCE



                   EXTRA EXPERTS, SERVICES
                         &  DEPARTMENTS




                                                                       KITCHEN





                                                                       Sushi Bar





                 NATURAL SOURCE & WELLBEING
                 Wellbeing Counselor





                                                                        Carvery
                                                                         Station


                  BULK FOODS
                  Organic/Liquid



                                                                      Salad Bar














                                                                      Self Serve
                                                                       Hot Food
                  CHEESE/DELI ISLAND
                  In-store Cheese Ambassador                                Bar




                                 • PET BOUTIQUE
                                 • LARGEST SELECTION OF ETHNIC FOODS




                                                        1570 18 Street  | Shoppers Mall  | 204-725-1134
                                                                 th]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Delivering Choice_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:44 PM  Page 1














































                                                                              Story by Erin DeBooy
                                                                              Photos by Erin DeBooy & Jeff de Booy


                      n a house with two teenage sons and an exchange  people or four meals for a family of four, and pick the
                      student, Melania Cannon knew that when her     recipes they’d like to try.
                   Ihusband had to work out of province for two       Every week, an insulated box lands on the doorstep,
                   months she was going to need a little back up.    with the meat and/or ﬁsh neatly packed on top of ice
                    Working full time as a lawyer and juggling a side job  packs and the produce and other ingredients
                   as well, Cannon said she started researching meal kit  separated and bagged for each recipe.
                   delivery subscriptions, hoping it would make life a  Cannon’s kids already each had a night of the week
                   little easier.                                    that they would cook, she said, and the boxes have
                    Cannon decided on Hello Fresh — one of the       helped teach them new skills and pushed them
                   handful of meal delivery services that delivers to  outside their comfort zone.
                   Brandon — a couple months ago, she said, and hasn’t  “They’d get into a rut … my eldest just made pasta
                   skipped a week since she signed up.               every Monday for about three months and that got
                    “It’s still very convenient,” Cannon said, adding that  really repetitive,” Cannon said with a laugh. “This gives
                   since her husband has come back home they still   them new ideas, they’re learning different things and
                   welcome the weekly delivery.                      they’re trying different things. Some recipes are
                    “I actually  ﬁnd it very comforting sometimes    deﬁnitely things that it wouldn’t occur to me to make,
                   because … I’ll get home from work on a really rough  and they’re really good … it’s a comfortable level of
                   day and I know I want to make some food but I don’t  experimentation in terms of what the food options
                   want to think too much about it, and it’s all just right  are.”
                   there. You just have to follow the steps.”         While some of the portions are a little lacking for a
                    Meal kits, whether it’s from Hello Fresh, GoodFood,  household with three growing teens, Cannon said
                   Chef’s Plate or Miss Fresh, all function on a similar  they’ve just made some small adjustments in order to
                   model.                                            make it work.
                    Customers sign up for a weekly plan that best ﬁts  “We just stretch it. If there’s a meal that comes with
                   their needs, whether that be three meals for two  potatoes, we’ll add a few more potatoes. If it’s chicken


              6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Delivering Choice_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:44 PM  Page 2









                   breast, we’ll throw in an extra chicken breast. You can
                   use the kit and just add a few more ingredients too to
                   make it for ﬁve people instead of four.”
                    And there’s also no food waste or leftovers going
                   bad in the fridge.
                    While Cannon doesn’t mind spending the money on
                   the weekly boxes — it’s cheaper and healthier than a
                   dinner with the kids at McDonald’s, she said — there
                   is a drawback in the packaging.
                    “They do pride themselves on being sustainable,  GoodFood Online Meal Ordering Service- Preparing Lamb-Zucchini
                   recyclable packaging and while that’s true, you’re  Meatballs with Fresh Rigatoni. (Jeff de Booy)
                   putting a lot of things into recycling each week,”
                   Cannon said, adding it would be nice if they had a
                   reusable bin or cooler you could return to them for
                   reuse.
                    While local grocery stories are jumping on the
                   online-ordering and click-and-collect train, it’s not to
                   compete with delivery services such as these.
                    “We haven’t seen much of an effect (from meal
                   delivery services),” said Ingrid Sian, assistant store
                   manager at Brandon’s Real Canadian Superstore.
                    Yet they have seen a lot of customers opting for
                   convenience, Sian said, partaking in Superstore’s Click
                   and Collect service where groceries can be ordered
                   online and delivered straight to your car at a certain
                   pick-up time for a small fee.
                    While Superstore doesn’t have a delivery service
                   yet, Sian said she believes that is the direction the
                   program is going in the future.
                    Walmart also has an online grocery-ordering option
                   that can be picked up ready to go in store, a
                   spokesperson said, and it’s free for orders $50 or
                   more.
                    At Sobeys Extra, manager Ryan Hackett said that
                   “business is growing immensely,” and while he can see
                   the beneﬁts of the delivery service, there will always
                   be a place for a local grocery store.
                    “Life is more hustle-
                   bustle as the years go
                   on, but people like to
                   hold on to the old-
                   fashioned way of
                   doing things,” Hackett
                   said. “I think grocery
                   shopping is one of
                   those things. Couples
                   like to go shopping
                   together, families go
                   shopping together, it
                   can really be a social
                   experience that brings
                   people together.”




                                                                                                                     7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Delivering Choice_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:44 PM  Page 3









                   GoodFood                                          some bruising on it that had started to go mushy, but it
                   www.makegoodfood.ca                               was only a tiny spot that I was able to cut off and
                                                                     continue on with cooking.
                    GoodFood is a Canadian company that works with
                   more than 20 Canadian farmers to offer fresh,     Experience:
                   seasonal and “unique” ingredients, according to the  The recipes were easy to follow and prepare, and
                   introduction pamphlet we received in our ﬁrst box.  included ingredients we wouldn’t usually gravitate to,
                    They offer three plans, the Classic plan ( two or four  which was really fun.
                   servings), the Easy Prep plan (two or four servings) and  We thoroughly enjoyed every meal — give or take a
                   the Family plan (four servings).                  few minor personal preferences (cilantro belongs in a
                    They offer some  ﬂexibility in terms of dietary  garbage can, but that’s just me).
                   requirements — such as dairy-free or gluten-free   Our favourite by far was the Keto Walnut & Spinach
                   options — and pride themselves on reducing food   Stuffed Pork Chop with Ghee Sautéed Mushroom
                   waste and using 100 per cent recyclable packaging.  Sauce, which we found out later was unfortunately an
                    For the recipes we ordered, they required us to have  additional $5.00 to order.
                   very few “pantry essentials”, which were salt, pepper  We found the portions to be quite small, with
                   and olive oil.                                    exception to the more expensive but delicious Keto
                                                                     dish.
                   Plan ordered:                                      At ﬁrst, my ﬁancé and I questioned everything we
                    Classic Plan                                     knew about cooking for ourselves — were we living a
                    Four recipes, each serves two                    gluttonous lifestyle? Wasn’t it normal to occasionally
                    $87.00 per week ($10.88 per serving)             want more salad or more than four ping-pong ball sized
                    Delivered every Wednesday, free delivery         meatballs?
                                                                      I was so curious (and slightly concerned) that I sent a
                   Ordering process:                                 box to my parents in Winnipeg to get their opinion. My
                    GoodFood’s website is easy to navigate, and we had  mother has cooked dinners for more than 40 years,
                   no problem choosing our food preferences and meals  surely she’d have the
                   for the week or skipping deliveries.              best idea on whether or
                    In order to cancel delivery you need to contact them,  not this was reasonable.
                   either through email, telephone or their online chat,
                   but it was suspended almost immediately.
                    The box arrived on time and as expected, tucked
                   neatly inside my back gate waiting for me to come
                   home and cook.
                    Everything we needed for each dinner was very
                   organized and easy to navigate, and the produce was
                   nice and fresh for the most part. A yellow beet had


























              8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Delivering Choice_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:44 PM  Page 4









                    The answer is we might have just picked smaller, less  were closed, so it’s possible it was just an
                   ﬁlling options.                                   unforeseeable circumstance.
                    While raving about how delicious each dinner was, a  Everything we needed for each recipe was neatly
                   chicken dish my parents ordered similar to our    organized and ready to go, and the instructions were
                   Turmeric Chicken Breasts with Spiced Chickpeas did  easy to follow.
                   seem a little lacking, my mom informed me.         The meat, produce and other ingredients were good
                    However, they also ordered a few pasta dishes, and  quality and in good condition.
                   found those to be as ﬁlling as they were ﬂavourful.
                    In both our experience and my parents’, food waste  Experience:
                   was deﬁnitely not an issue.                        The recipe cards were clear and concise, and made
                                                                     cooking techniques I previously thought were
                   Compared to local grocery store prices:           complicated very easy.
                    Per serving, GoodFood meals came out              Every meal was very tasty, and a lot of ingredients I
                   approximately $3 to $5 more than if you were to   am familiar with were used together in new and
                   purchase the ingredients at a local grocery store —  refreshing ways.
                   with the exception of the steak dish, which was either  For example, I’ve never made a chutney before — it’s
                   on par or more than grocery store prices depending on  always seemed too daunting for some reason. But
                   the cut of steak selected.                        there I was whipping up a tomato and balsamic chutney
                                                                     on a Tuesday.
                   Hello Fresh                                        Our favourite dish was hard to pinpoint, because they
                   www.hellofresh.ca                                 were all very good. The Turkish-Spiced Beef with
                                                                     Pickled Cabbage Freekeh Salad was the most
                    Hello Fresh spans across North America, however  memorable, and the quickest to disappear off our
                   Hello Fresh Canada works with Canadian suppliers to  plates.
                   supply “high-quality ingredients”, such as certiﬁed RWA  The portions we received was just enough. We
                   meat (raised without the use of antibiotics or growth  weren’t left hungry after but there deﬁnitely were no
                   hormones) and traceable and sustainable seafood and  leftovers.
                   seasonal produce.
                    They offer a Veggie Plan (two servings), a Pronto
                   plan, (two or four servings), and a Family plan (four
                   servings), each including a variety of recipes that
                   explore cuisines around the world.
                    For the recipes we ordered, they required us to
                   have “pantry essentials” such as salt, pepper, sugar,
                   butter, milk and olive oil.

                   Plan:
                    Pronto Plan
                    Four recipes, each serves two
                    $94.99 per week ($11.87 per serving)
                    Delivered every Monday, Tuesday or
                    Wednesday, free delivery

                       Ordering process:                              The recipe card also had a full list of the ingredients
                    Hello Fresh was simple to sign up with, choose your  as well as measurements for both two people or four
                   food preferences and pick and choose recipes to try.    people, so it is easy to save your favourite recipes and
                    Skipping a week or cancelling was is easy at well —  make them again in the future for yourself or even for
                   done with the click of a button.                  company.
                    Ordering was a little more ﬂexible given there are
                   three days you can choose for the box to be delivered.  Compared to local grocery store prices:
                   Our box was a day late, however there was bad      Per serving, the Hello Fresh meals came out
                   weather the day before and some of the highways   approximately $2.50 to $5 more than if you were to
                                                                     purchase the ingredients at a local grocery store.


                                                                                                                     9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Delivering Choice_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:44 PM  Page 5









                   General Takeaway
                    I deﬁnitely appreciated the convenience of having the                   single, going out or
                   recipes and ingredients ready to go for when I got                      ordering in almost every
                   home from work, and the food was quite delicious. All                    night, this would have
                   recipes were things I’d never make on my own on a                        saved me a lot of money
                   week night, some of which                                                and it would have been
                   included ingredients I’ve                                                something feasible I
                   never thought of using before,                                          could do.
                   and they were all very well-                                            If you’re curious about
                   balanced.                                                             either meal kit, I would
                    While my only complaint                                            recommend trying it. You can
                   would be that the portions                                         usually   ﬁnd  some  decent
                   were a bit on the small side, it                                  discount codes online (regular
                   was nice not having any food                                      customers get coupons to hand
                   waste, which is something I am                                    out to friends for a free box pretty
                   very guilty of (I once found a                                    regularly) and the service is fairly
                   lemon in the back of my fridge                                    easy to cancel if you don’t want to
                   that had started to fossilize).                                   continue.
                    As much as I liked the                                            Whether or not the service will
                   service, and even though it’s                                     work for you is circumstantial — I
                   only a few dollars more per                                       could see it simplifying someone’s
                   serving than grocery store                                        life and possibly saving them
                   shopping, I like to err on the                                    money, but I could also see it being
                   side of  ﬁscally responsible.                                     more expensive for some and not
                   However, if this was available                                    make much of a difference. Either
                   when I was younger and                                            way it’s worth a try.



















                  2 FULL-SIZE

                  SUNROOMS
                 ON DISPLAY!

                • FREE ESTIMATES •



               We specialize in building quality
              sunrooms and patios designed to fit
                your budget and your lifestyle.

              Your sunroom will be custom built for you.
              MAINTENANCE-FREE Sunspace Railings
             Available In A Variety Of Styles & Colours.
              Foundations to finishing – we do it all!                      th
                                                204-726-8488   |   1840 - 18 Street North in the Windsor Plywood building
                                                www.sunspacesunrooms.com    |   www.elitesunrooms.ca]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Hoppy Farm_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:35 PM  Page 1



















































                                                                        Story and photos by Michael Lee


                                                                                 hat began as a chance encounter with
                                                                                 a story on craft beer and hops has
                                                                        Wgrown into a full-on entrepreneurial
                                                                        venture for Randy and Lyn Tye — and they’re
                                                                        only just getting started.
                                                                         Located just south of Boissevain, the Tyes have
                                                                        run their family hop farm — Prairie Mountain
                                                                        Hops — for more than three years, standing out
                                                                        as one of the few producers in the province and
                                                                        drawing the attention of Manitoba breweries,
                                                                        including Winnipeg’s own Torque Brewing and
                                                                        Half Pints.
                                                                         The Tyes have put in a lot of hours into their
                                                                        newfound enterprise. But with the help of family
                                                                        and friends, the couple has managed to chart a
                                                                        steady path for themselves for what will
                                                                        eventually be their own personal project come
                   Randy and Lyn Tye – pictured in their home south of  retirement.
                   Boissevain – are one of only a handful of farmers     “I knew growing it wouldn’t necessarily be
                   producing hops in the Prairies. (Michael Lee)
                                                                        easy, but it would be just a matter of getting it
                                                                        right,” Randy said.




                                                                                                                    11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Hoppy Farm_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:35 PM  Page 2







































                     Randy Tye pictured with some of his plants.  A view of Lyn and Randy Tye's hop ﬁeld. (Facebook)
                     (Facebook)




                    Originally from London, Ont., Randy moved to      While some varieties of hops do grow wild in
                   Manitoba more than 30 years ago, where he met his  Manitoba, much of the large-scale production is
                   wife Lyn and built a career selling farm equipment,  done in the Pacific northwest.
                   including for Mazergroup.                          But located in a prime location, with relatively few
                    “It made it easier in that I understood marketing,”  frost-free days and good pasture, the Tyes figured
                   he said. “We got told by numerous lenders,        hops would do just fine where they are.
                   businesspeople, that one thing was to be able to put  And with the exception of Prairie GEM Hops near
                   it on paper, and draw it out, and figure out how to  Winnipeg, Farmery Estate Brewery in Neepawa and
                   grow it and where the rows were going to go, and  another producer in Moosomin, Sask., Prairie
                   what machinery, but somebody in the team had to   Mountain Hops is the only other hop farm in the
                   sell.”                                            region.
                    The Tyes considered a number of options to        “I went last year when their operation was still
                   generate revenue off their farm — a woodlot,      pretty new,” said Kathy Yan Li, a homebrewer in Shilo
                   Christmas tree farm and U-Pick — before settling on  and creator of Farm To Bottle, a podcast that traces
                   hops.                                             the origins of beer ingredients.
                    They started out with a test plot of 30 plants,   Co-founder and past president of the University of
                   building themselves a small-scale trellis and     British Columbia Brewing Club, a certified beer and
                   irrigation system, and producing a small crop come  mead judge, and a director for the Canadian
                   harvest.                                          Homebrewers Association, Li interviewed the Tyes
                    Fast forward to 2017 and the Tyes put            for an episode released in October 2017.
                   approximately 2,500 plants in the ground by hand   She said she even used some of their hops to create
                   on 2.5 acres.                                     a pretty good beer for herself. “It seems like they
                    “We knew it was going to be labour intensive, but I  really planned to go commercial from the very start
                   think until you get into it, you don’t realize how  and their plans really speak to that.”
                   labour intensive it is. That was probably the biggest  Prairie Mountain Hops currently grows eight
                   thing,” Lyn said.                                 varieties: centennial, cascade, comet, willamette,
                    The Tyes acquired a planter to help speed up the  nugget, Mount Hood, chinook, and most recently
                   process and this year, they added another four acres.  brewer’s gold, a plant that traces its origins back to
                   They hope to have 15 acres in all once finished.  Manitoba 100 years ago.

              12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Hoppy Farm_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:35 PM  Page 3







































                   The trellis built by Lyn and Randy Tye at their farm  Randy Tye explains how he plans to try out pelleting his hops this
                   near Boissevain. (Michael Lee)          winter. (Michael Lee)




                    The Tyes use a drip irrigation system and a       “We’re very proud and excited that they’re finding
                   targeted pesticide for aphids, as well as t-shaped  that we can grow great hops and they’re
                   poles to form their trellis, which helps maximize the  appreciative of it,” he said.
                   amount of space they have to grow.                 His and Lyn’s entry into the brewing scene also
                    But what makes Prairie Mountain Hops unique is   comes at a time when overall beer sales have
                   their wet hops, which instead of being dried are  dropped globally in recent years, but craft beer has
                   pulled straight from the vine and put into a batch in  gained in popularity.
                   order to extract as much flavour as possible.      According to Manitoba Brew Hub, a webpage run
                    Doing so means early mornings and long drives for  by Manitoba Liquor and Lotteries, craft beer is the
                   Randy, but the Tyes’ efforts seem to have paid off,  fastest growing beer segment in the province, with
                   with their hops having been used in batches of    Canadian craft-style beers making up approximately
                   Torque Brewing’s Finish Line IPA and Half Pints’s  12.5 per cent of all beer litre sales.
                   Fresh Hop Harvest Ale.                             “Back when I was growing up, the thing was you
                    “It’s a busy day for him that’s for sure,” said Chris  took a two-four of beer under your arm to the fire
                   Young, head brewer at Half Pints, “but it got us some  pit party. Those days are gone,” Randy said.
                   really nice hops freshly delivered.”               “People are now buying sleeves of beer that there’s
                    The Tyes recently bought a pelleter, which they  three different varieties in there, they’re talking
                   hope to test out this winter in the hopes of selling  about it, they’re trying it. It’s brought, actually, a lot
                   pelleted hops that can be packaged and stored.    of women back to the beer drinking industry,
                    “Going forward, I’m certainly interested in using  because they have something different, compared
                   more of his product, both pelletized and whole leaf  to just the same old, same old.”
                   hops,” Young said.                                 Just as people care about where their food comes
                    “... And so far, what I’ve seen from his stuff, I have  from, Randy believes the message of buy local has
                   no doubts.”                                       extended into the craft beer market as well, and he
                    For Randy, driving out to Winnipeg for a delivery  doesn’t expect it to change any time soon.
                   has more to do with customer service than anything,  “I don’t see that the desire of having local will
                   but it also gives him a chance to help create a   change for a long time. I don’t see that.”
                   “masterpiece,” as far as brewing is concerned.



                                                                                                                    13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[TwistOnTradition_Layout 1  18-12-05  9:45 AM  Page 1













                        A Twist On










                                                                     Story by Erin DeBooy
                                                                     Photos by Tim Smith



                            hile there’s a time and a place to       Twigg said. “Because we have oranges and cranberries
                            experiment with new and different recipes,  in our brine, we used those elements as our decoration
                   Wholiday dinners usually aren’t one of them.      as well. It’s all easy stuff to ﬁnd in the grocery store, too,
                    Tradition tends to trump the trends when it comes  it’s nothing extravagant but when it’s all put together it
                   to cooking family favourites, but the Culinary Arts  looks really nice.”
                   students at Assiniboine Community College are      The last thing any host wants is to cut into a dry turkey,
                   breaking out of that box in the name of tastier and  Twigg said, which is why brining the bird is a must.
                   more memorable feasts.                             “The brine is really what’s going to help keep it juicy …
                    In the Culinary Arts program Cuisine and Trends,  you don’t get your dry turkey anymore with a brine and
                   second-year students have the opportunity to learn  it’s not a hard addition to do,” Twigg said.
                   about a variety of cuisines and different ways of  To add more ﬂavour, Twigg said they also rubbed a
                   cooking, Culinary Arts instructor Bryan Hendricks  compound butter under the skin packed with garlic,
                   said. And it doesn’t take much to elevate a traditional  thyme, rosemary, clove and nutmeg.
                   favourite.                                         To ensure the gravy is equally as ﬂavourful, Twigg
                    “They’re taking regular food and adding a twist to it,”  suggested putting the turkey directly on top of a layer
                   Hendricks said.                                   of celery, carrots and onions instead of a rack, adding
                    Devilled eggs, for example, are a staple appetizer  more ﬂavours to the drippings.
                   that can be served a variety of different ways just by  “We really didn’t have to season (the gravy) very much,
                   changing the garnishes or the base of the ﬁlling, said  all the ﬂavours from the turkey are in it,” Twigg said.
                   second year Assiniboine culinary arts student Keenan  The cranberry sauce can also be punched up a level
                   Denis.                                            fairly simply, said second year Assiniboine culinary arts
                    “We did two sorts of bases, a horseradish base and  student Morgan Bone, who used orange and sparkling
                   then a wasabi base, and we also tricked out the shells  wine to give her cranberry sauce a twist.
                   a little bit by putting some in a beet brine and deep  “We tried to keep it simple,” Bone said. “It has a really
                   frying some others,” Denis said. “Home chefs can be  strong orange ﬂavour to it, but it doesn’t overpower the
                   really creative with the garnishes on top. Chives,  cranberries … really you can put a lot of different
                   bacon, wontons, banana peppers, roasted red       ﬂavours in it as long as you’re not overpowering the
                   peppers, caviare adds a nice dimension to it … you can  cranberry.”
                   really customize them.”                            The students also added different ﬂavours to and old
                    Having a piping bag with a nice tip also can go a long  favourite, Sticky Date Toffee Pudding, said second year
                   way in making devilled eggs look a step above the rest,  Assiniboine culinary arts student Jessi Coulter.
                   Denis said.                                        “We made a strawberry coulee to add a little ﬂavour
                    Presentation is also a key element to wowing guests  and colour to it. The pudding is quite sweet and we just
                   with the main event — the turkey, said second year  wanted to add a little bit of tartness to it,” Coulter said.
                   Assiniboine culinary arts student Kassandra Twigg.   “It’s just a holiday classic for home cooks or culinary
                    “You want lots of colour … and ﬂavours that coincide  chefs alike. It’s quite easy and you can change up the
                   with what we’ve already used (in the preparation),”  ﬂavours in so many different ways.”



              14]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[TwistOnTradition_Layout 1  18-12-05  9:46 AM  Page 2











                                                                     Wasabi Deviled Eggs
                                                                     INGREDIENTS
                                                                     12 hard-boiled eggs
                                                                     1 /4 cup mayonnaise
                                                                     1 /4 cup sour cream
                                                                     2 tbsp dijon mustard
                                                                     2 tbsp dill pickle juice
                                                                     1 tbsp wasabi
                                                                     1 /2 tsp salt
                                                                     1 /4 tsp white pepper
                                                                     2 pinches of cayenne
                                                                     INSTRUCTIONS
                                                                     – Cut eggs lengthwise and remove the yolk. Save the
                                                                      whites for later.
                                                                     – Combine yolks and all other ingredients into a large
                                                                      metal bowl.
                                                                     – Mix together until well combined.
                                                                     – Pass through a sieve to create a smooth mixture.
                                                                     – Fill a piping bag with mixture and pipe into your egg
                                                                      whites.


                                                                     Sparkling Orange Cranberry Sauce
                                                                     INGREDIENTS
                                                                     2 cup frozen cranberries
                                                                     2 oranges juiced and zested
                                                                     1 /2 cup white sugar
                                                                     1 /2 cup brown sugar
                                                                     1 /2 cinnamon stick
                                                                     1 /4 tsp vanilla
                                                                     1 /2 cup sparkling rosé wine (substitute Perrier water
                                                                       for non-alcoholic version)

                                                                     INSTRUCTIONS
                                                                     – Place cranberries and orange juice in a small pot
                                                                      and heat to a light simmer.
                                                                     – Stir in white and brown sugar and add the cinnamon
                                                                      stick.
                                                                     – Simmer lightly for 20 minutes, or until cranberries
                                                                      start to break down, stirring occasionally.
                                                                     – Add the vanilla and orange zest. Stir in and let cool.
                                                                     –To ﬁnish off, whisk in the sparkling wine or Perrier.



                                                                     CAN’T GET ENOUGH DEVILED EGGS?
                                                                     Visit brandonsun.com/trending for the
                                                                     ACC Culinary Arts program’s recipe for
                                                                     Horseradish Deviled Eggs.






                                                                                                                    15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[TwistOnTradition_Layout 1  18-12-05  9:46 AM  Page 3



































                   Turkey, Brined, Buttered and Beautiful            TURKEY PREPARATION
                                                                     You will need:
                   TURKEY BRINE
                   1  litre water                                    1 turkey (thawed)
                   1 /3 cup brown sugar                              vegetable oil
                   3  tbsp kosher salt                               water or chicken stock
                   1 /2 cup diced carrots                            brine
                   1 /2 cup diced celery                             compound butter
                   1  cup diced onion                                large dice carrots, celery, and onions
                                                                     fresh sage
                   Optional additional ﬂavours: Peppercorns, rosemary, bay  salt & pepper
                   leaves, thyme, orange slices, grapefruit slices, garlic cloves,  pastry brush
                   lemon slices, cranberries (muddled).              baster
                                                                     roasting pan
                   INSTRUCTIONS
                   – Add all ingredients into a large pot            – Place turkey in cooled brine and let sit for one hour
                   – Bring to a boil, stir occasionally until sugar and salt  per pound
                     are completely dissolved                        – Take turkey out of brine, rinse thoroughly and pat
                   – Let brine completely cool                        dry
                   – Brine can be made one to two days in advance    – Preheat oven to 325ºF
                                                                     – Rub compound butter underneath skin of turkey
                   COMPOUND BUTTER                                    and place fresh sage leaves between butter and skin
                   1 lb salted butter or margarine                    of turkey
                   1 clove garlic, pureed                            – Prepare roasting pan by placing diced carrots,
                   3 /4 tsp ground black pepper                       celery, and onion in bottom of the pan and add
                   1 /2 tsp fresh thyme, ﬁnely chopped                enough water or chicken stock to cover bottom as
                   1 /2 tsp fresh rosemary, ﬁnely chopped             well
                   1 /8 tsp ground clove                             – Place turkey in roasting pan on top of vegetables
                   1 /8 tsp ground nutmeg                            – Use pastry brush to brush vegetable oil onto turkey
                   1 /2 tsp poultry seasoning                         skin
                    1
                   1 /2 tsp kosher salt                              – Season turkey with salt and pepper
                                                                     – Place turkey in preheated oven and bake for 18 to
                   INSTRUCTIONS
                   – Soften butter                                    20 minutes per pound, until internal temperature is
                   – Add remaining ingredients and mix until combined   165ºF (Take temperature between thigh and breast)
                   – Compound butter should be at room temperature   – Baste turkey with fat (can use fat from drippings or
                     before rubbing under skin of turkey              butter, do not use juices) every 30 minutes while
                                                                      cooking

              16]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[TwistOnTradition_Layout 1  18-12-05  9:46 AM  Page 4









                   – Once cooked, remove turkey from oven and let rest
                     for 20 minutes, reserve all drippings for gravy
                   – Carve turkey and serve
                   TURKEY PAN GRAVY
                   2  cups turkey drippings
                   1 /3 cup ﬂour
                   1 /3 cup butter or margarine, softened
                   3 /4 tsp poultry seasoning
                   salt and white pepper to taste

                   INSTRUCTIONS
                   – Combine ﬂour and butter, set aside
                   – Strain and skim fat from turkey drippings
                   – Measure drippings and pour into medium pot
                   – While heavily whisking, add ﬂour and butter
                     mixture into drippings
                   – Bring to a simmer for 2 minutes over medium to
                     low heat
                   – Add seasonings



                   Sticky Date Pudding with Toﬀee Sauce              – Using an electric mixer, cream together butter and
                                                                      sugar, adding the eggs one at a time, allowing eggs
                   PUDDING
                   2  /2 cups pitted, and coarsely chopped dates      to be fully incorporated before adding the next.
                     1
                   1  /4 cups water                                   Scrape down bowl as needed.
                     3
                   4 tsp baking soda                                 – Gradually add the ﬂour mixture, scraping bowl as
                   2 cups all purpose ﬂour                            needed.
                   3 tsp baking powder                               – Stir in the date mixture by hand.
                   1 /3 tsp ground ginger                            – Pour batter into greased pan, and place into
                   1 /3 cups unsalted butter at room temperature      roasting pan. Pour the boiling water into the
                   1  /3 cups sugar                                   roasting pan until it is half way up the side of baking
                     1
                   3 eggs                                             pan.
                                                                     – Place into preheated oven, bake for 20 minutes and
                   SAUCE                                              then reduce heat to 325 F and bake for additional
                   3 /4 cups unsalted butter                          35 minutes or until a knife inserted comes out
                   2 cups brown sugar                                 clean. Serve hot.
                   1 cup whipping cream
                   1 /2 tsp vanilla                                  FOR SAUCE:
                                                                     – While pudding is baking, melt butter in a saucepan.
                   INSTRUCTIONS                                       Stir in brown sugar and cook while stirring
                   – Preheat oven to 350ºF.                           occasionally until dissolved.
                   – Place dates and water in a sauce pan, cover and  – Add whipping cream and vanilla, increase the heat
                     bring to a boil. Remove lid and let boil for 5   and boil gently, uncovered, stirring occasionally
                     minutes.                                         until slightly thickened, about 5 minutes. Serve
                   – Remove from heat, stir in baking soda and let stand  warm on top of warm pudding.
                     for 20 minutes.
                   – Meanwhile, lightly grease a 9x13 baking pan with  VARIATIONS
                                                                     A strawberry sauce can add a  ﬂavourful twist to this
                     butter.
                   – Set aside a roasting pan for the water bath, large  holiday classic. Combine 3 cups of frozen strawberries, 1
                                                                     cup sugar and 1 tbsp of lemon juice in sauce pot. Cook until
                     enough to hold the baking pan AND ﬁt a few litres  liquidy while occasionally stirring. Strain through a ﬁne
                     of boiling water.
                   – In a medium-sized mixing bowl, stir ﬂour, baking  mesh strainer into a different saucepan and bring to boil
                                                                     until thick enough to spoon over pudding.
                     powder and ginger.

                                                                                                                    17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Destinations_Asessippi_Layout 1  18-12-04  5:57 PM  Page 5
























                   By Melissa Verge

                    Instead of boarding a Boeing 747 for sun and  cheap price, to as much as you want to
                   sand this winter, Manitobans could try      invest in it.”
                   something a little different – and cheaper.  There   are  ice-ﬁshing  derbies
                    There are a number of activities people can do  throughout the winter around the
                   outside this winter for a staycation in the  province, including one on Pelican
                   province, said Colin Ferguson, president and  Lake, one on Rock Lake, and one on
                   CEO of Travel Manitoba.                     Killarney Lake.
                    “If you want to take the family skiing up in  “There’s lots of places and lots of
                   Asessippi for example, or head out to the   opportunities to go ice ﬁshing, and
                   Whiteshell (provincial park) Falcon trails, you’re  if someone wants to try ice ﬁshing
                   virtually in a cabin on a secluded lake,” Ferguson  I have never met an ice ﬁsherman
                   said. “In the north, you don’t even have to go  yet who wouldn’t be more than
                   that far north; some of the best ice ﬁshing exists  willing to drill a hole for somebody
                   on Lake Winnipeg.                           to try it,” he said.
                    Ice ﬁshing is a great activity to do close to  Besides ice ﬁshing, the north is also
                   home during long Manitoba winters, local    great for snowmobiling and cross-
                   ﬁsherman Clarence Sawatzky said.            country skiing, Ferguson said.
                    “Years ago, I kind of decided that I’m going to  “These are phenomenal opportunities,
                   live in Manitoba and enjoy, and I might as well  and people are starting to take note of them
                   enjoy the outside in general,” Sawatzky said.   and starting to experience them.”
                    “It’s just another dimension to summertime  For people in the Brandon area interested in
                   ﬁshing. Our winters are long, and if we don’t ﬁll  a quiet weekend away, there’s also the
                   it with different things, multiple things, then it  Wasagaming town site up by Clear Lake that’s
                   can feel even longer.”                      open on a year-round basis.
                    One of the nice things about it is it can be as  For a higher-end trip, staycationers could also
                   expensive or as inexpensive as you want, he  make the journey up to Churchill, he said. VIA
                   said. Although many activities will become  Rail service for passengers has also resumed
                   commercialized with, “You have to have this,  this month. First Air makes two trips to
                   you have to have that,” for ice ﬁshing, it’s not  Churchill from Winnipeg daily. One leaves at
                   necessary.                                  7:30 a.m. and arrives at 9:30 a.m., and one
                    “I know a guy who has ﬁshed on Rock Lake all  leaves at 4 p.m. and arrives at 8:30 p.m..
                   his life, and he ﬁshes with a simple stick and  “(There’s) polar bear viewing, Beluga
                   string and a jig. He’ll go down to the lake and  whale viewing or northern lights
                   ﬁnd where somebody else has drilled a hole or  viewing.”
                   watches for somebody to leave an area, then  Staycations are growing in
                   he’ll just go in and ﬁsh out of the same holes,” he  popularity, as those living in the
                   said. “So, you can go  ﬁshing for a relatively  province realize the great many








              18]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Destinations_Asessippi_Layout 1  18-12-04  5:56 PM  Page 6













                                                      things Manitoba     something in Brandon, they’re eating in the
                                                      has to offer.       restaurants and staying in the hotels, they’re
                                                       “People    are     experiencing more of what Brandon has to
                                                     seeing that there’s  offer.”
                                                     more and more          The fair, called the Royal Manitoba Winter
                                                    opportunities within  Fair, will be held from March 25 to March 30
                                                   the   province  of     at the Keystone Centre, and is held annually
                                                  Manitoba to explore,”   each year. It includes food and lifestyles trade
                                                he said, not only for     shows, a horse show and a cattle show.
                                              outside winter adventures,    Regardless of where they’re going in the
                                            but inside activities too  –  province, taking a staycation has many
                                         many of which are in Winnipeg.   beneﬁts, he said.
                                       “I would encourage people who have   “It’s less expensive, there’s not a lot of hotel
                                  not really spent time in Winnipeg to come  accommodations and it’s easy access to a lot
                                   into Winnipeg and see what it has to   of product,” he said.
                                   offer,” he said. “That’s an all-year-round  It’s also beneﬁcial for the province when
                                    thing; come in and experience all of the  Manitobans travel within their own province,
                                    attractions that exist within the city.”  he said.
                                     The Canadian Museum for Human          “It’s a big part of the tourism revenue that’s
                                    Rights opened up a few years ago, he  generated on an annual basis in Manitoba.
                                   said, and there was also some          I think it (accounts for) about 70 per cent of
                                   expansions made to the Manitoba        the total volume of business on an annual
                                      Museum. Hockey fans can take in the  basis, and the tourism industry is a 1.6 billion
                                         Winnipeg Jets at Bell MTS Place.  dollar industry annually.”
                                             “People are wanting to come    There’s lots of staycation opportunities that
                                              into   Winnipeg     and     are closer than people may think, he said.
                                               experience those new         “I think we surprise a lot of people when we
                                                offers. They can spend    talk about all the things that you can do in the
                                                 some time in hotels,     province of Manitoba, regardless of the time
                                                  they spend time in      of year. I think people are starting to take a
                                                  restaurants they spend  little bit more note of it, and thinking, ‘Hey, you
                                                  time visiting other     know what, why don’t we pack up the kids or
                                                  attractions in the city.”  just go ourselves or what have you and go and
                                                   There’s lots available  experience something in our own backyard,’
                                                 to people, whether       because when you do that you just ﬁnd out
                                                they’re keen on doing     how amazing this province is.’”
                                               something inside the city,   For other suggestions on where to go this
                                              or travelling outside of it to  year for a staycation within the province, there
                                            go camping or booking a resort  are a number of different places that are
                                         in a provincial park.            advertised on Travel Manitoba’s website.
                                       As well, Manitoba residents from the  “There’s lots of things to do in the city of
                                     Winnipeg area frequently come to     Winnipeg and throughout the province of
                                      Brandon for a staycation for the    Manitoba,” Ferguson said. “You don’t have to
                                       Brandon Winter Fair, he said.      go away to experience something from a
                                         “Those classify as staycations   tourism perspective.”
                                        (because) they’re experiencing


                                        Photos top to bottom: The aurora borealis as  seen just outside Brandon (Tim Smith); Earl McComb
                                        digs a ﬁshing hole at the annual Pelican Lake ice-ﬁshing derby in March 2018 (Michael Lee); The
                                        Canadian Museum for Human Rights in Winnipeg (George Fischer/submitted); Two polar bears hang
                                        out by a couple of tundra buggies in Churchill (Travel Manitoba/submitted).
                                                                                                                    19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[3714541_CBI_WeCare_Layout 1  18-12-05  9:55 AM  Page 1





















                                                          When you work with us – as a client, a customer, a referral agency
                   WE OFFER:                              or employer – you have a partner. A partner who is totally
                   Personal Care                          committed to excellence and organizing expertise around your
                   Hospital Sitting                       needs. By continually learning and developing new ways of
                   Companionship                          coordinating and delivering care, we improve access to services
                   Homemaking Help                        and healthcare outcomes. We provide the peace of mind you and
                   Accompaniment to Appointments          your loved ones need – Improving health. Enriching lives.






                  The care you need,

                                   when and where you need it.









































                              cbi.ca              204-727-4222     1540B Rosser Avenue, Brandon, MB

                                                  • FREE PARKING   • WHEELCHAIR ACCESSIBLE]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Dashing Through The Snow_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:22 PM  Page 1



































                                                                                    Story & Photos by Chelsea Kemp]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Dashing Through The Snow_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:23 PM  Page 2













                                                                                    ith a fresh dusting of snow on the
                                                                                    ground, paws crunching on the
                                                                            Wtrail, tail wagging like crazy and his
                                                                            best friend at his side one year old Husky
                                                                            Spirit is ready to hit the skijoring trail with his
                                                                            owner Di Ingram.
                                                                             An avid cross country skier and lover of
                                                                            dogs, Ingram was looking for an outdoor
                                                                            activity that encompassed both.
                                                                             “I had a dog and he had to come too,” Ingram
                                                                            exclaimed, “I just want my dog with me.”
                                                                             Finding skijouring to be the perfect ﬁt she
                                                                            embraced the art of the sport 12 years ago
                                                                            and has not looked back since. Skijoring is
                                                                            cross-country skiing with ones dog, with
                                                                            both working together as a team to ride the
                                                                            trail.
                                                                             Skijoring offers the chance to get out in
                                                                            nature, with a companion that enjoys the trip
                                                                            it as much as she does.
                                                                             “It’s being outside, it’s healthy for your dog
                                                                            and it’s healthy for you,” Ingram explained,
                                                                            “Winters a long time in Manitoba if you don’t
                                                                            have something to look forward to… we just
                                                                            wait for the snow.”
                                                                             The biggest piece of advice Ingram
                                                                            recommends to those looking to get into
                                                                            skijoring, is to start cross country skiing ﬁrst.
                                                                             Taking the time to ﬁrst learn the techniques
                                                                            of cross country skiing builds skills and
                                                                            conﬁdence. One can then apply these
                                                                            attributes to learn to ski with a dog.
                                                                             “You gotta walk before you can run,” Ingram
                                                                            said.
                                                                             When ready to conquer the skijoring trails,
                                                                            there are special skis available that are
                                                                            similar to skate skis.
                                                                             Getting started in Skijoring is easy. Ingram
                                                                            uses a ﬂexi leash, harness, safety skijoring
                                                                            belt with a quick release and her cross
                                                                            country skis.
                                                                             “Huskies, they pull instinctively,” Ingram
                                                                            added, “You put the harness on and they
                                                                            want to go.”
                                                                             Ingram has had some tumbles out on the
                                                                            trail, but with the soft cushion of snow and
                                                                            love of the great outdoors the activity is
                                                                            addicting.
                   Di Ingram and her dog Spirit are ready to hit the skijoring trail  Keeping her dog focused is the biggest
                   on Tuesday, Nov. 20, 2018. (Chelsea Kemp)
                                                                            challenge Ingram faces on the trail. She
                                                                            works to keep her dog from getting


              22]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Dashing Through The Snow_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:23 PM  Page 3













                   distracted, listening to her directions and
                   commands.
                    “They can stop and change direction on a
                   dime and when you are skiing behind them –
                   they do that very quickly,” Ingram chuckled.
                    With time the two work as well oiled
                   machine, Ingram said, with the two learning
                   to work together.
                    An experienced outdoors woman and dog
                   owner, Ingram has a good idea on what could
                   distract her furry companion. Her aim is to
                   anticipate what may distract her dog ﬁrst.
                    Although at times, she can end up in a big
                   heap.
                    Her craziest story involves her old dog
                   Scotty. The duo were out for a ride at dusk
                   when they encountered a herd of deer. The
                   deer, spooked by Ingram and Scotty, took
                   ﬂight away from the duo.
                    Scotty took off right after them.
                    “I’m attached so I go too,” Ingram laughed,
                   “We had a bit of white knuckle ride.”
                    The adrenaline-ﬁlled ride left Ingram
                   unharmed, but inspired her to get a quick
                   release for the harness so she can free
                   herself in case of a similar event.
                    “You have to be safe for yourself and your
                   dog,” Ingram said.
                    Skijoring offers the chance to let out your
                   inner adrenaline junkie, with the opportunity
                   to go on more curvy trails and twisty turns.
                   The more a person rides with their dog the
                   easier it gets, as the canines learn to follow
                   the trails.
                    A frequent visitor of the many trails in the
                   Turtle  Mountains,  Sprucewoods,  the
                   Brandon Hills, Riding Mountain National
                   Park and down by Wheat City Gold Course,
                   Ingram said there are a variety of places to
                   visit and skijor.
                    Trails are similar to ones that would be
                   found cross-country skiing. They are tracked
                   and packed; having the packed trails helps to
                   prevent build up of snow in dogs paws.
                    Skijorers avoid riding cross country ski trails
                   out of respect, because the dogs paws can
                   break down the grooves designed for cross
                   country skiers.
                    “We respect where they say no dogs for
                   skijoring,” Ingram explained.
                                                                           Alyssa Fletcher and her dog November go for a kick sled ride on
                                                                                        Monday, Nov. 12, 2018. (Chelsea Kemp)
                                                                                                                    23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Dashing Through The Snow_Layout 1  18-12-04  5:32 PM  Page 4
















                    However, you can visit
                   the back country when
                   you skijor, as long as
                   you bring wider skis.
                    Skiing       for
                   enjoyment, Ingram
                   and Spirit can
                   travel upwards of
                   25 kilometres in
                   a single outing,
                   with the duo
                   loving every trip.
                    “He gets to
                   really run, when
                   I’m skiing,” Ingram
                   laughed, “Especially
                   down the hill, it
                   would just be white
                   knuckles.”
                    While Westman does
                   not have a large skijoring
                   community, Ingram has seen
                   the community grow over the
                   years. There has also been a group
                   of kick sledders emerge in the area.
                    Kick sleds offer a family friendly
                   alternative to skijoring, allowing participants to
                   ride longer straighter trails with young kids.     “She’s excited to go, she knows we’re going to go out
                    Waiting somewhat patiently for the weather to turn,  on an adventure,” Fletcher laughed. “She loses her
                   Brandon mom Alyssa Fletcher is willing it to snow so  mind, she’s pretty pumped.”
                   she can get out on the skijoring trails.           Fletcher skijors with back country skis, giving her
                    Fletcher ﬁrst began kick sledding three years ago,  the ability to go off trail and ski closer to home.
                   getting her  ﬁrst pair of skis for skijoring last  “It’s just a really good outdoor option,” Fletcher
                   Christmas.                                        beamed, “I just love being outdoors with my dogs.”
                    “We just used the dogs that we had to ﬁgure out if it  November, a three legged dog, is able to pull the sled
                   was a sport for us,” Fletcher said.               using a special harness. This will be November’s last
                    A kick sled is signiﬁcantly smaller then a traditional  year as a kick sled dog.
                   dog sled, using one or two dogs instead of a team.  Having always had an interest in skijoring, Fletcher
                    The sled is propelled forward by kicking, with the  was inspired to pick up a pair of skis after watching
                   dog helping to provide a little extra speed.      videos on YouTube.
                    Unlike skijoring, kick sledding is not as dependent on  Researching skijoring, she learned about kick
                   snow. It can be used even on a slick sidewalk.    sledding, and found it was the perfect  ﬁt for her
                    Kick sledding with her dog November, Fletcher    family, so every member can get out in the snow.
                   enjoys the sport. November gets visibly excited when  “It’s just a great time,” Fletcher said. “Getting to the
                   she sees the harness, knowing it’s time to hit the trails  trail is the hard part.”
                   and work.                                          Fletcher’s Border Collie puppy McCoy, is her new
                    When the Brandon Hills are in sight, November    sled dog in training. She is excited to see what McCoy
                   bristles with excitement, knowing she is about to race  can do on the trail.
                   around the trails.

              24]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Dashing Through The Snow_Layout 1  18-12-04  2:30 PM  Page 5
















                                                                                              She has found that
                                                                                              interest in skijoring
                                                                                               and kick sledding is
                                                                                                on the rise, with
                                                                                                 many of her clients
                                                                                                 asking about the
                                                                                                  sport. It doesn’t
                                                                                                  take  long   to
                                                                                                  throw a harness
                                                                                                  on and attach
                                                                                                  the dog. The
                                                                                                  hard   part  is
                                                                                                  shaping a dog’s
                                                                                                  behaviour    to
                                                                                                 successfully skijor
                                                                                                or kick sled.
                                                                                                 Using a system of
                                                                                               commands, Fletcher
                                                                                             trains her dog in
                                                                                            targeting and queuing.
                                                                                          Targeting is training a dog
                                                                                        to touch targets; queuing is
                                                                                      building on targeted training so
                                                                                    a dog learns to recognize speciﬁc
                                                                                 commands combined with training a
                                                                             dog follow through on shaped behaviours.
                                                                         These training techniques can be used to build a
                    Having seen some skijorers and kick sledders reach  foundation to go kick sledding or skijoring with your
                   around 20 kilometres per hour, Fletcher is excited to  dog.
                   see how fast McCoy can go.                         “They’re really versatile, you’re not looking so much
                    Almost any dog can participate in the sport, though  for the trails,” Fletcher said.
                   she recommends a medium to large-sized dog for kick  Calling herself a beginner, Fletcher loves the sport
                   sledding, – she does have a friend who skijors with a  and hopes to see it grow in the community.
                   Corgi.                                             Finding kick sledding a nice alternative for new
                    The smaller the dog the easier they are to control,  moms or moms with young kids, Fletcher said it
                   but you have to work harder.                      encompasses the fun of skijoring, but it's easier to get
                    “You’re not just standing there being pulled,”   out on the trail with a young family.
                   Fletcher said.                                     Fletchers daughters Edith, three, and Rose, one,
                    Fletcher was drawn to the the spot of kick sledding  love getting out as much as their mom.
                   because it was something she could do with her kids  “I put Rose in her big snow suit and put her in the
                   and her dogs.                                     kick sled and November and I would go,” Fletcher
                    Interest in the sport is growing, said Fletcher, who  chuckled, “Rose really loved it.”
                   has hosted workshops at her shop Grassroots        For Fletcher it's important for her kids to see her
                   Grooming in the past that were well attended. Her  outside having fun and being healthy, and offers the
                   only wish is that Brandon had a bigger community  chance for her dogs to have a job and have fun.
                   that could help beginners learn the ropes.         “It’s what I love to do, it’s my passion,” Fletcher
                    “It’s not uncommon for people to ask about it, it’s  exclaimed with a smile.
                   just really easy to bring the family,” Fletcher said.


                                                                                                                    25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Destinations_Asessippi_Layout 1  18-12-04  5:50 PM  Page 1






















                                                                                          By Melissa Verge














                            hether you're carving a trail on the snow-  When Trending visited in November, when the
                            covered ski slopes, or sitting beside a warm  resort was still closed, the season of hills crowded
                   Wﬁreplace sipping hot chocolate topped with       with skiers and snowboarders ready for a downhill
                   ﬂuffy marshmallows, Asessippi Ski Area & Resort   rush and some wintry entertainment wasn’t far off.
                   prides itself in offering the public a wide variety of  The resort was slated to open on Dec. 7.
                   activities.                                        To help celebrate their 20th year in business, they’ve
                    “We have something for everyone,” says the resort's  had some interior renovations done, said Wanda
                   assistant manager, Shannon Johnston.              Guay, sales and marketing manager at the resort.
                    The resort is located approximately two hours     “We just decided it was time for a facelift,” Guay said.
                   northwest of Brandon, near the small town of Inglis,  “Everything is updated to kind of draw in people a
                   and just past Russell.                            little bit more. Our food court used to be quite closed
                                                                     off, but now it’s a nice big open area, which is just
                                                                     welcoming for people to come in.”
                                                                      The area was under construction when Trending
                                                                     visited, as workers bustled around the quiet resort
                                                                     getting all the details ﬁnished. It was expected to be
                                                                     completed by December.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Destinations_Asessippi_Layout 1  18-12-04  5:50 PM  Page 2













                    Also new this year is the addition of a barista station
                   and a bar area. They have a new tap system for a
                   localized bar that will offer  ﬁve  ﬂights of beer,
                   Johnston said.
                    “We’re working with a local brewery, Farmery, to
                   work on maybe an Asessippi beer or offer local ﬂights
                   of beer,” she said.
                    They’ve also updated a cabin that they have mid-hill,
                   where visitors can spend a few minutes out of the cold
                   by the ﬁre and get something to eat.
                    “(It’s great for) whether you’re coming out to ski for
                   the day, snowboard, or you’re bringing the grandkids
                   and you want somewhere cosy to hang out,” she said.
                    Outside, the resort has also made some updates with
                   their snow-making machinery in the hope that, moving
                   forward, the resort will be able to open earlier. It's a












                   project that they have been talking about for a few
                   years, Johnston said.
                    Snow was already being deployed at the resort in
                   November, spraying out onto the open hill and
                   creating a winter wonderland.
                    “In the past, we’ve had to wait for a certain
                   temperature to be at least -10 C or -11 C, and the
                   humidity had to be low, because basically we’d shoot
                   water through a big metal shoot into the air as high as
                   we could, so it could freeze on the way down,” she said.
                    With the snow-making upgrades, they can now
                   create powder at a warmer temperature.
                    “There’s some technology that if you mix compressed
                   air with water then it’s going to change the freezing
                   point of the water, it’s going to shoot it higher in the
                   sky, so that allows you to make snow at higher
                   temperatures,” she said. “The ideal once we get it all
                   working and that sort of thing is to be able to make
                   snow between -2 C and -5 C, so we don't have to wait
                   until that - 11 C temperature.”
                    They have ski hills for different levels, with
                   challenging, intermediate and easy trails. There is also  Photos top to bottom: Shannon Johnston, assistant
                   a tubing park, two terrain parks, and an expanded     manager, and Wanda Guay, sales and marketing
                   bunny hill with a magic carpet at the resort.         manager at Asessippi Ski Area & Resort stand under a
                    Throughout the season, there are activities for      snow-making machine on a chilly day in November
                   guests to do inside too, Guay said, including a small gift  (Melissa Verge); A snowboarder gets some air at
                                                                         Asessippi (Matt Goerzen); Shannon Johnston shows off
                   shop.                                                 skis available for rental at the resort (Melissa Verge).

                                                                                                                    27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Destinations_Asessippi_Layout 1  18-12-04  5:50 PM  Page 3











                                                                      “They’re just happy to do that.”
                                                                      There’s also the Powder Keg Pub, which is often
                                                                     quite busy after a day on the runs.
                                                                      Each year, between 46,000 to 55,000 guests come
                                                                     out to see what the resort has to offer, or to return to
                                                                     the slopes.
                                                                      Coming up this year, they will be open late over
                                                                     Christmas break until 7 p.m. every night leading up to
                                                                     New Year’s, Johnson said. On New Year’s Eve, they
                                                                     will have a celebration on the hill.
                                                                      It’s a unique countdown, Johnston said.
                                                                      “There’s a midnight torch run, so there’s two
                                                                     ﬁrework shows,” she said. “The last ﬁrework show is a
                                                                     midnight countdown, so we turn all the lights off and
                                                                     you ski and snowboard the runs with glow sticks
                                                                     under the ﬁreworks.”
                                                                      There are other events taking place throughout the
                                                                     season, including on family day when they will have
                                                                     their version of “The Amazing Race” put on for
                                                                     families, called the Asessippi Amazing Race. There are
                                                                     different activities set up that competitors can try,
                                                                     and it’s like a big scavenger hunt that’s open to
                                                                     everybody at the resort, Guay said.
                                                                      “The ﬁrst year we did it we had eight or 10 teams do
                                                                     it, and it runs throughout all day, and it’s open to all
                                                                     ages,” she said. “We have the real hard competitors
                                                                     that go into it, and then we have mom and kids that
                                                                     join, and it’s just things that they ﬁnd on the hill  to be
                                                                     able to get that bragging rights.”
                                                                      Recently, they started offering kite boarding at the
                                                                     resort, where the participants can learn more about
                                                                     the sport in a classroom environment, and then get a
                   Top: A skier tears down the Asessippi slopes (Matt  chance to go out and try it in the ﬁeld.
                   Goerzen). Bottom: Skiers and snowboarders make     “You have a kite that you’re attached to with a
                   their way up the chairlifts at Asessippi (Brandon Sun).  harness, and you have skis on and you just go through
                                                                     the ﬁeld,” Johnston said. “It can be ﬂat, and you can
                                                                     harness the wind with it.”
                                                                      For those who are looking to make it more than just
                    “It’s got lots of unique items in there, as well as  a day trip, although Asessippi doesn't have
                   jackets and outside gear, ski pants, that type of thing,”  accommodations directly on site, there are cabins
                   Guay said.                                        nearby that are rented out on Air B&B, as well as local
                    There are  ﬁreplaces at each one of their seating  hotels in the Roblin and Russell area.
                   areas inside, as well as a book corner where people can  For anyone new coming to the resort, the staff at
                   leave their books, and a virtual reality gaming area.  Asessippi can help plan a stay for you, catered to what
                    “There’s lots of people that we’ve discovered in the  you want, Johnson said.
                   last couple of years at our events, people that just  “We ﬁrst try to ﬁnd out what you’re looking for, what
                   want to come out and hang out for the day, not    you want to do,” she said. “Do you want to relax, if you
                   necessarily to ski or snowboard,” Guay said. “So, we  want to go skiing, and then we’ll build something for
                   just wanted to make more offerings.”              you from there. We suggest the best place for you to
                    Often, visitors who will come in and sit at one of  stay, build some activities (around that), whether it’s
                   their seating areas by the ﬁreplace and read a book,  a ski or snowboard lesson, or tubing we just try to
                   she said.                                         build what our guests want.”

              28]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[W
               Take a
                  Walk Thru Ouralk Thru Our
                  W
         3714540_WindsorPlywood_Layout 1  18-12-05  11:56 AM  Page 1           WOODSOODS





                  The Wood That Made Us Famous
























































                                                          Walk Thru Ouralk Thru Our WOODSWOODSWOODSWOODSWOODS
                                                         Take a
                                                         Take a
                                                         Take a
                                                          W Walk Thru Ouralk Thru Ourur
                                                          W Walk Thru O








                                    th
                       1840 – 18 Street North, Brandon
                                   204-728-4243
                    Fax: 204-727-2619 • Toll-Free: 1-800-224-7506
                  www.windsorplywood.com • sales@windsorplywood.net
                    Store Hours: Mon. – Fri. 8:00 am – 5:30 pm; Sat. 9:00 am – 5:00 pm
                 Some items may be cash & carry and we reserve the right to limit quantities. All items may not be exactly as illustrated.]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Million Dollar Home_Layout 1  18-12-05  10:39 AM  Page 1

















                                                   HOMES











                                                                                   Story and photos by Bud Robertson

                          ot a million dollars burning a hole in your  the liberty of attending a recent open house to see
                          pocket? -If you’re thinking of buying a house  what makes a million-dollar home worth $1 million.
                   Gin Brandon with all that money, you’re in         Listed at just under $1 million — $995,000 to be
                   luck.                                             precise — this property at 25 Southview Dr. is state
                    Take a leisurely stroll — or a brisk walk in winter —  of the art.
                   in southwest Brandon’s Brookwood neighbourhood     “It’s really spectacular,” said Re/Max Valleyview
                   and you’re sure to discover many homes in the     listing agent Graham Garden who, along with his wife
                   million-dollar or close-to-it range.              and co-listing partner Christie Garden, gave us a tour
                    But since you can’t just waltz into one of these  recently of the 2,404-square-foot, four-bedroom
                   homes, unless you’re a friend or a burglar, we took  four-bathroom home built in 2012.











































              30]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Million Dollar Home_Layout 1  18-12-05  10:39 AM  Page 2









                    “This home was a whole year in the design phase   The finished triple-car garage has in-floor heating.
                   before the hole was dug and construction started,”  As they continued their tour inside, Christie noted
                   Graham said. “It was two years from start to ﬁnish.”  the house is completely automated, with
                    When you step into the vestibule, you are        pushbuttons on the walls of the living room and
                   immediately struck by the view into the massive   bedrooms to control music, security and lighting.
                   open-concept kitchen.                              “At the back entry, one button actually shuts off
                    This house is no problem for tall people, with 10-  every light in the house,” Christie said.
                   foot ceilings on both levels, embedded with some 140        Christie points to a phone-charging station in one
                   LED pot lights.                                   of the three upstairs bedrooms that connects to the
                    To the left of the entrance way is the living room,  sound system throughout the house. The stations
                   featuring remote-control blinds — a feature repeated  are mounted in the bedrooms and the downstairs
                   in the kitchen and master bedroom — and a two-way  gym, so you can enjoy some tunes while working
                   gas ﬁreplace that faces into the kitchen.         out.
                    As you would expect at this price point, the kitchen  Automation can even be found in an unassuming,
                   is top-of-the-line, with stainless steel appliances, a gas  two-piece washroom down the hallway off the
                   range, built-in oven and microwave and a dishwasher.  kitchen. Step into the room and — voila! — the light
                   One feature you might not ﬁnd everywhere, though,  automatically turns itself on and off.
                   is a quartz counter top that continues to the ﬂoor  Enter the large master bedroom and you’ll find a
                   with so-called waterfall edges.                   seating area to enjoy some solitude and a door
                    Off the kitchen is a three-season sunroom with ash  leading to the outside patio.
                   hardwood ﬂooring (found throughout the home) and   Off the master is a large en suite with heated
                   an open-air patio with vinyl decking for barbecuing.  floors to keep your toes toasty, an enormous soaker
                    “There is not a piece of exterior wood anywhere  tub and walk-in shower with a rain shower head.
                   outside,” Graham pointed out. “It is all either metal or  Beyond the enclosed toilet is a large walk-in closet
                   stucco.”                                          with vinyl wrapped cabinets and drawers.
                    Speaking of outside, there are in-ground sprinklers  As she continued the tour, Christie pointed to the
                   front and rear and driveway lighting for arriving or  massive ash doors throughout the home, strong
                   leaving in the dark.                              enough to hold off a small invading army.]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Million Dollar Home_Layout 1  18-12-05  10:39 AM  Page 3


























































                    Back toward the kitchen area, a staircase with
                   custom stainless steel railings and embedded step
                   lights leads to the equally impressive walk-out lower
                   level, bathed in natural sunlight.
                    If you plan to venture outside in the cold weather,
                   three commercial heaters warm the large exterior
                   patio.
                    The family room features more heated  ﬂooring,
                   custom industrial carpeting and — if you get tired of
                   talking to each other — a television set swivels from
                   the adjacent bar into the room.
                    Speaking of which, the bar has two refrigerators, a
                   microwave oven, a dishwasher and an ice maker. You
                   can haul out a cold one and slide it over to your guests
                   seated along the quartz counter top.              mirrors, so you can admire your buff (or not-yet buff)
                    “The bar is pretty awesome,” Christie smiled.    physique as you’re working out.
                    Just off the bar is a movie room with surround    The three-piece downstairs washroom also features
                   sound.                                            automatic lighting and a walk-in shower.
                    On the other side of the lower level there’s a gym  Past the fourth bedroom, at the end of the hallway
                   with industrial rubber matting and ﬂoor-to-ceiling  is the custom laundry room.



              32]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Million Dollar Home_Layout 1  18-12-05  10:39 AM  Page 4









                    “Make every girl jealous,” Christie said noting the
                   custom drying racks, a massive amount of cupboards,  By the numbers…
                   a heated  ﬂoor and even a television to watch
                   programs between loads.                             Unlike super-heated housing markets in Toronto
                    Wrapping up their tour, Graham, who has been in   and Vancouver, Brandon tends toward “steady as
                   the real estate business for 18 years (Christie for 15  she goes,” says the executive ofﬁcer for Brandon
                   years), said he’s been a witness to the growth of  Area REALTORS.
                   million-dollar homes in Brandon.                    Jen Pearson said Brandon’s economy is
                    “As Realtors, we are fortunate to have the        dependent more on agriculture than the busts and
                   opportunity to be a part of selling somebody else’s  booms of Alberta’s oil industry.
                   dream,” he said.                                    “Here, it’s always been fairly stable,” Pearson said.
                                                                       That’s not to say the Wheat City doesn’t have its
                                                                      own mini-booms.
                                                                       Pearson, who started out as a Realtor in 2007,
                                                                      said business was in high gear back then.
                                                                       That year, 679 residential homes sold in the city
                                                                      of Brandon. Some 450 homes have been sold so
                                                                      far this year.
                                                                       “It was a very busy market back then,” Pearson
                                                                      said.
                                                                       She noted the arrival of immigrant families has
                                                                      helped boost the local market.
                                                                       This year, 11 homes listed at $900,000 or more
                                                                      were on the market as of the third week of
                                                                      November. None over $1 million has been sold so
                                                                      far this year, Pearson said.
                                                                       Statistics compiled by Brandon Area REALTORS
                                                                      show the average selling price of a home in
                                                                      Brandon to the end of September was $276,682.
                                                                      This includes duplexes, townhouses, single
                                                                      detached and detached homes. It does not include
                                                                      condos or mobile homes.
                                                                       The average price of a Brandon home 10 years
                                                                      ago was $196,556.
                                                                       Going back even farther, it becomes evident that
                                                                      buying a home in Brandon was once a much more
                                                                      affordable prospect.
                                                                       The real estate board’s statistics show the
                                                                      average selling price of an abode in 2003 was
                                                                      $108,224.
                                                                       Pearson noted building costs have also grown
                                                                      over the years, helping to drive up the price of
                                                                      homes.
                                                                       Meanwhile, Century 21’s annual national study
                                                                      of trends and changes in the price per square foot
                                                                      of residential properties in communities across
                                                                      Canada found condos and detached homes in
                                                                      Brandon are among the least expensive in the
                                                                      Prairies, valued at $196 and $248 per square foot
                                                                      respectively.
                                                                       By comparison, condos and detached homes in
                                                                      Winnipeg were $261 per square foot and $282
                                                                      per square foot, respectively.


                                                                                                                    33]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Destinations_Asessippi_Layout 1  18-12-05  11:00 AM  Page 4

























                   Story by Melissa Verge

                    Canadians desperately ﬂeeing their snow-covered
                   homeland in favour of warm sandy beaches has been a
                   trend for decades.
                    And, they’ve consistently been travelling to three
                   major destinations to make their escape, said Morgan
                   Bell, a spokesperson with WestJet. The top destinations
                   to which Canadians are traveling are still Cancun, Mex.,
                   Puerto Vallarta, Mex. and Las Vegas, NV.
                    “Year over year we continue to see that increased
                   demand (for those destinations),” Bell said. “We see the
                   demand, that’s why we do have the frequency available
                   to take Canadians to those destinations.”
                    WestJet offers multiple ﬂights a day leaving from
                   Winnipeg and going to Cancun, as well as going from
                   Winnipeg to Puerto Vallarta.
                    “Those beautiful beaches and the Mayan Ruins
                   probably make it consistently one of our most popular
                   winter destinations,” she said.
                    Las Vegas is also quite popular, and is a hot spot all year
                   round, she said. Winter time is no exception.
                    “The endless activity options for all ages and budgets,
                   entertainment, food and dining experience – (that)
                   really drives that trafﬁc down to Las Vegas,” she said.
                    There are different ways people book their vacations,
                   with all-inclusive options, or the option to just book a  “We really have options for every budget. There is
                   ﬂight.                                            really something for everybody, if they’re looking to get
                    “That all inclusive experience gives guests the upfront  away, they can do it on a low cost budget.”
                   costs for their entire trip,” she said. “We always see that  Flair Air is another way Canadians can escape the cold
                   there’s a lot of people that love that they can travel  for less this winter. The low cost carrier offers ﬂights
                   there and have no unexpected surprises once they’re in  from Winnipeg to Las Vegas, Phoenix, Miami, Orlando,
                   destinations.”                                    Palm Springs and Clearwater.
                    The all inclusive bookings with WestJet vacations are  Moving forward to next year, the popularity of Mexico
                   extremely popular, she said.                      and Las Vegas is likely going to stay the same, she said.
                    “We’re deﬁnitely seeing a lot of all inclusive packages  Those destinations have been consistently popular for
                   and bookings down there because they are kind of that  them for the past ﬁve years.
                   one stop shop. With WestJet vacations, you’re      “I think it’s deﬁnitely a trend that we see Canadians
                   essentially taken care of from the minute you get on  wanting to escape and get down to those warm
                   your ﬂight, to the minute you get home.”          weather locations,” she said. “If I was to make a guess, it
                    There are also those who would just prefer to book a  would probably remain consistent that our top selling
                   ﬂight. Regardless, they can appeal to lots of different  destinations aren’t going to change again that much in
                   people, she said.                                 the next ﬁve years.”

              34]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[3714542_BrandonUniversity_Layout 1  18-12-04  3:06 PM  Page 1]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[3714526_FormanHonda_Layout 1  18-12-04  5:42 PM  Page 1]]></page></pages></Search>