<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="40"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Introducing the NEW

now available at THE BRICK!

Savour a new, more luxurious level of sleep satisfaction with this Vertuo Ultra queen foam
mattress. Made by Canadian company Zedbed. On display now at THE BRICK BRANDON!

Locally Owned & Operated  Snowpedic Technology
                          Zedbed researchers developed an innovative process to infuse
                          high-quality foam with gel crystals to keep you cool as you sleep.They
                          also allow air to circulate throughout the mattress, keeping it fresh-feeling for years.

                           127 – 7th Street • Brandon • 204-727-4366 • www.thebrick.com]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY  3

The perfect cut
for stylish lawns

  Good summer growing needs good spring mowing.                      SHOWROOM LOCATED AT:
  With spring approaching, lawn care experts point out that
not all mowing techniques are the same. ”Simply mowing            1325 PRINCESS AVE. UNIT B
your lawn is not enough,” says John Ladds, the operations
manager at Weed Man Canada. “For the healthiest, most                           CALL FOR YOUR
attractive lawns, mowing properly makes all the difference.”          PERSONALIZED SHOWROOM OR
  The pros recommend brushing up on the following best
practices:                                                                IN- HOME CONSULTATION!

KNOW WHEN TO MOW                                                                                                 Anita

  Before that first mowing, make sure that there is no standing                       Haigh brandon
water and that your grass has had a chance to air dry. Any                                724.7791
excess debris should be removed as well. Mow frequently
enough to shave the top third of your grass blades while                                      blindsbyanita.com
maintaining a mower height of 7.5 to 8.5 cm. This could mean
two to three times per week during periods of rapid growth
such as spring and fall.

TUNE IT UP

  After sitting in the shed all winter, your lawn mower could
really benefit from some care. Whether you do it yourself, or
take it in to a shop, make sure you change the oil, and check
that all cables, spark plugs, air filters, brakes and wheels are
in good condition.

STAY SHARP

  A sharp blade ensures that your mower is cutting the grass
cleanly. Improperly shorn or frayed grass is not only unsightly,
but can also make your lawn more susceptible to disease.
Remember that new mowers require sharpening too; factory-
sharpened blades are not sufficient for mowing. Mower blades
need sharpening two to three times per season. You could
consider purchasing a second blade that can be switched out
when it's time to sharpen.

TECHNIQUE RULES

  If you mow north/south one week, try east/west the next.
Alternating your mowing direction keeps grass blades growing
straight, allowing for better air circulation and light
penetration. For a professional look, mow in straight lines
and overlap your wheel's line marks slightly. Keep lawn edges
looking clean by using a trimmer to shape areas around curbs
and sidewalks.

MULCH YOUR CLIPPINGS

  For much of the year it is recommended that you use your
mower's mulching functionality, as this returns valuable
nutrients back to the soil. For the first and last mow of the
year, however, attaching your mower's bag can help keep your
lawn clean and breathing easily.

» News Canada]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

Dulux Diamond paints along with popular paint swatches at the Dulux Paints Store in Brandon. (The Brandon Sun)

Lighter and brighter for 2016

                          Wanda Kurchaba            updating window coverings.                                  green colour) popping up.
                                                      Knowing what’s popular and what this                        While some of the popular home
#BUSINESSBUZZ
                                                    season’s trends are allows homeowners                       design magazines and television
Wanda Kurchaba is a Brandon freelance writer and a  to pinpoint where to start.                                 programs are showcasing and
communications and marketing specialist. This                                                                   highlighting palettes with pastels,
column on Westman’s business community appears        Sharon Warburton, assistant manager                       Warburton says we’re not seeing that yet
each Saturday. Contact Wanda directly with any      at Dulux Paints, said the trends in paint                   in Brandon, as we’re a little bit more on
story ideas.                                        colours for 2016 is definitely taking us                    the conservative side.
» kurch@wcgwave.ca                                  away from some of the bolder colours
                                                    that we’ve seen in the past.                                  “Most people are doing a main colour
  There is often a desire in the spring and                                                                     throughout, with a feature wall —
summer to freshen things up around the                “The colours this season are a lot                        whether that’s in the living room,
house, whether that’s applying a fresh              lighter and brighter and basically include                  bedroom or other space within the
coat of paint, adding new accessories or            any colour that has grey tones. Even if it                  home,” said Warburton.
                                                    is beige, it has a grey tone to it. We’re
                                                    saying goodbye to the deep, dark colours,                     If you’re wondering where to start in
                                                    like the chocolate browns, that we had                      terms of updating your home with new
                                                    been seeing in the past few years,” said                    paint colours, it’s best to pull together
                                                    Warburton.                                                  samples of things that will stay in the
                                                                                                                room, such as flooring and countertops,
                                                      One of their most popular colours is                      fabrics or favourite accessories. From
                                                    Zeppelin (30YY 46/036), which is a mix                      there, local professionals can help to co-
                                                    of grey and beige, but Warburton said                       ordinate a colour that will suit your taste.
                                                    they are also seeing a bit of aqua (blue-]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY  5                                             Your Total Project
                                                                                Supply Store
  “I always recommend taking paint samples home to see what
the colours will look there, with the lighting that already exists.           NEW CONSTRUCTION, COMMERCIAL PROJECTS
The fluorescent lights in the store can often give the colour a               & RENOVATIONS
different look from what you’ll see at home,” said Warburton.
                                                                              • DECKS   • KITCHENS • HOUSES • CABINS
  Other paint aspects to consider are the colour of the trim, as              • FENCES  • FLOORING • GARAGES • RTM HOMES
well as the type of paint that is going on the walls. Warburton
said that the trim colours are generally still white, but if                  Customized RTM Homes
homeowners do add a bit of colour, it’s very soft.                               to suit your needs!

  In terms of finishes, 98 per cent of walls are painted with an                               Save Build Time
eggshell finish. Eggshell has 10 to 15 per cent sheen, so it helps
to hide imperfections, yet it’s scrubbable and durable.                                         We can work on your foundation
                                                                                                and RTM simultaneously, which
  To complete the look of a freshly painted room, you might                                     reduces time to build.
want to think about updating your window coverings and adding
some new accessories.                                                                          Affordable

  Anita Haigh, owner of Blinds by Anita, said she’s experiencing                                We work within your budget
similar trends regarding colour choices when it comes to window
treatments.                                                                                    Custom Designed

  “We’re seeing a lot of neutrals. For us, it’s about light and                                    We make your dreams become
airy window coverings with slight metallic threads in them, that                                   reality. Design your own floor plan
may have a silvery or charcoal hue. Clients definitely want a                                      with our in-house draftsman,choose
classy, yet casual look with something that has longevity and is                                   your own finishes and much more!
easy to maintain,” said Haigh.
                                                                              SOUTH END LUMBER LTD.
  In determining what type of window treatments to purchase
for your home, Haigh said some of the key things to consider                           We’re Your Total Project Supply Store
are:
                                                                                         FREE ESTIMATES 204-728-1570
  • Are you concerned with privacy or how much privacy do you want?
  • How much light do you want in the room/space?                                                             Toll-Free: 1-866-728-1570 • Fax: 204-571-1200
  • Are you looking for energy efficient window coverings to keep the                        1550 – 13th St • Brandon • One block south of Richmond Ave.
heat in and the cold out?
  • Is safety a concern with children and pets; should you look for cordless                              info@seltimbermart.ca • www.setimbermart.ca
options?
  “As well, UV Protection is also very important for people.
They spend a lot of money on furniture and flooring, so they
want to protect their investments and increase the life expectancy
of them,” said Haigh.
  Overall, in terms of look and feel of the window coverings,
Haigh said that her customers are wanting to have clean lines
and open up the sight line to the outside. She’s finding that there
is a desire to bring the outside in and that’s why organic materials
are so popular.
  “People like the soft window coverings and not something
that is too cold or sterile. Many of the windows that we do still
have a valance or a cornice, where it’s covered with a fabric, but
it’s not poofy. A streamlined fabric cornice will be sleek and it
offers a good way to inject a patterned fabric into the design,”
said Haigh.
  So, as we say goodbye to dusty rose with swags and wall-to-
wall drapery, we welcome more organic materials to help
accessorize and complement the popularity of the neutral colour
palettes in paint and window coverings.
  “A lot of natural materials are very big this year, like live edge
tables paired with modern chairs or accent tables, such as coffee
and end tables with a tree-based wood look and a glass top,”
said Haigh.
  “The organic look goes with the neutrals of the blinds and
paint colours that are popular right now, but where you can have
some fun is by adding bold colours to your accessories. We’re
finding that people like to add turquoise, teals, burnt oranges
and yellows for accent colours.”
» The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[6 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

Culture trek: Define your backyard

  Your backyard should be a                and desires but you want to make sure                  trends director for Lowe’s.
place to relax and escape from             contrasting patterns are not competing                 “Unlike large-scale prints with
everyday life. While vacations             with each other.                                       lots of colours, two-toned
are short–lived, choosing                                                                         geometrics in the same colour
travel inspired décor lets you               “It’s important that different patterns              family work well together.”
soak in the cultures of the                are not complex and have the same tonal
world from the comfort of                  value,” says Cindy Jardim, style and                      Tips from Cindy to
your backyard for years to                                                                        incorporate Culture Trek into
come.                                                                                             your outdoor décor:

  You can easily create the                                                                          • Textiles are a great way to
feeling of an exotic destination                                                                  instantly transform your
with warm, earthy tones and                                                                       space. Replace a few pillows
lively patterns in a range of                                                                     and add a colourful outdoor
tactile textures.                                                                                 rug.

  One of the biggest themes                                                                          • Carry colour throughout
in outdoor living this year is                                                                    the yard with storage baskets,
one that the design experts at                                                                    lanterns, candle holders and
Lowe’s have called “Culture                                                                       planters.
Trek”. It uses unique artisanal items,                                                  • Add copper details to enhance this
whether acquired abroad or locally, to                                                look or splurge on a fire pit to give you
serve as a great jumping off point for a                                              the feeling of warm destinations on a
global-themed design.                                                                 cool evening.
                                                                                      » News Canada
  Mixing and matching different styles
can become a reflection of personal flair

     HARDWOOD,
   CORK & LUXURY
  VINYL FLOORING

HUGE AREA RUG
     GALLERY

CUSTOM KITCHEN &
  BATH CABINETRY

1003 - 13TH ST. • BRANDON • 204-726-3323 www.sunsetcreek.ca]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY  7

How to                                                                                          towards all
baby-proof your                                                                              booked in 2016
home from top to                                                 BOOK YOUR
bottom                                                           APPOINTMENT                  Keeping
                                                                 WITH US TODAY
  As babies grow, so does       on hard surface floors. While    BY CALLING               Wfoerst3ma0nyWeaarrsm!
their curiosity with the world  you might not see your toilet
around them. As your little     as a danger, the water inside    204.728.5900           Offer Expires December 31, 2016
one approaches each new         it and the lid can be a hazard
phase of life from crawling,    for your child. Try installing   I                              towards all
to walking and climbing,        a toilet lock to prevent little                              booked in 2016
basic household items can       fingers from getting smashed                BOOK YOUR
turn into potential hazards.    and to guard against too               APPOINTMENT
Make your house baby-safe       much curiosity.                      WITH US TODAY
by ensuring that any item
your baby encounters won’t        Window coverings are                      BY CALLING
hurt them.                      often a safety risk that is
                                overlooked. Hunter Douglas        204.728.5900
  First, consider the big       window fashions offers a
picture. Do all of your smoke   range of motorized options,      Celebrang 30 years serving you! Offer Expires December 31, 2016
and carbon monoxide alarms      like the Skyline Gliding
have batteries and have you     Window Panels, that              204-728-5900 | 945 – 24th Street, Brandon
tested them recently to ensure  eliminate the lift cords and                  www.raysﬁreplaces.com
they are working? Make sure     allow the product to be
you have baby gates at the      operated at the touch of a                       Mitchell Poole
bottom and top of every         button. Other window safety
staircase and place electrical  tips include placing your                              945 - 24th Street, Brandon, MB R7B 1Y5
covers on all outlets. Check    child’s crib and other                                 Phone: 204-728-5900 Cell: 204-729-7890
for sharp corners on your       furniture away from windows                            mitchell@raysﬁreplaces.com
furniture by getting down on    and installing childproof
the baby’s level to evaluate    screens or window guards to
areas that could do harm.       prevent falls.

  Next is the kitchen. This is    While you may have
a room where parents are        covered all of the obvious
typically distracted when       issues, consider the small
preparing, cooking or           things, too. Vacuum often to
cleaning so it’s important to   remove any small items that
eliminate safety risks that     could be a choking hazard for
could occur even if you turn    your baby, cover radiators
your back. Use bottom           and heating vents to prevent
cabinets for items that are     burns and clear cosmetics
safe for a baby to find like    and hair products off your
pots and pans and move          counters as they can pose a
cleaning supplies and           poison risk.
anything with harsh
chemicals to higher               We all want the best for our
cupboards.                      babies, so keep these tips in
                                mind to ensure they stay safe
  Safeguard against slips in    in all areas of your home.
the bathroom by using non-      » News Canada
stick mats in the bathtub and]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

Make sure that the tree’s mature size can be accommodated in the spot where you want to plant it. (Albert Parsons/For the Sun)

      Tree choices are endless

                            Albert Parsons      Besides the size and shape of the tree       height — and width — of the tree you
                                              itself, it is helpful to consider carefully    are considering buying.
GONE GARDENIN’                                what the foliage is like, so that you get
                                              the effect that you are looking for.             Besides size, the shape of the tree is
Albert Parsons lives, writes, and gardens in                                                 important, but you will have to consider
Minnedosa.                                      The tree size is important because you       its function before you decide on its
» communitynews@brandonsun.com                want it to fit the space allocated to it even  shape. Part of the consideration will also
                                              when it reaches its mature size. A             be that the shape of the tree sometimes
  Choosing a tree is no easy task —           massive Basswood tree will not fit             dictates how much space it will take up.
particularly if the tree is going to be a     between two houses that are only metres        For example, a columnar tree such as a
specimen tree that is to take centre stage    apart, while a small Mayday tree might         Brandon columnar cedar will take up
in the landscape.                             be dwarfed by very large neighbouring          much less space than a wider ornamental
                                              trees.                                         crab-apple.

                                                Too many trees are planted without             If you want the tree to screen an
                                              taking the mature size of the tree into        unsightly view, you want the tree to have
                                              account and then gardeners have to cut         a thick growth habit and to perhaps be
                                              and prune to try — often with little           evergreen so that its function can be
                                              success — to keep the tree within the          served all year round. You will also want
                                              bounds of its allotted space.                  such a tree to have branches right to the
                                                                                             ground and not be bare-trunked for
                                                Read the tags on trees at the nursery        several metres.
                                              carefully and take note of the mature]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                            9

  A shade tree must have a suitable shape so that its canopy
will provide adequate shade. You want the tree to be umbrella-
shaped, not tall and thin.

  If the tree is to be located near a driveway or patio, you want
one that is not constantly shedding twigs and branches, like
willow trees often do, or fruit — a characteristic of many fruit
trees.

  Consider the bark of the tree so that you get the most interest
that you can from a single purchase. Some trees have very
colourful or interesting texture to their bark, which is doubly
important in the winter —- as is the shape of the tree when it
has no leaves and the architecture of the tree are very visible.

  An Amur cherry has lovely cinnamon-coloured bark that has
the added feature of peeling just like paper birch do. The almost
white bark of birch trees can also be stunning. Many maples
and elms have deep grooves in their bark that create wonderful
texture.

  Don’t forget to notice whether the tree has flowers or fruit,
and how showy and long lasting they are. A mountain ash tree
has significant white bloom, and its big clusters of berries are
a prominent feature of the tree from soon after the flowers fade
until well into the winter — or at least until the birds get them.

  An ‘Ivory Silk’ Japanese lilac tree will provide bloom when
most other trees and shrubs have finished blooming, so take
note of when the tree produces its flowers and/or fruit. Finally,
take note of what the plant tag says about the leaves themselves.

» Continued on Page 10 Choosing a tree with interesting bark will make it a feature of the winter landscape.

                                                                        FREE

                                                                    Cordless Upgrade
                                                                    on Cellular Shades

                                                                    30%UP  OFF

                                                                    TO

                                                                    Rollers, Dual Concept
                                                                      Shades & Shadow
                                                                        Magic Shades

                                                                    Imagination . Innovation . Inspiration

                                                                      CALL Shelley Taylor
                                                                          204-761-7057

                                                                        FOR A FREE ESTIMATE]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

                                                                                                                                       Read the tag to
                                                                                                                                       see if the tree,
                                                                                                                                       like this sumac,
                                                                                                                                       has signiﬁcant
                                                                                                                                       fall leaf colour.

                                                                 The shape and width of the tree you
                                                                 are considering should be noted.
                                                                 (All photos by Albert Parsons/For the Sun)

« Continued from Page 9                                          All of these features of the leaves will affect their texture and
  Consider the size and shape of the leaves. Are they round or   appearance.

triangular? Simple (one leaf per stem attached to the branch),     Leaf colour is also important. Some trees have foliage that is
like a poplar tree, or compound (several leaflets attached to a  very deep green, while others have leaves that are bright green
stem that is then attached to the branch), like a mountain ash   or even slightly yellow. A few trees, such as the Schubert
tree?                                                            chokecherry, have coloured leaves so the tree has a very different
                                                                 effect when added to the landscape.
  Are the leaves shiny, dull, or perhaps hairy? Are the edges
wavy, lobed or serrated — and are they deeply serrated or          Leaf colour and shape, tree size and shape, density of foliage,
jaggedly toothed? Are the tips of the leaves pointed or blunt?   flower and fruit production ... the list goes on. There are indeed
                                                                 many things to consider when shopping for a tree!]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[NEW STYLES & DESIGNS FOR 2016

 KITCHENS, BATHROOMS, CUSTOM CABINETS & DESIGN

COME BY & SEE NEW POWER LIFT CUPBOARD & RECESSED
            UNDER CABINET LED LIGHTING OPTIONS

LOCALLY OWNED & OPERATED IN                   CALL US OR COME BY
 WESTMAN FOR OVER 19 YEARS!                   FOR YOUR ESTIMATE

                                GLEN GURR                                             MAPLE LEAF65TH ST. E.
                                                RICHMOND AVE. E.                                    (4 KM)
                                204.727.1016
www.infinitykitchenandbath.ca                                                   SHOWROOM
                               SCOTT GURR
                                              info@infinitykitchenandbath.ca
                                204.573.5182

                               BRANDON, MB]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[12 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

Four spring and summer home

                                 maintenance tips

  Winter weather can be
tough on a home — inside
and out. While maintenance
is a year-long task, now is the
ideal time to get your home in
tip-top shape so you can enjoy
it more in the sunny months
ahead — remember, they
don’t call it “spring cleaning”
for nothing.

  Here are four easy
maintenance tips to spring
your home back to life this
season.

FRONT DOOR FACELIFT              months, depending on the          documentation that came          and garden hose. Climb up
                                 type you’re using. With the       with it before beginning any     the ladder and begin to scoop
  With harsh weather comes       proper furnace filter, you’ll     cleaning task and confirm that   out the waste, interchangeably
cracked or peeling paint. A      reduce harmful airborne           the model is appropriate for     using a trowel or your gloved
fresh paint job can boost your   contaminants such as dirt,        the job. Remove any obstacles    hands, and dispose of it in the
home’s curb appeal and           dust and various allergens. To    that could cause tripping or     bucket. When the gutter is
provide a protective barrier     replace a filter, follow your     that might snag the hoses.       nearly clear, turn on the hose
from the elements. If your       HVAC system’s instruction         Turn off power to external       to flush the leftovers down the
front door is looking worn,      manual to ensure proper           electrical outlets and fixtures  waterspout, and the gutter
give it a facelift with a bold   installation. Lastly, make sure   and tape down plastic to cover   should drain. While you’re at
new colour. Many colours         there aren’t any gaps around      them. Trim back plants that      it, inspect your downspouts to
look different and less intense  the filter frame. If this is the  touch the home exterior and      see if they’ve suffered any
outdoors than they do            case, you may have the wrong      then water and cover all of the  damage. Downspouts should
indoors, so to compensate,       size.                             plants in the work area to       extend at least one to two
throw caution to the wind and                                      keep in the moisture. Never      metres from your home, so
go bold.  According to the       PRESSURE WASH                     direct pressure washers at       they can effectively direct
DIY Network, bright yellow       EXTERIORS                         people, animals or plants.       water away from the
and classic red are some of                                                                         foundation.
the more popular front door        Erase years of residue on       CLEAR OUT GUTTERS
colours.                         exterior surfaces by renting a                                       Maintaining your home
                                 pressure washer from your           Noticed the water isn’t        regularly keeps it refreshed, in
  Prep is equally as important   local home improvement            draining down the gutter?        prime condition after a rough
outdoors as it is in, so use a   store. Use it to clean decks,     Clear out any accumulated        winter and in tip-top shape all
quality painter’s tape to        walkways, fences and other        debris that could be clogging    year long. Visit
protect windows and trim and     outside surfaces. Pressure        the gutter system. For this      paintersmategreen.com for
ensure a flawless finish.        washers can have different        down-and-dirty task, you’ll      additional information.
Painter’s Mate Green can be      cleaning abilities, so make       need a pair of work gloves, a    » News Canada
used on many types of            sure to read the                  trowel, a stepladder, a bucket
surfaces and delivers
professional results —
without the premium price
point.

FRESHEN UP FILTERS

  Freshen up indoors by
cleaning or replacing HVAC
filters. Energy Star
recommends that air filters be
changed at least every three]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Relax… WE’VE GOT THE BEST
                             PRICES – SELECTION – SERVICE

   8 Person
   Hot Tubs

      STARTING AT

$33/biweekly

SLEEP BETTER

• Spend Quality Time
  with Family & Friends

• Soak Away Stress
• Rid Yourself of Aches

  & Strains

FREE DELIVERY & SET-UP*

                *Some restrictions apply

  Creasy Hot Tubs                                         SWIM SPAS
     & Billiards
                                                                • Year round fitness
       2500 Park Avenue • Brandon, MB                           • Enjoy hot tub & pool
        204-729-8827 or 1-877-241-9580
                                                                  benefits in one!
www.jacuzzimanitoba.ca • www.facebook.com/creasys               • Better investment
                                                                • Only a fraction of the

                                                                  cost of a pool

                                                             • As low as $143/mth

                                                   The Most Inexpensive
                                                   Hot Tubs In The World.

                                                            Let Creasy’s Show You
                                                            The Jacuzzi Difference.]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

  Rose quartz and serenity — the
   2016 colour trend of the year

         Crispin Butterfiled

DESIGN LIFE

Crispin Butterfield owns Urban
Theory Interior Design in Brandon;
find out how she can help you with
your own design projects.
» designchick.ca

  Every time a new year rolls       According to Pantone, the
around, a brand new trendy          soulful combination of Rose
colour-du-jour is announced         Quartz and Serenity also
to the world, representing          challenges         traditional
what’s to come in the world         perceptions of colour
of fashion, beauty, and design      association. Many parts of the
— and this year’s coveted hue       world are experiencing a
may surprise you!                   gender blur as it relates to
                                    fashion, which has in turn
  For the first time ever, the      impacted colour trends
blending of two shades —            throughout all other areas of
Rose Quartz and Serenity —          design.
are chosen as the Pantone           This more autonomous
Colour of the Year.                 approach to colour is
                                    overlapping with societal
  “As consumers seek                movements toward gender           in turbulent times.”
mindfulness and well-being as       equality and fluidity, the          How can you incorporate
an antidote to modern day           consumer’s increased comfort
stresses, welcoming colours         with using colour as a form of    these two airy and whimsical
that psychologically fulfill our    expression, and a generation      shades in your own spaces?
yearning for reassurance and        that has less concern about       The answer is simple: Find
security are becoming more          being typecast or judged based    small and coveted trinkets and
prominent”, says Leatrice           upon the tones and colours        treasures you can easily switch
Eiseman, executive director of      with which they choose to         out with these zen-inducing
the Pantone Colour                  adorn themselves.                 hues — decorative quartz
Institute®.                         Rose Quartz is described as       chunks, candles, pillows for a
                                    “a persuasive yet gentle tone     neutral sofa, or artwork laced
  “Joined together, Rose            that conveys compassion and       with hints of both shades.
Quartz and Serenity                 a sense of composure.
demonstrate an inherent             Serenity is weightless and airy,    And, of course, consider
balance between a warmer            like the expanse of the blue      mixing in other supporting
embracing rose tone and the         sky above us, bringing feelings   tones in navy blue, denim,
cooler tranquil blue, reflecting    of respite and relaxation even    celadon, and persimmon to
connection and wellness as                                            help carry this look into
well as a soothing sense of                                           beautiful, everyday living.
order and peace.”]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Commercial & Residential Services

                                                                       • Complete Design & Consultation Services
                                                                       • Full service landscape installation
                                                                       • Original designs, water features, hardscapes,
                                                                        outdoor living and more

                                  Retail Store with                    • Lechuza Planters (self watering)
                                Professional Advice                    • Perennials
                                                                       • Annuals
            SPRING HOURS: APRIL 24  JUNE 30                           • Shrubs & Trees
Monday – Wednesday & Friday 9am to 6pm • Thursday 9am to 9pm           • Water Features & Pond Materials
                                                                       • Gardening & Landscaping supplies
         • Saturday 9am to 5pm • Sunday 12pm to 5pm                    • Giftware and so much more

                   Concrete Dealer

We offer proposal per job or hourly rates for operator and equipment.  • All-year-round services for your landscapes • Spring clean
                                                                               • Monthly mowing • Fiesta Weed Control

Let our team make your dreams a reality!                               Richmond Ave.34th St.

   Southeast corner of 34th Street and Patricia Ave.                   Patricia Ave.         Shoppers
                                                                                                Mall
                Sales 204-727-7289 | Toll Free 1-866-727-7289           Alternative Landscaping
         Fax 204-727-7531 | info@alternativelandscapingltd.com                             18th St.

             www.alternativelandscapingltd.com]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[16 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

Fire up the barbecue with peanutty,
       Thai-inspired kebobs

  With the traditional Thai flavours of       • 1 tbsp (15 ml) ginger, finely grated     along with lime juice, sugar, fish sauce
lime, chili and peanuts, this mouth-          • 1 lime                                   and turmeric. Whisk until combined.
watering dish will add wow factor to your     • 1 1/2 tsp (7 ml) granulated sugar
next barbecue. For tender and tasty bites,    • 1 1/2 tsp (7 ml) fish sauce                2. Thinly slice steak against the grain
slice your meat against the grain and         • 1/2 tsp (2 ml) ground turmeric           into strips about ¼- to ½-inch thick (1- to
provide ample time for marinating.            • 1 flank steak, about 1 1/4 lbs (625 g)   2-cm). Place in marinade and stir to coat.
                                              • 1/2 small red onion                      Cover, stirring occasionally, and refrigerate
THAI FLANK STEAK KEBOBS                       • 1 red pepper                             for at least 4 hours or overnight.
                                              • Salt, preferably kosher, to taste
  Prep time: 15 minutes                       •  Thai basil, coriander leaves or           3. Oil grill and preheat barbecue to
  Marinating time: 4 hours                  chopped mint for garnish                     medium-high heat. Slice onion into thin
  Grilling time: 5 minutes                    •  2 tbsp (30 ml) peanuts, coarsely        wedges and cut red pepper into bite-size
  Makes 8 large skewers                     chopped                                      pieces. Thread kebobs, alternating pieces
                                                                                         of meat with onion and red pepper.
INGREDIENTS                                 DIRECTIONS                                   Sprinkle with salt. Grill for 5 minutes,
                                                                                         turning frequently, until meat is just
  •  1/2 cup (125 ml) unsweetened             1. In a shallow dish just large enough     cooked through and vegetables are tender.
coconut milk                                to hold meat, combine coconut milk,          Serve garnished with herbs and peanuts.
                                            peanut butter, chili sauce and ginger.
  • 1/4 cup (60 ml) peanut butter           Finely grate peel of 1 lime and add to dish    » News Canada
  • 2 tbsp (30 ml) hot Chinese chili sauce]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[• AIR CONDIIONING • DRAIN CLEANING

• FURNACES  • HOT WATER TANKS

• RENOVATIONS • SERVICE AGREEMENTS

“TRUE” 24 HOUR EMERGENCY SERVICE

            AFTER HOURS SERVICE
   FREE ESTIMATES • UPFRONT PRICING

Call (204) 728-6079 | 1622 13 St. Brandon

                www.mrwestside.ca]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[18 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

     Two day deck makeovers

  Anyone who has built a deck knows it       properly prepared surface allows for better  washer. Allow your deck to dry for at least
can be a long and expensive process. It’s    sealer absorption. An effective solution     24 hours. Then repair loose screws or
not a task you want to undertake every       is the Thompson’s WaterSeal Heavy Duty       damaged boards on the deck surface.
few years, so why not properly protect       Deck cleaner, but be sure to follow the
your investment?                             usage instructions. These products should    APPLY THE SEALER
                                             be applied with a staining brush and then
  There are a wide variety of do-it-         rinsed with a garden hose or pressure          Once your deck is dry you can apply
yourself products designed to make deck                                                   the sealer. Another popular DIY product
restoration easy. One weekend is all you                                                  for the job is Thompson’s WaterSeal
need to transform the look of your                                                        Penetrating Timber Oil, available in
outdoor wood surfaces.                                                                    natural, teak, walnut, pecan and
                                                                                          redwood. It is easy to apply with only one
  Refinishing your deck can be done in                                                    coat and an oil-based formula that
just three simple steps:                                                                  minimizes lap marks and colour
                                                                                          streaking. Allow your deck to dry for
PROTECT YOURSELF AND YOUR                                                                 another 24-hours before taking full
WORK SPACE                                                                                advantage of your new space.

  Wet the plant life around the deck, then                                                  With a properly sealed deck, you can
cover it to protect against product run-                                                  rest assured that your investment is
off. Wear old clothes, protective glasses                                                 protected against the damaging effects of
and gloves. Clear the deck of all furniture                                               mildew and bright sunshine.
and decorative items.                                                                     » News Canada

PREPARE THE SURFACE

  Clean the deck and remove mildew
stains, dust, dirt, oil, soot or grease. A

Create a peaceful

home simply by

soundproofing                                                                               Automation systems to
                                                                                            control your lights, locks,
  With televisions, home         install material designed for                              thermostats, and alarm
theatres, computers, video       use inside walls, ceilings and                             system from anywhere
games, stereos and cellphones,   between floors. Simply cut                                 in the world
our homes are louder than        with a serrated blade or bread
ever. By soundproofing certain   knife and push into place.
rooms in the house, you can      For the best soundproofing
turn your home into a quiet      results, install the stone wool
sanctuary and relaxing escape.   material in your media rooms,    High definition camera
                                 children’s      playrooms,       systems for your home or
  Insulation is key. Used in     washrooms and laundry            business
professional recording studios,
stone wool insulation is an      room. Because it provides
excellent acoustic barrier that  high sound absorption and
effectively absorbs sound        reduces the transfer of noise
thanks to its density and non-   from one room to another, the    Residential and commercial alarm systems
directional fibre structure.
                                 rest of your home will be left     2047175599
  For home use, industry         undisturbed and your life,
experts recommend a Roxul        uninterrupted.                   www.westmansecurity.ca
product called Safe n’ Sound                                                                Locally Owned & Operated
insulation. It’s an easy-to-
                                 » News Canada                    FREE alarm switchovers with 3 months of FREE monitoring]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                         19

Cottage ownership: Know what you’re buying

  There are few traditions more                A lawyer can determine whether a          municipality has transferred the rights to
Canadian than weekends at the cottage.       cottage is subject to easements, and can    this allowance to the individual property
For many families, a cottage property        tell you whether the access road is public  owners, members of the public are
provides the setting for both summer and     or private.                                 entitled to walk, or in some cases even
winter holidays, and allows multiple                                                     drive, along it. A lawyer can conduct
generations to spend time together.          SHORELINE RULES                             searches to reveal whether there is an
                                                                                         allowance and who owns it.
  To ensure that your time at the cottage      Where a cottage is located on the water,
is filled with relaxation instead of drama,  there is often a shoreline road allowance     There may also be rules about
be aware that cottage properties can differ  along the water’s edge that is owned by     construction at the edge of, or extending
from urban ones in important ways.           the local municipality. Unless the          into, the water. These rules can prevent
Consulting a lawyer before you buy can                                                   you from building a dock or boathouse.
protect you from unexpected problems.                                                    It’s not possible to tell whether you can
                                                                                         build a boathouse just because some
LIMITED ROAD ACCESS                                                                      neighbours have them. In many locations,
                                                                                         existing structures have been
  Some cottages can be reached only by                                                   “grandfathered”, while new ones are
crossing a neighbour’s property. Others                                                  prohibited.
have easements registered on title that
allow neighbouring residents, or even                                                      Working with a real estate lawyer
members of the general public, to travel                                                 familiar with rural properties can help
across the land.                                                                         you know what you’re getting — and
                                                                                         whether it includes peace of mind —
  Even where a cottage is accessed by a                                                  when you buy a cottage.
municipal road, its use might be seasonal                                                » News Canada
only. This might mean the municipality
won’t provide garbage collection, snow
removal or emergency services in winter.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[20 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

The breakfast nook is styled like a booth in an old-fashioned restaurant. (Ted Grant/Canadian Press)

The breakfast nook has been updated

BY MELISSA RAYWORTH                           “People, especially children, will      Canada, host of the “HGTV
                                            gravitate toward it,” Ryan says. “Who     Crafternoon” web series. Closed
  The term “breakfast nook” sounds          doesn’t like to get a booth at the diner  cabinets can be designed to match your
hopelessly trapped in the 1970s, but        over a table?”                            existing cabinetry, or you can add open
modern homeowners are embracing the                                                   shelving, she says, to “add texture with
style and practicality of built-in seating  PRACTICAL AND PRETTY                      baskets, show off your cookbook
in the kitchen.                                                                       collection, even use it to store large
                                              For homeowners with an open-plan        ceramic bowls that take up too much
  “The idea of the built-in, with the kids  kitchen, built-in seating creates a cozy  cabinet space.”
piled in it and the pillows” can bring the  gathering place that functions like a
casual fun of a beach house or              formal dining room but is right in the      Just be sure the design of the built-
farmhouse to any home, says                 heart of the cooking and socializing.     in seating area matches the architecture
Massachusetts-based interior designer                                                 of the rest of the house, says Crestin.
Kristina Crestin, featured this season on     In smaller kitchens, a nook allows      Sketch out what you want and plan
“This Old House.”                           the dining table to be positioned along   carefully before starting construction.
                                            a wall or in a corner without looking     If the breakfast nook will include a
  Maxwell Ryan, founder of                  as if it were stuffed awkwardly out of    window, she says, consider the height
ApartmentTherapy.com, says built-in         the way.                                  of the sill and whether it will hit the
kitchen seating can maximize space in                                                 backs of people seated along the wall.
smaller kitchens and highlight a great        Built-ins also offer lots of space for
window view. It can even become the         storage.                                    Also, be sure to use a pedestal table
most distinctive design element in your                                               so you’re not bumping into table legs
home.                                         “The space underneath a built-in        when sliding into the seats.
                                            banquette is ripe with possibilities,”
                                            says stylist and crafter Marianne]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                     21

COOL VARIATIONS                                                      backrest area behind the seating in a co-ordinatingcolour.
                                                                       “You can easily swap out the fabric on the seat or the paint
  If you can’t commit to a fully built-in breakfast area — or if
you worry your kitchen will look too much like a roadside diner      on the backrest anytime you want to shake up your kitchen
— Canada suggests adding a banquette to just one side of the         decor,” he says.
kitchen dining area.
                                                                       And here’s a secret: If you love this look but want to avoid
  “This gives you the best of both worlds,” she says, “an            the commitment and cost of real built-in seating, you can create
architectural feature that provides storage and easy seating, and    a faux version. Ryan suggests installing a large upholstered
the opportunity to mix things up with chairs.”                       bench along one wall and painting the wall around it with semi-
                                                                     gloss paint (easily wiped clean) to highlight the space. Add
  This approach is cheaper to build and easier to remove if you      pillows and you’ve got a perfectly cozy space where guests can
want something different later.                                      lean back and enjoy your kitchen.
                                                                     » The Associated Press
  One popular option: Extend the bench the entire length of
one wall, installing open or closed storage underneath.

  “A table at one end for kitchen dining, general seating for
those times when everyone ends up in the kitchen, and a space
near the door that serves as a landing area for shoes, backpacks
and jackets,” Canada says. “Add some hooks above the bench,
and baskets below, and you’ll find that clutter disappears
effortlessly.”

FABRICS

  One big draw of built-in kitchen seating is the softness and
colour of the cushions and pillows. A tip from Crestin: Invest
in high-quality fabric in a pattern and colours that are neutral
enough you can love them for years to come. Then get really
creative with fabrics for loose pillows, spending a bit less so you
can swap those out seasonally for new ones when the urge
strikes.

  To highlight the fabrics you’ve chosen, Ryan painting the]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[22 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

Another trend in housing is the diversity in exterior design. This J&G Homes residence, at 9 Southview Drive in Brookwood Estates, showcases the exterior that uses a
combination of materials — brick, stucco and metal siding. (Submitted)

  Bi-level making big comeback in

                                                house design

  What is new, is old. This is especially                                Wanda Kurchaba           of in the past.
true when it comes to design.                                                                       “We’re using more of a mixture of
                                                #BUSINESSBUZZ
  For instance, (if you’re female!) how                                                           finishes and customizing to the owners
many times have you gone to buy a pair          Wanda Kurchaba is a Brandon freelance writer and  style and taste. The combination of two or
of pants only to discover that flared/wide      a communications and marketing specialist. This   more materials that complements and
leg pants (modern bell bottom) are back in      column on Westman’s business community appears    contrasts, and adds a little detail and
style?                                          each Saturday. Contact Wanda directly with any    definition to the home from the outside is
                                                story ideas.                                      what is quite popular,” said Ellchuk.
  As with the fashion industry, trends in       » kurch@wcgwave.ca
housing are also often repeated.                                                                    In terms of product selection, Ellchuk
                                                said they are also affordable to build and        said there is a lot to choose from. She’s seen
  What appears to be making a comeback          can offer spacious front entrances, high          a bit of a trend back to a classic look on
in the new housing market is the bi-level       ceilings and open concept living.                 the exterior of the house and one company
floor plan. The bi-level, sometimes also                                                          that is offering a diverse product line is
referred to a split ranch style of home,          “Open concept living is still a key             James Hardie.
usually has a basement that is just four feet   element to a lot of our designs. Back in the
into the ground with an entry that is           day, you might have had a formal dining             She indicated that in some applications,
situated between the two floors.                room with an eat-in kitchen and a formal          customers are choosing a full board plank
                                                living room, but people aren’t interested in      siding, possibly adding shakes/shingles,
  Rebecca Ellchuk, a real estate agent with     that anymore. An open concept floor plan          contrasting the look with a coloured trim
HomeLife Home Professional Realty Inc.,         feels more spacious and helps to make sure        and then combining that with a stone or
specializes in the new home market for          there is flow from room to room and there’s       some other accent to make it really stand
J&G Homes and has definitely noticed a          a lot more natural light,” said Ellchuk.          out.
shift in market demand.
                                                  Alternatively, when looking at the                “Metal siding, but in a wood grain finish
  “As far as building goes, we’re seeing        exterior of the new homes being built             is really becoming popular, as it give you
quite a few bi-levels, which is a nice change.  within the city this year and last, there are     a classic design with a modern element,”
There seemed to be a steady production of       definitely some newer features being              said Ellchuck. “You can get it done in full
cabovers in Brandon in a lot of the             showcased that we haven’t really seen much        sheets or in a true siding look, whether
developments, but people have been                                                                that’s in the warm tones of the brown or
wanting something a little different from                                                         the coolness of the greys.
their neighbours down the street and now
there’s a good mixture of styles and floor                                                          “Exterior design is very diverse now. It’s
plans,” said Ellchuk.                                                                             just not the same stucco with build outs in
                                                                                                  slightly different shades throughout a
  A selling feature of a bi-level home is the                                                     neighbourhood anymore.”
more natural light because of the bigger                                                          » The Brandon Sun
windows in the lower level, as well as
maximized use of that same space. Ellchuk]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                        23

       Backyard entertaining

  Warmer weather means making the            matching side and coffee tables so guests  more intimate dinner parties as well, food
most of your backyard space. And dining      have a place to rest plates of food and    can be plated or served family style
is a simple way to extend your time          glasses.                                   allowing your guests to remain at the
outdoors. Whether it’s enjoying everyday                                                table and lose track of time as they eat.
meals, hosting an intimate dinner party      DINING SETS
or welcoming larger groups for a                                                        FLEXIBILITY
barbecue, there are a few things to            When it’s warm out, why not take your
consider when purchasing patio-dining        meal outside? Whether prepared indoors       If you can’t decide between an intimate
furniture.                                   or on the grill, outdoor dining sets are   dining set or a casual conversation set, or
                                             great for enjoying any meal. You can       if you just want the best of both worlds
CONVERSATION SETS                            bring indoor elegance outside with         but don’t have the space, look for a
                                             decorative table linens, candles and       conversation/dining combination.
  These are becoming increasingly            colourful tableware. Great for smaller,    Lowe’s offers the new Prescott dining set
popular to provide comfortable seating                                                  which includes a table, a sofa, two end
that replicates the living room. They                                                   chairs and two stools that can be used for
provide a great space to sit back, put your                                             seating or foot rests.
feet up and enjoy a good book in the
afternoon and provide the optimal area                                                    Whichever set you choose, you may
to linger long after a meal is done. For                                                also want to consider the ease of adding
less formal gatherings, food stations can                                               additional seating like matching chairs or
be set up, buffet style around the                                                      benches for when you have a larger group.
perimeter of the set. This allows guest to                                              Stools are great as extra seating or end
easily move around and talk to different                                                tables.
people while they make their plates of                                                  » News Canada
food. Look for a conversation set with

We specialize in building quality sunrooms                                              Peter Behrens
and patios designed to fit your budget and                                           & Keith Bourgeois
your lifestyle.
We carry the exclusive Weather Master® Vertical  The Weather Master®
Four Track Window System which opens from          Window System
top or bottom & allows 75% ventillation.

       • FREE ESTIMATES •

204-726-8488 email : sales@elitesunrooms.ca
                       www.elitesunrooms.ca]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[24 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

She Shed women’s answer to the Man Cave

  For years men have taken        adding things you love to         home. Personalize with           SURROUND YOURSELF IN
over basements, garages and       reflect your personal style.      exterior and interior paint      NATURE
even dens to be alone, indulge                                      colours, even wallpaper, a
in hobbies and enjoy décor        START WITH A GREAT                great mural or fun prints.         It’s about enjoying the
that lacks female influence.      BASE                                                               outdoors so place your shed in
Not to be outdone, the “She                                         COMFORTABLE                      a secluded spot or one with
Shed” is the latest trend for       It’s easy to find pre-          FURNITURE                        great views. Plant colourful
women looking to establish a      fabricated sheds to fit any       Daybeds,           outdoor       flowers around the she shed
place of their own in the         outdoor space and budget.         sectionals, loungers and         and in window boxes and
home.                             This will create the basic        recliners with fluffy pillows    bring the garden inside as well
                                  structure of your getaway and     create a cozy place to curl up   by decorating with plants and
  These tiny cottages are the     the palette for your décor.       with a good book.                freshly picked flower
perfect retreat for women         Lowe’s La Remise Cabana                                            arrangements.
looking for a little alone time   Shed has five-sided versatility,  LIGHTING
of their own. The beauty of       and is easy to install with no                                     AMENITIES
the She Shed is it can be         cutting required and all the        LED lights and chandeliers
whatever you want it to be. It    hardware included.                are easy to install and provide    Make sure you have
can be a place of relaxation,                                       great mood lighting. Task        everything you need so that
indulgence or a place of utility  DÉCOR                             lighting is also important and   you never have to leave. Build-
to get things done.                                                 interior table lamps or floor    in storage solutions, cupboards
                                    Make it your own, let your      lamps can be brought in as       and shelves to house a mini-
  There are no rules to           imagination flow and try                                           fridge, wine fridge and even a
building a She Shed — it can      things you may be hesitant to        they are protected from the   blender for the summertime
be as simple or elaborate as      do inside your                                 elements.           drinks.
you like and you can                                                                                 » News Canada
personalize your

 space by]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                            25

How to extend the life of your roof

  Year after year, your roof takes a         harmonizing the colour of the roof, after      brown, green, grey, red, blue, white,
beating. Wind, rain, snow, ice and sun       repairs for example.                           aluminum and clear. Its UV-resistant
can take years off your home's protective                                                   features preserve the roof's colour
shell and can lead to premature aging and      For as little as one fifth of the cost, you  throughout its lifetime.
expensive repairs. In fact, while some       can avoid the expensive replacement of
homeowners may not like to hear it, it       any sloping and aging shingle or sheet           Before applying the product to the roof,
can cost well over $4,500 to replace the     metal roof. Because the coating is opaque,     it is recommended to first add repair
roofing on a typical 1,000 sq. ft. house.    it improves the appearance of your roof        compounds such as Techniseal's Instant
There also comes a time when you simply      with a range of colours including black,       Leak Sealer or Waterproof Sealant
want to change the colour of the roof,                                                      around any openings such as the
even though it is still in good condition.                                                  chimney. Repair or replace aged or
                                                                                            damaged shingles and remove moss and
  However, there is an economical and                                                       mildew by cleaning out the roof surface.
environmentally-friendly protection                                                         Then simply paint the coating over your
against weathering. It's an innovative                                                      old asphalt shingle or sheet-metal roof
elastomeric roof coating known as                                                           with a roller or an airless sprayer.
RoofKeeper for asphalt shingles and
RoofSkin for sheet-metal roofing. The                                                         The ecological, water-based polymer
microporous, acrylic emulsion is applied                                                    coating contains no tar and helps keep
directly to the roofing material, just like                                                 away millions of tons of prematurely
a regular paint. Specially formulated for                                                   discarded asphalt shingles from landfills,
severe climates and strong winds, this                                                      while making you save thousands of
coating is ultra-adherent, stays flexible                                                   dollars.
and is guaranteed for up to 10 years. The                                                   » News Canada
product is also ideal for changing or

                                             FARM, RESIDENTIAL & COMMERCIAL
                                                               PROPERTY APPRAISERS

                                                                   Serving Western Manitoba Since 1977

Suite 30A, 1015 – 26th Street, Brandon            204-727-7100
Fax: 204-727-1563 Email: weir1@mts.net]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[26 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

David Hew used an app and online site caled HOUZZ to plan the remodeling of his family’s home . (Submitted)

Digital decor: harnessing the riches

of online design sites

BY SARAH WOLFE                            offer the following tips on how to                                   Don’t overlook retailers though. Paint
                                          harness the bounty of the Internet for                             company websites are an underutilized
  There’s Houzz. Remodelista. Home        your next project:                                                 home-design resource, says designer
design Twitter feeds. Tumblr accounts.                                                                       Karen Gray Plaisted.
And of course, the granddaddy of all      GET ORGANIZED
online decor depositories — Pinterest.                                                                         “Many times, clients have problems
                                            First, figure out the scope of your                              with colours,” she says. “Benjamin
  It’s easy to get overwhelmed by online  project and your goals. Re-doing your                              Moore, Sherwin Williams and PPG
resources when remodeling or              kitchen, for example, is a lot different and                       Paints all have fantastic interactive sites
redecorating. Where should you start?     more involved than finding a few natural                           to allow them to ‘try’ a colour out, or find
                                          accents for your living room mantle.                               a palette virtually first. It also helps me
  For homeowner Sarah Schuster                                                                               as a decorator to then narrow down the
Canahuati, creating an “ideabook” on        Are you going to do the work yourself ?                          array of colours to find the right one for
Houzz was the perfect way to mesh her     How-to blogs and sites like All Things                             them.”
rustic, farmhouse style with her          Thrifty, DIY Network and This Old
husband’s more modern tastes when         House are your new BFFs.                                             Annalisa Nash Fernandez, a business
they began renovating their home                                                                             owner and self-described “serial mover,”
recently.                                   Looking more for ideas to pass on to a                           started a Facebook group with friends
                                          contractor or designer? Head over to                               who are also into decorating.
  Home design experts and contractors     Houzz or Pinterest.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY  27

FIND YOUR STYLE                                                           Everything You Need
                                                                            for Inside & Out!
  Figure out what you love. Are you a boho-chic kind of girl or
do you gravitate more toward the clean, traditional lines of             FREE Computerized
craftsman-style homes?                                                  Deck Design Service

  “To use home-design websites to find your own style, I’d advise        Looking for that perfect outdoor area but don’t
you to pin or bookmark photos of every single room you love,”             know where to start? We can show you what
says Amy Bell, owner of Red Chair Home Interiors in Cary,                  your deck will look like, how much material
North Carolina. “The more rooms you save, the larger your ‘data
sample’ will be. Once you have collected many images, take a                you will need and more. Come in today for
step back and look for common themes that the images share.”                         a FREE, no-obligation quote!

  Are there recurring colours or colour combinations? Are you           1840 – 18TH STREET NORTH, BRANDON
drawn to dramatic contrasts, like white cabinets paired with dark
floors? Are the rooms sparsely or heavily furnished and                 204-728-4243
accessorized? What do you notice about architectural elements
like windows, doors, fireplaces and ceiling height?                     Fax: 204-727-2619

  “Having a theme and palette in mind really helps narrow down          Toll-Free: 1-800-224-7506
the infinite options on design sites and blogs,” says Patricia Leitao,  www.windsorplywood.com
marketing manager and blogger for the Boston-based site
homeyou, which matches homeowners with area contractors.                Store Hours: Mon. – Fri. 7:30 am – 6:00 pm;
                                                                        Sat. 8:00 am – 5:00 pm; Closed Sunday
CREATE A PROJECT PAGE OR BOARD

  “Collection” sites like Houzz and Pinterest allow users to
create an unlimited number of boards or “ideabooks.” Go big
and create one board for your entire project, or go smaller with
more specific boards like “paint colours,” ‘’accessories,”
‘’furniture,” etc.

  As a way to keep track of ideas, these are easier and more
visual than a list of bookmarks or a scrapbook of pages ripped
from books and magazines.

  They’re also a great resource if you decide to hire a contractor
or home designer.

  “We love going through our clients’ inspiration boards on
content-rich sites. It gives us an immediate look into their
personal style and preferences, and we can help them narrow
down exactly what will fit into their space and budget,” says
Margo Nathanson, a designer with InteriorCrowd.

DESIGN IT YOURSELF

  If you’re looking for the ultimate in control, IKEA, Lowe’s
and smaller sites like Roomstyler let you design your own rooms
from scratch with a virtual planner. Type in your room’s
dimensions, then drag and drop furnishings, windows and other
elements where you want.

  Try an unlimited variety of cabinet and countertop
combinations when remodeling your kitchen. Or see what your
living room would look like with wooden floors. Then tile.
Maybe concrete.

  Don’t like it? Simply press delete.

  Online:Houzz: houzz.com
  Pinterest: pinterest.com
  Apartment Therapy: apartmenttherapy.com
  All Things Thrifty: allthingsthrifty.com
  DIY Network: diynetwork.com
  This Old House: thisoldhouse.com
  Roomstyler: roomstyler.com
  IKEA Home Planner: www.ikea.com/ms/en—JP/rooms—
ideas/splashplanners.html

» The Associated Press]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[28 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

Outdoor design trends for 2016

  Canadian design enthusiasts have one        “Sofas that have all the chairs slotted   tableware.
more thing to look forward to this spring   underneath or coffee tables that sit right    “Combine colourful, vintage looking
as new outdoor trends emerge. Make          on top of the sofa make it easy to cover
your outdoor living area look as good as    and pack-up.”                               pieces with simple, modern whites or
it makes you feel so you can take                                                       greys. It’s not only about mixing colour
advantage of the season, whether you’re       Travis suggests her Chelsea               and pattern, but also old with new,” says
relaxing, playing or socializing.           Conversation set, which is designed         Travis. “Tableware has also come a long
                                            specifically for Canadian weather.          way, and now it’s easy to achieve a fun
  Debbie Travis, Canada’s lifestyle expert                                              yet sophisticated look with pieces that
who recently launched an exclusive          EUROPEAN INSPIRED PIECES                    appear to be ceramic but are shatter
partnership at Sears Canada, shares her                                                 resistant.”
favourite new outdoor trends.                 You can rejuvenate your outdoor living
                                            spaces by pulling inspiration from            Travis recommends being adventurous
SPACE-SAVING PATIOS                         Europe. Right now, it’s all about sleek,    with colour, fabrics and materials.
                                            modern pieces combined with rustic          Outdoor furniture made from multiple
  Multi-functional patio sets that save     accents. “Canadian barnwood is very         materials promotes a dynamic fusion
space are a go-to item this year.           cool at the moment and quite popular in     between the indoor and outdoor
                                            Europe. Consider using it to build an       entertaining space. Popular combinations
  “No matter how much space we have,        outdoor countertop or as flooring on the    for 2016 are wood and iron, stainless steel
it seems there’s never enough. That’s why   deck,” says Travis.                         and teak or aluminum and wicker.
it’s important to select versatile, space-                                              » News Canada
saving patio sets,” she advises. “When it   MIX AND MATCH
comes time to put away the patio set for
winter, we want to be able to stow it away    Mismatched is trendy, so mix up
easily and use minimal space.               accessories like throw pillows or]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY  29

How smart is your
               home?

The future is now
and with home
technology advancing
at such a rapid pace, it
can be tough to keep
up and know where to
start when it comes to
improving      our
capabilities. Research
estimates that half of
all Canadians will buy
a 'smart' home
product in the next
year. Here are three
game          changing
technologies to get
you started:

SMART KITCHEN

  Love to cook? Now your appliances can help you craft the
perfect meal. GE Appliances is launching its new Profile Infinite
Collection Range featuring Chef Connect. This technology
wirelessly connects the range to the over the range microwave
so that the two appliances work in sync. Cooking on the stove
at high heat? The range fan will automatically turn on.
Changing the clocks after a power outage? The two clocks are
connected so you can set the time once and forget it. More
information is available online at geappliances.ca

SMART THERMOSTAT

  For many of us, home heating and cooling make up half our
home energy use. Ecobee, a Toronto-based company, designed
the first wi-fi enabled smart thermostat that uses a series of
data points to make intelligent heating and cooling decisions
to save you money and reduce your environmental impact –
without any compromise at all. And with Ecobee3's room
sensors, you have a truly smarter thermostat, keeping you
comfortable in the rooms that matter most and saving you
money while you're away. Check out ecobee.com to learn more.

SMART DOORBELL

  Never worry about unwanted guests or solicitors again. Dbell
is a Canadian innovation that lets you check on who's at the
door, interact with visitors in real-, and answer your door right
from your smartphone or tablet, with no monthly subscription
fee. Travelling? You can answer your door while abroad,
monitor and record suspicious visitors and get notified from
the motion sensor. Dbell even has two-way audio and remote
camera capabilities to alert you when your kids get home. More
information can be found online at dbell.ca.

» News Canada]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[30 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

Quick and easy tips for painting a room

  Looking to improve the appearance of     TAPE                                            and primer. This paint allows you to
your home without spending an arm and                                                      skip a step in the process, while
a leg? If so, a fresh coat of paint is a     Painter’s tape is a great tool to protect     delivering added adhesion and
wallet-friendly way to rejuvenate your     the surface, prevent paint bleed and            smoothing out rough surfaces.
living quarters. Learn how to make your    provide professional-looking results. Tape
painting dreams come true with these       all borders of the room — molding,                Next, choose your sheen. This
quick and simple tips.                     ceilings and floors — before you start          should be done based on how much
                                           painting. When tape is applied in a long        traffic the area receives. Flat is most
PREP                                       strip, it can stretch and won’t lay flat or     commonly used on living room and
                                           stick properly, resulting in paint bleed.       bedroom walls; however, some people
  Of course you want to see a new,         Instead, tape off walls and trim in one-        prefer satin or eggshell enamel as they
beautiful colour on your wall right away;  foot sections for best results. When            offer a soft, velvety appearance. Semi-
however, spending some time on prep        applying, press down on the tape firmly         gloss is primarily used for cabinets and
work will provide better results and help  and smooth it out against the border. Tape      trim; and high-gloss paints are ideal
you achieve a lasting finish. Start by     removal is also a crucial step. Rather than     for the highest-traffic areas, such as
covering or removing furniture, dust and   waiting for paint to dry, carefully remove      kitchens and bathrooms, because they
wipe down walls thoroughly, and remove     tape at an angle while the paint is still wet.  clean easily.
light switch and outlet covers. When       This will keep the paint from bonding to
painting a bathroom or kitchen, HGTV       the tape, making it easier to remove and          If you’re looking for inspiration,
recommends washing the walls with a        therefore providing cleaner lines.              Pantone announced two colours for
solution of laundry detergent                                                              2016 — Rose Quartz and Serenity —
(approximately three teaspoons to four     PAINT                                           a blending balance between a warm,
litres of water) to remove any grease or                                                   embracing rose tone and a cool
residue.                                     If painting over a previously painted         tranquil blue. Both colours are perfect
                                           surface, consider an all-in-one paint           for giving any room a relaxing vibe.]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY  31

PAINT CONTINUED

  If you’re still unsure which colour to choose, many paint
manufacturers now offer testers to take home a few
favourite shades to try before buying several litres.

TOOLS

  To ensure the final results are just as attractive as the new
paint colour itself, it’s essential to use the correct tools for the
job.

  First, utilize brushes for trimming and painting around the
edges of the room. Be sure to choose the correct type of brush
depending on the kind of paint you’re using — natural brushes
are typically used for oil-based paints, while synthetic brushes
are ideal for latex or water-based paints. Also, consider using
an angled brush to get into tight spaces such as corners, windows
and trim.

  Next, you’ll need a roller to fill in large wall areas. When
choosing a roller, pay attention to which surface the product is
designed for (drywall, stucco, etc.), and the job. Rollers come
with naps of 1/8 to two inches or more. Generally, you should
paint smooth surfaces with a short nap, and rougher surfaces
— like stucco, brick and masonry — with longer nap so those
fibres can get the paint into every nook and cranny. Investing
in quality painting tools can help you achieve the professional-
looking finish you desire in your home.

  Don’t let the idea of updating a room intimidate you. With
the right tools and technique, the job can be done in a flash and
your home will look renewed in no time.

  For more painting tips, visit paintersmategreen.com.
» News Canada]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[One Call Can Do It All!

                              SALES
                              SERVICE
                              INSTALLATION

• Soffits • Eavestroughs      GUTTER VACUMING NOW AVAILABLE

• Fascia • Repair &
• Shingles Cleaning
• Siding • Cladding

www.brandoneavestroughing.ca  Unit 1 - 514 11th St E, Brandon

Hours: Monday - Friday 8am - 4pm, Closed Saturday & Sunday

                                             HOME
                                       RENOVATIONS

CALL TODAY FOR A FREE ESTIMATE!

DAUPHIN 204.638.5772]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                33

        How to get a designer-inspired

        home without the designer cost

When you walk through a        homeowners end up picking          Finding         visual        Cool colours create a space
professionally decorated       one colour for the entire          representation of what        that is relaxing and provide
home, there is a certain       home. Want to bring your           speaks to you is the best     styling options for either an
sense of harmony that flows    space to life with colour? Try     place to start narrowing in   urban or coastal feel.
throughout the space. This     the following steps:               on your style.
is because designers consider                                                                     Great design should
each room in terms of its      DETERMINE WHAT YOUR                DECIDE ON THE THEME           reflect the homeowner's
relation to another and        STYLE IS                                                         personality and should be
choose colours, furniture                                           Depending on whether        more fun than difficult.
and accessories that feel        What is your inspiration?        you choose warm, neutral or   HGTV Home by Sherwin-
cohesive. This is especially   Do you tend towards clean          cool colours, you can create  Williams has compiled 16
important given the            lines with a mix of retro or       a space that helps to set a   designer-inspired collections
popularity of open concept     vintage treasures? Do you          particular mood. Warm         to take the guesswork out of
homes.                         favour a traditional feel over     tones create a space that is  picking a cohesive colour
Now, not everyone hires a      a modern look? Do you              inviting and gives off a      palette for any home and
decorator or has a knack for   envision coming home to a          positive energy. Neutrals     style.
design that makes choosing     luxurious cozy space or            create a space that is cozy   » News Canada
complementary  paint           clean minimalist setting?          yet balanced as they
colours tricky, so most        These factors will influence       complement various looks
                               which palette you choose.          and stay relevant over time.

Choosing your

        home builder

  Choosing the right home builder can be a daunting task,         NOW 2.64%*
especially in today's active new home building industry.
Builders compete for your business with cutting-edge sales                          sunrisecu.mb.ca
presentations and use advertising and marketing materials
that paint the picture of the perfect home. But as a buyer, how   * Limited Time Offer. Some conditions apply. Rates are subject to change. The
do you uncover the difference between a good home builder,        Annual Percentage Rate (APR) is equivalent to the Annual Interest Rate, and
and a great one?                                                  assumes that no fee(s) apply. If fee(s) are required as part of the application
                                                                  processing, any fee(s) would increase your APR.
  Builders should not only be held accountable to build well-
constructed homes, but they also should stand behind their
construction and make sure their customers are supported
during the entire process.

  To find out more about a builder, ask any of your family,
friends or neighbours who may know of someone who has
recently purchased a new home or condo. Some questions to
ask are: what was your experience like? Would you
recommend your builder? How was the after-sales customer
service?

  A home builder's job isn't complete just because the last tile
has been laid. A great home builder ensures that their
customers feel supported long after they've settled into their
new home.
» News Canada]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[34 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

 Trendy gardens are adding lots of
          colour this year

  There’s nothing like colour to            aren’t sure about plant arrangement, try              backyard structures.  Fences
bring life back to our outdoor              pre-planted garden mixes. It’ll take the              and sheds are trending towards
spaces — and doing that with                guess work out of gardening but still                 darker colours like navies,
flair starts with imagination.              result in planters and baskets that are               blacks and dark forest greens.
                                            perfectly colour co-ordinated.                        If you’re planning on doing
  How do you envision the                                                                         some outdoor building, or
beauty of your property this                COLOUR ME GREEN                                       giving the fence a quick coat of
summer, be it the patio, the deck,                                                                paint, think about these colours
your terrace, or the entire                   Forget the white picket fence — the                 that are sure to give your
backyard? Picturing it and                  ever growing trend of backyard colour is              outdoor space a modern feel.
making a plan is an important               moving beyond the garden and into
first step, so to help jump start                                                               FOOD GARDENS
this process, let’s consult a
specialist on the topic.                                                                             Lastly, a trend that’s
                                                                                                  becoming even more of a
  Peter Cantley, a gardening                                                                      “movement” in the past few
expert for the President’s Choice                                                                 years is growing your own
brand, has put together his list                                                                  food. Whether it’s fresh herbs
of the biggest gardening trends                                                                   on the windowsill or planters
at the moment, bound to put you                                                                   and gardens filled with new
in the mood for your spades and                                                                   and exciting varieties of exotic
trowels:                                                                                          berries, growing our own food
                                                                                                  has never been more on trend.
BRIGHT BEGONIA                                                                                    Planting edibles is an exciting
                                                                                                  opportunity to learn about new
  Nothing says summer like                                                                        and different varieties of fruits
brilliant colours and again this                                                                  and veggies so don’t be afraid
year, gardeners are looking to                                                                    to experiment this season. Or
have their outdoor spaces dazzle                                                                  for something truly unique, try
with different shades and hues.                                                                   the PC Ketchup and Fries, a
Many have already dubbed 2016                                                                     unique tomato grafted onto a
“The Year of the Begonia” as                                                                      potato plant. Who knew that
this bright annual is winning fans                                                                you can grow tomatoes and
across both Canada and the                                                                        potatoes on the same plant? It’s
United States. It’s not just                                                                      just another exciting step in the
traditional begonias that people                                                                  world of gardening. 
are talking about, however. The
newest varieties are loaded with                                                                SMALL SPACES, BIG IDEAS
colours and bred to enjoy the sun
and shade. They’re prefect to                                                                        It’s no secret that urban
liven up any area of your                                                                         Canadians are moving into
garden.                                                                                           smaller spaces.  Downtown
                                                                                                  condo buildings are on the
RELAX AND LET THE PLANTS                                                              rise and there’s no room for a backyard
DO THE WORK                                                                           there. Amazingly, condo dwellers aren’t
                                                                                      letting their spaces prevent them from
  Have you always wanted to start                                                     enjoying beautiful potted plants. Low-
gardening but just can’t seem to keep your                                            maintenance tropical plants and terrace-
plants alive? Fear not. More and more                                                 friendly succulents can make any condo
new gardeners are learning that you don’t                                             or apartment balcony a delightful place
have to spend hours a day to impress your                                             to be.
backyard guests. Try low maintenance                                                  » News Canada
annuals like PC Gigantico Selosia
Dragon’s Breath to spice up your
planters. Or, if you love to garden but]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                      35

Consider simple home eco-improvements

                                 for easy savings

  Did you know that being        conditioning units working         brick-to-brick installation,      in the right places can reduce
environmentally conscious is     harder than necessary. By          because inserts can leave gaps,   cooling bills by 10 to 50 per
also an easy way to put money    topping up the existing attic      especially if placed in the old,  cent.
in your pocket?                  insulation you can                 inefficient jamb.
                                 significantly reduce the                                               Here are a few low-cost
  You can significantly reduce   amount of energy loss. A           HOUSE APPLIANCES                  DIY projects you can tackle
your carbon footprint and        popular product for this DIY                                         easily on your own for greater
energy consumption if you        project is Roxul Comforbatt          Replacing your furnace, hot     energy savings:
have an efficient home and use   insulation. It is easy to install  water tank, and air
cleaner products. Consider a     over existing attic insulation     conditioning unit with highly       • Caulk around windows
few, simple eco-improvements     and can easily be cut to fit with  efficient models is also a good     • Add weather stripping to
to reduce energy consumption     a serrated blade or bread knife.   way to lower your home’s          doors
and increase savings on your                                        energy use.                         •  Install low-flow shower
monthly energy bill:             WINDOWS                                                              heads
                                                                    LANDSCAPE YOUR HOME                 • Put aerators on faucets
INSULATION                         It’s usually obvious when it’s   FOR ENERGY EFFICIENCY               • Switch to energy-efficient
                                 time for new windows.                                                LED or CFL bulbs
  If your house is older,        Replacing worn and drafty            Plant a few tall, deciduous       • Change your furnace filter
chances are the insulation       windows can also improve the       trees near your home to             •  Set up a programmable
doesn’t meet the new code        comfort and overall look of        significantly reduce the          thermostat
requirements. An improperly      your home. If you want to          amount of solar energy            » News Canada
insulated attic is a primary     reap the greatest energy           passing through windows and
source of energy loss and        savings, request a custom          beating down on your roof. In
results in your furnace and air                                     fact, the right amount of shade

               Killarney, MB 204.523.8712                           BUILDING A
www.creativekitchensmb.ca | info@creativekitchensmb.ca               NEW HOME?

                                                                      Be sure to confirm your

                                                                        builder has coverage

                                                                        before you start and

                                                                        if not, see us about

                                                                    Course of Construction
                                                                         Insurance today.

        VISIT OUR 2500 SQ.FT. SHOWROOM                              BRANDON • 2830 Victoria Ave & Shoppers Mall
                                                                         WAWANESA • VIRDEN • CARBERRY • SHILO
           8.5 miles north of Killarney on HWY 18
                                                                      Phone: 204-729-4949 • Toll Free: 866-277-4949
Custom Cabinetry • Design Consultants • Professional Installation                   www.guildhmsinsurance.ca
    Sinks • Faucets • Quartz • Granite • Laminate Countertops]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[36 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

How to ensure a successful
  basement renovation

BY SCOTT MCGILLIVRAY             making your basement feel         income suites, fire protection
                                 comfortable, while keeping it     is also a vital consideration.
Canadians continue to fuel       safe and dry. For the best        Whenever possible, select
renovation spending across the   results, install a rigid board    building materials with a high
country, driven by upward        insulation, like Roxul            fire-resistance rating and look
growth in real estate prices     ComfortBoard IS, against the      for products that will not off-
and the rising cost to trade up  concrete foundation before        gas or contribute to toxic
to a larger home.                you stud the wall. The board      smoke in the event of a fire.
According to the Canada          is mechanically fastened or       Include additional exits in
Mortgage and Housing             adhered to the concrete           your renovation plan and
Corporation, basement            foundation wall, which            educate yourself on your local
renovations are expected to be   prevents thermal bridging         fire code.
a hot trend in 2016, as buyers   through the studs, providing                                         Finishing a basement can be
look to maximize available       better thermal performance.         Before you start your          a smart renovation. If done
living space rather than move    Finish with a moisture-           renovation, be sure to check     properly, it will add to a
and as young buyers look to      resistant and dimensionally       with your municipality to        home's value, increase its
offset the cost of               stable insulation between the     secure the right permits and to  function and provide greater
homeownership              with  studs to protect against          ensure that you're complying     enjoyment or income
potential income suites.         common basement issues            with local bylaws and building   potential.
While finishing a basement       such as mould, mildew and         codes.                           » News Canada
can be a great alternative to    rot.
moving –– especially if you
love your neighbourhood —        CHOOSE A FUNCTIONAL
there are some challenges        DESIGN
homeowners must be aware of
when tackling below-grade          Draw out plans, carefully
living spaces.                   taking into consideration any
Choosing the right products      low ceilings or small windows.
is vital to the comfort, safety  Try to incorporate structural
and function of your new         features into your design, such
living area. Look for ones that  as attractive wood beams.
help to maximize energy          Keep the space as open as
efficiency and protect against   possible. Select lighting that
moisture, fire and noise.        provides a bright, airy feel.
Here are the top points to
consider to ensure a successful  DON'T FORGET TO
basement renovation:             SOUNDPROOF IT

WATERPROOF IT                      Soundproofing is the
                                 ultimate solution to maximize
  Check the interior             your basement's quiet and
foundation and floors to make    privacy. Whether your
sure there are no existing       newfound space will function
moisture issues, water damage    as a home theatre, music
or mould problems. Address       room, home office or
any primary moisture issues      playroom, it will benefit from
before finishing the space.      quality acoustic insulation,
Examine grading to ensure        like Roxul Safe 'n' Sound. Not
water runs away from your        only is it highly effective, but
foundation.                      it's also easy to install.

INSULATION IS KEY                CONSIDER FIRE SAFETY

  It plays a critical role in      Since many basements are
                                 now being renovated as]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[MAY 2016 • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                 37

Five landscaping tips to increase

your property value

  Investing in landscaping can  your home in the near future,      CONSULT A PRO                 Their industry insights will
bring some of the biggest       tailor the landscaping plan to                                   ensure you are investing
returns for homeowners, yet     appeal to your target buyer.         Take a walk around your     dollars in the right places.
too often it remains            Families typically enjoy more      property with a real estate   » News Canada
overlooked or underdone. The    greenery and yard space for        agent or landscaper for tips
same care and attention we      children to play, and a small      and additional pointers on
apply to interior renovations   patio for entertaining. They       where to make improvements.
should be applied to the        are also likely to have less time
garden.                         to groom the property, so           Got
                                select plants that are native to
  “Curb appeal plays a huge     the region and easy to             Spring
role in selling your home and   maintain.
adding value to it,” says                                           Cleaning?
Michelle Sordi, director of     BE EQUIPPED WITH THE
marketing at Husqvarna, the     RIGHT TOOLS                          Let us do the
world’s largest producer of
outdoor power products.           Quality tools produce            Dirty Work!
“Enhancing your outdoor         professional grade results and
space with smart landscaping    help you complete tasks more            Need                     Drapes?
solutions is a great way to     efficiently. A lawn mower with     SeaSstoonraalgeF?UR            COATs?
invest in your home.”           an adjustable cutting deck                                       Duvets?
                                makes it easier to select the
  Sordi shares the following    height for cutting while a         Benetvtierronfomretnhte.      Brandon Cleaners
landscaping tips for            lightweight trimmer that is                                            204-571-3033
homeowners looking to           compatible with multiple            yBouerttcelroftohres.
increase their property value:  attachments minimizes the          Better for you.                      349 – 9th Street
                                number of tools in your shed.                                              Brandon, MB
NURTURE YOUR LAWN
                                PAVE THE WAY                                                        Monday - Friday • 7am - 5:30pm
  Once the snow melts, do an
assessment of your lawn and       Commonly referred to as                                                    Drop offs at Blue Moon or
look for any dead grass or      hardscaping, consider adding                                           Shoppers Mall Guest Services.
thinning patches so you can     a stone walkway or patio
quickly treat them. Also,       section. As well, care for the
remove any weeds as early as    shrubs and greenery that
possible so you can avoid       surround your home. This
breeding pests and diseases.    adds immediate curb appeal
                                and helps buyers understand
LANDSCAPE WITH A                the outdoor living space
PURPOSE                         available.

  If you’re planning to sell]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[38 THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME, YOUR WAY • MAY 2016

Rethink the classic sundae — on a stick!

  If you're looking for an indulgent treat,     • 1/3 cup (75 ml) peanut butter            Set over medium-high heat and bring to
this twist on the ice cream parlour classic     • 3 1/2 oz (100 g) bittersweet chocolate,  a boil, whisking continuously. Reduce
is just the trick. The combination of         chopped                                      heat and simmer gently, stirring
peanut butter, fudge and fresh fruit is sure    • 1 tbsp (15 ml) vanilla                   occasionally, for 5 minutes.
to delight kids and those young at heart.       • 1/4 tsp (1 ml) salt
This decadent sauce can be kept                 Ice Cream Sundae Skewers                     2. Remove from heat and whisk in
refrigerated for up to one week.                • 12 wooden skewers (4-inch/10-cm),        peanut butter, bittersweet chocolate,
                                              or long toothpicks                           vanilla and salt.
BROWNIE SUNDAE ON A STICK WITH                  • 12 brownie cubes (1-inch/2.5-cm)
PEANUT BUTTER FUDGE SAUCE                       • 12 small strawberries                      3. Thread each skewer with a brownie,
                                                • 1 large banana, cut into 12 slices (½-   strawberry and banana slice. Scoop ice
  Prep time: 15 minutes                       inch/1-cm thick)                             cream into 6 dishes and top with two
  Cooking time: 5 minutes                       • 6 scoops coffee, vanilla or chocolate    skewers. Drizzle sauce over sundae
  Makes 6 servings, plus 2 cups (500 ml)      ice cream                                    kebobs and garnish with peanuts.
of sauce                                        • 2 tbsp (30 ml) peanuts, preferably
                                              salted, coarsely chopped                     TIP
INGREDIENTS
                                              DIRECTIONS                                     Peanut Butter Fudge Sauce can also be
  Peanut Butter Fudge Sauce                                                                a replacement for traditional chocolate
  • 1 cup (250 ml) whipping cream               1. In a medium saucepan, whisk             fondue, to be served with your favourite
  • 1/2 cup (125 ml) brown sugar              together whipping cream, brown sugar,        fruits.
  • 1/3 cup (75 ml) honey                     honey and cocoa powder until smooth.         » News Canada
  • 1/4 cup (60 ml) unsweetened cocoa
powder]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[STARTS NOW!

Listen to StarFM weekday mornings
     at 8:15 to call in and qualify!

Enter at any  NEEPAWA
  of these
 Sponsors:             Creabysy’s
                          Hot Tub & Billiards
starfm.ca]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[BUDGET BLINDS AND LUTRON:

THE BRAINPOWER BEHIND YOUR SMART HOME

The Lutron
Smart App
for iPhone®,
iPad®, and
AndroidTM lets
you
automate
your home
at a touch
of a button.

0/.-/,+*)/,('+/,*&%'+*%$'#,/*"!,%',&"/ ,/*"!,%',*')

SMART SHADES +        SMART LIGHTS +                              SMART THERMOSTAT

                '+

*,%')*!,',!'&,'+$+/#%*!,
       "+*%,('+/,'#"&%*%$'#*

 ," ," ,),
,+                        204-727-4766


	,,*,/ ,&,,, ,+,,

*Applies to selected Lutron® window treatments by Budget Blinds®. Some restrictions may apply. Ask for details. Not valid with any other offers, discounts, or coupons. Valid for a limited time only. Offer good at initial time of estimate only. At participating franchises only.

©2016 Budget Blinds, LLC. All Rights Reserved. Budget Blinds is a trademark of Budget Blinds, LLC. and a Home Franchise Concepts Brand. Each franchise independently owned and operated. Franchise opportunities available. ©2016 Lutron Electronics Co., Inc.]]></page></pages></Search>