<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="4"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Thursday  February 11  2021   n  the BranDOn sUn                                                                          wetsman this week     retirement 2021     B1
                                                                                                                                                      n
                                                                                                                                                                          n































































































































































           We Are Here                                                                                                                • Suites & Villas Designed With You in Mind
                                                                                                                                     • Light Housekeeping & Laundry Services Included
                                                                                                                                  • Spacious Common Areas & Recreation Facilities

                                                                                                                                 • Recreation Sta for Outings & Planned Activities
                                                                                                                               • Varied Nutritious & Delicious Meals Created by our Red Seal Chef
                                                                                                                              • No Buy-in Fees or Long-term Leases
                                                                                                                             • Pet Friendly Suites Available
                                                                                                                             • On site Medical Clinic, Pharmacy, Salon & Shuttle Service

                                                                                                                                    BOOK YOUR PERSONAL TOUR

                                                                                                                                         TODAY 204-725-1340




          NOW RESERVING SUITES & ACCEPTING NEW RESIDENTS!                                                                      1340 - 10  Street, Brandon | www.rotaryvillas.ca
                                                                                                                                       th]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[B2     retirement 2021     westman this week                                                                                the BranDOn sUn   n  Thursday  February 11  2021
                               n
            n
        vARIOUS EFFORTS                                         ernment, the program can be accessed through SEARCordinator@  to health restrictions.
                                                                  Funded by United Way Brandon & District and the federal gov-
                                                                                                                          Like Prairie Oasis, Seniors for Seniors is closed to the public due
                                                                prairieoasis.ca or 204-596-1176.                          Seniors are at the high-risk end of the spectrum when it comes
                                                                  Funding for the line runs out at the end of March, at which point   to pandemic health effects, and most of them are taking the lock-
        REACH OUT                                               Todd points seniors to the Age Friendly Brandon Telephone Infor-  down seriously as a result.
                                                                mation Line at 204-729-2525, which is currently staffed weekdays
                                                                                                                          “The main (call) I get is, ‘When can I get a vaccination?’ That
                                                                from 7:30 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.
                                                                                                                        seems to be a real concern, so I just share with them what’s in the
        TO SENIORS                                              line was originally created to offer an easy-to-access database of   papers or what’s on the radio that morning,” Schonewille said.
                                                                  Age Friendly Brandon board member Susan Boyachek said the
                                                                                                                          Others just want to chat, which typically lasts around the 15-min-
                                                                                                                        ute mark.
                                                                activities and resources for seniors.
                                                                                                                          “We do have a nice talk and I tell them to call back anytime,” she
                                                                  But with very little going on as a result of ongoing health restric-
        IN ISOLATION                                            tions, it has served a very different purpose since it launched a few   said.
                                                                                                                          Efforts such as this are important, she said, as she has noticed
                                                                months ago.
                                                                  “With activities being very limited, especially in-person, the tele-
                                                                                                                          “When you’re down, you just don’t feel like doing anything, and
                                                                phone line in itself is a way to connect with people,” she said.  many seniors’ health deteriorate over the course of the past year.
        BY TYLER CLARKE
                                                                  So far, they’ve only been getting between 10 and 20 calls per   then you’re more apt to sleep and just haven’t got that energy, and
          Social isolation, loneliness and depression are ongoing concerns   month, but she said it’s still 10 to 20 more people who got linked   we’re all like that regardless of whatever our age is,” she said.
        when it comes to seniors, but they’re of much greater prominence   with resources and a social contact, which she considers an early   Being around other people and socializing — which they can’t do
        lately.                                                 success.                                                right now — typically gives people the lift they need.
          “They’re not doing well,” Prairie Oasis Senior Centre executive   The friendly voice on the other side of the line is Seniors for Se-  Schonewille said they’re trying out a number of ways to reach
        director Steve Todd said.                               niors executive director Margaret Schonewille.          out.
          “They are less engaged when you talk to them — they’re more   Between these conversations and those with Seniors for Seniors   A curbside lending library for books and puzzles has been active,
        withdrawn, and I think that’s because of long-term isolation.”  regulars, she said it’s safe to say seniors, in general, are struggling.  they’ve put together gift baskets for seniors and host a weekly meal
          Just about everything has been shuttered during level red restric-                                            program called Dinner is Served.
        tions, Todd said, and Prairie Oasis is no exception.                                                              “We were concerned that seniors weren’t going to eat or couldn’t
          They were able to operate at limited capacity during level orange,                                            go to the store and things with everything happening so suddenly,”
        but he’d be reluctant to reopen any time soon, even if the govern-                                              Schonewille said.
        ment OK’d it.                                                                                                     Last week saw 330 meals go out, which cost seniors $10 and are
          “With that new (COVID-19) variant … I really think it’s going to                                              delivered free of charge by Royal LePage staff, who have been at it
        take off again, which is unfortunate,” Todd said. “Rather than open                                             since the pandemic started in March 2020.
        and close again, I’m going to keep motoring through with limited                                                  In addition to receiving the meal, she said the delivery offers
        contact.”                                                                                                       recipients  the opportunity to  chat with  the delivery person  and
          This limited contact has resulted in many seniors’ only connec-                                               something to look forward to each week.
        tion with people being through the Meals on  Wheels program,                                                      Seniors for Seniors is also in the process of starting up a walking
        which Prairie Oasis continues to operate.                                                                       buddy program so they have someone to walk with, alongside oth-
          Volunteer delivery person Eleanor McCallum said this is unfor-                                                er efforts.
        tunate, since she delivers seven to 14 meals in a single hour, so                                                 Schonewille encourages anyone interested in these programs, or
        contact is limited.                                                                                             in receiving a dose of soul-enriching human contact, to call the Age
          “You’re on such a short timeframe that you don’t have a lot of                                                Friendly Brandon Telephone Information Line at 204-729-2525.
        time to chat, but I try to access how well they’re doing.”
          These visits have become even shorter and less personal during                                                » tclarke@brandonsun.com
        the COVID-19 pandemic, she said, adding they’re currently limited
        to brief contact at their front door while wearing a mask.                                                      » Twitter: @TylerClarkeMB
          To help stay in contact with seniors, Prairie Oasis has also been
        running the Seniors’ Engagement and Referral Program, which of-  Seniors for Seniors executive director Margaret Schonewille is
        fers seniors someone to talk to by email, phone, FaceTime or limit-  the friendly voice behind the Age Friendly Brandon Telephone
        ed in-person limits at the centre or a public place.    Information Line. (Tyler Clarke/The Brandon Sun)


            COOkING THROUGH THE COvID-19 pANDEMIC



              With most social activities going by the wayside, why not give  own home and work with them,” Schonewille said, adding that
            cooking a go?                                                 during pre-COVID times they’d visit with them in person, but
              Brandon Seniors for Seniors Co-op Inc. has released the  now they bring them books or puzzles to help keep them stim-
            “Cooking Through the COVID-19 Pandemic” cookbook in part-     ulated.
            nership with Healthy Together Now/Healthy Brandon.             They also phone people “just to bring some people into their
              Executive director Margaret Schonewille said the majority of  lives.”
            contributors have been local seniors, and there’s “quite a vari-  Books can be ordered by calling 204-571-2050 or by drop-
            ety” of recipes in the $10 book.                              ping by 311 Park Ave. East between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m. during
              Proceeds from the book go toward the Anti-Aging Isolation  weekdays.
            program.
              “We check in and we try to find seniors who are living in their  » The Brandon Sun





           At Pharmasave,
           what truly

           matters?                                             Knowing which

                                                                medications you
                                                                are taking and
                                                                understanding why
                                                                you are taking them.
















                      For All Your Pharmacy Needs




                                                • Prescribing for minor ailments


           Ask Your                            • Injection services (travel vaccines,
                                                  vitamin B12, shingles vaccine, etc.)
           Live Well                          • Free blood pressure testing


                                                 for customers
           Pharmacist
                                            • Personalized Compliance Packaging
           About                           • Online Prescription Refills



           Travel Health                  • Personal care


                                         • Confectionary


                                         • Sigvaris Compression Stockings

                                                              and much more!





          Seniors Discount 10% OFF EVERYDAY
                                                  *Excludes prescriptions




                PHARMASAVE BRANDON                   PHARMASAVE BRANDON CLINIC
                   2425 Victoria Avenue                  4 - 42 McTavish Avenue E.
                     Ph. 204-728-1062                         Ph. 204-728-3665
           Mon-Fri: 9am - 7pm | Sat: 10am - 4pm     Mon-Fri: 9am - 6pm | Sat: 9am - 4pm]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Thursday  February 11  2021   n  the BranDOn sUn                                                                          wetsman this week     retirement 2021     B3
                                                                                                                                                      n
                                                                                                                                                                          n
                                                                                            AMAZING bENEFITS TO


                                                                                            SENIORS HAvING pETS





                                                                                              Pets bring much joy to the lives they touch. So   chronic pain patients.”
                                                                                            it should come as no surprise that the 2019-2020   • FEELING OF PURPOSE: Caring for an animal not
                                                                                            National Pet Owners Survey, which was conduct-  only stimulates physical activity, but it also can
                                                                                            ed  by the  American  Pet Products  Association,   give  seniors  a  reason  to  get  up  and  go,  which
                                                                                            found that about 85 million families in the United   equates to a feeling of purpose.
                                                                                            States own a pet. In Canada, 7.5 million house-
                                                                                            holds are home to companion animals, states the   • ALTERED FOCUS: Having a pet can help seniors
                                                                                            PetBacker blog.                           focus on something other than physical or men-
                                                                                              Pets offer companionship and unconditional   tal health issues and preoccupations about loss
                                                                                            love. While they are fitting for any family, seniors   or aging, according to New York-based psycholo-

                                                                                            may  find  that  having  a  pet  is  especially  benefi-  gist Penny B. Donnenfeld.


                                                                                            cial.  The organization  A Place for  Mom,  which
                                                                                            helps match families with senior living residenc-  • INCREASED PHYSICAL ACTIVITY: Pets require care,
                                                                                            es, says pets provide a comfort system that pro-  and that interaction can get seniors moving more
                                                                                            duces measurable health results. Caring for pets   than if they didn’t have a pet.
                                                                                            and being around them can produce a chemical   • IMPROVED HEALTH: Ongoing research from Har-
                                                                                            chain reaction in the brain that may help to lower   vard Medical School has found dog owners have
                                                                                            stress hormones while also increasing produc-  lower blood pressure, healthier cholesterol levels
                                                                                            tion of the feel-good hormone serotonin.   and lower risk of heart disease than those who
                                                                                              This is not the only health benefit pets may   don’t own a dog.

                                                                                            provide. A recent study from the Mayo Clinic,
                                                                                            which looked at 1,800 people between the ages   • STICK TO ROUTINE: Caring for pets helps seniors
         STAY THE COURSE                                                                    almost half owned a dog. Having a dog was likely   ment can be important to ward off risk of depres-
                                                                                                                                      maintain a routine. Having structure after retire-
                                                                                            of 25 and 64 who had healthy hearts, found that
                                                                                            to spur heart-healthy behaviors, like exercising
                                                                                                                                      sion. Staying on top of feeding, grooming and
                                                                                            with the pet, eating well and having ideal blood
                                                                                            sugar levels.                             other pet needs also can help prevent cognitive
                                                                                                                                      decline.
                                                                                              Pets also provide emotional support and com-
                                                                                            panionship that can help seniors — including   » Wire Services
        IN RETIREMENT pLANNING those who may be divorced or widowed — feel
                                                                                            more secure and happy.  The National Poll on
        BY DREW MAY                               the business, some people on the cusp of retire-  Healthy  Aging  found  that,  among  respondents
                                                  ment are pushing it back by a year or two.
                                                                                            who had pets, 88 percent said their pets helped
        The COVID-19 pandemic has caused huge chang-  For those in the service industry, such as a bar-  them  enjoy  life,  and  86  percent  said  their  pets
        es in many aspects of life, but less so in retirement   bershop or a restaurant, Auriat said the pandemic   made them feel loved.

        planning, according to one financial planner.                                         Seniors considering getting a pet can explore
                                                  hit them hard.
                                                                                            the many benefits to doing so.

        The pandemic resulted in an initial downturn in   “Manitoba Hydro kept charging you and property
        the stock market, but that quickly recovered over   taxes are still due… and so it has pushed off their   •  REDUCE  PAIN: A 2012 study published in Pain
        the summer, said Kerry Auriat, an investment   ability to retire,” he said.         Magazine found therapy dogs provided “signifi-

        advisor at National Bank Financial. As a result,                                    cant reduction in pain and emotional distress for

        many people’s finances are still in-tact.
                                                  On the other hand, many people in agriculture
                                                  had a more prosperous 2020 because of a pro-
        “For many of my clients, they enjoyed very posi-  ducing growing season.
        tive years,” he said.
                                                  “If you’re a person who runs a business that’s                                                          OUR
        “There’s a real recognition that there’s a pandem-  considered essential it may well have been a good
        ic happening out there, on the other side there’s   year,” he said.                                                                               MISSION
        also a recognition that the pandemic does not                                                                                                     To respect aging

        necessarily equal finances.”                                                                                                                      by improving
                                                  Devron Jakeman, a wealth advisor at Fusion
                                                  Credit Union, said the pandemic wasn’t some-                                                            the personal
        Many retirees are already out of the workforce, so   thing anyone could see coming, but a strong plan                                             wellness of our
        they aren’t at risk of losing their jobs. While they   is still key before retiring. He also said the impact                                      members through
        may have seen big changes  in their  day-to-day   of the pandemic on retirement is highly depen-                                                  nutrition and
        lives because of the health restrictions, their pen-  dent on whether people are working, or if they are                                          opportunities for
        sions aren’t as at risk, he said.                                                                                                                 social interaction,
                                                  already retired.
                                                                                                                                                          recreation and
        “It’s been an impact on the quality of life, but I’m   The pandemic-induced volatility of the market                                              volunteerism.
        not seeing it from a financial planning perspec-  may have caused added emotional stress for peo-

        tive,” Auriat said.
                                                  ple over the past year, but a long-term vision is
                                                  key, he said.
        The Bank of Montreal’s annual retirement survey
        found similar results. According to BMO, 57 per   “If you’re buying long-term and you’re in your
        cent of Canadians surveyed living in the prairies   earning years… have a long-term perspective
        are confident they will have enough money to re-  on it, don’t get too short-sighted on what’s going

        tire on time, compared to 54 per cent nationally.
                                                  to happen in the next three to six months or the
                                                  next twelve months if that money is intended for   Let Amanda and her staff
        A total of 64 per cent of people in the prairies also   longterm savings,” he said.
        planned on making a contribution to their Regis-                                      impress you with hot home
        tered Retirement Savings Plan before the March   “Really stay the course on planning, especially if   cooked meals provided
        1 deadline, according to the BMO survey.  That   you’re earning hasn’t been affected. It’s easy to get   Monday through Friday.
        number is just below the 67 per cent of people in   distracted with COVID but make sure to keep fol-  Cold meals are available for
                                                                                                                                                                    $
        Ontario and British Colombia who intended to   lowing your plan.”                     weekends and holidays. Cooled or                      ALL MEALS ONLY  10   00
        make a contribution, the highest in the country.                                      frozen bulk orders are available for those out-of-town.  including taxes delivered.
                                                  » dmay@brandonsun.com
        The financial impact of the pandemic is also                                          To order call Amanda at 204-727-6641 ext 104 or email amanda.fast@prairieoasis.ca

        highly dependent on what kind of industry peo-  » Twitter: @DrewMay                                             241 8th Street Brandon, Manitoba
        ple are working in. Depending on the nature of
           8     SIGNS YOU MIGHT


                 NEED A HEARING AID


           Hearing impairments are common among older adults.
           While a variety of solutions exist, it’s important to
           recognize the signs of hearing loss so you can promptly
           seek treatment and restore your auditory acuity. Here
           are eight signs you might need a hearing aid.

              1. You think your loved ones mumble more than they
                used to

              2. You  confuse  similar-sounding  words  and  have                                          prairiewealth.ca
                trouble distinguishing consonants


              3. You often need to ask people to repeat themselves
              4. You struggle to follow conversations in noisy
                environments such as restaurants

              5. You have a hard time understanding people over
                the phone



              6. You ﬁnd it particularly difﬁcult to hear the voices of
                women and children
              7. You often increase the volume of the TV or radio

              8. You no longer notice everyday sounds like birds
                chirping or your phone ringing                         INDEPENDENT

           If you notice these or other signs that your hearing
           is declining, consult an audiologist. This health-care
           professional can propose solutions that suit your needs     UNBIASED                                                   Chris J. Veilleux
           and lifestyle
                                                                       ADVICE                                                      CFP, CLU, FMA, FCSI, CPCA, EPC


                                                                                                                                         President & CEO





                                                                       927-A 26th Street Brandon, MB R7B 2B7, 204-650-0909]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[B4     retirement 2021     westman this week                                                                                the BranDOn sUn   n  Thursday  February 11  2021
            n
                               n
               CREATIvE WAYS                                                                           Technostress among older adults

               TO kEEp bUSY THIS WINTER                                                       Do you feel overwhelmed when you turn   adults who struggle to adapt often compare

                                                                                              on your tablet, navigate your social media   themselves to so-called digital natives, which
        Making art can contribute to your over-    scrapbooks and macramé, there’s no         account or sort through your inbox? If so,   leads to feelings of inferiority.
        all health and well-being by helping to-   shortage of what you can create. For in-   you may be experiencing technostress. First
                                                                                              coined in the 1980s, this term refers to feelings  A WAY FORWARD
        improve cognition, concentration, self-    spiration, look online or visit your local   of stress, frustration, anxiety and depression   If left unchecked, technostress can serious-
        esteem and more. If you want to reap  library.                                        that are linked to an inability to cope well with   ly impact the well-being of older adults. If you
        these benefits and stave off boredom                                                  new technologies.                       struggle to cope with this type of anxiety, speak
        this winter, here are five creative activ- 3. pHOTOGRApHY                                                                     with a health-care professional. Additionally, if
        ities to try.                              This  artform  can  help  you  gain  a  new   A CHANGING WORLD                     you want to learn how to better navigate the dig-
                                                                                                                                      ital world, consider signing up for a computer
                                                                                              Though technostress can be felt by individu-
                                                   perspective of the world. Plus, it’s a great   als of all ages, it’s particularly common among   course or asking a family member for a tutorial.
        1. pAINTING                                way to hone your observation skills and    older adults. This is largely because most se-
        If you don’t feel comfortable starting  express yourself. From magnificent vis-       niors haven’t grown up, gone to school and
        with a blank canvas, a paint-by-num-       tas and bustling cityscapes to portraits   worked in a pluggedin environment the way
        bers  kit is  an ideal  way to  familiarize  of your pets and family members, you     younger people have. As a result, the ability to
                                                                                              adapt to changing technologies doesn’t come
        yourself with this hobby. In addition to  can use any type of camera to capture       easily, which can lead to an array of negative
        improving your dexterity, painting pro-    moments that fill you with joy. If you     feelings like despair, distress and shame.
        vides a chance to put your worries aside  want to add a social element to your
        and create beautiful artwork.              creative activities, find out if your local   A RECENT STUDY
                                                   community centre, library or retirement    In 2018, researcher Galit Nimrod conducted
        2. CRAFTING                                home offers classes. Alternatively, you    a study to assess technostress among 500 se-
                                                                                              niors in Israel. The results indicated that older
        Do-it-yourself projects help preserve  can plan weekly art sessions with friends      adults tend to experience stress when faced
        your fine motor                            and family members.                        with new technologies and feel pressured to
        skills and engage your imagination.                                                   use  them. The  study  also  revealed  that  older
        From greeting cards and murals to  » Wire Services

























          ALL SENIORSDinner is Served!
                             Dinner is Served!
             ATTENTION


               Seniors for Seniors meals consist of a roll/bread, salad, main course and a dessert at a cost
                of  10 per meal. Place your order on a Monday (1-7 meals) and it will be delivered at no extra
                  $
                            charge to your home by community volunteers on Friday.
                            If you need meals immediately, that can also be arranged.
                                 Our meals appear on our website in advance: brandons4s.ca under MEALS
                                  Can we be of service? For more information or to order, call 204-571-2050]]></page></pages></Search>