<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="32"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Your                      HOME










              YOUR            Way













                                     2019 Special Supplement




































                                                              3-Pc.
                                                       Sindal Bistro Set $99
                                                       Includes the table and 2 chairs.
                                                              SINDGPK3
                                                                                     Shanghai Hanging
                                                                                     Patio Umbrella $289
          NASSAU                                                                     Includes metal base
                                                                                     with 4 resin wedges.
          4-Pc. Conversation Set $599                                                SHANAOUP
          Includes loveseat, table, and 2 chairs. NSSAUBCN





                                      1858 - 18th Street North •  Brandon • 204-726-9225 • www.thebrick.com     Locally Owned & Operated




   yh_01_may_09_19_bs_01.crop.pdf   1                                                                     09-May-19   05:14:32]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                           3





















































      Darren Hossack and Wade Davidson, owner/operators of Westman Security & Automation, pose for a portrait at their office in Brandon. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
      Keeping your fortress secure






      BY BUD ROBERTSON            enterprises:  from  high-  owner’s phone allows them   a live-person monitoring
                                  deﬁnition     surveillance  to control their security sys-  station contracted by West-
         There is one very good   cameras to systems that    tem by arming or disarming   man Security and is then
      reason a big dog with an    control lights, locks and   it.                       automatically   forwarded
      attitude isn’t your best line   thermostats from anywhere   “They get notiﬁcations if   to the customer’s phone or
      of defence against some-    in the world.              even a door’s open, windows   computer, wherever they
      one who would invade your     “It’s come a long way    are open,” he said, “even if   are.
      home.                       from the standard of just   it’s not an alarm. They can   “You get logged in and
         “Because dogs like steak,”   a monitoring station call-  control their door locks,   you can see who’s there,” he
      chuckled Darren Hossack,    ing the customers to alert   light switches, thermostats   said, adding the system is
      co-owner of  Westman Se-    them,” Hossack said. “Now,   as well as locking and un-  motion-activated as well as
      curity & Automation Ltd.    in today’s age we have in-  locking (doors) and even   push-button activated.
      in Brandon along with part-  teractive security systems.   having a doorbell camera to   “So  when  somebody
      ner Wade Davidson.          So people can be connect-  see who’s at the front door.”  pushes the doorbell, it’ll
         Westman        Security  ed to their home via their   Hossack said the door-   actually alert you on your
      provides a wide range of    smartphone or computer     bell system is connected to   cellphone.”
      products and services for   anywhere in the world.”    the home’s Wi-Fi.
      both homes and commercial     An app on the home-        The video signal goes to         » Continued on Page 4]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019































































      Wade Davidson, one of the owner/operators of Westman Security & Automation, holds a wireless doorbell camera. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
      » Continued from Page 3     cameras, but we do have      The images can be saved   camera-based security sys-
                                  wireless options, as well   on the recording system for   tems, rather than just arm-
         Hossack said the system   now, which is all in high   about a month — in case   ing a home-alarm system
      has two-way voice connec-   deﬁnition,” he said.       police or others want to re-  with a keypad.
      tion “so you can actually talk   “Back in the day, you   view them — but that can be   “I guess most people are
      to the person that’s outside   used to see ... on the news   increased with more hard-  interested in seeing who it
      the door, so you can tell them   somebody robbing the store,   drive storage, he said.  is, actually,” he said,  “espe-
      to get lost, or police are on   and you can barely see what   “We can also, with our   cially with the social-media
      the way or please leave the   heck the person was,” Hos-  camera systems, we can have   aspect that there is out there
      package by the front door.”  sack added.  “Now, we have   it set up so if there’s motion   now.”
         The owner can also       high-megapixel   cameras   — let’s say in the backyard   They can post the image
      choose to unlock the door   that you can actually zoom   — it’ll send you a push no-  to Facebook or some other
      so a package can be left in-  in afterwards and get a   tiﬁcation,” he said, “and it’s   platform to see if anyone
      side the house instead of at   good, clear shot of who it is,   just one click away and you   recognizes the person at the
      the mercy of the weather or   as well as the night vision on   can see who’s there.”  front door.
      someone looking to steal it.  these cameras now, which is   Hossack noted more peo-
         “We try to hard-wire our   improved by 100 per cent.”  ple are opting to go with       » Continued on Page 6]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[(Formerly Kitchen Gallery)]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[6                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019













































      Monitors display security camera footage at Westman Security & Automation in Brandon. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
      » Continued from Page 4     installed in the basement, the
                                                                                Gott
                                  station will notify the home-                 Go
         Even turning the lights on   owner, or whoever the contact
                                                                            Spring
      and off remotely is another   person is, to let them know.
      aspect of home security, Hos-  Hossack noted it’s reas-               Spring
      sack said.                  suring to know you’ll be con-
                                                                               Cleaning?aning?
         “It’s not just the outside   nected to a live person if you           Cle
      lights, like your motion-acti-  want to call and cancel a false
      vated lights. We replace your   alarm rather than having to
                                                                                 Le
      actual light switches in your   go through a menu to reach                 Let us do the t us do the
      house with our special kind   someone.                                  Dirty Work!ork!
                                                                              Dirty W
      (of switches).”               The cost of security sys-
         If there is a breach of the   tems can range anywhere from
      security system,  “It’ll actu-  $500 to upwards of $5,000,
      ally turn the lights on in the   Hossack said, “depending on   Coveralls               Drapes?
      house,” he said. “And that’s a   what kind of a camera system
      good deterrent for any kind of   or how in-depth you want to      repairs              COATs?
      crook.”                     do with your security.”
         Hossack noted that in ad-  It also depends on whether          zippers             Duvets?
      dition to security, the people   the homeowner wants to au-
      at the monitoring station can   tomate the home to control
      also make the appropriate   the lights and thermostat.     Better for the        Brandon Cleaners
      calls if an alarm goes off.   “The nice thing with our      environment.               204-571-3033
         “So, for example, if the   systems is it’s completely
      smoke detector goes off in the   scaleable,” he said,  “ so you   Better for           349 – 9th Street
      house, they’ll dispatch the ﬁre   can start off with the basic   your clothes.            Brandon, MB
      department. If it’s a burglar   system and just add on every   Better for you.
      alarm, they call the police,   year if you want to.”                                 Monday - Friday • 7am - 5pm
                                                                                             Drop offs at Blue Moon or
      that sort of thing.”                                                                Shoppers Mall Guest Services.
         If there is a ﬂood sensor         » Continued on Page 7]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                           7









































      A smart automated lock, one of the automated security features available from Westman Security & Automation. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
      » Continued from Page 6     345 in 2017, The Brandon
                                  Sun reported earlier this
         While homeowners sign    month.
      a monthly contract for        As of February, there had
      monitoring, the equipment   already been 41 break-ins
      is owned by the client, Hos-  reported, a similar trend to
      sack said.                  previous years.
         The cost of such security   “There’s been a fair-
      systems may well be worth   ly progressive increase in a
      it to protecting one’s home,   lot of our property crimes,”
      especially as Brandon and   Deputy Chief Randy Lewis
      area are seeing continued   told The Sun. “They do oc-
      growth.                     cur in just about every area
         “Unfortunately,   with   of the city … there’s few ar-
      Brandon ... and the meth    eas that are 100 per cent free
      crisis that we have going on   of property crime.”
      right now, you know, there’s   He noted the increase
      a spike in break-ins and    in break-ins continues to
      people are worried,” Hos-   correlate with the amount
      sack said.                  of methamphetamine and
         The statistics back that   other drugs present in the
      up.                         community.
         Break-ins to homes and     “It’s for their own safety
      businesses across the city   and whatnot,” Hossack said
      continue to rise, according   of those who are installing
      to the Brandon Police Ser-  security systems.  “It’s not
      vice, with recent statistics   even just a possession thing          Collyer's Sales & Service
      showing no sign of slowing.   anymore. It’s a life safety.”                221 Rosser Ave
         There were 365 break-
      and-enters in Brandon in    » brobertson@brandonsun.com                Brandon, Manitoba R7A0J8
      2018, according to BPS sta-  » Twitter: @BudRobertson4                  collyersoutdoorpower.ca
      tistics, a slight uptick from                                             204-727-2491]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019

















































      Karin Griffin, co-owner of Alternative Landscaping, in the greenhouse on a warm spring day. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
      Turning your yard into an oasis





      BY BUD ROBERTSON            areas of landscaping, ex-
                                  cavation, yard care, green-
         Why just have a backyard   house operation and fenc-
      when you can have an oasis   ing, decks and railings.
      in which to relax and enter-  “We would start with
      tain?                       asking you  ‘What kind of
         “Everybody likes to be   landscaping are you looking
      outside, I would think,” said   at?’ and you’re going to tell
      Karin Grifﬁn, who owns Al-  me ‘I have no idea, because
      ternative Landscaping Ltd.   I’ve never landscaped before
      with her husband Chris.     in my life,’” said Grifﬁn.
         “It’s healthy, because     That’s where the brain-
      you’re getting that fresh air   storming begins.
      outside and time to be to-    The company comes up
      gether.”                    with an initial design us-
         A ﬁnished yard also helps   ing satellite images of the
      extend the space in a per-  property to present to the
      son’s home, Grifﬁn said.    clients. The cost of a design
         The company has ﬁve      depends on the complexity
      separate departments, each   of the project.
      with its own experts in the
                                         » Continued on Page 10]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019



















































      » Continued from Page 8     screen for them,” Grifﬁn
                                  said.
         The clients will get their   “But the No. 1 question
      money back if they decide   that we ask, and we do not
      to go ahead and hire the    let them leave without an-
      landscapers, Grifﬁn said. If   swering, is their budget.
      they decide to do the work   It’s probably one of the ﬁrst
      themselves, they can also   questions we ask them, even
      get their money back if they   on the phone.
      buy all the materials from    That question is crucial,
      them.                       she said, because they can’t
         Once they’ve decided to   design a backyard if they
      go ahead with the project,   don’t know what the cli-
      the clients then meet with a   ents are willing and able to
      company representative and   spend.
      go over the plans.            After that, the heavy
         Before the work begins,   work can begin.
      however, clients ﬁll out a    “We can do pretty much
      design questionnaire to de-  any size project,” Grifﬁn
      termine what they want to   said.  “Some are in phases.
      see in their yard.          We talk about a design and a
         “Then they would come    budget. So, maybe they have
      in and meet with us and     a budget this year of $5,000,
      would go over exactly what   and next year $5,000 and
      they’re looking for, that   maybe $5,000 the next year.
      kind of thing, with satellite
      images pulled up on a big          » Continued on Page 11]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                          11


                                                                                         » Continued from Page 10
                                                                                           “There could be years
                                                                                         of landscaping at people’s
                                                                                         houses, because of bud-
                                                                                         gets.”
                                                                                           In fact, Grifﬁn said,
                                                                                         they’ve worked with a
                                                                                         homeowner    outside  of
                                                                                         Brandon for some 10 years
                                                                                         now.
                                                                                           “Every year, we go in
                                                                                         and add a phase.”
                                                                                           The property features a
                                                                                         14-foot waterfall, a pond
                                                                                         the size of a small lake,
                                                                                         a massive outdoor kitch-
                                                                                         en and a vegetable garden
                                                                                         with raised beds.
                                                                                           “So many things,” Grif-
                                                                                         ﬁn laughed.
                                                                                           If someone wants to do
                                                                                         all the work themselves,
                                                                                         there are many things to
                                                                                         keep in mind, she said, not
                                                                                         the least of which is drain-
                                                                                         age.

                                                                                               » Continued on Page 12






                            SAVE UP TO 50% WATER WITH PREDICTIVE WATERING™




               SAVE                           MANAGE                                    SERVICE
              HYDRAWISE                     SITES FROM ANYWHERE                        SYSTEM PROBLEMS
         PREDICTIVE WATERING                 AROUND THE WORLD                          WHEN THEY OCCUR
















        A healthy, beautiful garden needs just the right amount of water to thrive.
           Hydrawise automatically adjusts watering based on highly accurate,
        internet-sourced local weather data. The system looks at the forecast and
         past history to ensure that just the right amount of irrigation is applied.

                204-728-0650  |  1515 Percy Street, Brandon  |  www dandbsprinklers.com]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[12                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019




















































      Karin Griffin, co-owner of Alternative Landscaping, in the greenhouse on a warm spring day.  (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)

      » Continued from Page 11  stones down.”
                                   Grifﬁn knows the pull
         “There are always ele-  of DYI.
      vations in your yard that,   “A lot of people will say
      to the naked eye, you can-  ‘OK, I’m going to go to ...
      not see,” she said.  “So,   a box store, and I’m going
      somebody wants to put in   to buy all these plants, I’m
      a patio and it’s draining   going to buy these blocks
      towards the house.”       and I’m going to put this
         There is also the matter   all down,’” she said,  “and
      of when to start a project.  then they put it all in the
         If there is still frost in   wrong spot and they don’t
      the ground, that’s not the   even put the block down
      time to be putting in a pa-  right.”
      tio, for example.            That’s not going to
         “We’re not out there,   make anyone happy.
      yet, even though it looks    “There’s nothing worse
      beautiful out and it looks   than spending a lot of
      like everything is great,”   money on something and
      Grifﬁn said.  “There is   it’s not right,” Grifﬁn said.
      still frost in the ground
      so that will cause heaving   » brobertson@brandonsun.com
      if we dug it too early and   » Twitter: @BudRobertson4
      packed it in and put patio]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019














































      A wattle fence made to protect a garden on a property in Contrada Petraro in the mountains of northern Sicily. In northern Sicily, fences are essential to protect
      gardens against wild pigs. (The Associated Press)
      » WATTLE FENCES...


      …Weaving branches takes time, yields rewards


         CONTRADA PETRARO,  19th century, but their numbers  wild pigs.                ing a fair amount, they can mal-
      Sicily — They come in the mid- have exploded since they were   Our farm, like much of the  function, and pose the obvious
      dle of the night and are gone by  reintroduced more than 20 years  countryside hereabouts, is patch- problem of causing nasty electric
      morning. But without fail, they  ago and crossbred with domesti- ily ringed by wire fences thread- shocks.
      leave their calling cards: Pronged  cated pig species, authorities say. ed with strands of barbed wire.   Sturdy wire fences with ce-
      footprints and gashes in the   Plant a vineyard? Don’t both- These fences weren’t designed to  ment posts are common. But I
      ground where they’ve dug with  er, locals told me. They’ll eat all  keep wild pigs out but to keep  found them unattractive, expen-
      natural abandon.           your grapes.               ﬂocks of sheep in. Held up by  sive and boring to look at with
         This nocturnal troublemaker   Put up a fence and they’ll ﬁnd  withered sticks and even sections  their uniformity in shape and
      in mountainous northern Sicily  a way in. These pigs can jump 3  of plumbing pipe, they were old  purpose. Besides, I was told that
      is the “cinghiale,” the wild pig, a  feet off the ground, I learned.  and falling over. They were use- pigs will get under them eventu-
      bane to those who tend a garden.  One neighbour told me he  less, and a nuisance. One section  ally.
         When I came to live with  was removing his vineyard due  cut across our land and had to be   As spring approached — and
      my wife and two boys on a small  to the pigs and their bottomless  removed both for safety and ease  with it an urge to sow seeds and
      abandoned farm that we bought  appetites.  “They’re terrible,” he  of passage. I didn’t want my boys  plant vegetables — we still had
      here in the Madonie Mountains,  said with regret.     to get caught on the barbed wire  no fence. And on several crisp
      the locals quickly instilled a fear   But I had visions of turning  while they were running and  winter mornings, I found the
      of the cinghiale in me. Accord- sections of our three acres into  playing.       telltale signs of wild pigs: big
      ing to many people, these ani- garden spots overﬂowing with   With wire cutters in hand, I  holes dug around olive trees and
      mals have made gardening near- carrots, tomatoes, cucumbers,  removed these obstacles.  along muddy trenches where
      ly impossible.             herbs, artichokes.            Many people string up elec- rains drained off our hillsides.
         The wild pigs disappeared   I began to think harder about  tric fences around gardens. But
      from Sicily around the end of the  fences that would keep out the  there are problems: Besides cost-  » Continued on Page 15]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                          15

      » Continued from Page 14            weaving twigs in opposite directions around
                                          the posts. So, if you start one twig on the in-
         The power of their snouts was impressive.  side of a post, it then gets woven around the
      The pigs root in search of tubers and other  outside of the next post, the inside of the next
      buried delights, and can make it look like a  one, and so on. The next twig fed into the
      mechanized tiller guided by a phantom got  fence goes the opposite direction: outside of
      loose overnight.                    post, inside, outside.
         As it happened, one evening as I read   It was quiet work. I cut and stripped
      Leo Tolstoy’s masterpiece “Anna Karenina,”  branches pruned from olive and ash trees,
      I paused halfway through one of his descrip- and listened to the water in a river running
      tions of Russian country life. He depicted a  far down along the valley bottom. The bells
      countryside strung with wattle fences.  of sheep and cows in far-off pastures twin-
         What exactly IS a wattle fence?  kled in the air; the wild shouts of herders
         I had a vague notion, but needed to look  were incomprehensible riddles that kept me
      it up in a dictionary. It was a eureka moment:  company. Sometimes, I paused in my slow,
      A wattle fence is made of sticks driven into  steady work to catch sight of a screeching
      the ground and interwoven with twigs and  bird rushing through the trees.
      branches.                              I started my ﬁrst fence in early March,
         Then I did the next obvious thing: an  and six weeks later I stood back and ad-
      internet search. Sure enough, a few people  mired my handiwork. Deﬁnitely, it had
      out in the world were wattling, and happy to  been a lot of work. But I was satisﬁed.
      show how it is done on homemade videos.  Aesthetically, it was pleasing in its in-
         A wattle fence is simple. It’s made by  exactness, rambling and irregular lines, its
      pounding posts into the ground — say 12  woodiness.
      inches deep — and then weaving twigs and   I was happy to have used twigs and   Writer Cain Burdeau weaves twigs and branches
      branches in and out of the posts. At the very  branches that otherwise would have been   between posts to make a garden wattle fence on a
      least, a twig needs to be woven around three  burned, either in the wood stove or as   property he lives on with his family in Contrada Pe-
      posts so that it stays in place.    bonﬁres.                            traro in the mountains of northern Sicily. In northern
         The fence’s robustness — and it does                                 Sicily, fences are essential to protect gardens against
      become surprisingly robust — comes from  » The Associated Press         wild pigs. (The Associated Press)































                                                      FARM, RESIDENTIAL & COMMERCIAL
                                                                          PROPERTY APPRAISERS


                                                                         Serving Western Manitoba Since 1977
         Suite 30A, 1015 – 26 Street, Brandon
                                     th
         Fax: 204-727-1563  Email: weir1@mts.net                           204-727-7100]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[16                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019

















































      Brandon resident Susan Hawkins waters her vegetables at Hummingbird Garden on the southeast corner of the city, a couple summers ago. (File)
      The garden evolves over time alongside the gardener


      BY ADRIAN HIGGINS          tastes and, most importantly,  ing of the gardener turned out  China, was once considered
                                 philosophies.              to be thugs or wild invaders.  the choicest of all viburnums
         Sometimes the long-distance   Since the 1990s, for example,   Another transformation is  but now is showing up in nat-
      gardener looks out the window  we have turned from ornamen- how a longtime gardener has  ural areas and on invasive plant
      and notices that the maple tree  tal to ecologically minded gar- changed over the years. This is  blacklists.
      he planted as a six-foot sapling  dening — to landscapes where  an interior evolution, inherently   Roach is singularly well
      21 years ago has become a shade  native plants play a larger role,  veiled, perhaps even to oneself.  placed to reﬂect on these chang-
      tree 25 feet tall and 20 across.  and where gardeners seek to   Plants that were trendy at  es.  Twenty-one years ago, she
         Maturity creeps up on you  provide refuge and sustenance  the time have become old hat  wrote a book, “A Way to Gar-
      — in trees, in the garden, in life.  to pollinating insects and oth- or disappeared.  Whither the  den,” that combined practical
      Year to year, the changes seem  er wildlife. Despite this move- Japanese snowbell tree, or the  aspects of gardening with its
      slight. Cumulatively, they are  ment, the world of gardening  Arnold Promise witch hazel or  more metaphysical rewards.
      enormous.                  has never been more multi- sedum Autumn Joy?          Her laboratory was her two-
         The same might be said of  faceted, it seems, with positive   Roach thinks of the  “it  plus-acre property in the Hud-
      the world of gardening itself.  trends in passions for succu- plants” she excitedly installed  son  Valley, 2 1/2 hours north
         I was chatting about this the  lents, houseplants, tropicals,  that would not be welcomed  of New York. At the time, she
      other day with another horti- organic growing and heirloom  today.  The houttuynia Cha- also had a high-pressure post in
      cultural scribe, Margaret Roach,  vegetables, and all the rest.  meleon, a leafy ground cover,  the New York publishing world,
      and was glad to hear that, like   Weather and climate pat- is impossible to remove, much  as editorial director of Martha
      me, she has thought a lot about  terns have changed, too, along  like equisetum, and both go  Stewart Living magazine. She
      the journey through the garden’s  with pests and diseases that  wild in wet soils. She planted  worked high in a skyscraper
      fourth dimension, time. Over  have materially altered what we  lamiastrum as a ground cover; it  with a staff of dozens.
      several decades, we have seen  grow. Ornamental plants once  also doesn’t know where to stop.
      marked shifts in plant palettes,  considered vigorous and ﬂatter- The doubleﬁle viburnum, from   » Continued on Page 17]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                          17


      » Continued from Page 16   the English herbaceous bor-
                                 der, colour-co-ordinated, very
         She left that behind 11 years  photogenic and impossibly de-
      ago, decamped full time to her  manding.
      garden and has developed  “A   Young, driven to perfection
      Way to Garden” as a brand of  and wanting to make a mark,
      sorts, with a website, blog and  you set yourself up for disap-
      radio show. She has revamped  pointment. We were too impa-
      her book, and its reworking in- tient for effect, not sufﬁciently
      evitably tracks the changes in  comprehending of the purpose
      her gardening outlook.     of gardening, and inevitably
         She painted herself -- too  way too hard on ourselves when
      modestly -- as a neophyte when  things ﬂopped.
      the ﬁrst edition came out, but   “I would run up here from the
      her examination of the temporal  city at weekends,” she said. “I had
      space between the old and new  to do this, I had to do that and it
      Roach illustrates that gardening  was never good enough. I could
      is a journey and not a destina- barely walk up the stairs after a
      tion. It is something you do and  day’s gardening. Nothing ever
      something you live, not some- looked like the beautiful pictures   Rena Nayar chucks a massive sunflower plant on a pile that she grew in the
      thing you have.            in the garden books of the day.”  community gardens in the southwest corner of Brandon in 2017. (File)
         This may seem obvious, but   Now her expanse of lawn, at
      when I asked her about her for- its edges, is allowed to revert to a  know their biology. I like that  made a conscious decision to
      mative years, I could see a mir- meadow, and she ﬁnds delight in  I would never (have) thought I  walk away from a high-pressure
      ror image of my own self in her  simple chores and observations,  would be a girl who loves know- career and reset everything,
      pained experiences.        in ﬁnding a caterpillar disguised  ing her weeds by name, but I  even if it was just in time for
         The 1980s and 1990s were  as a twig, and she loves to weed.  do.”             the Great Recession.
      decades  when   books  and    “I have my best thoughts   The other aspect of Roach’s
      glossy magazines trumpeted  weeding,” she told me,  “and I  gardening story is that she  » The Washington Post]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[18                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019



      A makeover for milkweed, for the sake of butterflies


         QUEBEC CITY, Que. —
      For generations, North Amer-
      ican farmers have despised
      milkweed and done their best
      to rid their lands of it. “I hate to
      have milkweed in my strawber-
      ry ﬁeld,” Nathalie Leonard says
      from her farm by the Quebec
      village of Lac-du-Cerf.
         So why does she have 60
      acres of milkweed growing on
      purpose? It’s for the sake of
      butterﬂies — the iconic mon-
      archs. And for a chance to turn
      milkweed into proﬁt.
         “Every weed,” she says,  “is
      only a weed because it’s in the
      wrong place.” Leonard and her
      partners in Monark, a co-oper-
      ative of farmers through Que-
      bec and into  Vermont, hope
      milkweed now has found its
      rightful place in their ﬁelds.
         Intrigued by the notion of
      helping to restore the sinking
      population of monarch butter-
      ﬂies — and persuaded by the
      stirrings of a new market —  Milkweed has long been considered a nuisance on North American farmlands but now, more than 100 farmers in Quebec
      these farmers began clearing  and Vermont are planting it in their fields to help restore the declining population of monarchs, which use that plant
      land or ripping out cash crops  exclusively for their eggs and to feed the caterpillars. The farmers are also tapping a new market for the milkweed
      and turning precious acres over  fibers. (The Associated Press)
      to a plant they’d previously
      seen as a nuisance.        experiment began, but where  public buildings and in back- remembered thinking.  “But I
         The   milkweed   make- the ﬁbre will go after the fall is  yards to give the butterﬂy a  listened.”
      over began when researchers  uncertain.               ﬁghting chance. A 2017 study   After learning that hun-
      in Quebec transformed the     The orange and black mon- at the University of Guelph in  dreds of Quebec acres were
      plant’s silky ﬁbres into a high- archs are wholly dependent on  Ontario found there’s nothing  already under milkweed pro-
      end insulation material for  milkweed. The plant is the only  more effective in this effort  duction, she reached out to
      winter clothing and advanced  host for their eggs and sole sus- than the all-you-can-eat buffet  farmers in Vermont whom she
      other commercial uses for it,  tenance for the caterpillars,  of a farmer’s ﬁeld of milkweed  considered innovators — peo-
      like sound insulation and ab- which feed on milky secretions  — visible from the sky, rooted  ple who would “want to listen,
      sorption for oil spills.  Winter  from the leaves. Milkweed has  in rich soil, and isolated from  wouldn’t laugh too hard, might
      coats stuffed with milkweed  been in rapid retreat, crowd- trafﬁc and pollution.  try it out.” Now, more than 100
      ﬁbre reached outdoor retailers  ed by urban development, at-  When University of  Ver- farmers in Quebec and about a
      in 2016, fetching $800 or more  tacked along roadways, and  mont agronomist Heather  half dozen in Vermont are pro-
      apiece.  The Canadian Coast  driven from pastoral land- Darby ﬁrst heard of Quebec’s  ducing milkweed for Monark,
      Guard tried milkweed garb  scapes by herbicides that spare  initiative, from a man who  of which Nathalie Leonard
      and liked it. And as a side ben- resistant corn and soybeans.  called looking for  Vermont  serves as president.
      eﬁt, the distinctive honey from   A ritual of autumn — crack- farmers to join, she was thrown.
      milkweed ﬁelds is prized.  ing the dry pods to watch the  Milkweed is toxic to livestock  THE PLANT
         Yet the company formed  seed-bearing white ﬂuff escape  — one study says it gives cows
                                                                                          The ecological and eco-
      to process and market the ﬁ- and catch the winds — has fad- “profound depression” on the
                                                                                       nomic promise of milkweed
      bre collapsed last year, forcing  ed.                 rare chance they eat it. It’s been   prompted Roger Rainville to
      the farmers who grow it to    But in recent years, as the  a mark of shame on farmlands,   convert 50 prime acres of his
      step in and try to make a go of  plight of the monarchs be- a sign of sloppy maintenance.
                                                                                       farm lining the Canadian bor-
      the whole milkweed initiative.  came more pronounced, com-  “Oh gosh, here’s another   der to milkweed several years
      They’re on track for perhaps  munities, schools and garden- one of those people with some
                                                                                       ago.
      their best harvest in the ﬁve  ers began planting patches  crazy idea and he wants farm-
      or so years since the milkweed  of milkweed along roads and  ers to grow milkweed!” she   » Continued on Page 19]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                          19


      » Continued from Page 18   so globally known,” Darby said,  ty, then we have no shortage  last winter, a decline of 15 per-
                                 “but also seeing it come togeth- of people who want to buy it,”  cent blamed in part on brutal
         “This was a whole ﬁeld, from  er with agriculture in such a  Leonard said.    storms that season.  The but-
      here to the woods, of just beau- beneﬁcial way.”         “We are really pioneers,” she  terﬂies covered more than ﬁve
      tiful alfalfa,” he said, gesturing   It takes two or three years  added.  “We could lose it all.  times that territory 20 years ago.
      over the dense green crop of  after planting for milkweed to  That’s how it works. You always   Now the cycle continues: On
      purple-ﬂowered milkweed, 3  ﬂower and produce the pods  need dreamers and people who  Rainville’s farm, monarch eggs
      miles (5 km) north of Alburgh,  bursting with ﬂuff. Once estab- are stubborn enough to keep  have been spotted on the leaves.
      Vermont, as he awaited the  lished, they can be irrepressible. going when people say it’s time   He and Darby have seen the
      monarchs on their northern    On her Lac-du-Cerf farm,  to stop.”                butterﬂies — and honeybees —
      summer migration.          Leonard will have her ﬁrst har-                       come in higher numbers, and
         “You get along roadsides and  vest this autumn, her second  THE BUTTERFLY     they anticipate more each year
      there’s not much fertility there.  year after planting. She’ll pick   The monarch population is   as the pathway becomes better
      I tell farmers, if you’re going to  the pods by hand because no   cleaved by the Rockies: Those   known through butterﬂy  “sig-
      grow this, if you try something  way has been devised to har-  east of the mountains winter in   naling.” Such increases have
      new, do it on your best soil,” he  vest them mechanically while   Mexico by the tens of millions,   been reported in Quebec, where
      said. Farmers from across the  preserving the long, wide ﬁbres   while much smaller numbers   milkweed farming got an earlier
      U.S. call him to ask how to get  essential for ﬁne clothing, the   in the  West migrate to Cali-  start.
      going with milkweed.       lucrative end of the market.  fornia. It’s one of nature’s mir-  Over coming months, the
         At Rainville’s farm, Darby   It’s a short harvest, about   acle migrations as the delicate   monarchs will get their ﬁll, ﬁnd
      waded into waist-high milk- three weeks, making for a la-  insect ranges over as many as   their wings and ﬂutter away
      weed, bending to sniff tightly  bor-intensive, inefﬁcient pro-  3,400 miles (5,500 km), as far   south, setting up the harvest for
      knit ﬂowers that she likened to  cess, and a bottleneck that pro-  as southern Canada, in a round   the milkweed they leave behind.
      lilacs. The ugly-duckling weed  ducers must overcome if they   trip that takes several genera-  It’s a fraught journey — for the
      was looking handsome and  are to make a milkweed indus-  tions to complete.      insects in their against-the-odds
      smelling ﬁne.              try take root.                Mexican ofﬁcials reported in   ﬂight, and for the farmers trying
         “What better opportunity to   “If we can manage to ﬁnd a   March that the wintering mon-  to help them and make a buck.
      preserve an insect that’s just so  way to harvest at a faster rate,   archs, clumped tightly in trees,
      dearly loved by so many people,  dry it and give it ﬁne quali-                   » The Associated Press
                                                            covered 6.1 acres (2.5 hectares)


          Brandon Shutters Roll-Up-Shutters





          RESIDENTIAL ROLL-UP SHUTTERS  !"   #$
            !! #!$       $  $!      " $   $ "  $  !$ # "!#
            $!#   # $ " !$    " $   #  $ "   # $" $  #
          "     # $ " #!  # $  !" $   #$      # $
           !" #   " $ !" $ !#       $     #   $   $ # #!#
           #   #!$     #$  " $  !#$     $ "!$   $  " # $  "
               #! $   "$"  #!$ !      $ "  #$!#     " $
               $ "  !" $ "!$     $  ## #! $   $     $ "! #!
              $!#   #$  $ "   $ !#  $    $ ## $ " #$ #  #
             $   #
          COMMERCIAL SECURITY SHUTTERS AND
          ROLL UP DOORS  !"   #$ !" #   " $   $   #
           "  !" $  "!$    #! #$  "  #!    $  $ !#
          #   !"  #    $ !" #  $ " !$   #  $   $   #  "!
           "  #!    $          "  $       #$  #!   #
           "   #!  $  !"    $          $   #     $
            "!# !"    $   #  $ "  !"  $          "!  #$!""
             $    $ "!#

                     !"  ! "    !      " !" " !  "        "    " !     "      ! "
                                  !           !            """ """     !           !]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[20                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019


      Give your flower and veggie seedlings some tough love



         Seedlings raised on win-
      dowsills or in greenhouses
      have been coddled to some
      degree and aren’t ready to face
      the great outdoors. A tempo-
      rary period called “hardening
      off ” can prepare these plants
      for more intense sunlight,
      wind and varying tempera-
      tures.
         Make this transition grad-
      ually, over the course of a
      week or two. A good place to
      harden off seedlings is in a
      somewhat sheltered spot out-
      doors, such as in a cold-frame
      (basically an open-bottomed
      box with a clear, removable
      cover) or near a wall in dap-
      pled shade. Or offer the seed-
      lings full exposure for limited,
      but increasing, periods.
      ACCLIMATION TO
      TEMPERATURE
         The changes that lower
      temperatures during the hard-
      ening-off period will induce
      in coddled seedlings depend
      on the nature of the seedlings
      themselves.
         Seedlings of cabbage, let-
      tuce, snapdragon, pansy and
      other plants that can eventu-
      ally laugh off cold even well   Gradual exposure of seedlings to outdoor conditions readies them for eventual planting out in the garden.
      below freezing develop that   (The Associated Press)
      tolerance for cold by building
      up sugars in their cells. Cold  AVOID SUNBURN         turn darker green. And sto-   Movement of plants has
      also changes the composition   Even in the absence of   mata, which are the tiny pores  yet another effect: It slows
      of their cell membranes.   cold, outdoor sunlight —   in leaves through which wa- stem elongation, which con-
         Seedlings of tomatoes,  which can be as much as 10   ter is lost and carbon dioxide  tributes to that stocky, lush
      marigolds, zinnias and oth- times more intense than light   and oxygen are exchanged,  green look that shows a plant
      er plants that cannot tolerate  streaming through a sunny,   become more quickly able to  has been well hardened off.
      temperatures much below  south-facing window — can    open and close in response to   So blow on, shake or gen-
      freezing suffer from so-called  injure  coddled  seedlings’  changing conditions.  tly brush your seedlings regu-
      chilling injury even at tem-  leaves.                                            larly to toughen them up and
      peratures below 50 degrees F.   Gradual exposure to more  SHELTER FROM WIND      encourage them to become
      Changes in plant membranes  intense light, beginning in   Stomatal response also   stocky plants better able to
      from chilling injury interfere  dappled shade or with just a  plays a role in a plant’s gradu-  handle the real world of the
      with sunlight driving photo- few hours each day in full sun,  al adaptation to wind. During   garden.  That, along with
      synthesis, so instead damag- thickens cell walls, ﬁbres, and  the hardening-off period,   spending a week or so out-
      ing toxins build up in leaves.  cuticles on both existing and  plants become able to re-  doors in a sheltered spot or
         As a tomato or other  new leaves.                  spond more quickly to drying   for only part of each day, will
      warmth-loving plant becomes   With increasing light ex- winds by closing their sto-  ease your seedlings’ transition
      hardened off through gradual  posure,  chloroplasts,  the mata. Even movement of the   to the garden so they hardly
      exposure to cooler tempera-  green, light-trapping energy  plant, whether from wind or   know they’ve been moved.
      tures, it becomes better able  factories in leaves, also move  anything else, plays a role in   Which is as it should be.
      to repair and prevent such  around and align themselves  making stomata more respon-
      damage.                    in such a way that the leaves  sive.                  » The Associated Press]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                          21

      Wild-looking and sustainable is the trend in garden design


         Whether it’s on an enor-                                                      designed in the 1980s by pio-
      mous estate or outside a little                                                  neering landscaper James van
      house, the modern garden aims                                                    Sweden, co-founder with Wolf-
      for wild-looking landscapes,                                                     gang Oehme of the Oehme van
      native species and seamless                                                      Sweden ﬁrm. In a departure
      transitions to natural surround-                                                 from the staid hedges, box-
      ings, according to a new book                                                    woods and perennial borders
      featuring the work of promi-                                                     that dominated the East End
      nent contemporary garden de-                                                     of Long Island at the time, von
      signers.                                                                         Sweden planted low-mainte-
         In “Garden  Wild:  Wild-                                                      nance grasses and other native
      ﬂower Meadows, Prairie-Style                                                     plants, and plants appropriate
      Plantings, Rockeries, Ferneries,                                                 for the seascape like lavender,
      and Other Sustainable Designs                                                    sedums, willows and magnolias.
      Inspired by Nature,” photog-                                                        Bringing native grasses right
      rapher Andre Baranowski ex- gle garden, explaining the de- beautiful.  They can be stun- up to the pool’s edge was con-
      plores a dozen very different  signer’s approach, the challeng- ning. Gardens can be gorgeous  sidered revolutionary at the
      gardens — all of them mostly  es posed and garden highlights,  and sustain wildlife, and at the  time, Baranowski says.
      devoid of manicured lawns and  with an eye to inspiring home  same time be easier to main-  In a garden in East Hamp-
      fussy pruning.             gardeners to try their hand at  tain,” says Baranowski, who  ton, New York, Eric Groft, of
         The focus, instead, is on  this more natural-looking ap- visited the 12 gardens hundreds  the ﬁrm Oehme van Sweden,
      sustainability and plant diver- proach.               of times, looking for the most  screened out trafﬁc using orna-
      sity. Featured garden designers   “Tons of money still goes  evocative images.   mental grasses, which have the
      include Oehme van Sweden,  into fertilizers and weed killers   “This wilder look is abso- added beneﬁt of deterring deer,
      Fernando Caruncho, Jorge  for traditional-style manicured  lutely catching on,” he says.  the book says.
      Sanchez and Piet Oudolf.   lawns, but I’m trying to show   The book begins with a gar-
         Each chapter explores a sin- people that weeds can be quite  den in Water Mill, New York,  » The Associated Press]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[22                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019





















































      Prairie crocus begin to bloom in a pasture on the north side of the Assiniboine River Valley north of Alexander, attracting bees on a sunny afternoon. The prairie
      crocus, Manitoba’s official flower, is  one of the first wildflowers to bloom in the prairies.  (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)

      Wildflowers: robust, low-maintenance, pollinator-friendly


         Gardeners trying to lure   “Ragweed, for example, is   Shop at a specialty nursery   “The ﬁrst step in starting
      pollinators to their landscape  a native plant but is consid- if you want to grow wildﬂow- a wildﬂower area is choos-
      would be wise to mimic na- ered undesirable because it  ers, Yiesla said.        ing an appropriate site and
      ture and plant wildﬂowers.  gives us hay fever,” said Sha-  “Wildﬂowers should be  matching plant species to
      The attractive perennials  ron  Yiesla, a horticulturist  purchased rather than dug  environmental factors such
      tolerate harsh climates, sel- with The Morton Arboretum  from the wild,” she said.  as climate, rainfall, pH and
      dom need fertilizing and re- in Lisle, Ill.           “This is often regulated by  soil type,” said Leonard Per-
      sist most diseases and insect   On the other hand, she  law and even if it is not, a tre- ry,  horticulture  professor
      pests.                     said,  “There are plants that  mendous amount of damage   emeritus with University of
         Wildﬂowers are durable,  people think of as wildﬂow- can be done to wild popula- Vermont Extension, in a fact
      too, requiring little or no irri- ers but they are not native.”  tions through digging.”  sheet.
      gation once established.   Queen Anne’s lace, for in-    Wildﬂower       varieties  “Whenever possible, try to
         “They bloom early and es- stance, came from Europe   generally are divided into  select native species as they
      tablish nicely to make a very  and has been around so long  three major groups: mead- often perform better than
      natural colony,” said Barry  that it has naturalized here.  ow, woodland and wetland.  non-natives,” he said. “Native
      Glick, owner of Sunshine      “Some people call it a  Plants taken from nature  species generally are more
      Farm and Gardens in Renick,  wildﬂower; some call it a  generally don’t survive being  attractive to pollinators and
      West Virginia.             weed,” she said. “Know some- transplanted because growing  beneﬁcial insects, too.”
         But beware: Some native  thing about each plant before  conditions can differ so great-
      plants are invasive.       you choose it.”            ly in residential backyards.       » Continued on Page 23]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[» Continued from Page 22   your area if you want lasting
                                 colours for years to come,
         Simply spreading wild- said Mike Lizotte, a man-
      ﬂower seed over unprepared  aging partner of American
      ground is inefﬁcient. Site  Meadows Inc. in Shelburne,
      preparation is important.  Vermont.
         Break up the soil and      “Finding a reputable seed
      eliminate weeds before sow- company or contacting your
      ing any seed. That will speed  local Master Gardening Ex-     Your lawn has a
      germination and reduce con- tension or native plant source
      fusion over what’s a weed and  would be great resources to    new best friend
      what’s a wildﬂower.        get you started in the right
         It usually is better to  direction,” he said.
      choose bare root plants, plugs   Landscapes may look di-
      or seedlings if you want your  sheveled once the ﬂowers
      wildﬂower gardening to be  fade but don’t be quick to re-
      faster and easier to manage.  move spent plants.
      Seeds are cheaper if you have   “The leaves produce food
      large areas to cover.      that help the plant grow and
         Study   package   labels become bigger and stronger
      closely when buying seed  the next year,”  Yiesla said.
      mixtures. Ideally, you want  “Also the plant may produce
      100 per cent pure seed with- seeds or fruit that feed birds
      out any ﬁll.               and wildlife.”
         It’s ideal to source natives
      or varieties that are proven in  » The Associated Press























                                                                   First visit                    LIMITED
                                                                                                    TIME
                                                                              95*
                                                                                                   OFFER
                                                                    $24                            when you
                                                                                                        k a
                                                                                                    boo
                                                                                                   lawn care
                                                                                                    program





                                                                     GET YOUR FREE LAWN

                                                                       CARE QUOTE TODAY

                                                                          204.285.9549
                                                               weedmancanada.com/brandon
                                                               *First visit $24.95. Taxes extra. Only valid with the purchase of five or more services. Up to 10,000 sq. feet
      A honey bee flies to an aster, a Manitoba wildflower found throughout the   total property size. Cannot be combined with any other offers or promotions. Offer expires July 15, 2019.
      province. (File)]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[24                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019



      Six little tricks that every cook should know




         There are certain small                            is. Use it pretty quickly, and  sticky ingredient, and it will
      skills that make life better                          when you store any leftovers,  slide right out. Cleanup is
      and easier. I’m well aware                            make sure to put a piece of  easier, too!
      that many of them take place                          fresh bread in the container   Now I’m off to google
      outside of the kitchen, and I                         with the sugar.            “how to change a tire.”
      probably don’t know as many
      of those as I should. I’m of                          HOW TO GET HONEY (OR       HOW TO PEEL GINGER
      no use if you have a ﬂat tire                         MOLASSES, MAPLE SYRUP  WITH A SPOON
      or need to calculate the cir-                         OR CORN SYRUP) OUT OF
      cumference of something or                                                          Ginger’s skin is thin
      want to ﬁnd your way out of                           A MEASURING CUP            enough to be scraped off
      the woods.                                               Anything sticky is just   with the edge of a teaspoon.
         But after many years                               plain hard to measure.  You   In fact, it’s easier to use a
      of clanking around in the                             pour it into the cup, or spoon,   spoon than a vegetable peel-
      kitchen, I have collected a   der the blade as it works to  and then into your bowl or   er because the spoon can get
      fair arsenal of cooking tips   pulverize the garlic.  pot, and a thick coating is al-  into the crevices and navi-
      and shortcuts. Here are a few                         ways left inside the measur-  gate over the bumps more
      that everyone should know:  HOW TO MAKE               ing cup, drip drip dripping,   easily. Also, this means you
                                 BUTTERMILK                 but never fully getting out   can have even a very little kid
      HOW TO QUICKLY                Unless we are really plan-  of the cup.  The quick hack   help with this kitchen task,
                                                                                       since they can’t nick them-
      RIPEN AVOCADOS             ning ahead, when  “butter-  is cooking spray. Just spray   selves with a spoon.
         If you have a hard avoca-  milk” comes up as in ingre-  the inside of the cup or mea-
                                                            suring spoon with nonstick
      do and you need it to be soft   dient in a recipe, it’s unlikely   cooking spray, measure your   » The Associated Press
      in a day or so, simply place it   most of us have it on hand.
      in a brown paper bag with a   Easy solution: Make your
      banana or apple and fold the   own. Place 1 tablespoon
      top to close it up. The natu-  lemon juice or white vinegar
      ral ethylene gases emitted by   in a measuring cup and then
      the other fruit will cause the   ﬁll it with milk to the 1 cup
      avocado to ripen faster. De-  line. I like to use whole milk,
      pending on how hard your   but you can also use 2%. If
      avocado is, it might take a   you see slight curdling, don’t
      couple of days.            worry — it won’t affect the
                                 ﬁnished product.  This may
      HOW TO MINCE               not be as thick as regular
      GARLIC SUPER FINE          buttermilk, but the acidity
                                 in the milk will perform the
         If you are using minced   same function — getting you
      garlic in a dish, particular-  to a tender, ﬂaky and ﬂavour-
      ly a dish where the garlic is   ful baked good.
      uncooked, big chunks are
      not what you are looking for.   HOW TO SOFTEN
      Just smash a clove or two (or   BROWN SUGAR
      ﬁve) with the side of a heavy
      knife, slip off the papery    If you have a day or two,
      skin, and start chopping on a   just place a piece of fresh
      cutting board. As the garlic   bread in a container with the
      gets chopped, add a pinch or   brown sugar, seal the con-
      so of kosher or sea salt, and   tainer, and your brown sugar
      keep chopping. The salt acts   will soften right up. If you are
      as an abrasive so the garlic   in a hurry, place the brown
      gets minced ﬁne, ﬁner, ﬁnest.   sugar in a bowl, place a damp
      Every once in a while, use   paper towel over it, cover the
      the side of the knife to smear   bowl with a plate and mi-
      the garlic against the cutting   crowave it for 20 seconds.
      board, then scrape it back up   Check to see if it’s soft, and
      and keep mincing.  You can   if not, continue microwaving
      hear the salt crunching un-  in 20 second bursts until it]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Difficult divesting chore


      can have its advantages



         In my 30s, just as I began   We spent at least nine
      acquiring (kids, house, furni- months sorting through the ac-
      ture for said house, etc.), I no- cumulation of 30 years of living,
      ticed that my parents suddenly  raising children and acquiring.
      stopped acquiring and began di- We tossed, we shredded, we
      vesting. It seemed like an abrupt  sold, we donated, we hosted   Everything You Need
      shift, as if a switch had been  garage sales. I donated maybe   for Inside & Out!
      thrown. Almost 40 years later, I  a thousand books to the library
      now ﬁnd myself doing the same. and to a charitable organization
         At that time, my parents  that raised gobs of money for
      were moving out of their capa- college scholarships by selling
      cious, mid-century ranch-style  used books.  We gave away or
      home in Massachusetts where  sold garden tools.  We tossed
      they had raised kids and added  dozens and dozens of tape cas-
      on rooms and renovated and  settes and eight-track tapes. We
      landscaped several times. They  tried foisting our possessions
      needed to get rid of things to  on our now-adult children who
      make the move to more com- were even more resistant than
      pact digs in a sunnier clime. I  we had been in accepting my
      was focused on getting my kids  parents’ castoffs.
      into the best school system,   Our outdated computers
      updating our ancient kitchen,  went to recycling centres. These
      purchasing some dining room  early Hewlett-Packard com-
      furniture — doing what we  puters had been learning ma-
      could with our modest ﬁnancial  chines for our children as they
      resources. What we couldn’t af- grew. Very quickly, though, the
      ford, I merely lusted after.  We  children had become our tutors.
      renovated each room of our  The oldest machine, practically
      drafty  Victorian manse, bit by  an original, was now a collector’s
      bit, spending all our spare time  item. That one we kept. Electri-
      poring over wallpaper choices,  cal tools, electronic devices and
      paint chips, upgrading windows  old calculators were part of the
      and window treatments, shop- collectibles for my engineer hus-
      ping at garage sales for toys and  band.
      bikes and household appliances   There were crib accessories,
      in decent shape.           toys and Lego bricks that had
         I think the desire to expand  to be sorted through. Heavy
      and acquire changes with age  luggage that was a wedding
      — driven in part by the need to  present, and the luggage that
      downsize, but also as part of a  my husband had brought with
      reckoning with mortality. One  him when immigrating to the
      begins to accept the truism: you  United States from Israel in his
      can’t take it with you, so you  20s. All of that went. There was
      might as well pass it on.  a record of our family’s history
         My husband and I moved  contained in all that was left.  • VINYL FENCING AND DECK BOARDS
      from New Jersey to the Wash-  It was painful, all this di-
      ington region eight years ago,  vesting. Painful and interesting.   • CEDAR SPUT RAIL
      not knowing what our new res- I spent hours shredding can-  • ALUMINUM RAILING
      idence would look like -- how  celled cheques and old income
      spacious, what style of house?  tax forms. Remember cancelled
                                                                           TH
      Would there be storage, a ga- cheques? Turns out old checks   1840 – 18 STREET NORTH, BRANDON
      rage, a basement, an attic, clos- are a peephole into personal   204-728-4243
      ets?  Would the living area ac- history and family economics.
      commodate our furniture? Both  This is what my therapist used   Fax: 204-727-2619
      my husband and I had ofﬁces in  to charge. This is how we some-  Toll-Free: 1-800-224-7506
      our house in New Jersey, large  how made it through seven long   www.windsorplywood.com
      ofﬁces. Would that be possible  years of college costs.   Store Hours: Mon. – Fri. 7:30 am – 6:00 pm;
                                                              Sat. 9:00 am – 5:00 pm; Closed Sunday
      in Washington?             » Washington Post]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[26                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019



      Keep trees healthy



      with regular pruning




         If there’s one group of  tree depends not only on your
      plants that cries out for reg- whims, but also on the plant’s
      ular and careful pruning, it’s  natural growth habit.
      fruit trees.
         Taste the sweetness of   GET YOUR TREE IN SHAPE
      a perfectly ripe pear:  That
      sweetness represents energy,   Begin pruning any new
      and that energy comes from   tree by cutting back broken
      sunlight.  With proper prun-  stems and dead or diseased
      ing, all the limbs of a fruit tree   wood to healthy tissue. If your
      bask in sunshine.          new tree is but a single stem
         Pruning also helps these   (called a  “whip” by nurser-
      trees strike a balance be-  ies), shorten it by one-third
      tween shoot growth and fruit   to promote branching. If it is
      production, so important in   already branched (the “feath-
      making sure they bear large,   ered tree” of nurseries), save
      luscious fruits year after year.   well-placed stems and com-
      Those shoots are needed for   pletely cut away all others.
      energy-producing leaves and   The ideal branching ar-
      for places on which fruits   rangement starts about half   Apples bear fruits on long-lived, stubby spurs of their trees, but even these
      hang.                      a metre (two feet) from the   must be pruned eventually to stimulate younger, new spurs and keep them
                                 ground and continues in a spi-
      THE YOUNG TREE             ral arrangement up the trunk   from overcrowding. (The Associated Press)
         The ﬁrst years are im-  with about 20 centimetres (8   how big its fruits are.  more stems need to be short-
                                 inches) between branches. In
      portant to a fruit tree’s fu-  the case of the open-centre   Especially  with  large ened.
      ture performance.  These are   tree, lop off the central stem   fruits, such as apple and   At one extreme are peach
      the years to help your tree lay   just above the third branch.  peach, individual fruits tend  and nectarine. They bear fruit
      down a permanent framework    In the case of the cen-  to be undersize and less sweet  only on stems that grew the
      of branches that can support   tral-leader and modiﬁed-cen-  with too heavy a crop. Prun- previous season, so need fair-
      loads of fruit and not shade   tral-leader trees, induce the   ing also removes some po- ly severe annual pruning to
      each other.                main stem to keep making new   tential fruits so the plant can  stimulate an annual ﬂush of
         Centuries of fruit growing   branches by cutting off about   pump more energy into those  vigorous, new shoots for the
      have spawned many different   a third of the previous season’s   that remain.    following year’s crop. Prune
      forms for trees, but three pre-  growth each year while the   Once a tree matures to  enough so that a bird could ﬂy
      dominate: the central-lead-  plant is dormant. The top bud   start bearing fruit, each year  right through the branches.
      er, the open-centre, and the   grows to become an upright   prune some stems and re-  Apple and pear trees, at the
      modiﬁed-central-leader.    shoot, a continuation of the   move  others  completely. other extreme, bear fruit on
         The central-leader tree is   leader, and lower buds become   Shorten stems where you  long-lived, very short, knob-
      shaped much like a Christ-  side branches. Select new side   want regrowth and increased  by branches, called spurs, so
      mas tree, with a single lead-  branches that are well-spaced   branching. Completely re- need little such annual stim-
      er — the trunk — ﬂanked    along the leader.          move stems where you do not  ulus. Eventually, though, even
      by shorter and shorter side                           want such regrowth, such as  spurs need pruning for rejuve-
      branches moving up the     THE MATURE,                where stems are overcrowded.  nation and elbow room.
      tree.  The open-centre tree                           Complete removal is also the   Most other fruit trees lie
      is vase-shaped, with three   BEARING TREE             way to deal with those vig- between the extremes of ap-
      or four main limbs growing    Once a fruit tree is ma- orous, upright shoots called  ples and peaches in bearing
      outward and upward.  The  ture and beyond the training  watersprouts, which are not  habit and severity of annual
      modiﬁed-central-leader tree  stage, then pruning it well  fruitful and tend to shade  pruning needed. Again, com-
      is a hybrid that starts as a  means striking a balance be- lower portions of the plant.  pletely remove some stems
      central-leader then becomes  tween shoot growth and fruit   The kind of tree you are  and shorten others to achieve
      open-centre.               production. How to achieve  pruning dictates the overall  a good balance of fruiting
         All these forms allow a tree  this balance depends on how  amount of pruning needed.  wood and stem growth.
      to “harvest” enough sunlight.  — or really where — a partic- The younger the stems on
      The ideal form for a particular  ular tree bears its flowers and  which fruits are borne, the  » The Associated Press]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                          27

      ‘Brew’ up your                                                                                    “Brewing”
                                                                                                        your own
                                                                                                        potting mix
                                                                                                        is very sat-
      own potting mix                                                                                   isfying and
                                                                                                        useful, and
                                                                                                        requires just
                                                                                                        a few basic
         My gardening season begins   Rather than pasteurizing the                                      ingredients.
      on my garage ﬂoor. Here I mix  soil, I prefer to avoid pests with
      potting soil that will nourish this  careful watering, abundant light,                            (The Associated
      season’s seedlings and replace  and other cultural conditions that                                Press)
      worn-out soil around the roots of  make plants happy and pests sad.
      houseplants.
         Why make potting soil?  SOIL IS GOOD, BUT
         Why bake bread?         NOT ESSENTIAL
         There’s really no special magic
      in good potting soil.         Good garden soil is hard to
                                 obtain in reliable and large quan-
      BASIC INGREDIENTS          tities, so most commercial potting
                                 mixes are made without any real
         The three basic ingredients   soil at all. These mixes are made
      in my mix are garden soil, min-  only from mineral aggregate and
      eral aggregate and organic mat-  organic matter.
      ter. Used alone, garden soil is too   You can make such a soil-less   derneath the pile and turn it over,  and recite a few incantations to
      dense for containers.      mix yourself by sieving together   working around the edge until  complete this brew that nourish-
         The mineral aggregate loos-  equal volumes of peat moss and   the whole mass is thoroughly  es my seedlings and houseplants
      ens up the mix to let water ﬂow   perlite. This mix has no nutrients,   mixed, and moistening it slightly  each season.
      readily into and through it. Ver-  so stir in a starter feed of one-  if it seems dry. Finally, I rub the
      miculite and perlite are two light-  half cup of dolomitic limestone   mix through a half-inch sieve,  » The Associated Press
      weight aggregates, the ﬁrst made   and some fertilizer whose nutri-
      from heated mica and the second   ent ratio is about 5-10-5. Real   HOT WATER TANK REPLACEMENT
      from heated volcanic rock. Sand   soil does add nutrients and other
      and calcined clay (“kitty litter”)   good things to a potting mix, so      STARTING AT    $       68   *
      are heavier aggregates, so are use-  I favour traditional potting mixes,                           per
      ful for top-heavy plants such as   which contain real garden soil.                         16month
      cacti.                        Even if you buy potting soil,                                  Subject to terms
                                                                                                    & conditions
         Organic matter in potting   keep a few bags of some type of
      soils acts like a sponge to absorb   mineral aggregate and organic                         No cost repairs.
      water, which plants can then draw   material on hand. No one potting                           No cost
      on between waterings. Organic   mix can suit the needs of every                              replacement.
      matter also buffers soils against   plant. Add extra aggregate to any
      drastic changes in acidity, and   mix used for cacti or succulents,                          EVERYONE IS
      keeps nutrients from washing out   and extra organic matter to any                           APPROVED!
      through the bottom of seedling   mix for plants such as African vi-
      ﬂats and ﬂower pots. Peat moss,   olets and begonias that like con-  AIR CONDITIONING
      sphagnum moss and coir (a by-  sistently moist soils.
      product of coconut processing)                             STARTING AT   $          99    *  INSTALLED
      are organic materials that you can   STIR THE BREW                          47       per month  Subject to terms
                                                                                                   & conditions
      buy. Compost and leafmold are
      two organic materials that you   For the ritual opening of the    Manitoba Hydro Financing Available
      can brew up yourself and, in con-  garden season, I give my garage
      trast to the previously mentioned   ﬂoor a clean sweep and then
      materials, also offer nutrients to   make a pile of 2 gallons each of
      plants.                    garden soil, peat moss, perlite and
         Some people pasteurize their   compost. On top of this mound I
      potting soil to reduce the threat   sprinkle a cup of lime and a half
      of pests. The key is to avoid too   cup each of soybean meal and
      much heat, which can bring its   powdered kelp. This is a mixed   www.brandonheatingandplumbing.ca
      own problems. Bake the potting   bag of ingredients, but I reason
      soil in the oven along with an em-  that plants, just like humans, ben-  CALL: 204-728-0180 |  24-HOUR EMERGENCY SERVICE
      bedded potato, and when the po-  eﬁt from a varied diet.
      tato is done, so is the potting soil.  I slide my garden shovel un-  SERVING BRANDON SINCE 1910]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[28                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019



      Optimize your home office






      Create a task-driven environment with proper lighting and colours


         These days, millions of
      people have the luxury of
      working from home. It’s
      convenient and comfortable
      — and the commute is un-
      beatable. But telecommuting
      comes with its own host of
      challenges. If you’re dealing
      with distractions and a lack
      of space, it can be difﬁcult
      to strike a balance between
      productivity and the creature
      comforts of home. Consider
      these tips as you design your
      home ofﬁce to make sure
      you get the most out of your
      space.
      CHOOSE YOUR
      SPACE WISELY
         Your home ofﬁce doesn’t
      have to be in an opulent li-
      brary, a hub of technology or
      even a room of its own. The
      most important thing is that
      its location stays consistent.
      Set aside a dedicated area in
      your home and use it exclu-
      sively for work.  This could   Studies show that painting your office blue improves productivity and increases focus. (Sherwin-Williams)
      be a small desk in the living
      room, a table in your bed-  barn doors. Once they’re  greys and greens are all beau- difference in your work-
      room or a zoned-off section   installed, you can slide the  tiful choices for a home with  from-home space. For ex-
      of the kitchen counter. Find   doors over the screens and  relaxation in mind. But those  ample, red-tinted lights are
      a spot that works for you and   remove the temptation to  original,  calming  colours good for sleep and rest, but
      completely give it over to   watch. Another good strat-  might not be the best choice  if you have them in a home
      its role as a workspace. And   egy is soundprooﬁng — es- for a workspace. Studies show  ofﬁce, they can hinder pro-
      be sure to avoid working in   pecially in ofﬁces that take  that painting your ofﬁce blue  ductivity. Instead, opt for
      high-trafﬁc areas like your   up entire rooms. Curtains,  improves productivity and  blue-tinted bulbs to improve
      kitchen table or living room   window inserts and acoustic  increases focus. And orange  alertness throughout the day.
      couch. Otherwise, you’ll ﬁnd   panels are all quick, easy ways  and yellow are great ofﬁce   Or, go for natural light.
      yourself constantly moving   to cut down on outside noise  accent colours, since they’re  Move your desk next to a
      your laptop, papers and sup-  so you can focus on the tasks  known to invigorate the sens- window and open up the
      plies to make room for guests.  at hand. If you need more ex- es, inspire creativity and help  shades to increase your
                                 tensive soundprooﬁng, con- with innovation. If you don’t  wakefulness, and consider a
      CUT DOWN ON                sider talking to a professional. have the space (or desire) to  skylight where more light is
      DISTRACTIONS                                          paint an entire room, con- needed. As far as arrange-
         Regardless of where you  RECONSIDER COLOUR         sider buying blue and orange  ment, many experts recom-
      situate your ofﬁce, it’s im-  When you last painted   picture frames or tchotchkes  mend having one large over-
      portant to cut down on sur- your home, you may have   for your desk.             head light and one smaller
      rounding distractions where  chosen colours that would                           “task light” to help you fo-
      possible. One strategy is to  help you unwind at the end   THINK ABOUT LIGHT     cus.
      cover visible TVs with trendy  of a long day. Whites, beiges,   Lighting can make a huge  » TNS]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                          29

      Smaller tiles hide wavy subfloor in older home



         During a bathroom renova-                                                        A four-by-12-inch, white
      tion, it’s not uncommon to en-                                                   subway tile was chosen for the
      counter a few minor obstacles.                                                   shower stall, shoulder-high
         When the reno is on the                                                       walls in the smaller room, tub
      second ﬂoor of a three-sto-                                                      walls and backsplash for the
      rey house built in 1906, the                                                     main vanity.
      list of unexpected hurdles can                                                      A larger 12-by-24-inch
      quickly escalate. Luckily, a few                                                 white tile was used for the
      select design choices can reme-                                                  shower bench-top, tub-top
      dy many of these “hard-to-ﬁx”                                                    surface and baseboard (split
      issues and still look fantastic                                                  in half along the length of the
      once implemented.                                                                tile) wherever the subway tile
         With   framing   accom-                                                       was installed above the ﬂoor.
      plished, the electrical run, the                                                    By using the larger tile as
      rough plumbing in place and                                                      baseboard, each section was
      the drywalling, taping and                                                       precisely cut to compensate for
      mudding stages completed —                                                       any ﬂooring height discrep-
      the ﬁrst coat of paint on the                                                    ancies, below the level line of
      ceilings and walls really begins   Mixing larger and smaller tiles creates a retro style.  the lowest row of subway tile.
      to reveal the light at the end                                                   Wherever the large white tile
      of the tunnel, six weeks into a  the esthetics of the era, a two- the initial pour were complete- was installed, a white grout was
      two-month, 150-square-foot  inch hex mosaic tile was cho- ly submerged under the second  used to make the surface ap-
      six-piece bathroom renova- sen to eliminate any subﬂoor  coat of leveller.  The second  pear solid and congruous. Ev-
      tion/expansion. And although  idiosyncrasy concerns. Nor- pour was allowed to set and  erywhere else, a mid-tone grey
      the walls have been made  mally, a small-tile mosaic is  the tiling began the following  grout would be applied.
      plumb and level, the subﬂoor  the tile of choice for a walk-in  morning.         » BossEnterprise@outlook.com
      of an old house is at the mercy  shower ﬂoor, as this tile easily
      of the joists’ integrity below.  follows the contours of a show-  CUSTOM WINDOW COVERING SPECIALISTS
         At this job site, the ﬂoors  er pan graded to a centre drain
      tend to sink considerably as  from all sides. This same mo-
      you move away from the ex- saic throughout the bathroom
      terior walls, as though the old  would now compensate for
      two-by-eight joists had bowed  imperfections along the sub-
      over time under the weight of  ﬂoor, virtually hiding any slight                         Draperies &
      each ﬂoor — a lingering issue.  peaks and valleys that may not                              Fabrics
      The planned bathroom expan- be eliminated by leveller, es-                                 Blinds &
      sion combines two existing  pecially closest to the exterior                                Shades
      rooms, each revealing a 1½- walls.
      inch, inconsistently ﬂuctuating   The old subﬂoor was ﬁrst                                Upholstery
      grade discrepancy, from the  prepped with a quarter-inch                                Interior Design
      exterior wall to the opposing  plywood throughout, to pro-                                  Shutters
      interior wall(s).          vide a smooth integral sur-                                      Bedding
         Because part of the de- face on which the heating coil
      sign includes heated ﬂooring,  could be installed, and onto
      which requires leveller to hide  which the leveller would even-
      the heating coils once laid out  tually be poured. To control the
      on the ﬂoor, the process of  leveller’s path, it was initially
      pouring the leveller would be- mixed quite thick for a strate-
      come an exercise in strategy,  gic spread, as it became quickly   1440 Rosser Avenue
      broken into two separate steps.  evident where the subﬂoor pre-  Tel. 204-726-8282
      Furthermore, it would be im- sented dips and low areas.     Toll free 1.866.320.3223
      possible to create an adequate-  To the best of my ability,   www.InteriorImages.ca
      ly level surface on which large  most of the heating coils were
      ﬂoor tiles could be installed  covered during this ﬁrst pour.
      — the subﬂoor was just too  The next day, any remaining
                                                                      C
      wavy, with too much variation  coils were coated during a sec-  Come visit our Showroomome visit our Showroom
      in grade.  What to do in this  ond pour, mixed to a more ﬂu-
                                                                  35% Off Blinds & Free Cordless
      instance?                  id consistency, to ensure that   35% Off Blinds & Free Cordless
         Thankfully, in keeping with  the coils not covered during]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[30                                     THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019


      Hard to deny the grandeur of a proper pergola



         What’s the main difference                                                    two inner posts along the outer
      between a four-post pergola                                                      length of the pergola.
      and an eight-post pergola?                                                          The early stage of the struc-
         Well, beyond the obvious,                                                     ture was carefully lifted into a
      the answer has everything to                                                     vertical position, held upright
      do with the length of the main                                                   with temporary bracing.
      tandem supports.                                                                    The two outer posts along
         The plan was to build a large                                                 the length of the entire span
      pergola, to cover the entire                                                     were then set into position and
      wing of the 30-foot-long deck,                                                   fastened to the partial main
      14 feet deep and nine feet high.                                                 beam.
         This cottage-country pergo-                                                      The other side of the main
      la requires a structurally sound                                                 beam, constructed in the same
      design that, once completed,                                                     manner, was then lifted into
      serves a primarily aesthetic                                                     position and secured to the
      purpose.                                                                         other side of all four posts.
         Hidden within the main                                                           With the ﬁrst main tandem
      tandem support beams and                                                         support beam in place, the sec-
      between the inner posts, ad-                                                     ond beam was built using the
      ditional boards make this lon-                                                   same step-by-step process.
      ger-than-usual pergola possi-  An eight-post pergola set atop a 30-foot-long deck creates an inviting outdoor   The upper edge of the tan-
      ble.                                                                             dem spans of both main sup-
         Generally, a straightforward   living space. (Winnipeg Free Press)            port beams were pre-notched
      pergola consists of four six-by- side is achievable. Prior to tack- splice board.  for the placement of the upper
      six posts and two sets of tandem  ling the pergola, the deck was   Once the three boards were  veins.
      two-by-eight main support  completely revamped.       all fastened together, this sec-
      beams, on which two-by-eight   The old top-decking was  tion was then afﬁxed to the      » Continued on Page 31
      cross-veins are mounted.   removed, revealing structurally
         Cross-veins are typically set  sound supports and joists.
      on 12-inch centres, and the   Extra support was built
      ends of both the upper veins  into the existing framework in
      and lower support beams can- all eight locations where per-     At Guild HMS we have the right
      tilever past the outer perimeter  gola posts would rest atop the   product at the right price to ensure
      of the post locations, often con- top-decking surface.
      toured in a decorative manner.  New         two-by-six          we have you properly covered.
         The posts are set atop a  brown-treated lumber was then
      rigid surface and during the  afﬁxed along the entire surface
      process of the build, each post  areas of the deck and stairs.
      is levelled and held temporar-  Two-by-eight fascia was in-
      ily into position with angled  stalled along the outer perim-
      bracing until a few of the up- eter of the visible sides of the
      per veins have been fastened to  deck, and one-by-six vertical
      the main support beams, pro- boards were afﬁxed below the
      viding enough rigidity for the  fascia to enclose the lower por-
      structure to stand on its own  tion between the decking struc-
      allowing the installation of all  ture and the ground.
      remaining veins.              To commence the eight-post
         The design of this eight- pergola build, all eight loca-
      post pergola places the posts in  tions of the posts were ﬁrst pre-
      such a way as to not block any  marked along the top-decking.
      of the windows along the side   One side of the outer tan-
      of the cottage.            dem beam was pre-built on the
         Because the windows are  ground by ﬁrst cutting each
      consistently spaced along the  board to 15 feet.
      face of the exterior wall adja-  A third board was then         BRANDON • 2830 Victoria Ave & Shoppers Mall
      cent the wing of the deck on  cut to the length of the gap          Wawanesa • Virden • Carberry • Shilo
      which the pergola will rest, a  between the two inner posts      204-729-4949  •   www.guildhmsinsurance.ca
      symmetrical placement of posts  and secured midway along
      from front to back and side to  the 30 feet of the beam as a]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, MAY 9, 2019 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                          31

      Embrace the wonder and warmth wood adds to a home


         When it comes to creating  or elements such as live edge.                                     These days,
      character, some may argue there  These are design elements in                                    many interior
      is no substitute for wood.  which instead of a saw cutting                                       designers and
         Real wood is unique, no two  a straight line, the natural edge                                homeowners
      pieces identical. For many rea- of a piece of wood is shown or                                   are looking
      sons, wood is one of the main  enhanced.                                                         to wood more
                                                                                                       than ever as a
      — if not preferred — materials   •  Protect your wood furniture                                  way to infuse
      of artisans.               by using a natural wax or orange                                      one-of-a-kind
         These days, many interior  oil. Never use chemical cleaners.                                  or unexpect-
      designers and homeowners are   •  Attend your local artisan fairs                                ed design
      also looking to wood more than  and curated shows. These events                                  elements into
      ever as a way to infuse one-of- provide a prime opportunity for                                  a space.
      a-kind or unexpected design el- you to look, feel and touch. Even                                (Darrell Sapp
      ements into a space.       if you don’t see exactly what you                                     / Pittsburgh
         Love the look of wood but  may be looking for, you will have                                  Post-Gazette
      need some ideas? Here are some  an opportunity in most instanc-                                  files)
      top tips:                  es to meet the artisan or crafts- veneered. There is nothing quite  ture decor element.
       •  Look for an inspiration or  man and discuss the options of  like the durability and quality   •  Look for opportunities to
      conversation piece. A single  them creating a custom piece.  that comes with purchasing an  place small, signature wood
      show-stopping wood piece can   •  Don’t be afraid to pair dif- item made of solid wood. Al- pieces into a room such as a
      help make a bold statement in  ferent woods together.  While  ternatively, many items are often  stool, side table or bench.
      a room.                    it is often best to pair similar  made using what is known as a   •  Place wood elements into
       •  Buy local. This is an oppor- tones of wood in a single space,  veneer, in which a thin piece of  rooms that may feel overly cold
      tunity for you to purchase a sig- one can mix different species of  wood is typically glued over par- or stark.  Wood instantly helps
      nature piece and support your  wood in a room.        ticle board.               warm up a space.
      community.                  •  Purchase solid wood items as   •  Consider an all-wood dining
       •  Consider organic shapes  opposed to products that may be  table. This can serve as a signa- » Tribune News Service
                                                                    “YOUR #1 CHOICE FOR PROFESSIONAL
      » Continued from Page 30   marvel at this accomplishment              LOCAL SECURITY”
                                 — the enhancement to the
         For this design, tandem up- cottage was undeniable.
      per veins 12 inches apart were   Although pergolas are often
      placed at 20-inch intervals.  perceived as primarily aesthet-
         The lower edge of all the  ic, they do serve a purpose.
      upper veins were also pre-    If positioned correctly, the
      notched to ﬁt atop the main  upper veins can provide a slim
      beams. One by one, the veins  amount of shade depending on
      were placed and dropped into  the time of year.
      position — they ﬁt just like a   In this instance, the veins
      puzzle.                    set in an east-west fashion,                             Automation systems to
         Once levelling and square  casting shadows when the sun’s                        control your lights, locks,
      conﬁrmations of the pergola  position in the southern sky is                        thermostats, and alarm
      were achieved, each of the up- lower during the days of spring                      system from anywhere
      per veins was then systemati- and fall.                                             in the world
      cally secured to both tandem   In the summer months,
      main beams.                however, when the sun is at its
         And to prevent the structure  highest, the veins do little to
      from swaying, 30-inch four- subdue the sun’s effects.      High definition camera
      by-four underside cross-brac-  Regardless, the grandeur of   systems for your home or
                                                                 business
      ing at a 45-degree angle was  this pergola makes it very spe-
      secured to the underside of  cial — even though you know
      the main support beams at all  you’re outdoors, it feels like
      eight six-by-six post locations  being inside an architectural   Residential and commercial alarm systems
      in a decorative manner, so as  room, ﬁlled with the sights and
      to not detract from the look of  sounds of nature.
      the pergola.                  And that just may be the     204-717-5599
         After taking a step back  greatest room of any cottage.  www.westmansecurity.ca
      to look at what had been                                                             Locally Owned & Operated
      achieved, it was difﬁcult not to  » Winnipeg Free Press     FREE alarm switchovers with 3 months of FREE monitoring]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>