<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="20"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[2016 SPECIAL SUPPLEMENT

FUN,
 FITNESS,
   FELLOWSHIP

         Welcome To                                          A BRAND NEW COMMUNITY LIKE NO OTHER

       Meadowbrook                                           Meadowbrook Vilage combines affordability and the tranquility
                                                             of country living with all the amenities at your fingertips.
            VILLAGE
                                                             • Starting at $149,900 • Live beside a golf course
                       formerly Campbell’s Mobile Home Park
                                                             • Move in ready  • One level living
Conveniently located 7kms East of Brandon
                                                             NEWMODULAR HOMES

                                                                   AVAILABLE NOW ON LOTS

                                                             Visit our on-site      BOOK YOUR     Melanie Ransome-White
                                                             sales team today      APPOINTMENT
                                                                                                   204-724-3470
                                                             7km East of Brandon,        NOW!
                                                             1km South of Hwy #1                          Barry White

                                                                                                   204-720-4199]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[JUNE 2016 • 55 PLUS GAMES • THE BRANDON SUN                                      3

      Being healthy, being social key to
            55 Plus Games’ success

BY WANDA KURCHABA

  With close to 1,000 participants registered in the 2016                        Participants churn along during the Nordic pole-walking predicted time walk at a previous Manitoba 55 Plus Games. (Submitted)
Manitoba Liquor and Lotteries 55 Plus Games in Brandon June
14-16,, event organizers shouldn’t have any issues meeting their
goals, which are to encourage those who are 55 years and over
to be active and socialize more.

  Games co-ordinator Karyn Heidrick said many participants
keep coming back year after year, no matter where the games
are held, because of the friendships that are made, for the events
and because of the sense of community.

  “The games are all about fun, fitness and fellowship. It’s really
for the participants and it’s about participation.They come and
see the same friends every year and they make new friends. It’s
about being active, about being healthy and being social and
that’s a happy way of life,” Heidrick said.

  This is the 34th year that the 55 Plus Games are taking place
in Manitoba. The Active Living Coalition for Older Adults in
Manitoba (ALCOA-MB) took over the lead role in organizing
the three-day event in 2011 from the Manitoba Society of Seniors.

  ALCOA executive director Jim Evanchuk said the event
aligned well with their organization’s philosophy and it made
sense to take it on.

                                                          » Continued on Page 6]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4 THE BRANDON SUN • 55 PLUS GAMES • JUNE 2016

                                                                       “We felt that it was such a
                                                                       wonderful program that was
                                                                       doing so much to encourage
                                                                       older adults in Manitoba to
                                                                       participate, that it was too
                                                                       good of a program to be in
                                                                       jeopardy.”

                                                                                                                               » Jim Evanchuk, ALCOA executive director

ABOVE: Glenda Wright lines up a lawn bowling throw at Stanley Park. This event is one of the staples at 55 Plus Games.                   Brandon’s Finest Selection of
BELOW: Pickleball is a relatively new competition at the Games, introduced by snowbirds returning from the southern U.S. (Submitted)      Home Décor, Cards & Gifts

                                                                                                                                      Come browse our shop’s extensive display of unique products

                                                                                                                                        • A wide array of purses, including popular Canadian Designer
                                                                                                                                          Matt & Nat and Fossil

                                                                                                                                        • Canadian Designer Jewelery
                                                                                                                                        • Hundreds of greeting cards for many different occasions
                                                                                                                                        • Thousands of Gift and Home Decor Ideas
                                                                                                                                        • Unique children’s books and toys
                                                                                                                                        • Gourmet coffee and teas
                                                                                                                                        • Original Artwork by Local Artist Rhonda Kullberg

                                                                                                                                              204-725-4664

                                                                                                                                        751 – 18th Street, Brandon (Beside Kullberg’s Furniture)
                                                                                                                                                    Monday to Saturday 10am - 6pm]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Keep active,                              All one bedroom suites
stay young
                                       NOW $2,995 or less
Visit us at Rotary Villas - An active
retirement community.                      Pet Friendly suites available.

                                          Book your tour before
                                          June 30 to qualify for
                                          our Spring Discounts.

Unit A - 1340 - 10th Street
   Brandon, MB R7A 6Z3
    info@rotaryvillas.ca

    www.rotaryvillas.ca]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[6 THE BRANDON SUN • 55 PLUS GAMES • JUNE 2016

Did he leave the competition in his wake? Swimming is one of the physical events at the 55 Plus Games, along with bowling, golﬁng, horseshoes, track and slo-pitch. However, there are also the “brain games” among
the 24 events, including card games such as cribbage, bridge and whist, as well as Scrabble. There are arts and crafts as well. (Submitted)

« Continued from Page 3                       Beausejour that Brandon would be the host city for experience for all the people that are supporting the
                                              2016. This is only the second time that the Wheat participants in the games. It became very clear really
“We felt that it was such a wonderful program City has hosted the event. The first time was 29 early on that Brandon was going to host a great set
that was doing so much to encourage older adults years ago in 1987 for the fifth annual event, which of games.”
in Manitoba to participate, that it was too good of happened to also be the first time it was held outside There are 24 different events for participants to
a program to be in jeopardy,” Evanchuk said.  the city of Winnipeg.                               compete in, which are split into two categories.
“The whole concept and idea behind the games “The host committee in Brandon has done a There are physical events such as bowling, golfing,
is really consistent with our mission, which is to wonderful job preparing, planning and making sure horseshoes, swimming, track and slo-pitch, but there
encourage healthy, active aging for older everything is in place to create that very positive are also events that are referred to as brain games.
Manitobans. That was an easy one, because it really experience for the participants who are going to be Events in this category include card games such as
aligned nicely with our philosophy, why we exist visiting Brandon over those three days,” Evanchuk cribbage, bridge and whist, as well as Scrabble.
and what we do.”                              said.
It was announced during the event last year in “They are also serving up a great opportunity and                 » Continued on Page 8]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Want Your Looks To Reflect The Way You Feel?

                                   Refresh your appearance with Soft Lift

                                   – a customized cosmetic treatment of

               Botox Cosmetic and Juvederm facial filler

                                   that gives you a balanced, natural-

                                   looking makeover, with no downtime.

Before  After

Make the most of you!

                                   Before                After

CALL TODAY TO BOOK YOUR FREE CONFIDENTIAL CONSULTATION

150–1300–18th Street, Brandon, MB  • NEW CoolSculpt      • Acne & Rosacea
             204-727-1920          • Botox Cosmetic      Management
                                   • Juvederm            • Latisse Eyelash
        www.laserskinvein.com      • Microdermabrasion   Treatment
                                   • Hydradermabrasion   • Glo Mineral Makeup
                                   • Laser Hair Removal  • Skin TX & Vivier
                                   • Chemical Peels      skincare lines
                                   • Photofacials        • Vein Treatments
                                   • Body Contouring     • Dermapen
                                   • Skin Tightening     • Antiaging Skin Care]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8 THE BRANDON SUN • 55 PLUS GAMES • JUNE 2016

Snowbirds import popular pickleball

« Continued from Page 6                  on the dimensions of a badminton          to the next. While it’s important to      It’s not all luck that leads to victory in the horseshow toss
  One of the more popular events,        court,” Heidrick said.                    promote participation in the event        — it takes a deft touch. (Submitted)
                                                                                   itself, Evanchuk said another goal is
which was introduced just two years        “The paddle is similar to an            to increase overall activity.
ago due to numerous requests from        oversized ping pong paddle and you
participants, is pickleball. Canadian    use a waffle ball, so it really combines    “There are three days of games, but
snowbirds have been playing pickleball   the various elements of all these         it is also about what happens year
as they travel through the United        sports.”                                  round,” he said. “We have all the
States during the winter months, as                                                science behind us with respect to the
the sport is well liked in southern        All in all, it will take close to 300   values and the benefits of being active.
retirement communities.                  volunteers to ensure the 55 Plus
                                         Games run smoothly and that                 “You’ve heard the term ‘move it or
  “It’s a racquet sport that is gaining  participants have an enjoyable time.      lose it.’ Quite simply, we are
a lot of popularity in Canada. It                                                  encouraging people to move no matter
combines the elements of badminton,        Having competitors return year after    what age or stage you are at. Physical
tennis and table tennis and is played    year to socialize and meet up with old    movement is very important.”
                                         friends is what helps to make the 55      » The Brandon Sun
                                         Plus Games successful from one year

    Tentative Schedule                                                                                           Seniors

TUESDAY, JUNE 14, 2016                                                                                            10% OFF!
                                                                                                                       Monday & Tuesday
  9 a.m. ..........................Opening Ceremonies ..................Keystone Centre
  10 a.m. ........................5 Pin Bowling – Singles ..............Thunderbird Bowl                         HAIR DESIGNS & NAILS       Book your appointment today!
  10 a.m. ........................18 Hole Golf – Gross ..................Glenlea Golf Club
  10 a.m. ........................Bocce Ball ..................................Rideau Park                       16TH & COLLEGE • 204-726-4293 • WALK-INS WELCOME • FREE PARKING
  10 a.m. ........................Cribbage – Pairs ........................Seniors for Seniors Co-op
  10 a.m. ........................Floor Curling ............................Kinsmen arena, Keystone Center       OSTEOPOROSIS CLINIC
  10 a.m. ........................Floor Shuffleboard ......................Riverview Curling Club
  10 a.m. ........................Slo-Pitch ....................................Simplot Ball Diamonds            Ultrasound and Risk-Assessment
  10 a.m. ........................Snooker – Individual ..................Army & Navy Club
  10 a.m. ........................Pickleball – Doubles....................BU Healthy Living Centre                June 22, 2016
  10:30 a.m. – 12 p.m.......Arts & Crafts ..............................Seniors for Seniors Co-op
  12:30 p.m. ....................Horseshoes..................................Brandon Legion                        This clinic will provide you with a quick, safe, and pain free
  1:30 p.m. ......................Cribbage – Singles ......................Seniors for Seniors Co-op               measurement of bone strength.* A pharmacist will review your
                                                                                                                   present and future risk factors. We will help you to develop a
WEDNESDAY, JUNE 15, 2016                                                                                           plan for an active and healthy life.

  8 a.m. ..........................9 Hole Golf ................................Glenlea Golf Club                   *$60 fee to cover the cost of the Ultrasound Bone
  9 a.m. ..........................3KM Predicted Walk/Run ..........Riverbank Discovery Centre                     Scan Consult.
  9 a.m. ..........................5 Pin Bowling – Team ................Thunderbird Bowl
  9 a.m. ..........................Duplicate Bridge ........................Prairie Oasis Senior Centre            CALL AHEAD TO BOOK AN APPOINTMENT
  9 a.m. ..........................Floor Curling ..............................Kinsmen arena, Keystone Center      204-728-3642
  9 a.m. ..........................Floor Shuffleboard ......................Riverview Curling Club
  9 a.m. ..........................Pickleball – Mixed Doubles ........BU Healthy Living Centre
  9 a.m. ..........................Scrabble ......................................Seniors for Seniors Co-op
  9 a.m. ..........................Slo-Pitch ....................................Simplot Ball Diamonds
  9 a.m. ..........................Snooker – Individual ..................Army & Navy Club
  9:30 a.m. ......................Lawn Bowling ............................Rideau Park
  9:30 a.m. – 4 p.m. ........Arts & Crafts – Viewing ............Seniors for Seniors Co-op
  11 a.m. ........................1KM Nordic Pole Walking..........Riverbank Discovery Centre
  12:30 p.m. ....................Swimming ..................................CFB Shilo Pool
  1 p.m. ..........................Contract Bridge ..........................Prairie Oasis Senior Centre

THURSDAY, JUNE 16, 2016                                                                                          4-42 McTavish Avenue East  Arlene Nabong
                                                                                                                 Brandon, MB , R7A 2B2      Pharmaccy Manager
  9 a.m. ..........................5 Pin Bowling – Team ................Thunderbird Bowl                         Ph: 204.728-3642
  9 a.m. ..........................18 Hole Golf – Net......................Glenlea Golf Club                     Fax: 204-571-6555
  9 a.m. ..........................Floor Curling ..............................Kinsmen arena, Keystone Center    www.pharmasave.com
  9 a.m. ..........................Floor Shuffleboard ......................Riverview Curling Club               Monday - Friday 9am - 6pm
  9 a.m. ..........................Pickleball – Doubles (Finals) ......BU Healthy Living Centre                  Saturday 9am - 4pm
  9 a.m. ..........................Slo-Pitch ....................................Simplot Ball Diamonds
  9 a.m. ..........................Snooker – Individual ..................Army & Navy Club                       Serving the Brandon
  9 a.m. ..........................Track ..........................................Brandon Community Sportsplex  area for over 50 years. P
  9 a.m. ..........................Whist ..........................................Seniors for Seniors Co-op
  9:30 a.m. ......................Lawn Bowling ............................Rideau Park
  9:30 a.m. – 12 p.m.........Arts & Crafts – Viewing ............Seniors for Seniors Co-op]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Hear the colours
of sound.

Redeﬁning the ease of listening.  It’s not just about hearing aids – it’s about hearing enhancement. Thanks to our latest
                                  innovation, we are entering into a new dimension of better hearing. Signia’s new
                                  technology is able to sense and analyze the acoustic environment more precisely than
                                  ever before, and respond to it accordingly. This precision allows it to isolate a single
                                  speaker among many, and enhance speciﬁc situational sounds like music on demand:
                                  for eﬀortless listening and truly dedicated sound experiences. Clinically proven.*

                                                                                                        signia-hearing.ca/insio-primax

  *Study conducted at the University of Northern Colorado, 2015, axamined the eﬀectiveness of the new features of primax by collecting and analyzing ongoing EEG data while subjects performed
  speech testing. For both primax features SpeechMaster and EchoShield, the objective brain behavior measures revealed a signiﬁcant reduction in listening eﬀort when the feature was activated.
  Signia GmbH is a Trademark Licensee of Siemens AG.

If YOU are having any hearing issues, WE CAN HELP!

           Call for an Appointment and let the experts at Advanced Hearing Clinic assess
               your hearing and provide you the best hearing solution for your needs.

                                          1-888-720-4327

                                  42 McTavish Avenue | 1st Street Plaza - Brandon, MB
                                          Unit C - 245 King Street East - Virden, MB]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10 THE BRANDON SUN • 55 PL]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[LUS GAMES • JUNE 2016  11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[12 THE BRANDON SUN • 55 PLUS GAMES • JUNE 2016

Get your game on

Golfers swing and putt during last year’s Manitoba Liquor and Lotteries 55 Plus Games. (Photos are Submitted)

                                                                                                                                         DAILY LUNCH &
                                                                                                                                         DINNER BUFFET
                                                                                                                                       with over 100 items!

                                                                                                               Loyalty Card - Buy 9 Buffets Get 1 FREE

                                                                                                                  Customer Appreciation Mondays $13.99 Buffet
                                                                                                                                                Excluding Holidays
                                                                                                                            20% OFF Seniors (65+)
                                                                                                                     50% OFF On Your Birthday (ID required)
                                                                                                                                  Specials cannot be combined with other discounts.

                                                                                                                      Prime Rib Carvery • Friday - Sunday

                                                                                                               DAILY BUFFET HOURS      SAT & SUN/HOLIDAY HOURS
                                                                                                               Lunch 11:30pm - 2:30pm  Lunch 11:30pm - 3:30pm
                                                                                                               Dinner 4:30pm - 8:30pm  Dinner 4:30pm - 8:30pm

                                                                                                                               BEST BUFFET IN BRANDON!

                                                                                                               201-18 STREET NORTH • BRANDON (204) 728-3888]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[JUNE 2016 • 55 PLUS GAMES • THE BRANDON SUN                                                         13

                                             Concentration          It may be all friendly competition at the
                                                                    Games’ many events — but the concen-
                                                                    tration is intense! (All photos are Submitted)

                                             Wteolctohme e

            Show Your Card & Save!                                     827 – 18th Street

       Oil Change Package includes:                                              204-727-5823
                                                                    www.greatcanadianoilchange.com
Up to 5L warranty approved oil, New car warranty-approved
         oil filter, Lube to manufacturer specifications,
                     and a great cup of coffee!

    Locally Owned & Operated • No Appointments • Warranty Approved]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14 THE BRANDON SUN • 55 PLUS GAMES • JUNE 2016

The Games combine recreational activities with social and cultural experiences. In fact, the fellowship is the key element that drives the event, participants and organizers say. There’s always great local entertainment
at the variety concert. “it’s more the sociability,”said one. “When you get to be our age, you don’t really care whether you win or lose.” (Submitted)

         Young at heart take part in
           Manitoba 55 Plus Games

BY DIANE NELSON                  is quite a friendly             in 2005.                        being hosted by the Brandon    to swimming and slo-pitch.
                                 competition — nobody’s not        The Active Living             Rotary Club and the United       The Games are open to
  It doesn’t matter if you win   good enough. It’s not about                                     Commercial Travelers James
or lose, it’s that you play the  how good you are. It’s about    Coalition for Older Adults in   B. Chrisp Council No. 448,     anyone 55 years of age or
game.                            getting out and being active,   Manitoba (ALCOA-MB) co-         is the 34th annual Games,      older and often welcome
                                 and participating is good for   ordinates the Games as a        and will feature more than 25  participants who are well into
  While that’s not the slogan    a lot of people.”               celebration of healthy living   age-friendly events ranging    their 90s.
for the Manitoba 55 Plus         “What I really get the most     and proof that Manitobans       from cribbage and Scrabble
Games, it certainly could be.                                    of all ages can lead active,                                               » Continued on Page 18
                                                                 engaged and healthy lives.
  About 1,000 participants       out of is meeting new people    And as Watson emphasized,
from across the province will    from across the province and    the Games combine
converge on Brandon from         reconnecting with ones I’ve     recreational activities with
June 14-16. And while they’ll    met before.”                    social and cultural                                            • Sitting at the Hospital
be coming together to take       Watson, who plays floor         experiences.                                                   • Community Care Homes
part in a variety of sports and  shuffle — which is essentially                                                                 • Homemaking Help
other activities, the purpose,   shuffleboard played with          “There’s always great local                                  • Infusion Clinics
for many of those involved,      sticks and discs — is one of    entertainment at the Tuesday                                   • Live-In/Respite Care
is not determining a             several            regional     night variety concert,” he                                     • Nursing
champion.                        representatives    from         said, “and there’s the banquet                                 • Personal Support/
                                 Westman. He’s been              on Wednesday. It’s great.”      204-727-4222
  “My big thing with the 55      involved, both as a volunteer                                   info@wecare.ca                   Attendant Care
Plus Games is the                                                  The Brandon event, which      www.cbi.ca                     • Accompanied Visits
fellowship,” said 70-year-old                                    is sponsored by Manitoba
Lyle Watson of Neepawa. “It      and a participant, since        Liquor and Lotteries and is     Helping you. Live your life. Call 1.866.729.3227
                                 Neepawa hosted the Games]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[would like to congratulate

     the Participants &

  Organizing Committee

            of the

   2016 MANITOBA
LIQUOR & LOTTERIES

   55 PLUS GAMES.]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[16 THE BRANDON SUN • 55 PLUS GAMES • JUNE 2016

  “For some people, it’s the competition. But for
  most, it’s about reconnecting with people. I like to
  emphasize that whatever level of competition or
  success you’ve achieved, you’ve participated and
  you’re active and you’ve enjoy the fellowship. It’s
  good for the mind, body and soul.”

                                                                              » Lyle Watson

  LeafSource contains natural elements
  that have proven to support joint health,
  reducing joint aches and discomforts
  caused by illness and normal
  athletic activity

               LeafSource effectively converts normal dietary
                elements into available components that are
                vital for increased daily energy and stamina.

               Hedley’s Health Hut

                         204-725-3131 • Shoppers Mall Brandon
                         hhb@wcgwave.ca • www.healthhutbrandon.ca

                                F R E E D E LIVE RY & P OSTAG E O N O R D E RS OVE R $50]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[18 THE BRANDON SUN • 55 PLUS GAMES • JUNE 2016

Play ball! While it’s important to promote participation in the events themselves, 55 Plus organizers say another goal is to increase overall activity — it is about what happens year round. The aim is to encourage people
to move no matter what age or stage they are at. “Physical movement is very important.” (Submitted)

« Continued from Page 14  when we all get together,” the “I can usually get a medal time scheduling — it just really enjoyed the experience
                          73 year old said.               — I’ve gotten a couple of doesn’t work out.”                of seeing more of the
While some of the more Todd has been taking part golds over the years, but I’m A lifelong farmer, Scott province.
popular activities like card- in the Games for the last 10 not consistent — there’s said being fit and active were “The sociability is great!”
playing (whist, cribbage and years or so, and said things always somebody hotter than necessities in that line of Scott said. “And you get to
bridge) and slo-pitch have have changed a bit over the me. I can usually get a silver work.                           see other towns in Manitoba.
pre-competitions that decide past decade.                 or a bronze.                  “You had to be fit to farm,” Some years it’s held up at The
who or which teams get to “We used to have to “But the good snooker she said. “I like sports, so I’m Pas, or Boissevain, Morris,
take part in the provincial qualify, but we don’t any players are still the older guys in quite a few sports. I golf and Steinbach. The Games
event, most are open — that more since there are only because we spend all of our and I swim and whatever.” are held all over — they’re
is, a person or persons can about 30 snooker players in time playing snooker rather Scott guesstimates she’s not just in one area.
just sign up and take part. the whole province,” he said. than 8- and 9-ball.”          been in at least 16 Manitoba
And the opportunity exists to “A lot of people are switching An enthusiastic five-pin 55 Plus Games, and has          » Continued on Page 19

represent Manitoba at the now to 8-ball, but the older bowler, 80-year-old Eleanor
National Games, which take people are still playing Scott, of Neepawa, has been
place in August this year in snooker.”                    taking part in the sport for  A Proud Sponsor of the 55+ Games
Brampton, Ont..
                          While Todd relishes the longer than the provincial 55
Dave Todd, of Ste. Rose, is opportunity to reconnect Plus Games have been in
part of the Parkland with his chums each year, the existence.
delegation, and the dedicated gathering is still a “I’ve bowled ever since the
snooker player is looking competition. But it’s Neepawa Bowling Alley
forward to seeing some of his definitely a friendly one.  opened in 1962,” she said
fellow snooker enthusiasts in “I’m no longer one of the with a laugh. “I do mostly
Brandon.                  hotshots, but I like being five-pin bowling in the
“We have a really great there,” he said. “It’s the only Games. I like the floor
bunch of people who attend time you get to see the guys shuffling but it’s pretty hard
and it’s like old home week from across the province. to go into both because of the    sunrisecu.mb.ca]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[JUNE 2016 • 55 PLUS GAMES • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                 19

    Prairie Oasis Seniors Centre
  and Seniors for Seniors Co-op

    will be hopping June 14-16
       with some of the “brain

games”competitions in bridge,
 cribbage, whist and Scrabble.
                     (Submitted)

« Continued from Page 18                       sociability. When you get to be our age, you    We’re here
  “And like Lundar is a small community, so    don’t really care whether you win or lose.”
                                                                                                  for you.
they went together with a couple of other        Watson said he feels it’s important to
places. And people do like going to the        encourage people on the younger end of the
smaller places. I think people enjoy it more.  scale to become involved in the Manitoba 55
                                               Plus Games. And he said if folks just want to
  “And sometimes they don’t have rooms so      come along to see what the Games are all
you get billeted out. And then you meet        about, they’re more than welcome.
people and then you stay friends forever!”
                                                 “In 2005, I was certainly one of the younger
  Scott has also earned her way to the         participants,” Watson said, chuckling. “So if
National Games in years past and said that,    someone comes as a spectator this time,
even though it’s on a bigger scale, the        maybe that will allay some fears.
atmosphere and the end result are the same.
                                                 “For some people, it’s the competition. But
  “People are there from all over Canada —     for most, it’s about reconnecting with people.
Inuvik, a few from Quebec and a bunch from     I like to emphasize that whatever level of
the East Coast or the West Coast or            competition or success you’ve achieved,
wherever,” she said. “And it’s the same thing  you’ve participated and you’re active and
at the Canadian Games as it is here — you      you’ve enjoy the fellowship. It’s good for the
can see people you haven’t seen for a long     mind, body and soul.”
time.                                          » The Brandon Sun

  “It’s a great thing. And it’s more the

                                                                                               Marcus Vasconcelos, B.Sc(pharm)

                                                                                                 Visit us at our NEW STORE
                                                                                                  with EXTENDED HOURS!

                                                                                                  2425 Victoria Avenue
                                                                                                      204-728-1062

                                                                                               Hours: Mon - Fri 9:00 am - 7:00 pm]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Motorcoach & Fly Tours       Celebrating 37 Years!

                          100% Manitoba owned and operated

                          Agawa Canyon
                          & Mackinac Island

                          8 Days - September 15

Maritimes & Newfoundland

16 or 21 Day Tours
with Fly-in options
September Departures

                          Oregon Coast &
                          California Redwoods

                          14 Days – October 11

Nashville, Memphis,
Branson & Pigeon Forge

14 Days – October 15 & 22

                 www.fehrwaytours.com

CALL for a brochure 1-800-263-3691 or see your Travel Agent]]></page></pages></Search>