<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="44"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[2018 Special Supplement

                                                                             Westman





                                                      Business]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[2                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018

























































        Lori Hildebrand, Office Manager and Technician for Dr. Kelleher’s Laser, Skin and Vein Clinic in Brandon, uses a state of the art laser hair removal machine.   (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
        Kelleher’s Skin and Vein clinic keeps




        customers looking and feeling their best






           There’s a difference between aging, and   “I think there’s a myth that laser skin-re-  Coolsculpting uses controlled cooling  mediately after. The treated area is usually
        aging gracefully.                    surfacing is a horrible, painful treatment,”  to eliminate the type of stubborn fat that  a little tender and some people feel it more
           That’s  Dr.  Barb  Kelleher’s  philosophy.  Kelleher said. “And it definitely is uncom-  resists diet and exercise. By  chilling fat  than others, but all things considered, it’s
        And the multitudinous services she of-  fortable, but in the old days they used to  cells to a certain temperature, the cell itself  pretty incredible how effective this leading
        fers at Dr. Kelleher’s Laser, Skin and Vein  have to sedate people. And now it’s tolera-  is destroyed and fat can never be stored on  method of fat reduction is.”
        Clinic are designed to keep people healthy,  ble with just a topical anesthetic.”  that area again. For it to be ultra success-  While Kelleher treats both women and
        happy, and feeling and looking their best.  Laser can improve the look of fine lines,  ful, Kelleher said it’s best if people are close  men in her practice, women between the
           The clinic specializes in hair remov-  wrinkles, acne scarring or other scars, some  to their ideal body weight in order to get  ages of 40 and 65 comprise most of her
        al, skin rejuvenation, vein treatments, and  forms of hyper pigmentation, and can also  the best results.  “That said, for large peo-  clientele. However, while the older group
        body contouring, and regularly adds new  remove moles on the face so the patient has  ple, we do a lot of de-bulking, and while  tends to keep quiet about their treatments,
        procedures to its repertoire.   While cos-  either no scar or less of a scar than would  they do remain large, they feel much better  Kelleher’s younger patients talk about
        metic treatments like sclerotherapy, botox,  result from removing the mole surgically.  in their clothing,” Kelleher said. “A BMI  them openly.
        and facial fillers have been around for de-  As well, laser energy can be used for  (body mass index) of 25 or less is best, but   “Thirty-somethings  are  telling  each
        cades, more recent advancements such as  treating issues such as vaginal dryness,  30 can also be done.       other,” Kelleher said.  “They’re talking
        coolsculpting, a non-surgical fat-reduction  stress  incontinence, and  lax  vaginal  walls   “The average procedure takes about an  about it. I love the thirty-somethings.
        technique, have come on strong, and im-  from childbirth, effectively restructuring  hour to complete and depending on the   “I find it interesting how things are
        proved not only the appearance but also  and restoring damaged tissue. A minimal-  individual,  the area  treated,  and the  de-  changing. They make no bones about it –
        the  confidence  of  many  patients.  And  ly invasive procedure with no downtime  sired results, some of my patients are happy  showing their friends their before and after
        while  some procedures  are  a bit  painful,  or anesthesia required, Femi-Lift is per-  with progress made after just one or two  pictures. Some of them even say, ‘I’m going
        most are much less so than many people  formed by gynecologist Dr. J. B. Helms  sessions. And because it’s non-invasive,
        might expect.                        and takes only about 15 minutes.    regular daily activities can be resumed im-  » Continued on Page 19]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[3712040_KelleherCosmetic_Layout 1  18-10-11  2:22 PM  Page 1





           “Talk to the Doctor




              to Get the Look You Want”





           The desire to “get the look you want” has more men and women seeking
           quick and safe in-office procedures to help maintain or reverse the
           effects of time, sun and living. Dr. Kelleher’s Laser, Skin and Vein Clinic

           provides effective non-surgical cosmetic treatments for both men and
           women. Patients are assured of receiving high quality, professional
           treatments performed by Dr. Barb Kelleher, BSc, MD and her qualified
           staff.


           CoolSculpting               Juvederm                   Acne & Rosacea
           FemiLift                    SilkPeel                    Management

           Fractional Laser Skin       JetPeel                    Latisse Eyelash Treatment
            Resurfacing                Laser Hair Removal         Glo Mineral Makeup
           Sculptra                    Chemical Peels             Skin TX & Vivier Skincare

           Dysport                     Photofacials                & Anti-aging Skincare
           Restylane                   Body Contouring            Vein Treatments

           Botox Cosmetic              Skin Tightening            Dermapen



           Call today to book your free confidential consultation

























                      Emmy, Technician – Lori, Office Manager/Technician – Dalelene, Technician – Heather, LPN – Britta, Reception  Dr. Barbara Kelleher, BSc, MD














                              th
                   150–1300–18 Street  |  Brandon, MB  | 204-727-1920  |  www.laserskinvein.com]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018






































































        Bernice Erskine, Joyce MacKay, and Phyllis Harburn enjoy Christmas decorating at Rotary Villas.
        Rotary Villas offers safe, secure and comfortable home




           There’s no place like home.       home in the safe, secure and comfortable  ment complex. It’s meant for those who are  a healthy living centre, games and sitting
           Whether you’re just starting your family,  environment Rotary  Villas provides. But  55-plus and offers an array of services and  room, billiard lounge, plus a library that is
        are an empty-nester, or perhaps beginning  what’s even more rewarding is to see how  amenities to ensure residents can enjoy a  supported by the Rotary Club of Brandon.
        the process of downsizing for retirement,  their lifestyle changes.      carefree and very independent lifestyle.  “It’s important to think of your parents
        there truly is no place like home.     “We do everything we can to make     With tantalizing  and delicious meals  and encourage them to live their best life
           That’s why making an informed deci-  Rotary  Villas feel like home,” said Ke-  carefully prepared with local flair by a  at any age,” Kehler said. “We all want to
        sion on where you’re going to live as you  hler, who also has a nursing background.  Red Seal chef, residents look forward to  help our parents find a place that is com-
        age gracefully is so important.      “Before long, residents are socializing and  meeting their friends for breakfast, lunch  fortable, safe and convenient, but we also
           Moving from a single-family dwelling  taking part in different activities. Moving  and dinner in the beautiful on-site dining  want them to develop friendships and not
        can be a positive experience, and those who  from a home that you’ve lived in for many,  room.  There is also light  housekeeping,  feel lonely. At Rotary Villas, we can make
        have made that decision may have discov-  many years can be emotionally draining,  weekly linen service, 24-hour on-site staff,  that happen.”
        ered that their lifestyle improves tremen-  but it can also be uplifting and can relieve a  and a la carte healthcare services.  While there are a number of retirement
        dously and their new residence quickly be-  lot of stress. You don’t have to worry about   While there are many benefits to living  communities in Brandon, Rotary  Villas
        comes their new home.                little things like cleaning the gutters or  in a retirement home, the added features  boasts several features that sets them apart.
           Jody Kehler, executive director of Rota-  shovelling the driveway. You can just relax  for socializing and taking part in other ac-  “Our security system is one-of-a-kind,
        ry Villas at Crocus Gardens, said it doesn’t  and focus on the things that you enjoy.”  tivities at Rotary Villas only make it that  we have an open, spacious environment,
        take long for new residents to feel right at   Rotary Villas is Brandon’s newest retire-  much more welcoming. The complex offers   » Continued on Page 9]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[WE HAVE EVERYTHING YOU NEED - AND MORE!
























                        IAN - PHARMACIST                            CIERRA, DANNI & JACKEE                             HANK & CYNTHIA
















                                             LOCALLY OWNED AND MANAGED


                 1340 - 10th Street • 204.725.1340 • info@rotaryvillas.ca • www.rotaryvillas.ca]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[6                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018























































        Chancellor Dental assistant, Shannon, checks a patient’s teeth. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
        Chancellor Dental provides smiles, relieves




        fears for patients with “humanized” dentistry





           While techniques in dentistry have progressed exten-  electronic x-rays, so that it’s painless – patients don’t have  notions of what can happen during a visit to the dentist,
        sively over the last several years, an innate fear about a visit  to be uncomfortable,” Mitchell said. “We’ve got a Panorex  Mitchell said. And the best thing people can do is trust in
        to the dentist still remains.                    (a full jaw x-ray) that goes right around the head so they’re  the professionals – the dentists, the hygenists, the assis-
           But that’s something the folks at Chancellor Dental are  not having all these contraptions around their mouth, or  tants, and the office staff – who are guiding them through
        trying to change.  “We want to humanize things a whole  being scared because they’re in closed, confined spaces.  the experience. If they’re uncertain about some aspect of
        lot more,” said Amber Mitchell, officer manager at Chan-  We really want to make the operatories comfortable, so  their treatment, they’re more than encouraged to ask ques-
        cellor Dental. “We’re told every day, ‘Oh, I don’t want to be  we make sure that our patients know we’ve got head pil-  tions.
        here. I didn’t want to come here.’”              lows, blankets, even headphones. We’ve got TVs and stuff   “The big thing is a lot of patients don’t verbalize to us
           So they’ve taken a proactive approach to trying to make  for them. We try our best to make everybody comfortable.  what they need,” Mitchell said. “So if they’re nervous or
        the thought of dental appointments, exams or procedures  Because as long as they’re comfortable, they’re a little more  they’re not sure of something, we find a lot of patients still
        less stressful for their patients. And Mitchell said it all be-  relaxed.”                        don’t ask. And we’ve tried to make our social media a place
        gins the moment a patient walks through the door.  Chancellor Dental’s primary focus is oral health and pa-  they can go before they even come into the office to get
           “It’s all about our staff,” Mitchell said. “We’ve hired  tient-centered care. But while techniques and treatments  some answers and some reassurance. We’ve posted all sorts
        staff, especially for the front desk, who are very inviting  have changed with the times, there’s one piece of technol-  of little tips on how to prepare for your dental appoint-
        and very bubbly and happy. If the patient seems nervous,  ogy that’s had a negative effect on the whole process. So  ment.
        then we kind of help settle things down a little bit, just by  instead of being more at ease, people are even more trepi-  “And we have lots of patients who say, ‘We don’t know
        those personalities. Everybody’s friendly, and it’s just like  datious now than they were in the so-called “olden days.”  how much dentistry costs. So we need an estimate.’ But a
        sort of like a spa. You’d never imagine you’re in a dental   “I find being fearful or paranoid is more common now-  lot of people don’t ask for that because money is a taboo
        clinic.”                                         adays,  actually,  because  the  Internet’s  more  available,”  subject. So we try to use our social media to get that out
           Improvements in approach, with the aid of advanced  Mitchell said. “So when people get on the Internet, they’re  there and to say, ‘You know what? Just ask us. We want to
        technology and superior equipment, has made dentistry,  not really seeing what happens.”          help you.’ But if you don’t ask we don’t know.”
        if not completely pain free, then at least a whole lot less   Easily accessible and often graphic imagery of proce-
        intimidating than it used to be.  “They’ve come up with  dures gone wrong are giving people completely erroneous   » Continued on Page 8]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018














































        Chancellor Dental receptionist Ashley takes appointment bookings. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)  Shannon, a dental assistant with Chancellor Dental, adjusts a Panorex Machine to take full jaw
                                                                                          x-ray. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)

        » Continued from Page 6              their working partnership is a success.
                                               “And they’re still going strong,” Mitch-
           One angle that’s been of significant im-  ell said with a smile. “And obviously we’ve
        portance recently is the hiring of front-of-  added dentists along the way.”
        fice staff who don’t have backgrounds in   Dental assistants will also help patients
        dentistry.  That way, when patients have   convey their concerns or fears or questions
        questions, they can answer them in every-  to the dentists, but again, it’s extra helpful if
        day language, without the confusion that   patients are open about their anxiety before
        medical lingo or jargon often brings.  the treatment begins.  “(Assistants) will try
           “We try and explain things from a more   to anticipate and ask questions of the pa-
        personal perspective, so we’ve been hir-  tients ahead of time,” Mitchell said. “And
        ing people who don’t have a dental back-  there’s no question that people should be
        grounds to work in the front office so we  afraid of asking.
        can explain things to everybody from a hu-  “We want them to know that we’re here,
        man perspective. Like, ‘You’re likely going  we’re friendly, we’re human, but please ask   thank you to our customers
        to be in pain but they’re there to get you  questions. Ask anything.”
        out of pain.’ And we’re going to use terms   As mentioned, the Chancellor Dental
        that are more common English rather than  website – chancellordental.com – is anoth-
        what a dentist might use.”           er tool the team is using to try to connect
           Mitchell estimated that about half of  with people and allay their concerns.
        Chancellor Dental’s patients are fairly re-  “It’s actually really cool because you
        laxed and the other half are uptight if not  can hover over the pictures and there are
        downright fearful. And usually that second  questions  in  there  that  each  person  has
        group consists of patients who haven’t been  answered,” Mitchell said.  “And they’re
        to the dentist in a very long time.  very random questions, like ‘What’s your
           “And  it’s  most  often  because  they’ve  favorite book?’ or ‘What was your favorite
        had a very traumatic experience,” she said.  toy as a kid?’ Things like that just to let the
        “So we try and reel back and make them  patients get to know the staff.
        comfortable and then ease them into the   “We want to make sure our patients are
        process because it’s just like doing anything  getting the best care that they can get and
        you’re scared of – you’re not just going to  that  they feel welcome and  calm. Every-
        jump into it.”                       body who’s coming to us needs to know
           In one form or another, Chancellor  that we are going to take care of them just
        Dental has been around for a long time.  as if they were our friends or family. Be-
        Drs. Jim Bonar and Alex Pappas have been  cause that’s what we do.”
        in practice together for about 35 years. And                                             204-726-1333       superiorautobrandon.com
        their longevity as a team makes it clear that  » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2018 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                            9

                                                                                                                      » Continued from Page 4
                                                                                                                      and we have a very active community –
                                                                                                                      those are all things that makes us unique,”
                                                                                                                      Kehler said. Rotary Villas also has a full-
                                                                                                                      time shuttle service that allows residents to
                                                                                                                      get to their next bridge game, to medical
                                                                                                                      appointments or to meet their friends for
                                                                                                                      coffee.
                                                                                                                        The complex is also home to Ginger-
                                                                                                                      snips Salon, Flatland Drugs, Dr. Mere-
                                                                                                                      dith’s Medical Clinic and Camelot Person-
                                                                                                                      al Care.
                                                                                                                        The three-storey building has 12 differ-
                                                                                                                      ent layouts within the 108 suites, including
                                                                                                                      studio, one-bedroom and two-bedroom
                                                                                                                      apartments. As well, some of the two-bed-
                                                                                                                      room villas have an additional three-season
                                                                                                                      room. Rotary Villas is 100 per cent locally
                                                                                                                      owned and operated, and is an integral part
                                                                                                                      of the community.
                                                                                                                        “We are proud to be locally owned and
                                                                                                                      operated – our staff and our residents are
                                                                                                                      from Brandon and the surrounding areas –
                                                                                                                      plus we make an effort to buy most of our
                                                                                                                      products locally,” Kehler said. “Supporting
                                                                                                                      the community that we live and work in is
                                                                                                                      as important as developing our own com-
                                                                                                                      munity within Rotary Villas.”
                                                                                                                        Without a doubt, Rotary  Villas offers
                                                                                                                      a carefree, convenient and comfortable
                                                                                                                      environment so that residents can enjoy
                                                                                                                      retirement living the way it’s meant to be
                                                                                                                      enjoyed.
        Pam Stacey and Don Roy walk their dogs together at Rotary Villas.  Don Benzie and Art Robilllard chalk up for a game of billiards at Rotary Villas.  » The Brandon Sun



               Trails West Inn,



               Chicken Chef,



               Beer Vendor



               & The 40





                              All Under One Roof

















                   th
            210 - 18 Street North, Brandon • the40.ca
            Call 204-727-3800 to reserve your room

            www.chickenchef.com • 204-727-2433]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018


        Home decorating



        products that meet your




        budget, not break it





           When folks hear the word  “budget,”  homes. So within about a two-hour con-
        they sometimes assume that means cheap.  sultation, we  can  suggest,  design,  select,
           But where Budget Blinds is concerned,  measure, and price. And there’s no charge
        nothing could be further from the truth.  for that consultation.”
           “The name is confusing for some peo-  And customers soon discover that Bud-
        ple,” said Sue Swarbrick, who, along with  get Blinds has a whole lot to offer.
        her husband Gord, own and operate Bud-  “We pride ourselves first of all on more
        get Blinds in Brandon. “When we’re asked  product offerings than anyone else has,”
        about the word ‘budget,’ we usually say that  Sue said. “We have 27 vendors that we can
        we like to provide a product for everyone’s  bring product in from. So with all the win-
        budget. So it doesn’t necessarily mean it’s  dow covering companies out there, what
        the  least  expensive  – it  means that  we’ll  sets  Budget  Blinds  apart?   “The  number
        work to find something for your particular  one thing, I believe, is our vendor alliance
        budget or your particular project. So yeah  – that’s something that we’re very proud
        – the name throws people. But we certain-  of, that we have access to so many prod-
        ly still want to put a good custom product  uct lines,” Sue said. “We’re not a one-trick
        into your window. We are a custom house.  pony. Number two would probably be our
        No cut-downs, no pre-measures, no noth-  service. I believe that we provide probably
        ing like that.”                      the best service in the industry. So that
           Sue worked for Budget Blinds in Regi-  means it’s kind of a no-hassle service guar-
        na and became really enamoured with the  antee. And we also go where others won’t
        business, as did Gord.               go – for one window or two windows, we
           “It met both of our skill sets,” she said.  go and help out.
        “So seven years ago we took a look at where   “We provide exceptional service, and we
        we’d like to own, and we came to Brandon  follow up with warranties with the vendors
        and fell in love. I think at the time, there  and follow things through on the custom-
        was an article out about this being the sev-  er’s behalf. Our warranties also set us apart.
        enth best place in Canada to live. So we  We have the manufacturer’s warranty on
        came over and had a look and really fell in  our products, but we also provide custom-
        love with it and decided this would be a  ers  with  a  five-year,  no-questions-asked
        great place to do business. We like the size  (warrantee) as well. Which literally means
        of it.                               you have a one-time replacement on every
           When they started the business in  window in the first five years, no questions
        Brandon, Sue looked after sales, design,  asked. It’s very cool.”
        aesthetics, and décor, while Gord did the   Additionally, Budget Blinds carries
        installations. But what began as just a hus-  what Sue termed “unique products,” which   Back Row: Gord Swarbrick, Shane Swarbrick, Laurie Smitzniuk. Front Row: Barb Engel, Sue Swarbrick, Nadiia
        band-and-wife team now employs an ad-  includes tableau, a decorative grill resin   Samotiy. (Submitted)
        ditional full-time installer, one-and-a-half  product out of Texas. They also deal in area
        more consultants, and a full-time office  rugs, music systems, as well as draperies.  thing we’re both very jazzed about. So it’s  I leave their home, and they say, ‘I am so
        worker.  Budget Blinds is a franchise com-  And they’re also moving into smart home  the product, it’s the business model, it’s the  excited about this!’ That’s really what does
        pany, and the Swarbricks own one of 1,100  automation, where blinds can be tied into a  family of Budget Blinds – that 1,100 of us,  it for me – finding that product where they
        franchises across the continent. Accord-  home’s security and lighting systems.  we actually all get to know each other. We  say, ‘Ah – there it is! That’s the one!’
        ing to Sue, Budget Blinds is the “number   “Automation is really taking off in the  attend conventions with each other regu-  The Swarbricks  enjoy the  challenges
        one retailer of window coverings in North  marketplace,  and  we’re  doing  more  and  larly, so there’s a sense of belonging within  they encounter each and every day and
        America.”  The  Brandon  shop  provides  more of it all the time,” Sue said.  us as well. And support for each other. And  are grateful to be able to provide products
        both residential and commercial service,   The mainstays of the business are still  then the other thing that gets me really ex-  that are useful and helpful to people. And
        and operates from the U.S. border to the  honeycomb shades, roller shades and a  cited is finding people that love it as much  speaking of people, that’s the entire reason
        Saskatchewan border, as far north as Swan  product referred to as a horizontal shading  as we do that work with us.”  they take so much delight in their business.
        River, and as far east as Headingley.  system.                              More than anything, the Swarbricks  “We really, really care about what we do,
           “So we’re busy,” Sue said. “That’s why   “As well,  an everyday  classic  –  people  and their staff absolutely love working with  and that’s important,” Sue said. “And what
        we need the big team – we have four vans  love top-down, bottom-up honeycombs,  their customers. Sue’s passion for her craft  makes our company so great is our custom-
        in our fleet now and we put on a lot of  and they’re energy efficient,” Sue said.  is evidenced by the smile on her face and  ers.  We’re so grateful for our customers,
        miles.”                              “And we provide a lot of finishing touches.”  the sparkle in her eyes as she talks about  and we’ve developed such wonderful re-
           Customers  can either  come in  to  the   The Swarbricks are ultra-enthusiastic  what she does – and who she does it for.  “If  lationships with them as we get to know
        showroom or phone and book an appoint-  about  their business, and  there are many  you think I’m passionate here, you should  the people of Westman and discover how
        ment  for an  in-home consultation.  “We  reasons why.  “Gord and I believed that if  see me in the homes,” she said with a laugh.  much we appreciate them. It’s our custom-
        call our vans rolling showrooms,” Sue said.  we worked as hard for ourselves as we had  “I love being in people’s homes and find-  ers that make us great.”
        “The products that are here are also in our  for someone else, we would eventually suc-  ing the right product for them. They’re so
        vans and we take that to the customers’  ceed,” Sue said. “And we’ve found some-  thrilled. It’s so cool to see, especially when  » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Blinds • Shutters • Shades • Drapes • Home Automation



































                                                                                                CALL



                                                                                                TODAY





                                                                                                The In-home consultation is

                                                                                                Free... Anywhere in Westman.

                                                                                                We bring the showroom to you,

                                                                                                offering Style and Service for
                                                                                                every budget.



                                                                                                We help you select, then

                                                                                                measure and price your project.



                                                                                                There’s still time to order to

                                                                                                update for the Holidays AND

                                                                                                we have Gift Certificates

                                                                                                available!




               204-727-4766


                                                                                         Blinds • Shutters  • Shades
               381 Park Avenue East, Unit B                                              Drapes • Home Automation
               Brandon, MB

               BudgetBlinds.com]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[12                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018



































































        The Planet Kia dealership at 415 18th St. North in Brandon
        Fuel efficiency key driver for KIA owners






           For 16 years, Planet Kia on 18th Street  tanks of fuel and I believe it averaged about  wheel drive sedan, and it comes equipped  into the kind of vehicle they want, he said.
        North in Brandon has been locally owned  85 miles per gallon,” he said.  with their first twin turbo v6 engine.  “We probably are the most flexible too,
        and operated by Mike Plante and Sean   In a world where the cost of everything   “There’s definitely some exciting things  whatever kind of vehicle you’re looking
        Stark.  The dealership, which offers both  is continuing to rise — groceries, rent, hy-  put into that car,” Raimbault said.  for we really work hard we work with the
        new and used vehicles, is a great place to  dro —  it’s even more important to own a   “It’s competing against things like the  banks and make sure that it not only fits
        buy  a  car,  said  Adam Raimbault  general  fuel efficient car like the Kia Niro, he said.  four series BMW, the Audi A5, it’s com-  your budget, but that we can actually make
        sales manager.                         “When you can get a cross over like  peting against cars that are 65,000 to  it happen for you.”
           Raimbault has been working at Planet  the Kia Niro that not only fits the room  100,000 dollars, and it’s beating them,” he   They also have a wide range of inven-
        Kia in Brandon for 10 years.         for your family but gets 85 miles per gallon  said.                      tory available at the dealership, new and
           “Our sales team and our finance team,  or more, it’s hugely important, especially   The Kia Stinger costs under $50,000  used. They bring in a wide range of vehi-
        they have good customer rapport,” Raim-  when it comes to looking at your budget.”  to purchase. For customers that don’t have  cles from across Canada.
        bault said. “We’re here to help.” The Kia   The Kia Niro is also affordable to pur-  that kind of cash laying around, they also   Those who work later evenings in Bran-
        Niro is one of the new vehicles that they’re  chase, he said, starting at $25,000 to buy.   offer great finance options, he said.  don may still have some time to stop by the
        quite excited about carrying this year, he  It’s advertised on their website as “roomy,   They’ve recently expanded their finance  dealership,  as  it’s  open  late,  open  until  8
        said.                                versatile, and fuel-efficient, the 2018 Niro  department at Planet Kia on 18th St.   p.m. most nights of the week.
           The car holds the Guinness world re-  is one capable crossover-hybrid.”   “We have probably one of the best and
        cord for best fuel mileage on any hybrid   What’s also new and exciting this year  most equipped finance offices in Brandon  » The Brandon Sun
        vehicle.                             and available at Planet Kia is the Kia Sting-  for any kind of credit,” he said.  They really
           “It drove coast to coast  in just over four  er, he said. The sports car is their first all  work with the customer to ensure they get]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[“Highest Ranked Brand in Initial Quality in the U.S., 4 Years in a Row”
                                                                        Mass Market
                                                       +        NO-CHARGE








                                       FINANCING Φ              MAINTENANCE                                                *
                                                                       ON SELECT MODELS
                                                              2019s NOW AVAILABLE






                                       2018 Sorento
                                                                                                                             2018 Soul
                                       “Highest Ranked                      2018 Sportage                                    2018 Soul
                                       Midsize SUV in Initial   When equipped with optional autonomous emergency       When equipped with optional
                                                                                                                       When equipped with optional
                                                                                                                      autonomous emergency braking
                                       Quality in the U.S.,   braking and HID headlights; applies to vehicles built after   autonomous emergency braking
                                                                                                                     and HID headlights (EX Tech trim).
                                       2 Years in a Row”            June 2017 (EX Premium and SX trims).             and HID headlights (EX Tech trim).









                                                                                                                  2019019
                  2                                              2019                                             2
                  2019019
                                           LX FWD                                        LX FWD                               LX AT
                  Sorento SX shown ‡                             Sportage SX Turbo shown ‡                        Soul SX Turbo Tech shown ‡
                  FINANCE FROM                                   FINANCE FROM                                     FINANCE FROM    $1,785 DOWN AT
                   $ 86          $ 0  DOWN AT                     $ 80          $ 0  DOWN AT                       $ 59           1.99     %

                    WEEKLY Φ  1.99% FOR 84 MONTHS                  WEEKLY Φ  1.99% FOR 84 MONTHS                    WEEKLY Φ    FOR 84 MONTHS
                        INCLUDES $750 BONUS                                 STANDARD                                         AVAILABLE
                                                                           • KEYLESS ENTRY                                • PANORAMIC SUNROOF
                             STANDARD                                     • REARVIEW CAMERA ∑                         • HEATED FRONT AND REAR SEATS
                          • HEATED FRONT SEATS                           • HEATED FRONT SEATS                        • 8’’ INTEGRATED NAVIGATION SYSTEM
                           AND STEERING WHEEL
                           • REARVIEW CAMERA ∑                              AVAILABLE
                                                                    • SMART KEY WITH PUSH-BUTTON START
                             AVAILABLE                                     • DYNAMAX  AWD
                                                                                  TM
                          • 7-PASSENGER SEATS                            • BLIND SPOT DETECTION ∑
                        • 5,000 LBS TOWING CAPACITY                      • PANORAMIC SUNROOF
                           • DYNAMAX  AWD
                                   TM
          5 YEARS            / 100,000 KM  W                      ° °              COMPREHENSIVE    ROADSIDE ASSIST
                                                                                                    ROADSIDE ASSISTANCE ANCE
                             / 100,000 KM  WARRANTYARRANTY
                                                                                   COMPREHENSIVE
                                                                                                    ANYWHERE IN NOR
                                                                                                    ANYWHERE IN NORTH AMERICATH AMERICA
                                                                                   POWERTRAIN TRAIN
                                                                                   POWER
          5 YEARS / UNLIMITED KM ROADSIDE ASSISTANCE
                             / UNLIMITED KM ROADSIDE ASSISTANCE
                                                                                   100% TRANSFERABLE
                                                                                   100% TRANSFERABLE
          kia.ca/BestYet
         Offer(s) available on select new 2019 models through participating dealers to qualified retail customers who take delivery from October 2 to 31, 2018. Dealers may sell or lease for less. Some conditions apply. See dealer for complete details. Vehicles shown may include optional accessories and upgrades available at extra cost.  All offers are subject to change without notice. All pricing includes delivery and
         destination fees up to $1,785, $100 A/C charge (where applicable). Excludes taxes, licensing, PPSA, registration, insurance, $499 dealer documentation fee, fuel-fill charges up to $100 and down payment (if applicable and unless otherwise specified). Other lease and financing options also available.  Φ0% financing is only available on select new models to qualified customers  on approved credit. Representative
         Financing Example: Finance a new 2019 Sorento LX FWD (SR75AK)/2019 Sportage LX FWD (SP751K)/2019 Sorento LX FWD (SR75AK)/2019 Soul LX AT (SO752K) with a selling price of $29,130/$27,180/$29,130/$21,980 at 1.99%/1.99%/0%/1.99% for 84/84/48/84 months for a total number of 364/364/208/364 weekly payments of $86/$80/$140/$59 with $0/$0/$0/$1,785 down. Payment amount includes $750/$0/$750/$0
         Bonus. Cost of borrowing is $2,070/$1,932/$0/$1,435 for a total obligation of $29,130/$27,180/$29,130/$21,980. *No-charge maintenance offer available on the purchase, lease or finance of new 2018 Rio, 2018 Forte, 2019 Soul, 2019 Sportage, 2019 Sorento, 2019 Sedona, 2018 Stinger and new demo Kia models (2018 Rio, 2018 Forte, 2019 Soul, 2019 Sportage, 2019 Sorento, 2019 Sedona, 2018 Stinger) within
         6 months and 12,000 km and is eligible for a limited time between October 2 and 31, 2018. Two-year coverage will include the first four service intervals, every six months or 12,000 km, whichever comes first, all in accordance with the Kia Protect Service Advantage pre-paid maintenance contract. This offer provides customers with an estimated $900 retail value, based on the average
         cost of two-year or 48,000 km basic pre-paid maintenance plan. All terms and conditions of the Kia Protect Service Advantage pre-paid maintenance contract apply to this offer. Please see your Kia dealer for complete details.   ∑ None of the features we describe are intended to replace the driver’s responsibility to exercise due care while driving and are not a substitute for safe driving
         practices. Some features may have technological limitations. For additional information regarding the various features, including their limitations and restrictions, please refer to your vehicle’s Owner’s Manual. ‡Model shown Manufacturer Suggested Retail Price for 2019 Sorento SX (SR75JK)/2019 Sportage SX Turbo (SP757K)/2019 Soul SX Turbo Tech (SO85DK) is $44,865/$39,595/$30,095. The
         2018 Soul was awarded the 2018 Top Safety Pick+ by the Insurance Institute for Highway Safety (IIHS) for model year 2018. U.S. models tested. Visit www.iihs.org for full details. The 2018 Sportage was awarded the 2018 Top Safety Pick by the Insurance Institute for Highway Safety (IIHS) for model year 2018. U.S. models tested. Visit www.iihs.org for full details. The Kia Brand received the
         lowest rate of reported problems among mass market brands in the J.D. Power 2018 Initial Quality Study of new vehicle owners’ experience with their own vehicle after 90 days of ownership. Visit jdpower.com/awards. The Kia Sorento received the lowest rate of reported problems among midsize SUVs in the J.D. Power 2017-2018 Initial Quality Studies of new vehicle owners’ experience
         with their own vehicle after 90 days of ownership. Visit jdpower.com/awards. Information in this advertisement is believed to be accurate at the time of printing. °Unlimited roadside assistance is only applicable on 2017 models and onward. For more information on our 5-year warranty coverage, visit kia.ca or call us at 1-877-542-2886. Kia is a trademark of Kia Motors Corporation.]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018























































        Staff pose for a photo at the Adult & Teen Challenge Super Thrift store. (Douglas Portz Photography)
        Thrift Store helps fight addictions in Westman





           The Adult &  Teen Challenge Super  that we raise stay right here in the West-  In addition to its proceeds supporting
        Thrift store is not your regular thrift store.   man area to help us pay for the programs  the program, the Super Thrift store pro-
           With more than 12,000 square feet of  we run here for the women,” said Lowes.   vides its participants with work experience.
        retail space, it’s one of the city’s larger thrift   Adult &  Teen Challenge is a Chris-  Even though they opened in July, the
        stores, and is stocked by items that have  tian organization that helps both men and  Adult &  Teen Challenge  Super  Thrift
        been donated to the Adult & Teen Chal-  women around the globe overcome addic-  store’s grand opening was held on Septem-
        lenge charity.                       tion and change their lives. Their centres  ber 8th and Lowes said they were prepared.
           The  organization established  itself  are located in more than 125 countries   “We were about to open and I said to
        northwest of Brandon in 2008, and has op-  worldwide.                    one of the girls, “I feel like we’ve got ev-
        erated as a women’s centre since 2012.  Their goal is to create locally sustainable  erything but the kitchen sink.” The girl re-
           An international faith-based live-in  programs where men, women and families  plied “Oh, we’ve got one of those upstairs.”
        addictions program, the local centre is for  can find lasting freedom from addiction   The thrift store provides a great place
        women only and was expanded a couple of  and discover the life-changing power of  for the women from the shelter to give
        years ago to double in capacity to accom-  Jesus Christ.                 back.
        modate 16 students and four staff mem-  The programs that Adult & Teen Chal-  “They are part of the work force of the
        bers.                                lenge offer here in Westman include addic-  store.”
           Kim Lowes, the director for the Adult  tion prevention, recovery, and community   It’s also a great way to boost their
        & Teen Challenge Super Thrift store, also  support groups for both addicts and family  self-confidence as well help them begin to
        runs the Adult & Teen Challenge Wom-  members. Successfully recovered addicts  interact with the community in a positive
        en’s Shelter in Brandon that has the same  often return to the centers to teach pro-  way.
        name.                                grams themselves, with first-hand knowl-  The Adult &  Teen Challenge Super
           The thrift store’s profits go directly to  edge and the idea to keep on giving back to  Thrift store sells furniture, factory direct
        funding the shelter whose objective is to  the community.                mattresses, housewares, clothes, tools,
        better the lives of the women who have   “The thing that most people are realiz-  sports equipment, pet supplies, and more.
        been struggling with addiction. The best  ing is that addiction is the surface of the  Check them out at 127 Seventh Street, and
        part – it all stays within our local commu-  whole thing. Underneath all of that is the  support the community while you shop.
        nity.                                hurt, the pain, the struggles, and that’s what
           “All of the proceeds for the thrift store  we really try and conquer,” Lowes said.  » The Brandon Sun      (Douglas Portz Photography)]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[16                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018
















































        From left, Jessica, Jenny, David, and Cherrill. (Submitted)
        Both film and digital processing services




        on offer at Brandon Photographics






           You  might  say  that  Brandon  Photo-  just give it up – let the others do it’,” said  town does,” Hrabok said. “There aren’t any  cameras/processing stores, and it gives you
        graphics is going back to the future.  Hrabok. “So we dismantled the machine,  other photo places in Brandon. “Somebody  the opportunity to have conventions, listen
           Despite the fact mobile phones that  nut by bolt by screw, and got rid of it. It  asked me the other day,  ‘How is it that  to speakers, find out what others are doing,
        take pictures are ubiquitous, some people  ended up in the dumpster unfortunately,  you’re still standing?  What did you do?’  see what the coming trends are. So that’s
        still prefer to use a camera and film. And  because it was kind of one of those piec-  And I basically said, ‘We outlasted them.’”  helped us a lot.”
        for those in this area who do the latter,  es of equipment that nobody wanted.” But   Hrabok said that, surprisingly, consid-  But she stressed that Foto Source is
        Brandon Photographics is the only game  over the years, as digital mostly took over  ering all the other advancements that have  not an overlord – simply a buying group
        in town.                             from film, the other film-processing loca-  been  made  over  the  last  few  years,  once  that gives Brandon Photographics greater
           At the same time, they’ve developed an  tions started shutting down.  they got back into film processing, it was  purchasing power and a network of other
        app that allows people to place their or-  “One by one, all those other businesses  still the same old same old. “The technolo-  professionals with whom to compare notes.
        ders for numerous different items on their  disappeared,” Hrabok said. . So there was  gy hasn’t changed it a bit,” she said. “It’s the  “We’re independent,” she said.  “And the
        phones.                              us. And we had gotten rid of our machine.  very same process it was when we got rid of  only thing we don’t do here is sell equip-
           “It’s interesting to us because it’s on  And people were coming to us and saying,  our old machine.”       ment. And that’s an area that’s really lack-
        two different ends of the spectrum – it’s  ‘I still have a film camera, it’s taking lovely   But she made it clear, too, that pho-  ing in Brandon – there isn’t a camera store
        going backward to film-developing and  photos, I don’t want to get rid of it, so what  to finishing is the focal point of Brandon  here anymore.”
        it’s going forward to ordering pictures on  do I do with my film?’”      Photographics.                         In  addition  to  owner  David Tschetter,
        your phone,” said photographer Cherrill   To meet customer demand, Brandon   “It’s our business,” Hrabok said. “It’s not  there are three full-time staff members at
        Hrabok. “So it’s a little bit of everything.”  Photographics partnered with a processing  a lost leader. It’s not something we do on  the store, and they do – and can do – just
           While Brandon Photographics does all  company in Winnipeg. But that business’s  the side as part of something else. We’ve  about anything.
        types of photo-finishing, the company got  turnaround time was quite lengthy, and the  expanded into other areas such as photo   “We do processing, we do framing, we
        out of film processing five or six years ago  price was a bit high, and since film buffs  gifting, photo books, the app, the kiosks  have albums, we have photo gifts – so pret-
        because there weren’t enough rolls coming  were  coming  to  Brandon  Photographics  – things that keep us relevant. Some of  ty much the spectrum, which makes us dif-
        through the shop to justify operating a ma-  to have their pics sent away to be finished  the other stores were chains so I feel like  ferent from a lot of places,” Hrabok said. “A
        chine that needed to do a certain amount  anyway, the business figured it might as  they  had  access  to  things  that  maybe  we  lot of places are camera stores, or they’re a
        of processing to keep its chemistry stable.  well cut out the middle man. So they pur-  didn’t, because we’re just a little indepen-  lab, or they’re a portrait studio. And other
        Plus there were other competitors in the  chased a small machine and started pro-  dent Mom and Pop operation. And so we  than  the  equipment,  we’ve  kind  of  com-
        Wheat City who did volumes of that type  cessing film again.             have actually signed on with Foto Source,
        of work. “And we just thought, ‘Well, we’ll   “That’s something that nobody else in  which is a buying group for photography/  » Continued on Page 18]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Passports                                             Frames                          iPhone

                                                                                                                                 Film
                         &                     Photo                        &                        App &  Developing

                 Portraits                      Gifts                 Albums                       Online




                                                                                                Ordering







                                           We Can Print Your Photos!



                            Order Online: lab@brandonphoto.com

















              848–18 Street • 204.727.3263 • www.brandonphoto.com
                               th]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[18                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018


















































        » Continued from Page 16              We can do a sterling silver chain and a
                                                                                    The Wood That Made
                                              pendant. We have dog tags, we have a lit-  The Wood That Made
        bined everything.”                   tle charm bracelet. We have housewares –
           One of the things Brandon Photo-  things like coffee cups, travel mugs, trivets,
                                                                                                    Us Famous
        graphics has become a leader in is iden-  cutting boards. Phone cases. We can put           Us Famous
        tification photos. Passports, citizenship   whatever photo you want on pretty much
        documents, visas, and gun-license regis-  whatever item you want. It’s endless what
        trations are only a few of the ID pictures   you can do.”
        Brandon Photographics can take.  “And   And all that and more can be done us-
        they come from all different countries, all   ing the Brandon Photographics app! A free
        different requirements – they might have   download from The App Store, photofin-
        a different head size versus a different out-  isher Jenny May said the company is ex-
        er size,” Hrabok said. “They might have a   cited about the possibilities using the app
        different background, they might have to   provides. “It’s an app you can go to on your
        see their ears or they might have to be on   phone – you can order all of your prints,
        glossy paper. There’s just an absolute ton   any print size is available on there – any-
        of ID requirements that we have to keep   thing that we do in store is available on the
        up on. And we’ve really created a name for   app,” May said. “So you can go in there and
        ourselves in being whatever it is you need,   you can order books or you can order mugs
        if you can tell us what the specifics are, we   or you can order 500 prints or anything!”
        can create that for you.”              A person can browse Brandon Photo-
           Brandon Photographics has begun to   graphics’ vast selection of options, make a
        outsource a few of their items, because al-  selection and then order online. And the
        though their 18th Street location is prime,   turnaround time is usually very quick.
        their space is limited. So things like print-  “A lot of people are using online order-
        ing on acrylic or brushed aluminum is done   ing,” she said. “It’s so convenient because
        elsewhere, but almost everything else is   you can do it on your phone and it’s only
        done in their shop.                  one stop – all you have to do is come here
           And photo gifting has become a boom-  to pick up your stuff. We can pretty much
        ing business, as people take to embellish-  do whatever anybody wants – technology’s
        ing all sorts of things with special pictures.   pretty awesome now.
                                                                                                TH
        “We  probably  have  somewhere  around   “It’s super easy and even people who are   1840 – 18 STREET NORTH, BRANDON • 204-728-4243
        200 items that we can put your photo on,”   not computer savvy are having a really easy   Fax: 204-727-2619 • Toll-Free: 1-800-224-7506 • www.windsorplywood.com
        Hrabok said with a smile. “There’s sections   time with it. Probably three times a day we   sales@windsorplywood.net
        such as apparel – we can do T-shirts, we   hear, ‘Oh, that was so easy! That was so
        can do socks, we can do aprons, we can do   great! So convenient!’”        Store Hours: Mon. – Fri. 7:30 am – 6:00 pm; Sat. 8:00 am – 5:00 pm
                                                                                   Some items may be cash & carry and we reserve the right to limit quantities. All items may not
        neckties, flip-flops. There’s also a jewellery   » The Brandon Sun         be exactly as illustrated.
        section where we can do a cuff bracelet.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[YOUR PHARMACY TEAM                                                     OCTOBER 2018 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                  19

                                                                                » Continued from Page 2              to look older and older.
                                                                                to tell my mom to come in and see you.’  “I had a guy come in who was ten years
                                                                                   Younger women are looking at cosmetic  younger than me and he looked ten years
                                                                                treatments as preventative measures, Kelle-  older than me,” Kelleher continued.  “He
                                                                                her said – they notice the sometimes deep  said, ‘If you use all these chemicals you’re
                                                                                lines on their mothers’ or fathers’ faces and  going to get cancer.’ Sunscreen is a chemi-
                                                                                see the lines starting to form on themselves  cal but it helps you NOT get cancer.”
                                                                                and take steps to avoid having them devel-  While only about 10 per cent of Kelle-
                                                                                op further.                          her’s patients are male, the women who
                                                                                   And while there’s still a lot of cosmetic  seek her help are sometimes reluctant, but
                                                                                surgery going on, Kelleher’s procedures are  want to improve their appearance. And
                                                                                non-invasive, which is far less drastic than  while getting older is inevitable, people go
                                                                                going under the knife.               to other great lengths to look attractive.
                                                                                   “For instance, with filler, we’re trying to  And cosmetic procedures can be effective
                                                                                do a non-surgical face lift,” Kelleher said.  additions to that pursuit.
                                                                                “And it doesn’t cost as much. It’s still ex-  “We do our nails and we do our hair and
                         • Prescribing for minor ailments  • Free Personalized Compliance  pensive, but not as expensive as surgery.  we shave our legs and get laser hair-remov-
                         • Injection services         Packaging                 And there’s no downtime unless you get a  al, which is much more convenient, and we
                                                                                small bruise.”
                                                                                                                     don’t mind talking about that,” Kelleher
                         • Online Prescription Refills  • Sigvaris Compression Stockings  Taking care of oneself should be a  said. “So what’s the difference?”
                         • Personal care             • Confectionary            no-brainer  for  most  folks,  but  Kelleher   Anyone curious about what Kelleher
                                                                                said many men don’t do nearly as much  and her staff can do for them is welcome to
                         • Free blood pressure testing  and much more!          as women do to protect their skin. Her  book an appointment for a free consulta-
           MIKIL KAPADIA
           Pharmacy  Mgr.  for customers                                        strong feelings about this subject came to  tion. And Kelleher said she and her associ-
                                                                                a head a few weeks ago, when a man came  ates are always up front with people about
                            Seniors Discount 10% OFF EVERYDAY*                  to see her. He’d never worn sunscreen, and  what they can expect.
                                                                                it showed.
                                                                                                                       “They always get advised about what we
                                          Excludes prescriptions                   “I’m on a vendetta right now about how  think would be the best thing for them,”
                                                                                poorly men care for their skin,” she said.  Kelleher said.
                                                                                “They come in in their later 40s and early   For more information about Dr. Kelle-
                                             FREE CITY WIDE DELIVERY            50s. They come in with sun damage and go,  her’s products and procedures, visit lasersk-
                                             2425 Victoria Avenue | 204-728-1062     ‘I don’t wear sunscreen.’ They need to have  invein.com.
                                              Hours:  Mon - Fri  9:00 am - 7:00 pm  a skin regimen and look after themselves. If
                                                   Sat 10:00 am - 4:00 pm       you’re not wearing sunscreen you’re going  » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[20                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018


























































        Westman Communitcation Group can be found at 1906 Park Avenue in Brandon. (Theresa Nett/The Brandon Sun)
        Westman Communications offers a local,



        personal touch for your business needs






           Starting  a  news  business?  Want  up-  to internet.”                proud of the support given to the company  gramming.
        grades  to existing  communication devic-  Westman Communications Group of-  by local businesses in the region. Westman   In 2008  Westman Communications
        es? Or are interested in checking out a  fers a competitive advantage to its custom-  Communication Group uses cutting edge  Group acquired two local radio stations, Q
        new communications provider?  Westman  ers, due to the size of their operation. “We  technology to makes these services work.  Country 91.5 FM and 94.7 Star FM. They
        Communications Group can give you ex-  are much more flexible than a lot of larg-  “Our products are state-of-the art,” he said.  also runs a local news website that includes
        actly what you need.                 er companies, and we are able to come up   Keys said the best part of his job, is the  weather updates and winning lotto num-
           Westman Business, a division of West-  with customized solutions,” Keys said. “We  relationships he gets to build with clients.   bers called Manitobanet.com., and have
        man Communications Group, has been  get to know our customers better, and work   “I like the close interactions that we  their own TV station called WCGtv. The
        helping local businesses grow through re-  more closely with them.”      have with our customers.”            company encourages all of their customers
        duced costs, efficient  higher  speeds, and   Westman Communication Group of-  Keys has been the Director of Westman  to let them know what types of local con-
        dedicated customer support.  Westman  fers voice services that include long dis-  Business for six years and has over 30 years  tent they would like to see on the station.
        Business services director Bud Keys says  tances plans and toll free numbers. Their  of experience in communications.  West-  There is no other communication compa-
        the organization has helped many compa-  internet services come in fiber and high  man  Communication  Group  was  estab-  ny quite like  Westman Communications
        nies design communications, and they do it  speed options, and their data services in-  lished as a co-op in 1977. Westman invests  Group, which contribute so directly to the
        all with a personal touch.           clude web hosting, dedicated internet, and  each customer’s  equity back into its own  community.
           “We do a lot of high-speed data conduc-  managed services.            operations. This enables them to acquire   “I like working for a small company
        tivity for businesses between their branch-  They also offer television services. In  new services that they can offer their cus-  rather than a big provider,” Keys said. “The
        es, and hosted PBX,” Keys said. PBX is  addition to providing television services  tomers, and guarantees local programming  employees here are more than just a face
        an acronym for Private Branch Exchange  to individuals, Keys noted,  “we provide  and local employment. They also use the  with a name, and so are the customers.”
        phone systems. “Anything you would gen-  business T.V. for hotels, care homes, hos-  equity to provide scholarships to local stu-
        erally need for a business from phone lines  pitals and other businesses.” Keys said he is  dents, and free educational television pro-  » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[22                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018




                                                  ‘Sky is the limit’




                                                  in the city’s





                                                  southeast






                                                  INDICATORS POINT TO CONTINUED PROSPERITY

                                                  AS CHREST PLEDGES A FOCUS ON INDUSTRIAL

                                                  DEVELOPMENT









































                  By Matt Goerzen                                ing. VBJ Developments first presented the idea to the   “You have to be in this somewhat market responsive.
                                                                 Brandon and Area Planning Department in 2011, and  The developer needs to be market responsive - they need
                    In what will be his second political mandate as mayor  was followed up by an application for urban expansion in  to go where they feel the tenants want to go. And the
                  of the City of Brandon, Rick Chrest said that he foresees  2014. Background studies were prepared by the applicant  place they want to be is in that area.”
                  continued steady growth for the community he leads.  prior to the process picking up steam in 2017.   During the next four years, Chrest said he would also
                    While he gives a nod to the fact that Brandon’s busi-  And while the Manitoba Municipal Board accepted  like to see greater movement on industrial development
                  ness community remains strong and stable, Chrest ad-  the annexation proposal, and Brandon City Council vot-  in the city.
                  mits he is at least a little impatient to see a few initiatives  ed to officially sign the agreement, the RM of Cornwallis   “We want to ratchet things up... in the southeast end
                  move along a little faster.                    council decided last June to postpone its decision.  of Brandon,” Chrest said. “Our people have worked really
                    “A lot of things take longer than my liking,” Chrest   “(The south end of Brandon) is destined to be a com-  closely with industrial partners to jump start a better ap-
                  said in an interview earlier this month.       mercial node,” Chrest said. “Again, the process just takes  proach to industrial development in our southeast end.”
                    While there are always projects he would like to see  way longer than I would like. But we’re close to the finish   Asked what kind of developments he would like to see
                  move forward faster, Chrest was referring to a proposed  line.”                                in the southeast industrial area of the city, Chrest said,
                  170-acre development southwest of the Patricia Avenue   The previous council moved away from attempts to  “the sky is the limit.”
                  and Highway 10 intersection that has prompted the city  develop Brandon’s northern property and instead con-  “We would look at anything. But we do have a strong
                  to annex the land from the RM of Cornwallis.   centrated on commercial developments to the south,  agricultural flavour. We’re called the Wheat City after all,
                    The annexation process has been years in the mak-  which Chrest said made more financial sense.  and agribusiness is a strong suit for us. And we have quite]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2018 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           23









































































  a bit in metal fabrication as well.”              And while KPMG has since ceased that analysis, giv-  as late as 2016, was ranked among the top three in the
     These already-existing clusters of businesses in Bran-  en all the indicators – a low unemployment rate, strong  country by KPMG.
  don – both agricultural and industrial – act as a magnet  population growth, GDP growth and disposable income   There are, of course, hurdles to be met, especially
  for similar companies to set up shop.           spending in the retail sector – it appears 2019 will be  when it comes to the retail sector. The growth of online
     “If we didn’t have metal fabrication here, it would  another solid year for the city.       shopping has had a negative effect on the bottom line
  be difficult to get someone to come here,” Chrest said.   “If you look at that type of an indicator, and you look  of large retailers in the community. And yet, Trudel said
  “When you have a reasonable footprint, you have a  at the overall environment which KPMG would have  there has been solid growth in the service sector this year,
  chance of attracting more.”                     evaluated, there has been no backward sliding,” Econom-  in the range of 2.2 per cent. And the projection for 2019
     Over the course of his first four years as mayor, Chrest  ic Development Brandon director Sandy Trudel said.   looks similar.
  has joined his fellow elected officials in overseeing steady   Save for a slight increase in May, Brandon’s localized   “Overall, the projection for retail is that they remain
  growth within the city, even as unemployment numbers  unemployment rate has consistently come in lower than  strong.”
  in Brandon spiked between 2016 and 2017.        last year’s rates, month over month.  The city’s GDP   While Brandon’s manufacturing sector and retail ser-
     As The Sun reported in last year’s Westman Business  growth remains at 1.4 to 1.5 per cent annually, and Bran-  vices allow the city to be diversified enough to weather
  section, the Wheat City has earned a competitive edge as  don has maintained a strong population growth that is  ups and downs in the economy, it remains highly depen-
  it relates to the affordability of doing business – at least  well above the national average.  dent on its surrounding rural communities.
  according to a 2016 report by KPMG on how cities’ eco-  Municipal taxes have been kept well below the rate of
  nomic competitiveness stack up against each other.  inflation, and the city’s commercial property tax ranking,   » Continued on Page 29]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[24                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018

































































        The Great Canadian Oil Change garage at 827 18th Street. (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)
        Great Canadian Oil Change a family affair






           Great Canadian Oil Change is Bran-  filters, batteries, and any other products   What makes these two franchises spe-  marketer and supplier of premium brand
        don’s well known leader when it comes to  that they work with. With their 21-point  cial is that Blair’s whole family contributes  lubricants and automotive services, with
        caring for your personal vehicles. Part of  inspection, they can identify if your wiper  to  running  the  shops.  “My  son Braiden  sales in more than 140 countries. The com-
        keeping your car running is regular clean-  blades need to be replaced or if a bulb is  manages the Brandon location and my  pany was established in 1866.
        ing and check-ups.                   burned out on your vehicle. In fact, they’ll  other son Matthew just took over in Por-  “Valvoline is rapidly growing. They are
           “We  do anything  from oil  changes  to  even replace it for you.     tage,” said Blair.  Blair still does the hiring  going to be an even bigger name in the in-
        fuel filters, air filters, transmission ser-  Blair became an expert in servicing ve-  himself, and oversees the operations along  dustry,” Blair said.  “The customers won’t
        vices, cooling system services, differential  hicles while working at dealerships since  with his wife.       really notice anything different. It will still
        services,  transfer  cases,  anything  that  has  the 1980s. He had always wanted to own   The announcement Blair is most excit-  be Great Canadian. The same name will be
        to do with maintenance on your vehicle,”  his own service shop.          ed about is an expanding partnership with  on the sign, the same great people will be
        said Mike Blair, the owner of Great Ca-  “I heard Great Canadian Oil Change  Valvoline.                       working here, and there will be same owner
        nadian Oil Change franchises in Brandon  was looking for a franchisee in Brandon.”   “We have some good news that is go-  at the franchise level. You’ll hear a lot more
        and Portage La Prairie. “The only thing we  It was the opportunity Blair had dreamed  ing to be great for our customers and our  about them now though.”
        don’t do is repairs.”                of.  He and his wife, Bridget, bought the  business,” Blair said.  “Valvoline has been   Great Canadian Oil Change started in
           The locally-owned drive-thru oil  franchise and opened their first shop in  our partner for the last five years and we  1978 in Saskatoon. It’s expanding still, and
        change  facility, found at 827-18th St.,  Brandon eight years ago. “It was built from  use their products in our shops. We have  offers oil changes and other services with-
        offers convenient oil change services, but  the ground up” Blair said. “It’s still pretty  a great relationship with them. Now they  out customers having to book appoint-
        also transmission, differential and radia-  young  in years.” Quite  happy  about  his  have become the umbrella that the 71  ments; it’s just like a drive thru. All of the
        tor services as well. They also carry quality  success, he went on to open another fran-  Great Canadian Oil Changes are under.”   services they offer are warranty approved.
        product lines in terms of oil, air filters, fuel  chise four years later in Portage La Prairie.  Valvoline Inc. is a leading worldwide  » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[3712033_GreatCdnOilChange_Layout 1  18-10-12  11:27 AM  Page 1





                 Our Team is Here to Get You Road Ready











                           Oil Change Package Includes:
                          Up to 5L warranty approved oil,

                         new warranty approved oil ﬁlter,

                        Lube to manufacturer speciﬁcations,
                             and a great cup of coffee!











































                                                                                   Mike             Braiden            Cody              Ben





                        Locally Owned & Operated


                           • No Appointments • Warranty Approved
                                                                                  Jason              Paul             Colby             Jamie


                                                                         Open 7 Days a Week for your Convenience!


                                                                                 Monday - Friday, 8 am – 8 pm; Saturday, 8 am – 6 pm;  Sunday, Noon – 4 pm

                                                                                                                  th
                                        CAA Recommended                              204-727-5823  |  827 – 18 Street, Brandon
                                        CAA Approved
                                        CAA Member Discount                                      www.greatcanadianoilchange.com]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[26                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018
















































        Rental Experts in Brandon art 155 Glen Street. (Theresa Nett/The Brandon Sun)
        Rental Experts goes the extra mile for its customers




           There are plenty of other companies in  here,”  Wannop  said.  “We get  that  every
        the same business, but the key for Rental  day. People say,  ‘I didn’t know you were
        Experts is that they don’t care what their  here!’ And we’ve been here for three years.
        competition does.                    So we are here, we are available, we are an
           To paraphrase the old song, they do it  option.
        their way.                             “The big companies are all here too –
           With a focus on good, old-fashioned  there’s rental companies everywhere – but
        customer service, a large inventory, and a  you don’t have to deal with the big multi-
        genuine willingness to help, Rental Experts  nationals. The locals are here.”
        has carved out its own niche in the three   Rental  Experts two owners are proud
        short years it’s been operating in Brandon.  to have been born and raised in Manitoba,
           Started by two friends in Winnipeg 16  and Wannop has lived here since he was 12
        years ago, Rental Experts brought on an-  years old. His staff is all from Brandon, too.
        other friend, Doug  Wannop, to manage  And it appears the citizenry is very happy
        its Brandon operation. All three men have  to deal with people who have local roots.
        worked for corporate stores, and all three   “Our  client  list grows daily – a  lot of
        much prefer the independent approach.   contractors, some industrial clients, some
        “We rent pretty much everything,” Wan-  homeowners, heavy equipment guys as
        nop said.  “Port-a-Potties, homeowner  well, the heavy construction guys, land-
        equipment, lawn and garden, aerial equip-  scapers, builders, welders – all of them,”
        ment, booms and scissors, skid steers, scaf-  Wannop said.
        fold – it’s pretty much you name it, we’ve    And the company’s philosophy is   Rental Experts manager Doug Wannop. (Theresa Nett/The Brandon Sun)
        got it.”                             knowing their customers and providing ex-
           Although the business is growing and  ceptional customer service.     to come in after hours, but if someone says,  day and we’ll work it out. It’s that kind of
        expanding on a daily basis, the name of-   “Dealing with people and being able to  ‘Hey – I really need to unload this on Sat-  stuff that people don’t realize we do. Or
        ten confuses people who think they’re in  shake a hand, and say hello, or come in on  urday – just don’t call me before 8 o’clock  somebody says, ‘Geez – I’m in a bind – can
        the property rental business, which they’re  Saturday to help somebody out, instead of  – let me sleep in a little bit – and I’ll meet  I get a tool?’ And I’d say, ‘Well, it’s Sunday,
        not. And Rental Experts wants to ensure  saying, ‘No – we’re not open’ – that’s im-  you at the shop. I’m 10 minutes away. It’s  but let me meet you there.’”
        every customer becomes a repeat custom-  portant to us,” Wannop said. “The corpo-  not like I have to drive two hours to go to    Rental Experts offers everything from
        er, which is why they’re working hard to  rate stuff is very regimented – they don’t go  work. Ten minutes from the shop, so if you  short-term to long-term rentals – anything
        establish a bigger reputation in the public  any extra mile for anybody. And that’s what  need to unload something and it’s really  from  daily  rentals  to  as  long  as  someone
        consciousness.                       we do – we go that extra mile.      kind of messing up your weekend, then  wants something for. And unlike many
           “It’s mostly people  don’t know  we’re    “I’m on call all the time. Nobody likes  we’ll do it. Or just hold on to it until Mon-  » Continued on Page 28]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[YOUR RESIDENTIAL AND CONSTRUCTION SPECIALISTS



                      155 Glen Avenue, Brandon, MB  |  Ph: 204-728-4447  |  www.rentalexperts.ca











                                                            Manitoba Owned & Operated
                                                               Rentals • Sales • Service





























































                                                          PROUD SUPPLIERS OF









                                          BRANDON’S RENTAL EXPERTS




                                    COME SEE DOUG WANNOP AND HIS FRIENDLY STAFF ON THE NORTH HILL!]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[28            THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018


        » Continued from Page 26              have this?’ I want to say ‘yes.’ So that the
        of their corporate “competitors” – a word   next time he comes back, he just comes
        Wannop doesn’t like – Rental Experts car-  here first.  We’re big on that – we stock
        ries a complete stock of all sorts of products   things that most people don’t for just that
        from names such as Stihl, Husqvarna, and  reason.”
        Toro.                                    In addition to the  aforementioned
            “We have a full inventory here, and if  items – and this is just a sampling – Rentals
        we come up short here, we’ve got access to  Experts carries things like marking paint,
        the branch in  Winnipeg,”  Wannop said.   Chapin sprayers, and hammer drill bits.    Connie Wilson, Nail Tech; Cassie Piwniuk, Hair Stylist and Nail Tech;
        “The store in Winnipeg is quite a bit larg-  And having rare and minor items on hand        Melissa Hardy, Owner; Jalisa Creasy, Hair Stylist
        er, so if we have to, we can pull from them   has become part of reason for the compa-
        as well.”                            ny’s success.
            And if Rental Experts doesn’t have
        what you need, there’s a pretty good like-   “I need to be that one-stop shop where                            • HAIR
        lihood they’ll get it.               the guy comes in here and goes, ‘Oh – I                                   • NAILS
             “I had a customer in here just today   forgot my hard hat – have you got hard
        talking about the potential for some work,   hats?’ Well yes, I do,” Wannop said. “It may                      • EYELASH
        and we may have to buy tools for it – we  not be the cheapest hard hat in Brandon,
        don’t carry what he wants,” Wannop said.  but it’s here and you don’t have to drive                               EXTENSIONS
        “But I think we can make money on it and  to another store. That’s one thing we re-
        he’s happy to deal with us. He doesn’t want  ally pride ourselves in – we look after the
        to deal with the corporate side.     customers, we stock things, and we carry      Exclusive Brandon vendor of    Pure Anada Natural
            “I can talk to the two partners in this   products that people want that no one car-  Rocky Mountain Soap  Cosmetics available in salon
        company, and we can make a decision, nor-  ries anymore.
        mally within hours, whether to buy a tool    “People can just call and find out if we
        we need or we’ve got an opportunity here   have  what  they’re  looking  for  –  they  can
        to do this thing, and I don’t have to wait
        for corporate.                       call me anytime,” Wannop said, and then
            “In most corporations nowadays, there’s   laughed. “I’m seemingly always here.”
        just a lack of interest in carrying stock, be-    To contact Rental Experts, call 204-               204-728-5060
        cause the liability is dead stock. I want a  728-4447, or email doug@rentalexperts.ca.        1003 13th Street, Brandon
        customer to walk in here and go,  ‘I’ve
        looked everywhere around town – do you  » The Brandon Sun                                      ~ WALK-INS WELCOME ~


                                                                                              Now Accepting



                                                                                                 New Patients





                                                                                                Please call 204-728-9540 to book today!





                                                                                                                      OUR DENTISTS:


                                                                                                                      Dr. Brad McNiven, DMD

                                                                                                                      Dr. Paul Chen, DMD


                                                                                                                      Dr. Todd Kruk, DDS

                                                                                                                      Dr. Tom Breneman, DMD


                                                                                                                      Dr. David Truong, DMD

                                                                                                                      Dr. Hundoo Kim, DMD





                      204-728-9540  |  2425 Victoria Avenue, Brandon  |  Second Floor – Unit D]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2018 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           29

        » Continued from Page 23             province was the same.  The wheat was   “The pipeline activity has definitely  front, so that everyone knows the costs
           “If our farm communities do well, so   just excellent. The canola was average. Soy  helped retailers in Brandon,” said Bran-  they’re getting into, and that it can be done
        does Brandon,” Trudel said. “I’m waiting to   beans are disappointing everywhere.”  don Chamber of Commerce president Jeff  in an expedient manner so they can get on
        see what’s happening with this cold spell   Commodity prices have stayed sol-  Hood.  “You see some increase in traffic  with business.”
        that hit us.”                        id - “not strong, but solid,” Mazer added,  throughout town.  You know people are   There is also the business of downtown
           The weather in the Westman area this   stating that there remains good canola out  spending money on grocery stores, restau-  redevelopment, particularly following last
        fall has been unseasonably cold, and much   in the fields, and soybeans – what crop re-  rants,  hotels,  and  other  markets  in  the  May’s disastrous fires which destroyed a
        of harvest in the western part of the prov-  mains – can stand a fair amount of water.  area.”                number of businesses. There are also sev-
        ince has been at a standstill. While Key-  “In this business, you have to imagine   But as nice as this little financial gain is  eral open lots either for sale or currently
        stone Agricultural Producers president Bill   that the glass is half full.”  for local retailers, Hood noted that this is  underdeveloped.
                                                                                                                        While Chrest said the downtown re-
        Campbell recently warned that the cost   And there’s more to agriculture than  only temporary, and is not part of a sustain-  gion remains a concern, and that there is
        of such a cool wet spring is “going to be   just the harvest season. Producers with  able economy.
        significant” – possibly in the millions of   livestock have seen some stable years.   “Those people won’t be here forever,”  no doubt the May fires were a significant
                                                                                                                      setback, he sees ongoing growth and a lot
        dollars – not everyone in the agricultural   “There’s optimism out there. Com-  Hood said. “So, we’re trying to put a fo-  of optimism in the city – not just down-
        industry is as concerned.            modity prices are strong, Cattle prices are  cus on economic growth in the city. It’s a   town, but throughout the city.
           “I’m feeling the pain.  This is brutal-  strong. Pork prices are OK,” he said. “Op-  culture shift – make it top of mind with   He likened every new business opening
        ly stressful and painful,” said Bob Mazer,   erations are probably as efficient as we’ve  government, but also the business com-  or expansion to getting a hit at a ballgame.
        president and CEO of Mazergroup Imple-  ever seen therm. This is a bump in the road.  munity as well. Everyone has to be able to   “This is like hitting singles,” Chrest
        ments. “But I’ve been farming for 50 years   Those that are in the business of farming  work together and prop each othesr up so   said. “You have to keep hitting them and
        and we’ve always got a crop off. Is there a   aren’t going to say that ‘because I had four  we have a success.”  hitting them, and the Brandon Downtown
        bunch of heartache and stress and difficulty   or five bad weeks – forget it.’ They will buy   For Hood, this includes pushing the city   Development Corporation is really helping
        involved? Yeah. But it won’t take much to   equipment, upgrade and continue to make  to further reduce red tape so that existing   those instances.
        get back out on the field.”          the business decisions on what they need to  businesses have the ability to grow, and to   “Then you’d hope for some bigger hits,
           Mazer’s optimism stems from his farm-  continue to be efficient.”     ensure that the city is nimble enough to at-  or some home runs as a game changer. The
        ing background, which is necessary to keep   Further afield, local retailers are also  tract new business.    Brandon University-led initiative down-
        going  year  after  year,  even  after  difficult   feeling a financial bump from the ongoing   Hood used the example of the new ex-  town would be a very large scale proposi-
        crop yields. But there’s more to it than that.   pipeline  construction activity in southern  pansion at Precision Toyota on 18th Street.   tion. We’re hopeful that we will get some
        Before the wet weather descended, harvest   Manitoba. Enbridge’s Line 3 construction  While their expansion is going through,   traction. That would be quite transforma-
        yields were looking pretty good across the   and replacement program spans more than  “which is great to see,” Hood said the pro-  tional. But in the meantime, we’ll keep
        province.                            1,600 kilometres, crossing three provinces  cess to get to this point was very slow.  hitting the singles and doubles and keep
           “We were clicking along pretty reason-  and three U.S. states. And all those work-  “We all understand there are regulations   moving forward.”
        ably, and then we started into harvest,”   ers need food, lodging, and have money in  that have to be put in place and enforced,”   mgoerzen@brandonsun.com
        Mazer said.  “Pretty much all across the   their pockets.                Hood said. “We just want everything up   Twitter: @MattGoerzen



              GOT




              BIG





              PLANS?






              Call us!







              FARM,                                                                                                   Roland Weir

              RESIDENTIAL                                                                        Appraisal Associates

              & COMMERCIAL

                                                                                                                             th
              PROPERTY APPRAISERS                                                                Suite 30A, 1015 – 26 Street, Brandon
                                                                                                    204-727-7100     Fax: 204-727-1563

              SINCE 1977                                                                                                         weir1@mts.net]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[30                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018




        Giant Tiger focused on



        quality products




        at low prices



























































        Giant Tiger in Brandon. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
        RENOVATIONS IN 2016 HAVE PROVIDED A MORE CUSTOMER-FRIENDLY SHOPPING ENVIRONMENT AT THE LOCAL STORE

           Giant Tiger is the all-Canadian, family, discount store  location. “I really enjoy operating a business in Brandon,  been to Giant Tiger store lately, now is the time. There
        focused on saving you time and money. There are more  “Keber said. “It has a small town feel here and you can rec-  are new fall items and new fashions arriving daily. “Our
        than 235 Giant Tiger stores in communities across Cana-  ognize many people in the community.” Giant Tiger has  company has a buying office in Montreal, Canada’s fashion
        da and each one is stocked with affordable, on-trend home  tried to become a part of the important fabric that binds  capital,” Keber said. “We sell clothes that will keep you
        and family fashions, brand-name groceries and everyday  Brandon and Westman together. “We very much appre-  dressed in style. As a store manager, I have control over
        necessities at low prices,                       ciate the support from the community and we return the  the merchandise purchased to best suit the needs of the
           Giant Tiger is no stranger to the local business commu-  favour happily by getting involved with the events taking  community.”
        nity, as it roared onto the scene back in May 2005.  place in Brandon and area,” Keber said. “We are very in-  From a business standpoint, it’s important to note that
            In August 2016, Giant Tiger underwent an extensive  volved in community activities, and we continue to sup-  Giant Tiger was established in 1961 in Ottawa and now
        renovation of the entire store to offer shoppers a new store  port dozens of events and schools in the Westman area.”  grown to more than 235 locations in Canada.
        experience with bright colours and easy to navigate aisles,  The support in the community hasn’t gone unnoticed by   The North West Company (NWC) and Giant Tiger
        while  continuing  to  keep  the  same  focus  on  customer  those frequenting the store.         have a master franchise agreement in place, which grants
        service that the community has come to know the store   “Brandon has always been a successful location,” Keber  NWC the right to open and operate Giant Tiger stores in
        for. Curtis Keber, who has been in the retail industry for  said. “Last year we were ranked number 11 in overall sales  western Canada.
        more than 30 years, is the store manager for the Brandon  with more than 235 stores in the company.” If you haven’t  » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[GIANT TIGER’S EXCLUSIVE BRANDS











                                          CONFIDENT. STYLISH.                                                CASUAL. CURRENT.


























                                ALWAYS CASUAL. ALWAYS COMFORTABLE.                                   ALWAYS STYLISH. ALWAYS RELAXED.


























                           ENERGETIC. FUN.                    BE. YOURSELF.                 BE. ADVENTUROUS.                    ACTIVE. LIFE.










          Giant Selection of Current Fashions









             GIANT TIGER
             CANADA’S BEST-KEPT SECRET.
             FOR YOU. FOR LESS.


             2626 Victoria Ave, Brandon  •  300 - Mountain Ave, Neepawa]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[32                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018


        Advanced Hearing offers the latest in audio aids





           Ask  most  people  and  they  will  likely  say
        hearing aids are simply an amplifier you put in
        your ear.
           Nothing could be further from the truth.
           Millions of dollars of research go into today’s
        hearing aids, and they can do things that were
        unthinkable only 20 years ago.  With faster mi-
        croprocessors and learning technology, today’s
        devices are nothing short of mini supercomput-
        ers that you can wear inside your ear.
           Now, let’s think about that for a minute.
        The inside of your ear is not a friendly place for
        an electronic device.  Ear wax, moisture, outside
        elements, sweat and daily activity all take their
        toll.  Your device must withstand the daily pun-
        ishment of how the human body works.
           But that’s not all. It’s what this amazing little
        machine can do for you that’s most important
        to you and your loved ones.
           Imagine being able to have a conversation in
        a crowded mall or restaurant because your de-
        vice lowered the background noise and directed
        its attention on the person you were speaking
        to. Today’s devices are smart, focused, and they
        learn about you and your daily activities, so you
        can create a customized experience unique only
        to you.  The more you wear them, the better
        they get.
           Set them to stream music from your smart-
        phone or to watch TV while others in the room
        can watch at a comfortable volume.  No more
        “Can you turn it down!” conversations.
           So now you have an idea of what is need-
        ed.  A supercomputer that learns about you
        and your daily routine.  And it must be small
        enough to fit in your ear, be discreet and be able
        to handle the daily rigours and elements that
        you body subjects it to every single day.
           And now, new research is also showing that
        hearing loss treated sooner can help prevent or
        delay the onset of dementia.  A recent study by
        Dr. Frank Lin and colleagues at Johns Hop-
        kins University found that essentially untreat-
        ed hearing loss seemed to speed up age-related
        cognitive decline.
           Dr. Colleen Wiebe, with AdvancedHearing   In front: Megan Stanley, BC-HIS. Back from left to right: Alison Radford; Dr. Colleen Wiebe, Au.D.; Janissa Cassells. (Supplied)
        Clinic Ltd. in Brandon, says most people wait
        for anywhere between seven and ten years after
        first noticing hearing loss before seeking pro-
        fessional help.The teams at Advanced Hearing
        Clinic or Stokes Hearing and Audiology Ser-
        vices will perform full audiometric testing, fit
        you with an appropriate hearing device, provide
        unlimited adjustments and hearing aid scans,
        offer annual hearing evaluations and provide a
        60-day risk-free trial to make sure you have the
        best device to meet your needs.
           “Everyone has different hearing loss,” Wie-
        be says. “It can be as unique as a fingerprint.”
           Their clinic in Brandon is the place to go to
        try out the most up to date hearing aids.
           “Anything that’s new we like to try it, and
        we always let people know when they come in
        if they’re trying one of the newer ones and to let
        us know what they think.”

        » The Brandon Sun                        Advanced Hearing Clinic’s Brandon location storefront at 42 McTavish Avenue East. (Supplied)]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[#HearingFact: Hearing loss leads to cascading cognitive effects



                                                                                        Older adults with mild-to-moderate
                                                                                        hearing loss performed poorer

                                                                                        on cognitive tests of memory

                                                                                        than those of the same age who

                                                                                        had good hearing.







                 MEET THE TEAM AT ADVANCED HEARING CLINIC AND STOKES HEARING AND AUDIOLOGY!




















































                                        We are dedicated to helping you improve your overall
                                                         well-being and hearing health!






                                                         Your Hearing is a valuable asset,
                   Hear Better… Live Better
                                                   make a Hearing assessment part of your
                   204.727.4327                                annual health check up!                                204.725.5151

                                                        Call to schedule an appointment!
               42 McTavish Avenue, Brandon, MB                                                                   305 – 18th Street North, Brandon, MB
                  brandonadvancedhearing.ca                                                                            stokeshearingclinic.ca]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[34                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018


















































        Performers cast shadows on a screen during a dress rehearsal for a presentation of Out of the Shadows. The performance took place at the Western Manitoba Centennial Auditorium.  (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
        Great performances a part of the show at the WMCA





        BRANDON’S PREMIER

        STAGE LOOKS TO EXPAND ITS

        QUALITY ENTERTAINMENT


           The Western Manitoba Centennial Au-
        ditorium has been providing entertainment
        to the  citizens  of  Westman  for 50 years
        Each year they host five or six events and
        partner with promoters to bring other acts
        to the facility, throughout the course of the
        year.
           This fall, they’re going to be bringing in
        two artists from Manitoba, William Prince
        and Rayannah, said general manager, Franz
        Lehrbass.
           Their goal is to bring artists to the com-
        munity that people might otherwise not
        have  the  privilege  of  watching  perform.
        William Prince and Rayannah will per-
        form on October 27 for the series opening
        concert..
           “It’s occurred to us for a while that
        there’s a lot of talent in Manitoba,” Leh-
        rbass said. “People in Brandon can get ac-
        cess to the Brandon talent, but there’s a lot
        of talent centred in Winnipeg that we don’t
        » Continued on Page 36               Dancers celebrate the Chinese New Year with a performance at the Western Manitoba Centennial Auditorium. (Michael Lee/The Brandon Sun)]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[36                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018
















































        The cast and crew of Cabaret meet in the basement of the Western Manitoba Centennial Auditorium prior to the curtain raising on the 7 Ages Productions. (File)

        » Continued from Page 34             buying a show and selling and marketing
                                             it. Back in 2009, they partnered with Dau-
        get access to, they might be going all over   phin’s Countryfest to present country art-
        the place, Toronto, Calgary, Vancouver, to   ist Terri Clark. Since then, they’ve learned
        perform, but they’re not necessarily coming   and grown, Lehrbass said, and they now   Something for Everyone!
        to Brandon. It’s just sort of pulling those   present the five or six events each year. This
        folks out from Winnipeg to Brandon for   gives them a couple of advantages. “We are
        a day.”                              able to bring some shows to Brandon that
           Prince is a young Anishinaabe singer   might otherwise just not come here,” he   Weekly Entertainment & Daily Specials
        and songwriter from Peguis First Nation.   said. Also, if they’re able to do this well,
        In 2017, he won a Juno Award for Con-  there’s the opportunity to make a little bit
        temporary Roots Album of the Year. Leh-  extra money over the course of the year,   in Georgie’s Lounge
        rbass said he’s looking forward to hearing   which is good for their operating budget,
        Prince perform at the auditorium, because   he said.
        of his authenticity.  He will be performing   “We’re working really hard here, but we
        his own original songs on stage.     are quite under-funded, he said.”
           Rayannah,  who  will  also  be perform-  Their goal is to expand on the amount                     Great Selection
        ing, blends noise  into music by running   of quality entertainment coming to Bran-
        her voice, breath, synth and percussion   don, he said. The Western Manitoba Cen-                    of Coolers & Cold Beverages in the
        through loop pedals.                 tennial Auditorium is located at 205 20th
           “I was immediately drawn to her cre-  St. in Brandon.                                          Keystone Beer Store’s Well-Lit Location
        ative musicianship  — technically sophisti-  From October 18 to October 20, the au-
        cated and sonically intimate – and started   ditorium will be presenting the broadway
        looking for an opportunity to include her   musical, “Newsies”. The musical is about a
        in our series,” he said.             group of underdogs who come together to   Gondola Pizza
           The auditorium launched their first ever   take on the most powerful people in New
        performance series this year.        York to fight for what they believe in.      for Delivery, Pick-up or to enjoy
           “In presenting a series of events, we can   Brett Kissel will be coming to the audi-  in Georgie’s Lounge
        target the interests, priorities, and passions   torium on Nov. 2 for his “We Were That
        of different groups of people. We can draw   Song” tour.                        Order online at dashdelivers.ca
        more of the community to the  WMCA     The Western Manitoba Centennial Au-
        and achieve a broader and deeper impact in   ditorium is all about bringing people who
        the lives of the citizens of Western Mani-  live in the community of Brandon or in the
        toba,” he said.                      surrounding areas, some good, quality en-                      1050 - 18th Street
           Ever since 2009, the auditorium has   tertainment.                                           across from the Keystone Centre
        been  presenting  events  —  which  means                                                            204-728-6620
        that  the  venue  takes  on  the  full  risk  of   » The Brandon Sun                            www.keystonemotorinn.ca     Please drink responsibly.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2018 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           37













































        Colby Pilling leaps in the air during a song while playing Cosmo Brown during the dress rehearsal for École secondaire Neelin High Schoolís production of Singing in the Rain at the Western Manitoba Centennial
        Auditorium (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[38                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018





























































        Dr. Scott Mather and Dr Nathan Vercaigne at Brightside Dental clinic. (Theresa Nett/The Brandon Sun)
        Look to Brightside for modern dental philosophy





           When was the last time you took a trip  ers. They want their patients to know that  large fillings have been proven to crack  planning is key.  Cavities and dental prob-
        to the dentist? If the answer is “when I had  from the moment they walk through the  teeth over time and that crowns are a bet-  lems don’t go away.  They only get worse
        a horrible toothache” or “only when I have  door, they’re going to have a different kind  ter  option.  Is placing a large filling still an  over time – and become more expensive -
        to,” perhaps its time to look at the Bright-  of dental experience — one that replaces  option? You bet, but it’s not the best long  if left untreated.” said Mather.
        side of dental care.                 reactive dentistry techniques with a more  term solution.” Dr. Mather said.  “Planning is especially important for pa-
           Dr. Scott Mather and his partner Dr.  proactive philosphy.               Advances in technology have also im-  tients to do before they retire.  All of a sud-
        Larry Cogar created Brightside Dental   “A big paradigm shift is happening in  proved options for better care for patients.   den your insurance coverage has changed
        Care together in 2008, and since then have  dentistry, to everyone understanding the  For example, Brightside  Dental was the  and you may not have the same financial
        expanded to four dental clinics in Brandon,  benefits of longer term care,” Dr. Scott  first clinic in Brandon to offer same day  means. I want my patients to be educated
        Shilo, Portage, and Gladstone. Brightside  Mather said. “It’s really a shift from being  crowns.  Instead of messy impressions and  about the condition of their mouths and if
        clinics  have a  modern, cozy  design, with  reactive to proactive — proactively treating  two  or more  trips  to the  dentist,  Cerec  they wish to have their natural teeth for a
        large comfortable chairs. As the company  your teeth before they give you pain.”  technology allows Brightside to provide a  lifetime, there are steps to be taken to get
        notes on its website, Brightside has made   Dr. Mather, who oversees the Brandon  quick turnaround for crowns — the process  there, and we can help them achieve that
        it their priority to understand the concerns  and Shilo locations, keeps his patients well  takes about two hours - and alleviates a lot  goal”.
        of real patients so that they can make the  informed about the best treatments avail-  of concern and stress for the patient.  And that philosophy is what drives not
        entire experience as simple and enjoyable  able, and recommends the ones that will   Brightside’s proactive philosophy helps  only  Drs.  Mather  and Cogar, but  all the
        as possible.  “We want our patients to come  benefit them in the long term.  “Dentist-  patients understand and realize their per-  talented dentists at Brightside.
        in and not even feel like they are in a dental  ry has changed a lot over the years, as new  sonal dental goals.  Proactive dental care   If you would like to book an appoint-
        clinic,” said Dr. Mather.            studies and practices provide better ways to  starts  with  regular  check-ups and  clean-  ment with Brightside  Dental Care in
           Over the course of their careers, Drs.  help patients look and feel their best.  For  ings, extends to better treatment options,  Brandon, call (204) 727-7136, or visit their
        Mather and Cogar have built their prac-  example, studies have shown that the use  and goes one step further, by focusing on  clinic at 25-144 Sixth Street. For their oth-
        tices on personal relationships and the  of fillings to repair large cavities is not a  providing patients with the opportunity  er locations, visitbrightsidedentalcare.com
        happy, healthy smiles of satisfied custom-  permanent solution.  We now know that  to keep their teeth for a lifetime.  “Proper  » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[NOW




                                                                                                                            OFFERING

                                                                                                                             DENTURE
                      Brightsidedentalcare.com
                                                                                                                              SERVICE!








                                                                                                                                       30+ Years
                                                                                                                                       Experience





                      Brightside Dental Care


                      @brightsidedentalcare                                Dr. Scott Mather,   Dr. Lauren Davies,  Dr. Nathan Vercaigne,  Drew Trapp,
                                                                               Dentist            Dentist            Dentist           Denturist
                                                                                     Great locations to choose from!

            Here at Brightside we take a “real-people”
            approach to dentistry.Our practices were                                               #25-144 6th St. -204-727-7136
            built on personal relationships and the happy
            healthy smiles of satisfied patients. We want                                                                        BRANDON
            you to know, from the moment you walk
            through the door, that this is going to be a                           44 Tupper St. N
            different kind of dental experience.                             PORTAGE LA PRAIRIE

            Call to book your new                                                    24 Mill Street

            patient exam today!                                                       GLADSTONE

                                                                                      Canex Mall
                                                                                            SHILO







                                                                                  Let’s talk about Cerec Crowns


                                                                                  l Cerecs CAD-CAM technology shortens the
                                                                                     time it takes to get a crown from weeks to hours.
                                                                                  l No bulky uncomfortable impressions
                                                                                  l No temporary crown for several weeks while the
                                                                                     permanent crown is being made in a laboratory
                                                                                  l No need for a second appointment!]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[40                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018
































































        Tech Olaf Juechter replaces camshaft bearings on a semi truck in the Beaver Truck Centre at the corner of First Street and the Trans-Canada Highway. (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)
        Beaver Truck Centre offers customers




        state-of-the-art, affordable services







           Since 2015, husband and wife team Pat and Marie  spacious. With a wide variety parts on display and Vol-  1996 and felt that opening a second location in Brandon,
        Southall have been running Beaver Truck Centre in Bran-  vo trained technicians, the staff at Beaver is ready to keep  would benefit our large customer base in Brandon and the
        don.                                             their customers on the road.                     surrounding Westman area. The Brandon location is lo-
           “It was pretty exciting to be given the opportunity to   Pat worked his way up the ranks in the company, start-  cated at the Northeast corner of the Trans-Canada High-
        run your own store,” Pat said.                   ing in 1998 working as a mechanic. The company provid-  way and Highway 10.
           The centre offers parts, service, new and used truck in-  ed lots of opportunity for advancement, which Pat took   The state of the art facility is 16,000 square feet, with
        ventory, all at an affordable price.             advantage of, from being a service advisor, warranty ad-  10 service bays, and an extensive line of parts inventory.
           “People are often hesitant of dealerships because they  ministrator and assistant service manager. All of the dif-  They have both new and used Volvo trucks for sale, as well
        think they’re going to pay too much. Being fair is one of  ferent roles that he took on over the years made him well  as a variety of other makes of pre-owned trucks.  Volvo
        the many things that our company has worked hard at over  suited for his current position as Branch Manager of the  has come out with some new models that they recently
        the past 20 years.” Pat said. “Both Beaver Truck Centre  Brandon location.                        launched like the VNR and VNX, with a different body
        locations pride themselves on offering superior custom-  “The company has a great atmosphere at both loca-  style than some previous models offering an improved
        er service, which is why we ensure that we have trained  tions, which is one of the many things I enjoy about Beaver  level of safety, comfort, style and fuel economy that our
        knowledgeable and friendly staff.”               Truck Centre,” Pat said.
           Inside  the state  of the  art building, it’s bright  and   Beaver Truck Centre in Winnipeg has been open since   » Continued on Page 42]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[“LEAVE IT TO BEAVER FOR ALL YOUR TRUCKING NEEDS”


























































              125 Middleton Ave. East                                                                             204.571.9100


              1st St. North & #1 Hwy                                                                    www.beavertrucks.com]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[42                                                                                     THE BRANDON SUN • WESTMAN BUSINESS • OCTOBER 2018


                                                                                                                   » Continued from Page 40
                                                                                                                   customers are accustomed to.
                                                                                                                     The couple both said that their favourite
                                                                                                                   part of running Beaver Truck Centre in Bran-
                                                                                                                   don is being able to help the customers.
                                                                                                                     “It’s usually not a pleasant experience to
                                                                                                                   have a break down, so we do everything that
                                                                                                                   we can to be fair and make it go as easily as we
                                                                                                                   can for the customer,” Pat said.
                                                                                                                     “When customers come in experiencing an
                                                                                                                   unpleasant situation and then leave smiling and
                                                                                                                   happy, then that means we have done our job.”
                                                                                                                     Besides great customer service Beaver Truck
                                                                                                                   Centre is also able to provide OEM and af-
                                                                                                                   termarket parts at a very competitive price.
                                                                                                                   “Everyone is looking to make the most of their
                                                                                                                   hard earned money, and that goes for any in-
                                                                                                                   dustry.”
                                                                                                                     Offering great customer service on all levels,
                                                                                                                   means people will come back again.  “People
                                                                                                                   put a lot of money, time and effort into social
                                                                                                                   media, but still the best form of advertising is
                                                                                                                   going to be word of mouth,” Marie said. “If we
                                                                                                                   can have customers leave here with a good ex-
                                                                                                                   perience, they will share their experience and
                                                                                                                   that’s what’s going to bring people in.”
                                                                                                                     If you haven’t had the chance to stop by the
                                                                                                                   new Brandon location, please stop by and meet
                                                                                                                   their friendly staff, have a tour of their state of
                                                                                                                   the art facility, check out the sales inventory
                                                                                                                   and of course have a coffee.
         Tech John Banman takes a moment to smile while standing under a truck axle performing differential oil change at the Beaver Truck Centre at the corner of   “We can’t wait to meet you!”
         First Street and the Trans-Canada Highway. (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)                                 » The Brandon Sun


















                      2 FULL-SIZE


           SUNROOMS ON DISPLAY!

                     • FREE ESTIMATES •




                    We specialize in building quality
                  sunrooms and patios designed to fit
                    your budget and your lifestyle.
                   Your sunroom will be custom built for you.
                   MAINTENANCE-FREE Sunspace Railings
                   Available In A Variety Of Styles & Colours.
                  Foundations to finishing – we do it all!




                      1840 - 18th St N                           204-726-8488                               www.sunspacesunrooms.com

                in the Windsor Plywood building            email : sales@elitesunrooms.ca                        www.elitesunrooms.ca]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[OCTOBER 2018 • WESTMAN BUSINESS • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                           43
        Victoria Landing is all about senior care







                                                                                                               Everyone experiences the natural process of aging
                                                                                                             in different ways. Some folks might remain active and
                                                                                                             independent, yet over time, they might find that they
                                                                                                             could benefit from assisted living while remaining still
                                                                                                             very active in their community. Others might find
                                                                                                             themselves needing greater assistance within a secure
                                                                                                             living space, particularly if their health or memory is
                                                                                                             declining.
                                                                                                               “We  are  an Aging-In-Place  community,”  said
                                                                                                             Claudia Nohr the Executive Director of Brandon’s
                                                                                                             Victoria Landing Retirement Residence. “We supply
                                                                                                             our residents with the daily support they need to con-
                                                                                                             tinue an active, healthy, independent lifestyle.”
                                                                                                               Age-in-Place living is the philosophy that allows
                                                                                                             residents to remain at this lovely residence through-
                                                                                                             out the years as needs change. The team at All Seniors
                                                                                                             Care is committed to ensuring the highest quality of
                                                                                                             life for our residents. Designed to enhance daily en-
                                                                                                             joyment and well-being on a continuous basis, the ex-
                                                                                                             clusive QOLA program provides the All Seniors Care
                                                                                                             team with the ability to learn about resident’s specific
                                                                                                             needs and individual preferences.
                                                                                                               Prior to moving in each resident is consulted on
                                                                                                             dietary wishes, medical needs, recreational, and phys-
                                                                                                             ical activity preferences. After all the information is
                                                                                                             consolidated a personal profile is created and specif-
                                                                                                             ic programming developed. Families can feel assured
                                                                                                             that their loved one’s needs are met daily in a holistic
                                                                                                             approach including mind, body, and soul.
                                                                                                               “Victoria Landing is all about taking care of seniors
                                                                                                             and providing them with a good quality of life in a
                                                                                                             setting that’s been designed to adapt to their changing
                                                                                                             needs and allow them to age in place gracefully,” con-
                                                                                                             tinues Nohr, “we have created a secure living area that
                                                                                                             exceeds expectations for support.  Whether helping
                                                                                                             new residents adjust, assisting with personal grooming
                                                                                                             or going for a walk, staff members are committed to
                                                                                                             providing a supportive family environment.”
                                                                                                               Adding to the ease, dedicated staff members take
                                                                                                             care of light housekeeping duties, provide emergen-
                                                                                                             cy response and organize fun activities, both on site
                                                                                                             and off. “Our person-centred philosophy allows us to
                                                                                                             identify each resident’s unique attributes, values and
                                                                                                             history,” Nohr explains, “enabling us to create indi-
                                                                                                             vidualized levels of programming that are flexible to
                                                                                                             changing health needs.”
                                                                                                               Enhancing the experience, residents can take ad-
                                                                                                             vantage of on-site amenities, including fitness centre,
                                                                                                             games room, salon, a theatre and even private dining
                                                                                                             room for special family celebrations. Perhaps best of
                                                                                                             all, couples with different care needs can remain to-
                                                                                                             gether in an environment that allows them to age with
                                                                                                             grace.
                                                                                                               “Victoria Landing is a safe, beautiful neighbour-
                                                                                                             hood that offers seniors gracious living while provid-
                                                                                                             ing peace of mind for families,” closes Nohr. “They
                                                                                                             know their loved ones are looked after in a beautiful
                                                                                                             building that offers a vibrant and creative lifestyle
                                                                                                             within peaceful, elegant surroundings. We feel there is
                                                                                                             nothing else like it.”
                                                                                                               For more information, call 204-271-6000 or drop
                                                                                                             by for coffee and a visit at 10 Victoria Ave. E. (right
                                                                                                             beside the Brandon Regional Health Centre). Details
                                                                                                             are also posted on the All Seniors Care website at
                                                                                                             allseniorscare.com.
        Victoria Landing Retirement Residence Exective Director Claudia Nohr and the new Lifestlye Director Jillian Garbutt. (Theresa Nett/The Brandon Sun)  » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>