<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="40"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[HomeWay

                                                    YOUR








          YOUR
                                                    Improving your Space: Inside and Out

















































                2018 Special Supplement




                                THE ONE THAT STARTED IT ALL!                           Voted one of
                                                                                      Brandon’s best
                                       SAVING YOU MORE                             Home Furnishings store

                               SAVE $600      %                          SAVE $530      %
                               Bella Eurotop  60OFF +                    Cresent Eurotop  50OFF  +
                               Pocket Coil Queen                         Pocket Coil Queen
                               Mattress Set  All Sizes                               All Sizes
                               Reg. 999.97  BELLAFQP                     Mattress Set
                                                                         Reg. 1059.97  CRSENTQP
                                   QUEEN                                    QUEEN
                                   SET                                       SET
                                  399                                      529
                                 $                                        $
                                  After Discount                    FOAM ENCASED  After Discount              FOAM ENCASED
                                                                    POCKET COIL                               POCKET COIL
         1858 - 18th Street North  |  Brandon  |  204-726-9225  |  www.thebrick.com  |  Locally owned and operated]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Wayne Pascoe with Weed Man spreads fertilizer pellets on a yard in the the west end
     of Brandon. (File)
         Going green on                                              SHOWROOM LOCATED AT:


                                                                 1325 PRINCESS AVE. UNIT B
     the inside and out                                                        CALL FOR YOUR

                                                                      PERSONALIZED SHOWROOM OR
     BY IAN FROESE
                                                                         IN- HOME CONSULTATION!
       Whether you flex your green thumb on your lawn or inside a cli-
     mate-controlled residence, regular maintenance is nothing to slouch
     at.
       “Your lawn is just like your body,” said David Hinton, the
     owner/operator of Weed Man in Brandon. “If you want to get in                        Anita
     great shape, you need to do regular, ongoing physical fitness.”                      Haigh
       Hinton said his phone would be ringing once those pesky dan-                             brandon
     delions begin sprouting on Westman lawns, but he said the weed is                          724.7791
     not the problem itself but is the symptom of a larger issue.
       Without proper fertilization, aeration and watering, a lawn suf-
     fers.
       “If you don’t do anything, that’s when the turf thins out and the
     weeds take right over.”
                                                                                          blindsbyanita.com
     » Continued on Page 4]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018

     Mowing your lawn too short can damage the turf



     » Continued from Page 3

       He said the  “most frequent
     sin” people commit is mowing
     their grass too short. Grass
     should be cut at 2.5 or three
     inches, usually the highest set-
     ting on your mower, he said.
     “The turf will be stronger.”
       Hinton also encourages wa-
     tering the lawn during dry peri-
     ods and utilizing a good
     fertilizer. At Weed Man, a slow-
     release granular fertilizer is em-
     ployed.                                                                            Cranesbills, or hardy geraniums, have
       The small pellets break down                                                     been gaining in popularity over the past
     gradually, feeding the lawn over                                                   decade. Geraniums will tolerate a lot of
     time.                                                                              abuse. (File)
       A single application lasts 120  Here are a few tips:  have frilly foliage and, depend-
     days in the soil.                                       ing on the variety, their leaves  pearance belies its tough-as-
                                                                                        nails constitution.  This is a
       Hinton explained that a                               carry aromas such as chocolate,
     healthy lawn takes work.    THE WAYS HOUSEPLANTS        rose or lemon. If in doubt about  water plant, closely related to
       “What we always try to stress ARE ABUSED              whether a geranium is thirsty,  papyrus, so it cannot tolerate
     is to do a little bit all the time,”  Poor light is not the only  don’t water.     drying out. But watering cype-
                                                                                        rus is a no-brainer; just set the
     he said.                    abuse you might suffer upon a  Cyperus is a houseplant
       More people are hearing the  houseplant. Many people forget  whose especially graceful ap-  pot in a deep saucer that you al-
     message, said Hinton, who took  to water them, or they water                       ways keep filled with water.
     over the Brandon franchise a  them too much.
     decade ago.                   Also, as plants grow, they need
       “If you go by the garden cen-  to be divided and repotted, or
     tres, or even the home improve-  shifted to larger pots. A house-
     ment stores, everybody’s got a  plant should not grow so fast  Let us help you build
     huge garden centre attached to  that frequent repotting is neces-
     it now.”                    sary.                                   your backyard oasis!
       “It’s more and more options
     all the time on different plants,  SOME HOUSEPLANTS
     different furniture and firepits,”
     he continued.               TOLERATE ABUSE
       “I think when we have such  Yes, there are plants that can
     short summers here in Mani-  survive, and even look perky,
     toba, people really love to be  with little light, neglectful or ex-
     outside when they can.”     cessive watering, and little other
       Growing plants doesn’t need  care. And they’re not all cacti.
     to be solely an outdoors pursuit.  Take dumbcane and spider
       Even if you’re horticulturally  plant, for instance. Both are hard
     impaired, you can take heart:  to kill, yet keep up appearances
     there are houseplants even you  with little attention. Spider
     can grow.                   plant can fill its pot rapidly and
       You’ll have to forgo colour if  send out new “babies” all over
     you require a truly tough house-  the place, but that’s only with
     plant.                      good growing conditions.
       Flowering takes too much of  For best results, grow an all-
     a plant’s energy, which comes  green variety of spider plant,                         Quality Pool &
     from good (or at least reasonably  rather than one with white                         Hot Tub Sevice & Installation
     good) growing conditions, in-  stripes in its leaves. All green                       • 20 Years Experience
     cluding abundant light. Don’t  spider plants, with more chloro-                       • Weekly & Monthly Maintenance
     look for colour in leaves either,  phyll, tolerate low light better.                  • Serving Westman & Area
     because plants with colourful  Geraniums also tolerate an
     leaves have them only when  amazing amount of abuse. They
     there’s plenty of light so that  won’t flower under these condi-  1514 Rideau St., Brandon
     they can do more with less  tions, so in that case why not  thepooldoctor@mymts.net • www.thepooldr.org
     green.                      grow scented geraniums? Many           204.573.8014                CANADIAN MADE]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Customized
                                                                   RTM Homes to
                                                                 suit your needs!


                                                                          RTM Packages
                                                                      starting at  109,900
                                                                                          $























     Think of succulents as the new African violets. They thrive indoors or out. Succu-
     lents are easy to deal with, are resistant to disease and thrive in the dry humidity
     common inside homes in winter. (Associated Press)
     SUCCULENTS
       Succulent plants — which include but are not limited to cacti —
     are obvious houseplant candidates for non-gardeners. If you’ve killed
     them in the past, it was probably because of too much water, a sit-
     uation easily avoided if, when you first get the plant, you repot it  Save Build Time
     with an equal volume of perlite or sand mixed into the potting soil.
     The perlite or sand lets water run right through the mix, making it  We can work on your foundation
     impossible to overwater. Alternatively, repot the plant in potting  and RTM simultaneously, which
     mix formulated especially for succulents.                        reduces time to build.
       Succulents present an amazing array of shapes and textures of
     greenery. In that well-drained potting mix, it would be almost im-  Affordable
     possible to kill an aloe plant. Its leaves remain soft, fleshy and
     smooth, just as if you’ve been lavishing it with care.           We work within your budget
       Kalanchoe hardly looks like a desert plant, yet it survives neglect
     in proper style.                                                 Custom Designed
       The same could be said for burro’s tail, ideal for hanging baskets  We make your dreams become
     with its ropy stems swathed in fat leaves.                       reality. Design your own floor plan
       Jade plants respond to good conditions by growing rapidly and
     flowering, but they look almost the same when grown in utter neg-  with our in-house draftsman,choose
     lect. Grow this succulent as a bush or a small tree. When the plant  your own finishes and much more!
     grows too large for your likes or its pot, it’ll get along fine for a long
     time with its stems just trimmed back to whatever size you want,
     rather than needing to be repotted.                       SOUTH END LUMBER LTD.
       You would think that plants called living stones would be tough
     houseplants — and they are. They do look like stones, however, so  We’re Your Total Project Supply Store
     they might not satisfy the seasonal urge for lush greenery.
       Then again, if you just need some kind of garden experience this
     time of year, you don’t need greenery.
       Get a decorative tray and emulate in miniature the famous Zen
     landscape at Ryoan-ji in Kyoto, Japan; it consists of a rectangular
     plot of neatly raked quartz sand surrounding artistically clustered  FREE ESTIMATES         204-728-1570
     groups of rocks.
                                                                                    Toll-Free: 1-866-728-1570 • Fax: 204-571-1200
                                                                         1550 – 13th St • Brandon • One block south of Richmond Ave.
     » ifroese@brandonsun.com, with files from the Associated Press              info@seltimbermart.ca • www.setimbermart.ca
     » Twitter: @ianfroese]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[6                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018



























                                                                                          Pulling of a monochromatic colour
                                                                                          scheme such as white can be a dan-
                                                                                          gerous proposition. If it’s done cor-
                                                                                          rectly however, the results can be
                                                                                          incredible.
        WHITE HOT INTERIOR DESIGN TIPS TO GET THE PERFECT LOOK


       It's a hard scheme to pull off,  knubby, sleek, watery, shimmery,  room. So for those of you eyeing  Crispin Butterfield
     but when it's done right, a white,  organic, leathery, woody, knotty,  the cotton duck sofa or pearly
     monochromatic space can look  and cozy for a warm and invit-  cashmere pillows... perhaps it
     stunning! It takes thoughtful  ing atmosphere... vital again  might be wise to consider a
     planning, integration of texture  when trying to avoid stark and  slightly warmer or darker op-
     and perfect undertones, smart  cold design.             tion.
     fabric choices … not exactly an                           I love beautiful looking
     easy feat to pull off, but if you're  THE PERFECT WHITES  spaces, but it's not all that fair to
     brave enough to take the plunge,  I have a go-to white I use in  constantly be hawking and
     here are a few things you need  almost all of my spaces that re-  keeping your kids out of any
     to know to make your spaces  quire a soft, pure shade: OC-65  space in your home for the sake  DESIGN LIFE
     sizzle in white...                                      of its design integrity. Some-
                                 Chantilly Lace by Benjamin
                                 Moore is a design favorite across  thing to definitely consider... de-  Featured in Style At Home Maga-
     TONE ON TONE                the board, and it's no secret why.  cide on warmer and more  zine, Covet, Canadian Retailer, and
       The ultimate rule of doing a  When paired with other colours  texturized pieces (so wear and  The National Post; Crispin Butter-
     white room: Layer. Use varying  it still retains its 'whiteness',  tear over time is camouflaged  field owns Urban Theory Design,
     shades of white, cream, plat-  while melding softly into the  best), or wait until university!  Brandon’s premiere design firm.
     inum, pearl, and linen. If you  colour scheme. When used in                         » urbantheoryinteriordesign.com
     don't layer your white tones, you  contrast with other finishes, COMMIT
     may end up with a hospital  OC-60 will act as the perfect  You can't pull this look off if
     room for a living space. Rooms  backdrop. Another few favorites  you only go half way with it...
     that lack dimension in the form  you'll often see in magazines are:  otherwise you might end up
     of tone-on-tone layering often  OC-17 White Dove (Benjamin  with a confusing mess of a
     feel stark, harsh, and institu-  Moore), Swiss Coffee 1812  colour scheme. If you want to
     tional - so unless you're aiming  (Behr),  Powderface  CLW  add some pops of colour here
     for an ultra-pure and minimal  1034W (General Paint), and  and there absolutely do so, but  I once test-painted a large
     aesthetic, don't get too matchy  Antique  White (CIL RM  stick to the 80:20 ratio: 80 per  blob of off-white paint over the
     with your materials and finishes.  43YY 78/053).        cent white and tones of white,  a living room wall colour just to
                                                             and 20 per cent accent colour(s).  see if I could handle the  change
     TEXTURES                    NOT EXACTLY KID             Take the white throughout for  from dark to light. It's a major
       Crucial in almost every envi-  FRIENDLY               walls, furniture, drapes, and  jump to instantly go from what
                                                                                        you’ve been comfortable with.
     ronment (not just the white   Sadly, there is a catch 22.  maybe even flooring if you’re  Design tip:  paint a few test
     ones), texture is a perfect way to  Children - as loveable and  feeling brave, but you can then  patches and see them at differ-
     add depth and interest to your  adorable as they are - do not  add in a hit of colour with the  ent times of the day first, then
     monochromatic palette. Play up  make great low-maintenance  odd pillow, frame, throw, lamp  commit — Sometimes you just
     combinations of glossy, ruddy,                          shade, or small decor item.
                                 accessories to the all-white                           have to dive right in!]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[SWIM SPAS

                                                                                    • Year round fitness
                                                                                    • Enjoy hot tub & pool
                                                                                      benefits in one!

                                                                                    • Self Cleaning
                                                                                    • Better investment
                                                                                    • Only a fraction of the
                                                                                      cost of a pool
                                                                                                 $
                                                                                    • As low as  120/month



                                                   WE’VE GOT THE BEST


          Relax… PRICES – SELECTION – SERVICE




               8 Person

               Hot Tubs

                STARTING AT
              $ 55/month





           SLEEP BETTER

           • Spend Quality Time
             with Family & Friends
           • Soak Away Stress
           • Rid Yourself of Aches
             & Strains






                                                          FREE DELIVERY & SET-UP                       *

                                                                                   *Some restrictions apply
                 Creasy Hot Tubs


                        & Billiards                                      The Most Inexpensive



                   2500 Park Avenue • Brandon, MB                       Hot Tubs In The World.
                    204-729-8827 or 1-877-241-9580                              Let Creasy’s Show You
        www.jacuzzimanitoba.ca  •  www.facebook.com/jacuzzimanitoba             The Jacuzzi Difference.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018










































     A section of Rona's  3,000 square-foot display area is seen, including one of its kitchen options.(Submitted)
         THE KITCHEN IS THE HEART OF THE HOME



     BY IAN FROESE                    Norosky added that granite re-
                                    mains a leading choice for counter
       More and more homeowners are  top material, while wood is making
     treating their kitchen as an gather-  a comeback.
     ing place.                       A recent innovation, waterfall
       “People gravitate to the kitchen,”  countertops is making waves. Unlike
     said Michelle Jacobson, a design  a traditional counter top, the hori-
     consultant with Brandon RONA.  zontal surface doesn’t stop at the
     “People are starting to realize that it  edge, but curves toward the floor.
     can be more artistic.”           To keep these pristine counter
       Homeowners are opting to spruce  tops clutter-free, people are seeking
     up where they cook meals with a  creative storage solutions like deep
     modern ambience.               drawers to hide garbage and recy-
       Flat-panel cabinet doors and  clables.
     wood textures are popular choices,  “A lot of people want out of sight,
     she said.                      out of mind,” he said.
       “Putting money into your kitchen  While often coloured in an
     or into your bathroom is definitely  earthly tone, cabinets aren’t as
     putting equity into your home.”   cookie-cuttered as they once were,
       These days, people are incorporat-  Norosky said.
     ing a heaping of colour into their  Consumer choice is one explana-
     kitchen through two- or three-toned  tion.
     colour schemes, explained Scott  “You can have the same colour
     Norosky, owner/operator at South  cabinet but then have a dozen dif-
     End Lumber in Brandon, which in-  ferent (types of) doors,” he said.
     stalls cabinets and counter tops.  “The combinations are endless.”
       “White cabinets for the majority
     and then a darker colour for the is-  » ifroese@brandonsun.com
     land, that’s really popular.”  » Twitter: @ianfroese                        MICHELLE JACOBSON]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[GRILLS | SMOKERS | FLAME TABLES | AIR CONITIONERS



                                                WE HAVE
                                                WE HAVE
                                                WE HAVE                                 Patio Flame Tables
                                                                                        by
                                           EVERYTHING
                                           EVERYTHING
                                           EVERYTHING                                    Choose style & colour


                                                      YOU
                                                      YOU
                                                      YOU

                                               NEED FOR
                                               NEED FOR
                                               NEED FOR





                     GRILLIN’






                                                      AND








































                  204-728-5900                                                               RAY POOLE
       945 – 24 St., Brandon
                   th
                                                                                             4 Canadian Products
               www.raysﬁreplaces.com
                                                                                             4 WETT Certiﬁed]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10                                                      THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018










































     Families are choosing to use pools and hot tubs as a centerpiece to their backyard, according to Paul Smith with The Pool Doctor in Brandon.

                 INVESTING IN THAT BACKYARD OASIS


     BY IAN FROESE               be just a wood panel.”      for approximately five years.  finishes, and even natural brass,
                                   Salt-water pools have become  Akin to an underwater tread-  like Brown Jordan’s classic Kan-
       Luxury may only be a back-  popular for consumers pursuing  mill, swimmers paddle continu-  tan collection.”
     yard away.                  a low maintenance option that’s  ously against a water current in  Casual Living’s features edi-
       Paul Smith with  The Pool  softer on the skin than a tradi-  a swim spa. The machine can  tor, Jennifer Bringle, said deco-
     Doctor said consumers are in-  tional pool saturated in chlorine.  adjust for resistance and water  rative accessories, too, are being
     vesting in their homes as gas  “It’s mostly ease and it’s a lot  temperature. Built like a hot tub,  elevated.
     prices rise and the cost of a cot-  gentler on the skin,” Smith ex-  it’s insulated for winter-use.  “We’re not talking the tiki
     tage becomes out of reach.   plained.                     “They’re pretty neat, “ Creasy  torches and scratchy coir rugs of
       “They find it a lot easier put-  Hot tubs can also be a source  said.            yore,” she said. “Innovations like
     ting the money into their back-  of summer bliss, said Devon  Luxury can take many other  solution-dyed  acrylics,
     yard and having their family  Creasy, general manager of  forms in the outdoors.   polypropylene  weaves  and
     time in their own backyard.”  Creasy Hot Tubs and Billiards.  Think velvet cushions.  Tai-  water-resistant LEDs mean that
       Some families have chosen   His clients are entering the  lored detailing. Rich, soft uphol-  outdoor accessories offer the
     pools as their centerpiece.  Brandon store better educated  stery. Lacquered or carved  same level of on-trend style and
       Above-ground   swimming   than they were years ago. Not  artisan-made furniture. And lots  luxury as their indoor counter-
     holes instead of in-ground pools  only for entertaining, hot tubs  of other high-end elements that  parts.”
     are the way to go for swimmers  are seen as investments in self-  bring the elegance and sophisti-  Barclay Butera, a designer in
     pursuing a cost-effective option,  care. Some models have massag-  cation of a richly finished inte-  Newport Beach, California, has
     said Smith, a pool retailer in  ing  jets  for  therapeutic  rior to a home’s outdoor space.  a collection for Castelle that
     Brandon. He said pools are not  treatments, while the high-heat  “Think fully upholstered sofas  would look equally at home on
     simply plopped onto a yard with  conditions can help with relax-  covered in performance chenille  a city terrace as on a suburban
     no concern over aesthetics. De-  ation and stress relief.  fabric that’s just as soft as tradi-  pool deck.
     signers are paying attention to  For a pool and hot tub in one,  tional chenille,” says Waynette  “I was inspired by this mag-
     the siding. They even draw upon  swim spas offer an appealing  Goodson, editor-in-chief of Ca-  nificent geometric ceiling carv-
     Greek influences in its design.  choice.                sual Living and Exterior Design  ing I saw in an English manor
       “There weren’t many options  “It’s truly like a modern-day  magazines.           years ago,” he said. “I’ve incorpo-
     20 years ago” when it comes to  swimming pool,” Smith said of  “Then there’s Carrara marble  rated this pattern into the fret-
     appearances, he said. “It used to  the product, which Creasy sold  tabletops, Italian volcanic rock  work.”]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[2018 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                              11






































                                                                                             The new party patio includes a
                                                                                             poured concrete bench, teak
                                                                                             furniture and a steel-topped bar
                                                                                             illuminated by cafe lights.
       The collection’s aluminum   Vondom collaborates with in-  on an iron frame given a rich  Brown Jordan’s Suncloth fab-
     frames are hand-cast in sand  ternational designers and archi-  golden glaze.      ric    collection  includes
     using a process that eliminates  tects on high-concept resin  European midcentury mod-  menswear-style houndstooth,
     air pockets, making the material  decor with an edge.  That in-  ern looks are also finding their  tweed and even sweater prints.
     nearly as solid as iron. Frames  cludes Ramon Esteve’s geomet-  way outdoors. For Gloster, Pe-  Elaine Smith, a former jewelry
     accented with artisan-applied  ric Vela collection, which uses  tersen’s chic, minimalist Blow  designer in England, now de-
     brass details cradle deep tailored  LED lighting in the bases, so  side table perches a sliver of teak  signs runway-inspired luxury
     cushions, and the pieces are  seating and tables seem to float  on a smoke, coffee or emerald-  outdoor pillows.
     crisply done in Butera’s signa-  slightly at night, to ethereal ef-  hued ceramic base. And Cecilie  On solution-dyed Sunbrella
     ture navy and white.        fect. Planes and angles create  Manz’s Atmosphere collection  fabric that resists fade or mildew,
       The pieces are made using the  sculptural pieces of art that are  pairs a curvy, powder-coated  she incorporates dressmaker de-
     same techniques as fine interior  also a sun chair, bench and  aluminum frame with a slim  tails like silky fringe, hand-
     furniture, with carefully finished  planter.            teak seat, then pads the sofa and  crafted knots and jewelry
     joinery, hours of hand-finishing,  Also at  Vondom:  Teresa  chair backs in hues like night-  embellishments. Her patterns
     custom detailing and thick,  Sapey’s Adan collection of giant  shade, salmon, quince and  range from jaunty nautical mo-
     high-quality cushions. Charac-  faceted heads has an Easter Is-  lichen.           tifs to animal and tribal prints to
     teristics like these, including the  land vibe. And ultramodern  For those seeking a more tra-  florals.
     use of marine-grade steel and  chairs by designers Eugeni  ditional look, Richard Frinier’s  Sunbrella’s Makers Collection
     durable tropical hardwoods like  Quitllet and Jorge Pensi are  Archipelago collection for Cen-  includes weather-resistant fab-
     Costa Rican teak, are the hall-  cloaked in gleaming gold or sil-  tury features richly carved and  rics that evoke fine wools, hand-
     marks of top-end outdoor fur-  ver, combining avant garde with  stained teak seating and tables  loomed Peruvian cottons or
     nishings.                   elegance.                   that evoke British and Dutch  metallic-thread linens.
       Prices tend to reflect the lux-  Tropitone’s Cabana Club col-  Colonial style.     Other outdoor fabric houses
     ury features. Butera’s three-  lection blends woven, metal and  The new Lilly Pulitzer collec-  are being inspired by antique
     seater sofa lists for around  upholstery elements in roomy,  tion at Pottery Barn includes the  tapestries, quilting or Japanese
     $5,000.                     contemporary seating inspired  designer’s signature preppy-nau-  kimonos. And some are using
       At Gloster, the Cradle out-  by luxe resorts in Bali and the  tical prints on outdoor soft ac-  specialty yarns to create sump-
     door daybed designed by Lon-  Cote d’Azure.             cessories, and crisp, white,  tuous pearlescent or silken tex-
     doner Henrik Pedersen is a    CB2’s new outdoor collection  trellis-patterned planters.  tiles  that  withstand  the
     framed circle of powder-coated  includes Ceci  Thompson’s  Many designers’ patterns dis-  elements.
     aluminum and teak with a thick  French Riviera-inspired ma-  pel the notion that outdoor fur-  » ifroese@brandonsun.com, with
     slab mattress, and retails for  hogany and cabana-striped sofa.  niture should be printed with  files from the Associated Press
     around $13,000.             A daybed poises slim cushions  tropical motifs.        » Twitter: @ianfroese]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[12                                                      THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018


































































     Anita Haigh of Blinds by Anita in her retail showroom at 1325 Princess Avenue. (File)
                 GET THE LIGHT YOU WANT AND NEED



     BY IAN FROESE               nance while on the market for  designs, Haigh explained.  drapery.
                                 window coverings.             “Most times the accessories  The standard cord is being
       While large, expansive win-  “They don’t want anything  are less dollar value, whereas  phased out of blind systems for
     dows let the light in, window  that’s too fussy,” she said.  window coverings are a little bit  reasons of safety (children have
     coverings ensure the glare from  “They’re looking for energy ef-  more of a money investment,”  died from strangulation) and
     any sunlight is kept in modera-  ficiency, privacy and fairly neu-  she said. “People are going to  aesthetics.
     tion.                       tral palates.”              want more longevity.”        Handles or motor mecha-
       Anita Haigh, the owner of   In accessories like rugs, throw  They opt for timeless colours  nisms are the way to go.
     Blinds by Anita based in Bran-  pillows and decorative vases,  like greige, a combination of  “There are no excess cords
     don, said her clients are after a  people are more eager to exper-  beige and grey. They also want  anymore,” Haigh said. “Nothing
     simple design and easy mainte-  iment with unique colours and  blinds that’ll pair well with  is dangling.”]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Everything You Need

                                                                      for Inside & Out!
       Sue Swarbrick, who co-owns the Budget Blinds franchise in
     Brandon, said solar shades are in style.
       The roller shades block some light without blocking your view.
     During the daytime, strangers cannot see through them it the out-        YOU’RE INVITED TO OUR
     side.                                                           HUGE PARKING LOT SALE
       “They’re very crisp,” Swarbrick said. “Not a lot of fuss to clean         MAY 25 & 26
     and they really do solve a problem.”
       An exciting development in window coverings is the growing
     prevalence of voice activation. Using devices like Amazon Echo and
     Google Echo, people can draw their blinds by talking or pressing a
     button on their cell phone or iPad, Swarbrick said.
       Smart home automation is “really hitting mainstream now.”

     » Continued on Page 14




















                                                                  FREE Computerized
                                                                  FREE Computerized
                                                                Deck Design Service
                                                                 Deck Design Service
                                                                Looking for that perfect outdoor area but don’t
                                                                 know where to start? We can show you what
                                                                  your deck will look like, how much material
                                                                  you will need and more. Come in today for
                                                                         a FREE, no-obligation quote!





                                                                            TH
                                                               1840 – 18 STREET NORTH, BRANDON
                                                               204-728-4243
                                                               Fax: 204-727-2619
                                                               Toll-Free: 1-800-224-7506
                                                               www.windsorplywood.com
     Sue Swarbrick of Budget Blinds can ﬁnd the perfect fabric for your next set of  Store Hours: Mon. – Fri. 7:30 am – 6:00 pm;
     drapes. She also said shades that block part of the sun like above are hot right now.   Sat. 9:00 am – 5:00 pm; Closed Sunday]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018




























     Ray Poole from Ray’s Fireplaces in Brandon said the right ﬁreplace can look like ﬁne art in the right space. (Submitted)
     » Continued from Page 13      Table and console lamps are a  TRY NEW ACCESSORIES   too big a commitment, try
                                 great choice because they’re less  All three designers mentioned  painting the back wall inside a
       At Ray’s Fireplaces in Bran-  expensive than ceiling fixtures                    bookcase. Even better, line the
     don, fireplaces come in wood,  and “add a unique cheerfulness  that new throw pillows can eas-  back wall of a bookcase with a
                                                             ily change the look of a living
     gas or electric varieties, while  and a functionality,” Martin says.  room sofa.   high-end wall covering in a rich,
     stoves heated through gas, wood  “They’re stylish and effective.”  “They bring in a pop of  textured fabric, perhaps with a
     and pellet are also available for  Candles can also brighten up  colour and pattern, but don’t  light-catching sheen.
     sale.                       a room and can boost your   overwhelm the space,” Martin
       While the kinds of heating  mood if you choose the right  says. And because they can be PLUNDER YOUR OWN
     instruments may differ, they’re  scent.                 inexpensive, pillows let you take
     alike in their push toward en-                          risks with unexpected colours.  THINGS
     ergy-efficiency.            GET SOME GREENERY             “Sometimes I’ll pick a colour  Items that are getting little at-
       Consider wood fireplaces,                                                        tention in one room can some-
                                   If you flip through decor
     which co-owner Ray Poole say  magazines, Howard says, you’ll  that’s not even in the room, but  times take on new life if you
                                                             somehow it works,” she says,
     can be just as efficient as a wood  see “plants and living things on  “because you’re introducing an  relocate them. Try swapping a
     stove.                      every surface.”             element that kind of adds an  framed piece of art from one
       Design-wise, fireplaces can                                                      room with one from another. Or
                                   He recommends adding a few
     look more like fine art than a  new plants or even  “clipping  imperfection.” easy  accessory:  give a second chance to a framed
                                                               Another
     bulky addition against the wall  something from your backyard  Howard suggests swapping out  item you put away in a closet
     where the fire is crackling.   or from a wooded area near your  the books on your coffee table  years ago.
       No matter the accessory, an                                                        “We never have enough walls
     artful arrangement can make a  house.” Living in Florida,  for new ones with beautifully  for everything we love,” Martin
                                                             designed covers.
                                 Howard often will “clip a palm
     difference in any room of your  and put it in a vase on a con-  “I like to have my coffee table  says.
     home.                       sole,” he says, to brighten up his  full of books,” he says. Buying  Another option: Take smaller
       Here, Florida-based interior                                                     items out of their frames and
     designer Andrew Howard and  home’s entrance when guests are  new ones changes the look a lit-  swap in something else, such as
                                                             tle, leaves you excited about
                                 coming over.
     two other interior design experts  Martin feels the same way  reading something new and  postcards or small prints you’ve
     — Deborah Martin and Jenny  about vases of fresh flowers, and  provides conversation starters  collected but never framed.
     Dina Kirschner, both designers  suggests you don’t wait for  with guests.            When Howard wants to
     based in New York — offer ad-  guests.                                             make a change to a room in his
     vice on small but powerful dec-  To keep costs down, she rec-                      own home, he often searches
     orating moves that can bring  ommends choosing flowers with  EMBRACE BRIGHT COLORS  through items he hasn’t used
     fresh style.                                              In many hotels and restau-  lately. Don’t be afraid, he says, to
                                 a long shelf life and adding  rants while visiting Scotland,  give a second chance to decora-
                                 plenty of less expensive greenery
     WARM UP YOUR LIGHTING       to the vase.                she noticed  “the unapologetic  tive pieces that you once dis-
       Decorative lighting is an ef-  Kirschner agrees that flowers  use of colour — colour every-  missed as outdated.
                                                                                          “Decorating cycles so much
     fective decor pick-me-up, says  and plants, especially in a color-  where.” Even tartan plaid  now,” he says.  “You’re seeing
                                                             throws in neon colours, not nor-
     Martin, because it adds the  ful planter, can change a room.  mally her style, struck her as  trends from so many other years
     warmth and light we’re all crav-  Even a big bowl of citrus fruit  beautiful and mood-boosting.  come back.”
     ing.                        on a dining table or coffee table  Add colour with a bright
       “A lamp in the window when  can bring a hint of spring, with  throw blanket, she suggests, and
     you come home at the end of a  bright colours and fresh scents,  consider painting a focal wall in  » ifroese@brandonsun.com, with
                                                                                        files from the Associated Press
     long day,” she says,  “signals  she says.               a rich, energizing colour. If that’s
     home. It signals cozy.”                                                            » Twitter: @ianfroese]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[SPRING

           CELEBRATION


                    Come see us today!

























                BBQ SEASON IS HERE!                               WE SELL MORE FLAT PANEL
                                                                    TVS THAN ANYONE ELSE!
















                                      STOP IN AND TEST OUT OUR
                                               SOUND ROOMS!















             CUSTOM INSTALLATIONS!                                        BEST BRANDS IN

                HOME, BUSINESS & MOBILE                                       CAR AUDIO!

                                                                 121-17th N Street, Brandon

                                                            (204)728-7743 | 1-855-623-2995
                                                            SHOP ONLINE AT extremeelectronics.ca


                                                           STORE HOURS: MON TO WED 10AM - 7PM | THURS & FRI 9AM - 9PM | SAT & SUN 10AM - 6PM
        Some products are in limited quantities or not available at all locations. Pictures or illustrations may differ from original product on sale. Taxes not included. This promotion may not be combined with any other offer. Some errors may occur, if it’s the case, we apologize and details will be posted in the store.]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[16                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018





















































     This area rug is actually composed of several tiles.(Associated Press)
           GALVANIZE A ROOM WITH THE RIGHT RUG



       There was a time when de-  to life and, with their movement  knots reflecting movement and  graphite background, suggesting
     signers and decorators consid-  and colour, accentuate the other  drama via textural elements.  dawn breaking. An embossing
     ered floor coverings to be  design elements in the space.  Flowers are the theme of artist  technique is applied during the
     background elements in a room.  “There’s something galvaniz-  Bari J. Ackerman’s collection for  tufting process to create a rich,
     Rugs and tile were meant to be  ing” about having art underfoot,  Grandin Road . Her exuberant  tactile pile that highlights the
     practical, not attention-getting.  he says. “It envelops an interior  contemporary paintings lead to  pattern.
       That’s changed. Now, the  in a way that wall-mounted art-  stylish contemporary rugs,  Glass and ceramic tiles are an-
     floor is often one of the   work cannot.”               hand-hooked by artisans.    other good medium for floor art,
     strongest elements in a space.  Stark Carpet has a Brueghel-  New York’s Doris Leslie Blau  with their smooth textures and a
     Today’s wide range of artistic  esque  floral  rug  called  Gallery stocks a Dali-esque col-  range of size possibilities from
     floor designs are often inspired  Botanique; the rich, deep hues of  lection of wool rugs inspired by  tiny mosaics to large slabs.
     by art and nature.          an Old Master’s palette are  the freewheeling expressiveness  “Tile is super-durable, so re-
       “Painterly rugs with evocative  brought to life in softly loomed  of children’s artwork. Each rug is  gardless of design, floors will
     strokes and striking colour com-  wool. Their Sapphire collection  a composition of colorful swoops  look beautiful and withstand
     binations are often the perfect  includes Ether, inspired by  and swaths.           wear and tear for many years,”
     foundation for many of our  American artist Helen Franken-  Turkish rug maker Stepevi  says Alena Capra, a designer in
     room designs,” says Jamie Drake,  thaler’s Abstract Expressionist  pixellates bird-wing imagery,  Fort Lauderdale, Florida. “Thin
     who runs the Drake/Anderson  stain painting. And there’s  which is then loomed into a tex-  tile products can be installed
     design firm in Manhattan with  Peppy, inspired by  Willem de  tural rug in a palette of seven  over existing floor tiles, making
     his colleague, Caleb Anderson.  Kooning’s 1955 work  “Police  hues. On another rug, blossoms  it easier than ever to give floors
     “These rugs help bring a room  Gazette,” with various hand  are rendered in gold against a  a stylish makeover.”]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[2018 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                              17

       Says Italian architect Paola Marella: “Technological
     progress has expanded the range of finishes available
     for ceramic tiles. For example, digital printing ... has
     extended the confines of images beyond the individual
     piece. But screen-printed and hand-printed tiles retain
     their appeal.”
       That appeal is especially apparent when the artist’s
     technique is obvious, as in Ornamenta’s Manifesto
     collection of porcelain tiles screen-printed with ab-
     stract images that were initially rendered free-hand on
     canvas.
       New Ravenna features a Chinoiserie bird-on-
     branch pattern made of marcasite, mica, pewter and
     quartz glass. The design was by artist Sara Baldwin of
     Exmoor, Virginia. Also here is Manhattan artist Gail
     Miller’s moody “Black Pool” painting of deep eddying
     water and a storm-tossed sky, rendered in tiny, hand-
     cut mosaics.
       Settecento’s Animalier collection features python,
     cheetah and leopard-skin prints on large porcelain
     tiles. And Italian company Sicis offers intriguing mo-
     saic collections patterned like realistic feathers or
     lizard skin.
       If you like the look of tile but you rent or can’t oth-
     erwise use the real deal, consider Home Smith’s Beija
     Flor vinyl mats. They come printed with a range of
     patterns like encaustic, mosaic and geometrics; it’s
     flooring that looks like a master craftsman or artist
     spent hours working on it.
                                                  By adding a colourful shag area rug and matching cushions to your existing neutral palette, you’ve
     » The Associated Press                       already got a retro look without buying new furniture. (Canadian Press)]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[18                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018






















































     A crowded hip hop bar during Plant Nite where people learn the craft of terrarium building. (Associated Press)

                    PLANT NITE REPLACES PAINT NITE


       At a crowded, downtown bar  only need a squirt or two of  ing a few years ago, and that’s  to live with little light or water-
     one recent Saturday night, the  water.”                 when I saw these things (terrar-  ing.
     lights were dim, hip-hop music  The two-hour lesson, called  iums) getting popular,” said  Likewise, terrariums have a
     played and most everyone had a  Plant Nite, was part of a pro-  Diandra Escamilla, a 28-year-  devoted following on many so-
     drink in hand.              gram that started in Boston in  old Boston resident who at-  cial media websites, such as Pin-
       The bar itself was covered  2015 and has spread to 32 states  tended Plant Nite. “I was seeing  terest,  Twitter and Facebook,
     with succulents, and the table-  and Canada.            them everywhere, on social  where plant-lovers exchange
     tops with accoutrements like  It’s operated by a company  media — my friends started  pictures, ideas and opinions of
     paintbrushes, plastic spoons and  called Paint Nite that capitalizes  having them, so I started to get  the miniature glass gardens.
     planters of potting soil.   on the do-it-yourself movement  interested.”             The latest terrarium trend
       A good-sized crowd was here  and a clientele willing to pay for  Terrariums are hot. Many  took off in the beginning of the
     to learn the craft of terrarium  an experience — such as a  major retailers — not just gar-  decade, according to Maria Col-
     building.                   primer on building terrariums  dening stores like Home Depot  letti, author of “Terrariums —
       “Now, these succulents are  for your home.            — are selling them. Some   Gardens Under Glass: Design-
     very hard to kill, I promise,” said  These miniature landscapes  IKEA and West Elm stores, for  ing, Creating, and Planting
     Lindsay Webber, the efferves-  are encapsulated in containers  instance, have offered build-  Modern Indoor Gardens” (Cool
     cent 28-year-old instructor of  made of blown glass, ornate clay  your-own kits full of electric-  Springs Press,  2015).
     the class on terrariums. “You’ll  pots or a variety of other mate-  colored rocks, tiny animal  “Everyone thought it would
     only have to water them once  rials.                    figurines, moss and popular suc-  be a phase and even drizzle
     every two weeks or so, and they  “I started getting into garden-  culents — hearty plants adapted  away,” Colletti said.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[2018 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                              19

       That wasn’t the case.
       Colletti, who teaches classes on terrarium building
     through the New York Botanical Garden’s adult educa-
     tion department, said terrariums’ portability and low
     maintenance makes them greenery mainstays that are
     here for the long haul.
       “What could be better for an office or home to have a
     bit of nature where we view our miniature green world
     every day of our lives?” she said. “As our electronic digital
     world’s requirements increase, terrariums remind us of
     the larger wonder of the planet we live on, Earth.”
       Terrariums date back at least to the early 19th century.
       They enjoyed a pop-culture moment in the 1970s, said
     Megan George, author of “Modern Terrarium Studio:
     Design and Build Custom Landscapes with Succulents,
     Air Plants and More” (Fons and Porter, 2015).
       George and her mother own a Durham, North Car-
     olina, plant shop called Zen Succulent, where customers
     can partake in a DIY terrarium bar. Today’s terrariums
     are different, she said.
       “The terrariums in the 1970s were in large globes that
     sat on the floor — they might have a large base to it,”
     George said. “People are living in smaller spaces now and
     they want something that fits on the tabletop; something
     that also functions as decor.”
       For Swetha Ramachandran, 28, of Boston, who at-
     tended Plant Nite, a terrarium’s appeal is simple.
       “They’re cute,” she said, matter-of-factly. “And I like
     the containers they come in.”
     » The Associated Press
































                                                      FARM, RESIDENTIAL & COMMERCIAL

                                                                          PROPERTY APPRAISERS

                                                                         Serving Western Manitoba Since 1977
        Suite 30A, 1015 – 26 Street, Brandon
                                    th
        Fax: 204-727-1563  Email: weir1@mts.net                           204-727-7100]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[20                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018





















































     This boy's room is decorated with space-themed three-dimensional wall decor items.
                     REDESIGN BEFORE SCHOOL’S OUT



       The last weeks of school can  SIMPLE CHOICES          a great way to add personality.  where kids  “might be putting
     be the perfect time to reboot a  In choosing a colour palette,  “We used to do baby colours,  their hands, and where they
     child’s bedroom.            keep it as simple as possible, says  but I think the important thing  might sit,” he says. Even if your
       Ideally, the room should be  Beldock. She suggests limiting  is to do strong, handsome  child is neat, “his friend might
     easy to keep organized and great  the number of colours to create  colours they can live with and  wipe Cheetos all over every-
     for concentrating on homework.  a stylish space that feels orderly.  grow into,” Beldock says.  thing and not think about it.”
     It also needs to be decorated in  Use white paint on walls, she                      Patterns, too, can help hide
     way that’s cheerfully kid-  says, and then bring in just one DURABLE FABRICS       wear and tear. Davin recom-
     friendly and but not too age-  bold accent colour, like red, navy  For those who worry about  mends using a patterned carpet
     specific, so you won’t have to  or magenta, perhaps through a  using a lot of white in a child’s  that’s “forgiving with stains” to
     redecorate too soon.        patterned rug and colorful bed-  room, where it could easily get  add colour and style to a child’s
       We’ve asked three interior de-  ding.                 dirty, Howard notes that out-  room. “By the time they grow
     signers — Brett Beldock of New  Another trendy but timeless  door fabrics and rugs have be-  out of it, it might be time to
     York-based Brett Design Inc.,  option: Use charcoal paint on  come just as pleasant to the  change the carpet anyway,” she
     Florida interior designer An-  the walls with crisp white trim,  touch as indoor items, and  says.
     drew Howard, and Catherine  then add a white-and-charcoal  they’re far more durable. So  She adds that organic cottons
     Davin of Pittsburgh-based   patterned rug, and bring in  light colours can be much more  and other fabrics made without
     Davin Interiors — for some or-  bolder colours through books  easily cleaned than they would  harsh dyes can be durable, and
     ganizing and decorating strate-  and keepsakes displayed on  have been a decade ago.  are becoming more popular with
     gies for children’s rooms.                                                         health-conscious parents.
                                 shelves. Colorful lamps are also  Use outdoor fabrics in places]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[22                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018






























































     Storage becomes critical in small spaces.
     » continued from Page 20      Davin suggests hunting for  capacity, keep one drawer or one  Another small-space strategy:
                                 flea market finds, like old ar-  big bin on a shelf empty for  Howard suggests adding built-
     OPEN AND ORGANIZED          moires or Queen Anne dressers  quick cleanup of clutter.  in storage beneath window seats
                                 offering plenty of space. “You                         or anywhere else there might be
     SPACES                      could paint it bright pink or  SMALL ROOM STRATEGIES   unused space.
       “Don’t over-furnish,” says  shiny black or whatever colour                         For lighting in small rooms,
     Davin, because kids are likely to  you need,” she says.   Large furniture pieces can  wall sconces are great because
     want a big open space to spread  “We never do that ‘matched  make a small room feel smaller,  you don’t have to worry about
     out on. Include only furniture  set of furniture for a child’s  and yet some of them may be  kids knocking lamps over.But
     that’s necessary.           room’ anymore.”             needed. Beldock says one cre-  even in small rooms, Beldock
       And while some open shelv-  Bunk beds with drawers are  ative strategy to keep desks and  suggests investing in a full-size
     ing is great for displaying  also useful, and even young kids  storage units from dominating a  desk. When a child is young, it’s
     favourite items, all three design-  can learn to put away their toys  room is to use transparent,  nice to be able to pull up a sec-
     ers recommend plenty of closed  and clothes in these low draw-  durable Lucite for these large  ond chair at the desk for a tutor
     storage for kids’ rooms. Deep  ers. Remember, says Howard,  pieces. For one design project,  or family member helping with
     drawers, bins with lids and cab-  that you will always need a bit  Beldock created an entire wall of  homework. Once kids get older,
     inets with doors will all help  more storage than you think. So  Lucite bookcases, and she has  they’ll be ready to use that full-
     kids stash their items.     rather than filling all storage to  designed a clear Lucite desk for  size desk all by themselves.
                                                             CB2.]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[50%
                                                                     50%
                                                                     50%





                                                                        OFF
                                                                        OFF
                                                                        OFF
                                                                        OFF
                                                                        OFF



                                                                       YOUR FIRSTYOUR FIRST
                                                                       YOUR FIRST
                                                                           SERVICE                 * *
                                                                           SERVICESER









     TOUCH OF PERSONALITY
       Although the goal is a timeless space that won’t need too much
     redecorating as a child grows, be sure to incorporate a few special
     items that express a child’s interests. Davin often includes framed
     prints like movie posters or depictions of favourite animals, or one
     big item like a surfboard. “For one little girl, we did a swing chair
     and fairy lights in her room,” Davin says. The items don’t have to
     be expensive, she says, but they should be chosen to highlight what
     the child loves.
       Howard agrees, but cautions parents to remember how easily kids’
     tastes can change.
       “If they like blue now, they’re going to like red tomorrow,” he says.
     So strike a balance between giving the child a voice in choosing
     some items, and letting the grown-ups make the bigger design de-
     cisions.

     » The Associated Press











                                                                      *When booking 5 or more services
                                                                      *When booking 5 or more services
                                                                      *When booking 5 or more services










                                                                              204-728-9333
                                                                              204-728-9333
                                                                              204-728-9333
     Dramatic oversized art can be a great way to decorate a contemporary child’s room.  weedmancanada.com/brandon
                                                                  weedmancanada.com/brandon
                                                                  weedmancanada.com/brandon
     TOP: Personality adds charm to any kid’s room, but remember they will grow out of
     many of their passions as a child]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[24                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018






















































     A bedroom in a New York City apartment being used as a woman cave, with a scarf hung on the wall, futon with throw pillows, a reading lamp, works of art and keepsakes
     from loved ones and other decorative touches. The room is kept as a chore-free tranquil space for relaxing, reading, crafts and other quiet pursuits.(Associated Press)
          ‘WOMAN CAVE’ BECOMING MORE POPULAR


       When people find out that   It is a bedroom in my apart-  the years, we’ve had a lot of  given me: a bowl, art, scarves
     I’m an empty nester with a  ment once occupied by children  (mostly joyful) commotion in  (one draped on the sofa, one on
     “woman cave” in my New York  and other people who no longer  this relatively small three-bed-  the wall). A coffee table with a
     City apartment, they seem to  live under my roof. At least at  room apartment — including a  TV and old laptop that my son
     have a lot of questions. So I re-  the moment, they don’t.  few periods when we had five  set up for me so I could watch a
     cently created this FAQ about it  2) Why do you need a woman  people living there, sharing one  movie or show, but so far I
     for Facebook friends, which led  cave?                  bathroom — so it’s just nice to  haven’t. Bunches of lavender and
     to a whole other round of com-  Because the TV is often blar-  have a tranquil spot to relax  mint that I picked from my win-
     ments and questions.        ing sports in the living room  now.                    dowbox after the first frost,
       If you’re curious about woman  (my husband lives in the apart-  4) What is not allowed in the  hanging upside down to dry.
     caves or maybe you’re dreaming  ment, too) and the kitchen’s not  woman cave?        6) Do you socialize in the
     of creating your own, here’s my  comfy and my bedroom is for  Food. Strife. Clutter. Noisy  woman cave?
     FAQ and the comments and re-  sleeping.                 things. No beverages other than  No. It’s a solitary place.
     sponses it generated.         3)  What do you do in the  decaf tea.                Though I might consider letting
                                 woman cave?                   5)  What is in the woman  my friends from high school
     WOMAN CAVE FAQ                I sit on the futon and enjoy  cave?                  visit.
                                 the calm. I do projects like or-  A futon with nice pillows. A  7) Is there anything missing
       1)  Where and what is this
     woman cave?                 ganizing recipes. I write lists.  really good reading lamp. Beau-  from the woman cave?
                                 Occasionally I nap or read. Over  tiful things that loved ones have  No. It’s perfect.]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[2018 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                              25











































     COMMENTS AND QUES-          allowed in my woman cave.
                                   Comment: “Those are practi-
     TIONS ON WOMAN CAVE         cally the same rules I have for
       Comment: “No food or bev-  my man cave/media room.”                     Turn that new home into your
     erages other than decaf tea?? I  Response: Perhaps we are de-
     could forgo the food but would  scended from the same cave
     broaden the beverage menu to  dwellers.
     include some select favourites of  Comment: “Because my dad  dream home
     mine.”                      is severely handicapped, they
       Comment: “No cheese?”     created a bedroom for him
       Response: My husband once  downstairs in the old den of my                   with a
     brought me a snack to be nice,  childhood home. My mom now
     but it spilled and then I had to  has the whole upstairs to herself,  Purchase Plus Improvements Mortgage.
     clean it up. I just want the  so she converted my sister’s old  Talk to a qualified Mortgage Broker today
     woman cave to be neat and   bedroom into her woman cave
     clean without any effort.   (although she doesn’t call it   about including home improvements costs
       Comment: “Sounds  blissful.  that).”                                in your next mortgage.
     What about a few joss sticks?  Response: Women give a lot
     Or would incense be distract-  to other people in their families
     ing?”                       and sometimes a small tranquil
       Response: I have a tiny laven-  space is really essential to keep
     der pillow if I need aromather-  them going. My years in this
     apy. That’s enough.         apartment are often a blur from
       Comment (from a neigh-    when kids were little and there
     bour): “I’d like to invite you up  were never even five minutes of
     to my woman cave. The thing I  quiet or an inch of privacy. Part
     like most about it is that it’s al-  of the trance I go into in there is
     ways clean. No one else’s stuff.”  just processing all the memories
       Response: Exactly.        and the ups and downs. A room
       Comment:  “There was a    of one’s own is not just a
     commercial a while ago that  metaphor (or the name of a
     called it a ‘She Shack.’”   book).
       Response: That suggests dis-
     order and crudeness. Neither is  »The Associated Press    (204) 727-2177 |  www.centummortgagechoice.com]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[26                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018



















































     Vintage light ﬁxtures are making a comeback.


                          STEPPING INTO THE LIGHT
       Creative new shapes and     Chin’s also a fan of Stickbulb,  firm Manooi used Swarovski  say Brandon Quattrone and
     technology mean that home   a lighting component created by  crystals to craft sinuous fixtures  Mat Sanders of Consort Design
     lighting fixtures often do far  RUX studio in New York City.  evocative of infinity symbols.  in Los Angeles.
     more than provide illumination.  The “stick” is offered in maple,  Bocci showed fixtures made by  “You want it to be the wow
     They can be exciting and sculp-  walnut, reclaimed heart pine,  injecting soda water into hot  factor in a room. If you’re hang-
     tural works of art.         ebonized oak or redwood that’s  glass, then folding and stretch-  ing a dining room chandelier,
       “Designs are now not only a  been salvaged from one of New  ing it into pearlescent pendants  keep the surrounding walls sim-
     source of light, but a distinctive  York’s old water towers. Fitted  that looked like giant glowing  ple, with a minimal piece of art-
     feature of an interior design,”  with an LED, the sticks attach  ribbon candy.     work or some subtle shelf
     says New York architect West  to a central metal element and  Designer  Tom Dixon took  styling.”
     Chin.                       can be configured into various  over Milan’s iconic old theatre,  Designer Ghislaine Vinas did
       Chin recently hung a frothy  shapes, like fireworks or can-  Cinema Manzoni, to show his  that in a Montauk, New York,
     cluster of LED glass bubbles  tilevered mobiles.        furniture and lighting. One col-  beach house project. She hung
     over a dining table in a mini-  “I’d guess the design process  lection was called Cut; the  Alvaro Catalan de Ocon’s PET
     malist apartment on Manhat-  has been affected in the most  faceted clear or smoky fixtures,  Lamp chandelier in an all-white
     tan’s High Line. The fixture’s a  liberating way with the develop-  with mirrored finishes and met-  dining space. The brightly hued
     focal point in an otherwise spar-  ment of the LED bulb,” Chin  alized interiors, resembled enor-  lights, hanging on colored cords,
     ely decorated space. In a Flat-  says.                  mous futuristic crystals.  bring in an element of playful-
     iron duplex, he placed a trio of  At Milan’s Salone del Mobile  “When we’re planning a room  ness.
     mesh orbs over the staircase;  this April, the Euroluce lighting  that calls for a large piece of  Other intriguing fixtures new
     when the lights are on, shadows  exhibition halls showcased  statement lighting, we always  to the marketplace employ
     dance theatrically against a pan-  LEDs and other technology in  start with that piece first, build-  modern technology with a nod
     eled feature wall.          imaginative ways. Hungarian  ing everything else around it,”  to classic design.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[2018 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                              27

       Corbett Lighting’s Theory ceiling fixture is an ode to
     midcentury Italian design, with horizontal spokes alter-
     nating clear glass and gold-leaf iron rods. Calibrated
     LEDs gracefully cast light up and down. Metropolis’ in-
     terconnecting, hand-forged iron cubes surround an LED
     light source, and the whole thing is suspended on aircraft
     cables. The piece melds 21st century and modernist de-
     sign.
       The shape of Humanscale’s Vessel quartz crystal pen-
     dant conceals a glare-free LED that makes it seem lit from
     within. The effect would play well in a hallway or over a
     long table or island.
       Restoration Hardware’s collection of forged brass, steel
     or bronze pendants in drum, funnel or dome shapes has
     an industrial vibe.
       Jonathan Browning was inspired by ‘60s French mini-
     malist design for his Aquitaine series, which features slen-
     der brass, nickel or bronze tapers tipped with faceted
     LEDs, suspended on black cord. And a turn-of-the-cen-
     tury Venetian design is updated in the soft curves of Icaro,
     with fiberglass replacing Fortuny silk, and gold or silver
     metal-leaf trim adding romantic flair.
       At Rejuvenation Lighting, designer Brendon Farrell of
     Portland, Oregon, has a floor lamp with an elongated
     linen drum shade perched on a brass stand; the stand is
     embedded in a white or black oak ball base. And art meets
     engineering in Contrapesso, O & G Studio’s pendant, in
     which an LED-lit glass ball is counterbalanced by a small
     brass or bronze globe. It’s lighting made acrobatic.
     » The Associated Press
                                                    A steel chandelier from Restoration Hardware.  (Washington Post)]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[28                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018



















































     A selection of throw pillows. Fresh, energetic hues like coral and red are part of a vibrant palette along with bold pattern.
         WHY DO SOME MEN HATE THROW PILLOWS?



       It’s a well-known decorating  LOVE ‘EM OR HATE ‘EM                               excess air.
     fact that throw pillows are an  Bill Herren designs pillows as DROP ZONE             She also recommends that
     easy and inexpensive way to  part of his job as creative direc-  If you don’t want throw pil-  “active households” (those with
     change the look of a room.   tor for  Woodard, an outdoor  lows to end up on the floor, pro-  pets, children or messy hus-
       They can add colour, texture,  furniture manufacturer in Cop-  vide a “drop space” for them, says  bands) consider using pillows
     interest or a dash of holiday  pell, Texas. “I get such grief from  Suzanne Lasky, an interior de-  made with durable, outdoor fab-
     cheer.                      everybody about my throw pil-  signer and owner of S Interior  rics.
       But that doesn’t mean every-  lows because I love my throw  Design in Scottsdale, Arizona.
     body appreciates them.      pillows,” he says. “I know why  A bench at the foot of the bed, TRYING OUT TRENDS
       The internet is full of women  men hate them: They don’t want  a basket near the couch or a side  Smith, who designs luxury
     (and their interior designers)  to put them back.”      chair would all do, she said.  outdoor pillows in weatherproof
     complaining that husbands don’t  The anti-throw-pillow crowd  “You need that so you don’t  fabrics, estimates that about a
     understand the decorative as-  also might not know what to do  get annoyed that your $100 silk  third of them end up indoors.
     pects of throw pillows. Pillow  with the pillows once they re-  pillow is on the floor,” she says.  For some people, pillows are a
     aversion among men is a real  move them from a piece of fur-  And if you’re going to indulge  way to indulge in trends without
     thing, says pillow designer  niture, says Herren, who   in different looks for summer  really making over a room, she
     Elaine Smith.               introduces a new pillow shape  and winter, or holiday-inspired  said. She often incorporates the
       “It’s become a joke, but it’s  each year for the company’s col-  pillows embellished with rein-  latest  from the fashion runway.
     only a joke because it’s true.  lection. His solution: “Just throw  deer or flags, Lasky suggests in-  Past collections have included
     They don’t understand why we  them on the floor — especially  vesting in space saver bags —  a “gladiator pillow” and a “hula
     need to have eight pillows on  those made with outdoor fab-  storage bags that let you com-  pillow” based on clothing Smith
     the bed,” she says.
                                 rics. They’re so easy to clean.”  press items by vacuuming out  spotted on the catwalk.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[2018 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                              29

     PILLOW TALK
       Also popular are pillows that say something, says
     Susan Hardin, owner of The Little Birdie pillow
     company in Calhoun City, Mississippi. Building on
     the popularity of small signs and plaques featuring
     inspirational sayings, she began adding words to her
     designs. Pillows emblazoned with the words “Be Still”
     and “Live Simply” are among her top-selling designs.

     COMFORT COUNTS
       Colour, shape and size all matter when you’re se-
     lecting a throw pillow, but nothing is more important
     than comfort, said Asad Syrkett, a senior editor at the
     architectural design website Curbed.com. He regu-
     larly leans on his favourite accent pillow and uses it
     to prop up his laptop.
       “You want it to look great and be comfortable,” said
     Syrkett, who once penned a blog post entitled,
     “Throw Pillows: In Defence of a Divisive Home Ac-
     cessory.”

     ODDS OR EVENS
       Syrkett considers himself a throw-pillow minimal-
     ist, keeping only one on his couch. But he keeps an
     open mind: “Do what you want. Don’t overthink it.”
       Smith says the size of your couch should be a con-
     sideration, but agrees there are no firm rules.
       “I like an odd number; some people prefer pairs,”
     she says.
     » The Associated Press]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[30                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018





















































     This undated photo provided by Vern Yip shows Yip at his home in Atlanta with his family and dogs. Families with pets have several options for durable, attractive ﬂooring
     that will stand up to even the most rambunctious pets, including wood ﬂooring with ﬁnishes that resist scratching from claws and waterproof ceramic tile designed to look
     like stone ﬂooring. (Associated Press)
                   DESIGNING WITH THE PET IN MIND



       It’s gotten easier to have a  Here, Yip and two other inte-  in my island in my kitchen.’”  “It used to be, a few decades
     house full of pets without sacri-  rior-design experts — Betsy  Often, the planning starts  ago, that if you put down a ce-
     ficing the home decor you want.  Burnham, founder of Los An-  with the biggest elements: walls  ramic tile floor, it just looked
       Interior designer Vern Yip, a  geles’ Burnham Design, and  and floors.           like ceramic,” Yip says.
     judge on HGTV’s “Design Star”  small-space expert Kathryn  Paints have become much   This tile is good for animals
     and a dog person, says new tech-  Bechen — offer some tips:  more pet-friendly (and kid-  because it “looks like stone, but
     nology has led to a variety of                          friendly) in recent years: “There  unlike stone it doesn’t absorb
     stylish and pet-friendly home-  PET PLANNING            are a lot of paint companies now  urine or other things if your dog
     furnishing options.           Many pet owners today “are  that have flat paints that are  has an accident.”
       “The furniture and home-  designing a space around their  wipe-able,” a feature previously  And don’t forget the little
     decor industry has really   animals,” Burnham says. “Most  offered only with glossy paints,  things: If your pets are very ac-
     rounded the corner and come to  of the time, I hear, ‘Oh, we’ve  Burnham says.     tive, minimize the number of
     realize that this is a way of life  got dogs and a couple of cats  Flooring options have also ex-  items on tabletops and put more
     for a lot of people,”  Yip says.  and three kids, so please be  panded: Wood flooring compa-  fragile things on higher shelves,
     Durable, easy-to-clean paints,  mindful that we can’t have any-  nies have developed finishes that  especially in small rooms,
     antimicrobial  stain-resistant  thing too precious.’ Then there  resist scratching, Yip says. Ce-  Bechen says.
     rugs and more mean that a   are these really specific requests,  ramic tile designed to look like  Add a lidded basket or storage
     beautiful home and a furry pet  like, ‘I’d like a built-in dog bed  stone flooring is another practi-  ottoman to stash pet toys when
     are no longer incompatible.                             cal option.                guests come over.]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[2018 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                              31


































                                                                                                 Gayle Plessner watches
                                                                                                 her dogs play in their
                                                                                                 Shannon Ggem-designed
                                                                                                 mud room with water-re-
                                                                                                 sistant ﬂooring.
     FABRIC STRATEGIES           and cleaning with animals in a
       Fabrics that can withstand life  small space,” Bechen says.
     with pets used to be rough and
     often unappealing to touch, Yip SEPARATE SPACE
     says. Now, you can find stain-re-  It’s a luxury to have a room
     sistant and antimicrobial fibers  devoted to pets, or to have a
     in a range of styles and soft tex-  large mudroom to create a sort
     tures. Burnham suggests looking  of pet bedroom. But  Yip says
     for textiles made with a finish  that’s becoming more common.
     called Nanotex, which makes   When guests who aren’t com-
     the fibers stain-resistant and  fortable with animals come to
     waterproof.                 visit, a dedicated room gives pets
       If you have cats, it’s also help-  “a space that’s theirs, that they
     ful to choose fabrics that are  can retreat to that doesn’t feel
     smooth.  “We sort of embrace  like punishment,” Yip says. Even
     leathers and flatter weaves so  if the space does double-duty as
     that the cat can’t get their claws  an office or laundry room, you
     into it,” Burnham says.     can create a secure area for a pet
       Leather is also a good choice  by keeping their stuff all in one
     because it’s durable, and it can  place.
     look even more attractive with a  Get creative by adding some-                        Our mission is to be the most
     bit of time and wear.       thing to entertain your pet                            knowledgeable, skilled, ethical, and
       Bechen suggests avoiding very  (Yip’s dogs have an aquarium to                     helpful real estate professionals
     light-colored fabrics if dark pet  look at), and create a sleeping                          available.
     hair will frustrate you (or very  space they’ll love.
     dark fabrics if your pets have  “Cats love to climb,” says
     light hair). Print patterns are less  Bechen, so cat owners can add a
     likely to show pet hair than  shelf around the perimeter of a
     solids are, she says. And it helps  laundry room or mudroom and
     to keep an attractive throw blan-  put their cat’s bed up there. It      204-724-5690
     ket on your pet’s favourite furni-  creates a perfect perch for the  Unit 101 – 244 10 St. Brandon, MB  R7A 4E8
                                                                                    th
     ture, and then remove it when  pet to feel safe while surveying
     guests come over.           the room.                        www.integralrealty.ca
       “You’ll notice a lot more hair  » The Associated Press]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[32                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018










































     ADD COLOUR WITH                                                “YOUR #1 CHOICE FOR PROFESSIONAL

                                                                             LOCAL SECURITY”
         YOUR CABINETS





       Conventional wisdom says to use neutral colours or simple wood
     stains for anything as permanent as kitchen cabinets.
       Homeowners craving a burst of colour have generally been ad-
     vised to bring it in through easily changeable items like curtains or
     seat cushions.                                                                         Automation systems to
       But home-design TV shows and blogs are changing that calculus                        control your lights, locks,
     by showing colorful, painted kitchen cabinets that look like a com-                    thermostats, and alarm
     mitment worth making.                                                                  system from anywhere
       Lately, “the natural materials are just not satisfying people,” says                 in the world
     designer and apartmenttherapy.com founder Maxwell Ryan.
       “People are loving contrast right now,” including kitchens with
     bold colours and stark contrasts of black and white.
       Designer Brian Patrick Flynn recently filled the kitchen of
     HGTV’s new “Urban Oasis” giveaway house with bright blue cab-  High definition camera
                                                                 systems for your home or
     inets and a blue island in the centre of the room.          business
       This cheerful colour fills the room with energy in a way that tra-
     ditional stained-wood cabinets couldn’t.
       “I think designers love painted cabinetry in kitchens because, as
     opposed to wood, it’s the strongest way to create a defined palette,”  Residential and commercial alarm systems
     Flynn says.
       “It’s a great way to really add tons of personality to a space that’s
     more about task than it is decoration.”                     204-717-5599
       Here, Ryan, Flynn and Massachusetts-based designer Kristina  www.westmansecurity.ca
     Crestin offer advice on how to fill a kitchen with on-trend colorful                   Locally Owned & Operated
     cabinetry while still having a room you’ll love for years to come.  FREE alarm switchovers with 3 months of FREE monitoring]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[2018 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                              33

     COLORFUL COMPROMISES
       “Do you want it to be timeless
     and you might always love it but
     might never be jazzed about it?”
     asks Crestin. Neutral cabinets,
     especially white ones, remain a
     safe and popular bet. But she
     says homeowners who are
     drawn to bolder colours and use
     them thoughtfully often end up
     happy.
       Sometimes, the answer is put-
     ting colour on only half the cab-
     inets.
       “Since I’m a fan of going big,
     I can go with fire-engine red
     cabinets all over and never
     flinch,” Flynn says.
       “However, if a client is hesi-
     tant about that much colour in
     the kitchen, I’m a fan of doing
     the lower cabinets or just the is-
     land cabinets in a colour, then
     going white or grey with the
     others.”
       This approach, he say,  “will
     balance out the intensity of the
     cabinets and also make sure
     there is some visual breathing
     room so the eye can rest.”  In this kitchen, designed by Jennifer Gilmer, warm grays help create a cozy feel. The color of the cabinets is complemented by
       Colorful lower cabinets can  other tones in the space. (Bob Narod)
     also look great combined with
     open shelving on top, Ryan says.  CHOOSING YOUR SHADE     HOT WATER TANK REPLACEMENT
     Or paint the lower cabinets
     black, and then tile or paint the  “My rule for choosing the                STARTING AT      $       27   *
     wall behind the upper, open  right colour is to stick with                                            per
     shelving in a bold colour you  those that have grey, white or                                 13 month
                                                                                                    Subject to terms
     love.                       black undertones, versus those                                      and conditions
       “If you can get away with less  with yellow or yellow-beige un-
     storage,” Ryan says, this open-  dertones,” Flynn says. “Once the                             No cost repairs.
     shelf approach makes small  sun goes down and you use your
     kitchens feel larger, while the  interior lights, the colour will                                 No cost
     colorful wall behind the shelves  probably read somewhat true to                               replacement.
     adds personality without being  its values.”
     as overpowering as a full room  If you’re ordering new cabi-                                   EVERYONE IS
     of colorful cabinets.       nets, ask about getting a custom                                    APPROVED!
                                 paint colour for a slightly higher
                                 charge (probably as much as a
     EMBRACING THE BLUES         20 per cent upgrade) rather than
       Although black cabinets are  settling for a shade you don’t  TANKLESS WATER HEATERS
     trendy (Ryan just did his   love, says Crestin. If it’s not pos-  STARTING AT                 *
     kitchen with black cabinets and  sible to order the exact colour             $  39       99    INSTALLED
     white countertops), Crestin says  you want, consider ordering                            per month  Subject to terms
     many homeowners fall in love  cabinets unpainted and hiring a                                    and conditions
     with a blue kitchen.        painter once they arrive.
       Blue shades, especially navy,  Or if you’re comfortable with
     can feel “historical and timeless,”  ambitious DIY projects, you
     she says, but also a bit more ex-  could paint new or old cabinets
     citing than basic wood or crisp  yourself. But Ryan points out
     white. A stately navy blue is a  that while older cabinets made
     safe bet that can then be en-  of solid wood can be sanded and
     livened further in ways that are  painted successfully, the results
     risk-free, like  “layering on a  are often different with cheaper  www.brandonheatingandplumbing.ca
     spring green or chartreuse”  ones.                         CALL: 204-728-0180  |  24-HOUR EMERGENCY SERVICE
     through dish towels and cur-  » The Associated Press
     tains.                                                              SERVING BRANDON SINCE 1910]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[34                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018

                A PERFECT GARDEN TAKES PLANNING



       We gardeners are waiting im-                                                               Albert Parsons
     patiently for winter to finally
     give up its grip on the garden so
     that we can begin to create our
     2018 outdoor gardens. Al-
     though the actual physical
     process of gardening is our main
     source of satisfaction, coming in
     a close second is all the planning
     and designing that comes first.
       We have to decide what to
     plant and where to plant it. We                                                     GONE
     have to decide on whether to in-
     troduce some new elements to                                                        GARDENIN’
     the garden and we play around                                                       Albert Parsons lives, writes, and
     with colour schemes and differ-                                                     gardens in Minnedosa.
     ent plant combinations in antic-                                                    » wtw@brandonsun.com
     ipation of the time when we can
     actually get outside and plant.
       Perhaps this year in the plan-
     ning of your garden you will
     consider doing something a lit-
     tle bit different by creating a
     theme garden.  Whether the
     project is simply the creation of
     one garden room or encom-
     passes the entire landscape,
     choosing a theme around which
     you build your theme garden
     will be a rewarding challenge.
       Creating a theme garden will
     give you a chance to explore
     your creative side, allow you to
     use design techniques that you
     have never tried, and perhaps
     grow some plants that you have
     not before included in your gar-
     den.
       What is a theme garden?                                                          Using old agricultural artifacts will add
     Simply put, a theme garden is a                                                    to an agricultural-based theme garden.
     design concept around which
     the garden (or garden room) is  pieces of old farm implements.   you be limited to using smaller  garden.
     constructed. Every aspect of the  You might simply create a  annuals and perennials if the  Golden leafed hostas and
     garden is tied into a single  garden room that has a dis-  space is a small one, such as a  bright yellow creeping Jenny are
     theme to create a unified effect.  tinctly formal look, a lush trop-  narrow side yard? How much  two plants that have great yellow
       You can decide on whatever  ical  atmosphere  with  a  space will be available for acces-  foliage. Keeping foliage colour
     theme you like.  You might  Mediterranean   appearance.  sories and how will they be in-  as well as bloom colour in mind
     choose a colour and make that  There are many possibilities;  corporated into the garden?  allows you to create even more
     your theme; choose purple   you just have to let your imagi-  A colour theme is one of the  interest in your garden.
     and/or burgundy flowers and fo-  nation loose.          easiest themes. A vibrantly  Creating a more sophisticated
     liage to create a dark moody gar-  When you have decided on  bright yellow “sunshine” garden  colour theme garden with a bit
     den or you might construct a  where you are going to under-  can easily be produced using  more atmosphere might involve
     sunshine garden of yellows and  take your project and whether it  plants with yellow flowers. For  using dark purple hues. Bur-
     oranges.                    is to include the whole garden or  the best impact, use varying  gundy leafed ninebark, Othello
       Consider the accessories you  just one area of the landscape,  hues and tones of the colour to  ligularia with its large leaves
     have on hand or have recently  you will have to decide what  add interest and variety. Perhaps  having deep burgundy under-
     acquired. These  accessories  plants would be suitable for that  bright yellow Inca and Lulu  tones, and appropriate varieties
     might suggest a theme. Perhaps  particular location. Will it be a  marigolds can be combined with  of heuchera might be compan-
     you will create a garden with an  shade garden or one in full sun?  pale yellow day lilies and some  ions for purple flowering plants
     agricultural theme, including  Will there be space for larger  taller Lorraine Sunshine heliop-  like salvias, monkshood, cam-
     agricultural artifacts and equip-  plants such as shrubs and large  sis – using variegated foliage will  panulas (including Blue Clips)
     ment like old wagon wheels or  herbaceous perennials or will  add to the overall effect in any  and sages.]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[2018 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                              35









































     Bright red salvia will add punch to a hot garden. Heliotrpe could be used in a sensual garden appealing to the senses or in a moody blue/purple themed garden.
       Annuals, including lisianthus, petunias, and pansies might also be
     used in such a colour scheme. Including plants with blue-tinted fo-
     liage such as dwarf blue spruce and blue hostas while further em-  WHAT IF
     phasize the colour theme.
       If a colour theme does not appeal to you, then perhaps you will  WE CHANGED
     experiment with a themed garden room.                                                 Westman Reality Ltd.
       A Mediterranean garden using reclaimed bricks and lots of herbs  EVERYTHING?
     and brightly coloured flowers such as nasturtiums and marigolds
     might fit into a space in your landscape.
       Want to try your hand at creating a xeriscape? Select an area of
     your garden where you have difficulty growing things. Lay down  Coming Soon… New Branding!
     landscape fabric and cover it with attractive rock or mulch of some
     kind.                                                        and that is only the beginning.
       Then select a few specimen plants and some suitable objects
     (these might be rocks or logs) and create your xeriscape. If the lo-  As we continue on our quest to defy   BIG BOLD AMBITIOUS MOVES AHEAD
     cation is truly inhospitable to plants being planted in the ground,
     use containers.                                              mediocrity, we will continue adopting
       Perennial grasses are very suitable for xeriscape gardens, as are  best-in-class marketing practices, investing
     small shrubs such as barberry. Perennials with substantial foliage
     that stays attractive all season, such as day lilies, are another possi-  in new technologies and creating exciting
     bility.                                                     resources that will beneﬁt YOU the client!
       Maybe you have always wanted to create a very formal looking
     garden space, inspired by pictures of the formal gardens in France
     and Italy. Planting low hedges of perennials, such as cat mint, or  Century 21 Westman Realty Ltd.
     shrubs such as cotoneaster, to form hedgerows around flower beds  2915 Victoria Avenue, Brandon, MB
     or along walks will be time consuming, but in the end rewarding
     when you finally see the finished product.                               204-725-0555
       At the other end of the scale, perhaps whimsy is more to your lik-  www.century21westmanrealty.com
     ing and you have some whimsically garden accessories that you
     would like to use - this theme would be informal and fun and the
     plant choices could be an eclectic mix of your favorites – no formal-  “Excellence – Accountability – Commitment”
     ity here. Have fun creating a theme garden this summer.
                                                                       THE GOLD STANDARD
     » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[36                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018


















































     Using metallic on items such as chairs or on an exposed wire chandelier can change the look and feel of space. (The Associated Press)
              METALLICS CAN WORK IN MANY SPACES



       Decorating is all about adding a bit of cheer and sparkle, a task  brassy, the silvers appear a bit whiter, and even shades of rose gold
     made easier by the recent popularity of all things metallic. With  and coppers are a bit less orange.
     winter’s shortage of daylight, the sheen of metallic furnishings, fabric  So even if you’re using several colours of metals, she says, “that
     and decorative pieces can add a dose of the brightness and warmth  palette becomes a bit softer.”
     so many of us are seeking.                                Another way of getting metallic shine in a subtler way: Use mer-
       “We love metallics because of the glamour they lend to our lives  cury glass, which shows a range of soft colours in a metallic sheen
     by catching and refracting light,” says New York-based interior de-  when it catches the light.
     signer Young Huh.                                         Huh says mercury glass is her favourite metallic “especially in vin-
       And “there is nothing more magical or festive than metallic  tage or retro feeling ornaments. It’s not too garish and looks well
     touches during the holidays.”                           day or night. Buy some boxwood topiaries and pair with mercury
       The trick, she says, is not going overboard with too much glittery  glass, and you’ll have a wonderful winter look that isn’t confined to
     goodness.                                               Christmas.”
       “A little sparkle goes a long way,” Huh says. “If everything is high-  Crestin agrees: Last year, she mixed in mercury glass candlehold-
     octane shine, your home will look a little sad in daylight.”  ers of different sizes with greenery along her mantel, and loved the
       We asked Huh and two other interior design experts — Massa-  look enough to do it again this year. They gave off a warm glow even
     chusetts-based Kristina Crestin, and Sarah Fishburne, director of  when the candles weren’t lit, she says.
     trend and design for The Home Depot — for advice on using
     metallics during the holidays in ways that will look great all winter.  CASUAL COPPER
                                                               Last year, after Crestin found a pretty “Merry Christmas” sign
     HARD MATERIALS, SOFT LOOK                               made of punched copper, she began adding more copper items to
       Fishburne has been seeing a trend toward softer metal shades,  her holiday decorating. She included planters covered with copper
     which look sophisticated. “A little more white going into them is  foil (similar to gold leaf), copper serving bowls for entertaining, and
     the best way to describe it,” she says. The golds are paler and less  LED lights on copper wire that she wove into holiday greenery.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[2018 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                              37

       Silver combined with organic materials
       is a hit. (Earnest Home)







































       She took the same approach for a client who wanted to freshen
     up her holiday decorating: Crestin brought in a selection of copper  BUILDING A
     ornaments for the client’s tree and mixed other copper items in
     throughout the room.
       “We used half of what she already had and then supplemented           NEW          HOME?
     coppery tones,” she says.
       The technique works with any type of metal: “Maybe you edit
     what you have a little bit,” Crestin says, and then supplement with
     ornaments and decorations in copper or another metal this year.
                                                                                    Be sure to confirm your
                                                                                     builder has coverage
     EASY ADDITIONS
       Sparkly metals also look great alongside organic and natural tex-              before you start and
     tures, Huh says: “For instance, what’s prettier than silver with                 if not, see us about
     burlap?”
       Buy a selection of simple terracotta planters or flower pots in dif-      Course of Construction
     ferent heights, and spray paint some of them in metallic shades, says
     Fishburne. “There are so many fantastic metallic spray paints,” she               Insurance today.
     says, in shades of rose gold, soft golds and silvers.
       Fill them with poinsettias, artificial or real, in whatever colours
     appeal to you. If the plants begin to wilt, or you get tired or them
     after the holidays, keep the same pots but switch them out for suc-
     culents.
       Huh agrees that flower pots are a great place to add metallic ac-
     cents: “You can switch out some of your usual cachepots or acces-
     sories with items that have a bit of glimmer,” she says.
       Finally, Crestin points out that metallic scrapbooking paper from
     a craft store can be the perfect way to affordably add one more dose  BRANDON • 2830 Victoria Ave & Shoppers Mall
     of metallic shimmer to your holiday decorating. Buy several sheets
     in a colour you like, and use them as a dining table runner with vo-  WAWANESA • VIRDEN • CARBERRY • SHILO
     tive candles and little silver-toned planters on top.
       For just a few dollars, she says, “it makes such an impact.”  Phone: 204-729-4949  •  Toll Free: 866-277-4949
                                                                           www.guildhmsinsurance.ca
     » The Associated Press]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[38                                                       THE BRANDON SUN  • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • 2018


                                                                                            Digital doorbells, like this one
                                                                                            from Ring, can synch up to your
                                                                                            phone so you can see who is at
                                                                                            your door before you answer it.














































                 NOT YOUR AVERAGE DOORBELL


       Before electricity, doorbells rang via a  ple of vintage-look ones are stamped with a  area, not only for visitors but for packages.
     complex rigging of mechanical pulleys. Vis-  “ring” or “please ring” note, in oil-rubbed  With many of these units, you can speak
     itors pulled a rope or turned a key-like affair  bronze or burnished finishes.   with the person ringing your bell, chatting
     — think Downton Abbey’s elaborate system  Got a vacation home near the water?  directly with the FedEx or UPS driver, for
     to summon staff, but on a smaller scale for  Consider a doorbell shaped like a turtle,  instance, about where and when to leave a
     the masses.                          crab, scallop or starfish. There are cast-metal  delivery.
       The electric doorbell was invented in  ones shaped like hummingbirds, daisies and  According to Consumer Reports’ Eric
     1831, and by the early 1900s was all the rage.  dragonflies. You could opt for a cabin-y look  Hager, the smart doorbell business has
     Chimes and bells could be heard from any-  with a doorbell in the form of a pine forest  grown enormously in the last several years.
     where in the house; a tremendous conven-  or bear, or go full rustic with a truly Old  He acknowledged concerns about tech sys-
     ience for homeowners and visitors alike.  School bell on a rope, in brass cast like a  tems’ vulnerability to hackers, but said
       Today, you can co-ordinate the look and  horse’s head.                  homeowners seem willing to take on those
     sound of your doorbell to your home’s style.  Rhode Island artisan Michael Healy, who  risks for the convenience and other safety
     You also can embrace the internet age with  crafts outdoor art and hardware, has a door-  features of smart doorbells.
     video doorbells that can be answered from  bell in the form of a fox head in nickel silver,  Adorne’s wireless video intercom kit in-
     thousands of miles away.             brass or oiled bronze. He’s got little alliga-  cludes an outside doorbell camera and an
       If you’re renovating an older home, the re-  tors, frogs and palm trees, and a monarch  inside intercom.
     tailer Rejuvenation has several retro-style  butterfly hand-cast in bronze and brass, with  Homeowners can see who’s at the front
     doorbells. There’s a round oak bell, popular  its wings a rich green patina.   door from different locations in the home.
     in the late 1800s and early 1900s, with a  Ready to go high tech with your entry-  The unit can be powered by a long-life bat-
     porcelain button. A midcentury starburst  way? Having a “smart” doorbell, with video,  tery, or you can hook it up to existing door-
     style comes in chrome or brass. And a cou-  allows you to keep an eye on your front door  bell wiring.]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[2018 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                                              39

       NuTone’s Knock video
     doorbell has a motion sen-
     sor, night vision and op-
     tional  alarm.  It  lets
     homeowners travelling any-
     where in the world speak
     with visitors at their door.
     It’s also touted as rugged
     enough to withstand ex-
     treme weather.
       The Ring doorbell has
     HD video, infrared night
     vision, and two-way chat
     from your phone, tablet or
     PC. Added features: cus-
     tomizable faceplates, and an
     optional plan for video
     cloud storage, video sharing
     and cellular backup if your
     internet goes down.
       You probably have a cus-
     tom ringtone on your mo-
     bile phone, so why not have
     a custom sound on your
     doorbell? A digital doorbell
     from iChime lets you
     record your own greeting or
     choose from their sound li-
     brary.
     » The Associated Press

                 Top of the Line Pair...
            Brandon Heating & Plumbing and Lennox















                                                                CLICKBEFOREYOUDIGMB.COM








                            LENNOX RESIDENTIAL HVAC
                            Furnaces, Air Conditioners, Solar, Indoor Air Quality Systems
            FREE Wi-Fi thermostat & AC Cover *On select products








                                                                                        westmancom.com
         204-728-0180    www.brandonheatingandplumbing.ca]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[ȩ
                             s ȩȩ
                                                        ȩ D Sȩȩ
                    "LINDSȩsȩ3HUTTERSȩsȩ3HADESȩsȩ$RAPESȩsȩ(OMEȩ!UTOMATIONsSDNIL "  ȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩ ȩ  3 H  Sȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩ ȩ R  3 H A E ȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩ ȩ E ȩȩ R$  A  Sȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩȩ ȩ E  M  ȩ M ȩ U! ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ Eȩ  O T  M  O I T A  N
                                                         s
                                                                      ȩȩ O(s
                                                                      ȩ P
                                           ȩ E T T U
                                            s



         OUTDOORliving





















                                                                Let a Budget Blinds
                                                                Let a Budget Blinds
                                                                Let a Budget Blinds
                                                                Style Consultant
                                                                Style Consultant
                                                                Style Consultant
                                                                show you how new
                                                                show you how new
                                                                show you how new
                                                                advances in fabrics
                                                                advances in fabrics
                                                                advances in fabrics
                                                                and materials make
                                                                and materials make
                                                                and materials make
                      FlexShade ZIP
                      FlexShade ZIP
                      FlexShade ZIP
                                                                outdoor living easier
                                                                outdoor living easier
                                                                outdoor living easier
                                                                and more beautiful
                                                                and mor
                                                                and more beautiful
                                                                than ever before.
                                                                than ever before.
                                                                than ever befor

                                                                Motorization adds
                                                                Motorization adds
                                                                Motorization adds
                                                                ultimate ease of use.
                                                                ultimate ease of use.
                                                                ultimate ease of use.




         204-727-4766
         204-727-4766
         204-727-4766
                                                                              ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ  ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩ
                                                                                    ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ
         381 Park Avenue East, Unit B
         381 Park Avenue East, Unit B                                         ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ ȩȩ  ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ ȩ
                        venue East, Unit B
         Brandon, MB
         Brandon, MB
         " U D G       N I L " T E  D  C   S
         "UDGET"LINDS COM MOC]]></page></pages></Search>