<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="30"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[THE










                       COMMUNITY











                               LEADERS










                           AMONG US









































































































                                                     JUNE 21, 2018











                                                     A SPECIAL SUPPLEMENT OF THE BRANDON SUN]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[2  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                           THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018

        » COMMUNITY LEADER OF THE YEAR, SPONSORED BY BDO

        Luhowy an ‘unsung hero of her community’






















        BY MATT GOERZEN
          Tireless. Selfless. Dedicated.
          These are, perhaps, the most apt descriptions of
        Shoal Lake resident and longtime Westman-area
        volunteer Cory Luhowy.
          Dubbed by those who nominated her as an
        “unsung hero of her community,” Luhowy has
        played a part in nearly every event and been a
        member of nearly every committee that can be
        found in Shoal Lake for the past eight years. And
        her time spent as a community volunteer is much
        longer if you count her previous 18 years living in
        nearby Minnedosa.
          And she does it all with a positive attitude — a
        self-styled “git ‘er done” work ethic — and lists,
        oh so many lists.
          “Lists are fantastic,” Luhowy said with a laugh.
        “They keep you organized and you make sure you
        are where you’re supposed to be on a certain day
        and have a certain thing done by a certain time.”
          The list of organizations and causes Luhowy has
        given her time to over the past decades is daunting.
        She has helped organize fall and spring suppers,
        done catechism teaching and church cleaning.
          From her time on various committees and
        boards, she has worn many hats, from bookkeeper,
        hockey and baseball team manager, to trustee,
        canteen manager, fish fry organizer, and even
        ensuring Canada Day celebrations got off the
        ground.
          She is the current treasurer of the Shoal Lake
        Chamber of Commerce and the Shoal Lake
        Agricultural Society, and the secretary of the Shoal
        Lake Curling club. Luhowy volunteers time in the
        Shoal Lake Communiplex kitchen, is part of the
        St. Helen’s Parish Council, and does makeup and
        ticket sales for the Strathclair Drama Club.
          She credits her father for her volunteer spirit —
        he was her role model for how to care about and
        give time to her community.
          “He was a saint,” she said. “He took the bull by
        the horns and got things done. You have to make
        a plan and you stick to it.”
          If there is something to be done, the community
        is pretty much guaranteed Luhowy will be involved.
        She knows how to get a group organized to take
        on a task, lays out her expectations and lets people
        do their jobs under her guidance.
          “She’s just on so many committees,” said Sheri
        Baydak, a volunteer with the Shoal Lake
        Agricultural Society and one of the people who
        put Luhowy’s name forward for the award.
          “It’s not too often you get someone on just about
        everything in the community. And she gets nothing
        to do it. She works her little butt off. She’s basically
        one of the first to step up. If it wasn’t for her
        knowledge and commitment and help — she’s
        really got the brains for all the financial part of it.”
          With all of these volunteer commitments,
        Luhowy still manages to work full time with the
        Strathclair Credit Union branch in Shoal Lake. In
        fact, she says being employed close to home gives
        her the ability to take on many volunteer roles in
        the community, and get so much done.
          “I’m very fortunate to be able to work at home
        (in Shoal Lake) and I think that’s what makes my
        accessibility so easy too, that people can just stop
        in,” Luhowy said. “‘I hear you’re collecting for this
        or do you need my name for this.’ Yup, very
        accessible.”
          But even a long-serving volunteer like Luhowy,
        who admits her volunteer efforts seem to fall into
        an annual pattern, can find new challenges. Last
        October, Luhowy took on a new role as a member
        of the Shoal Lake Community Foundation, a
        charity organization that provides financial support
        to local initiatives.
          Established in 2013, the Shoal Lake Community
        Foundation’s mission is described on its website as
        to “continuously support and enhance the lives of
        the residents of Shoal Lake and Oakburn through
        grants that inspire community leadership.”
          The Shoal Lake Community Foundation is part
        of a wider network of community foundations that
        originated with the creation of The Winnipeg
        Foundation in 1921.
          As per the Endow Manitoba website, every gift
        made to an endowment fund at a community
        foundation is pooled and permanently invested.
        The interest earned on these funds is then
        distributed as grants to support a variety of local
        charitable projects. The capital is never spent,
        ensuring a lasting source of support for a
        community.
          While she’s still learning the ropes on the
        foundation — “I’m still pretty green,” she said —
        Luhowy says she has found this new challenge
        interesting, and she seems excited to be part of
        something big and lasting.
          “It’s like leaving a legacy for your community to
        raise funds to turn back into the community,”
        Luhowy said. “It’s something very new for me,  Shoal Lake resident Cory Luhowy has been named this year’s Community Leader of the Year. (Submitted)
        and something I’ve never been a part of before.
        And I have a lot to learn.”
          Nevertheless, her community obviously values
        all the time and effort she has put back into the
        region. Like Baydak said, volunteers are the  “
        lifeblood of any small community, and Luhowy is
        a testament to that fact.                       “It’s not too often you get someone on just about everything in the community. And she gets nothing to do it.
          “If we didn’t have our volunteers who are willing  She works her little butt off. She’s basically one of the first to step up.
        to help, we wouldn’t have anything,” Baydak said.
        » mgoerzen@brandonsun.com                                                                                                                          — Sheri Baydak
        » Twitter: @MattGoerzen]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[www.bdo.ca]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                           THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018

        » COACH AWARD, SPONSORED BY SHUR-GRO FARM SERVICES LTD.

        Caldwell an “inspirational leader in the coaching world”



        BY DIANE NELSON
        groundwork was built as a“
          From teaching school to
        coaching hockey, Bob Caldwell
        is “an inspirational leader in
        the coaching world and the

        Bobcat.”                      “I love working with
          So said Caldwell’s nominator  the kids and there’s
        Merv Tweed. And he had        nothing better than
        plenty more praise to send
        Caldwell’s way. Caldwell, a   going on the ice with
        Hamiota product, played two   a group of coaches
        seasons with the Brandon      that you’ve passed
        University men’s hockey team  on something to that
        and helped Brandon capture    make kids better,”
        back-to-back Great Plains
        Athletic        Conference          — Bob Caldwell
        championships in 1973-74 and
        1974-75.
          And Caldwell has parlayed
        his acumen and expertise in more than 40 years of coaching at
        the local, national and international levels.
          Hockey Canada honoured Caldwell with the Gordon Jukes
        Award in 2015, recognizing his contributions to amateur hockey
        at the national level.
          As well, he was one of the driving forces behind the formation
        of the National Coach Mentorship Program and was skills
        coach for Hockey Canada’s U17 national team.
          According to Tweed, Caldwell’s coaching credentials include
        global assignments. He coached Poland’s under-18 team and
        mentored coaches in Romania. The International Ice Hockey
        Federation also brought Caldwell in as a skills camp leader for
        youth, and he was part of the IIHF’s coach development
        exchange program.
          Closer to home, he served as an assistant coach with Andy
        Murray in 2012 with the NCAA Division 1 Western Michigan
        Broncos.
          In 2004, Caldwell spearheaded, and is still involved in, the
        Breakfast Club in Deloraine, an early-morning program that
        gives young players a chance to work on their hockey skills. The
        concept is now used across the country.
          He was named Hockey Manitoba’s Volunteer of the Year in
        2012 and inducted as a member of the Deloraine Royals into
        the Manitoba Hockey Hall of Fame in 2015.
          “On a personal note,” Tweed wrote, “Bob has served as
        teacher, coach, father, and parent to all of my children, and I
        know he has played a significant role in their life successes.”
          Despite all his accomplishments, or maybe because of them,
        Caldwell has no intention of throwing in the towel anytime
        soon.  “I guess when you get old, there’s stuff in your rearview
        mirror – I work with Hockey Canada ad Hockey Manitoba
        doing stuff so hopefully I’ll keep doing it for as long as I can,”  Community Leader Award “Coach” category recipient Bob Caldwell is pictured on the rink. (Submitted)
        Caldwell said.
          Caldwell credited his own coaches and mentors in Hamiota  of chances to share his experience and his knowledge with  Although Caldwell retired a few years ago, he still enjoys
        with helping him achieve all that he has, and they have a special  players of all ages.                         working with youngsters – and not-so-young-sters – who share
        place in his heart thanks to their support early in his life.  “I taught high school for 35 years so I’ve worked with kids  his passion for hockey.
          “My dad died when I was seven years old and I really  all the time and had an opportunity with Hockey Canada to …  “I love working with the kids and there’s nothing better than
        appreciated the people who made time for me and took the time  work with kids all over the world involved with hockey. So it’s  going on the ice with a group of coaches that you’ve passed on
        to make sure I got to games and stuff,” Caldwell said. “So they  been a lot of fun.”                            something to that make kids better,” he said.
        made a lasting impression on me.  “I’m really grateful for what  The next big thing on his to-do list is Hockey Canada’s special  Despite all his other accolades, Caldwell, like many nominees,
        they did and just the inclusiveness and giving me opportunities.  project in China, where he’ll go, hopefully in November, to give  was taken aback and humbled by being recommended for a
        That’s always kind of been in the back of my mind.”     some coaching clinics and show the Chinese “how we coach  Community Leader Award.
          Caldwell said he really enjoyed playing hockey when he was  in Canada. And then we’ll go on the ice with some of the  “It came right out of the blue,” he said. “And I sure didn’t
        younger, but at this point, he’s keeping fit so he can still get on  youngsters. They have the Olympics in 2022, so there’s a real  expect it.”
        the ice and coach. And hockey has provided him with plenty  push on to have the country get excited about hockey.”

        Tosh credited with coaching youths in life, as well as in sports



        BY DIANE NELSON

          Formerly of Glenboro, Glen Tosh has been
        a resident of Souris for the past decade, and
        wasted no time getting involved in the
        activities of his new community once he
        arrived.  But prior to that, about 12 years ago,
        Tosh was named Sport Manitoba’s Volunteer
        of the Year. That honour is presented to a
        sport volunteer in the Westman Region for
        his or her significant contributions to the enhancement and
        development of amateur sport. And those who selected Tosh
        deemed him “the epitome of the community volunteer,” lauding
        his resume as “both long and impressive.”
          He coached senior hockey and led his club to the 2004
        Provincial B Championship – Glenboro’s first in thirty years.
        In 2005, he coached the Glenboro high school hockey team,
        was behind the bench for the minor bantam development hockey
        club, served as a director for Hockey Manitoba, was president
        of the Tiger Hills Hockey League and served as a player/coach
        with the Cypress River Comets Intermediate Baseball team.
          Over the years, Tosh coached bantam baseball, high school
        baseball, badminton, the high school girls’ volleyball program
        (they won a provincial title in 1996), and was involved in the
        community’s junior golf program.
          As if that wasn’t enough, Tosh has served as president of the
        Glenboro Golf and Country Club, chairman of the Glenboro
        Community Development Corporation and was a board
        member of the Glenboro and Area Community Foundation.
          Then came the move to Souris, where his list of
        accomplishments and accolades continued to grow. According
        to nominator Mark Ryckman, Tosh has coached his own
        daughter Brynn’s all-girls Souris Minor Hockey for the past
        seven years.
          He also manages her extended-season team and coached the  Community Leader Award “Coach” category ﬁnalist Glen Tosh. (Submitted)
        past five years with his son Ty’s hockey team, which included
        coaching four years of the extended hockey team, and is  him aside from other coaches is that he not only develops his  He takes particular delight in watching his young players
        managing Ty’s spring hockey team. Tosh is the           players’ skills, he also focuses on teaching his players about  develop, seeing their skills improve and witnessing them grow
        coordinator/coach for the Breakfast Club every Wednesday  respect, sportsmanship, hard work, and dedication. His players  as human beings. And there’s no denying the bond between
        morning during hockey season in Souris. He’s also an Assistant  truly develop and mature as people having him as a mentor.  coach and players is special.  “The relationships I’ve developed
        Coach with the Souris Elks Senior Hockey Club.          Glen stresses the importance of having fun and that there is a  with all the kids I’ve coached over the years – that’s really
          Tosh’s contributions don’t end there. He’s also coached his  lot more to be gained by playing sports than just winning a  something,” Tosh said. “I’ll see kids who are not kids anymore
        daughter’s baseball team for three years and his son’s for four.  game.”                                        at a social event or something and they’ll come up to you and
          “Glen is well prepared for his practices – he is able to efficiently  High praise indeed. And Tosh practices what he preaches,  just remember you as their coach.
        and effectively instruct during the limited practice time,”  because what he likes best about what he does is being able to  “The hope is that you’ve not only taught them about the sport
        Ryckman said in his nomination letter. “He himself is always  encourage others.                                 but to be good people and good citizens and hopefully to give
        taking extra coaching clinics for – in the end – the betterment  “That is definitely the beauty of sports – the teamwork, the  back to their community when the opportunity arises.”  Tosh
        of the kids. In addition to the coaching Glen does, he has been  camaraderie that you develop working together as a team for a  said he was astonished to be nominated for a Community Leader
        the president of Souris Minor Hockey and is currently past  collective goal,” he said.  That said, while the fun is in the playing  Award. And he emphasized he does what he does for the kids
        president. He’s past manager of the Souris Elks Senior Hockey  and the sharing, the occasional victory doesn’t hurt.  “I would  and the community, not to gain attention for himself.
        Club, president of the Southwest Hockey League (Senior),  say all the teams I’ve coached have had a standout moment or  “I certainly don’t coach for the accolades or the attention,”
        Hockey Manitoba Director, president of the Brandon Real  so at some point, but this year’s bantam girls team winning the  he said. “I do it because I not only love the game, but I love the
        Estate Board, and member of Souris-Glenwood Foundation  provincials, the gold medal this year – it was unexpected, but  kids – I love working with the other coaches and the kids to
        Board.                                                  seeing their reaction was really rewarding,” he said. “They’ve  make them better at the game and make them better people.
          “Glen volunteers his time whenever help is needed at  won three out of the last five years. But this year 12 out of the  “And there’s a lot of great coaches out there, so I’m very
        community events. What makes Glen a great coach and sets  14 (players) were in their first year. So that was really special.”  surprised and very honoured.”]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[As a proud sponsor, Shur-Gro would like

                                       to congratulate all of this year’s

                                   Community Leader Award winners.



                                 You inspire all of us and we thank you


                                  for making Westman a better place.                                                                         2018












































                   Anniversary



                   Message
                                      from Ron














                     In 2018, Shur-Gro Farm Services will celebrate its 50th year in
                     business; Munro Farm Supplies celebrates its 60th year; and
                     South East Seeds its 10th year. We wish to thank our customers
                     and suppliers for helping us reach these milestone anniversaries         More recently, we have built new fertilizer plants at Wawanesa,
                     and invite all to help us celebrate this year!                           Waskada, Shoal Lake, MacGregor, Westbourne, Killarney and
                                                                                              Oakville. In addition, two new warehouses have been
                     We moved to Brandon in 1968 and I became a Shell agent selling           constructed at Brandon Terminal and four seed plants have been
                     fuel, fertilizer and farm supplies. We were Simplot and Elephant         constructed at Waskada, Killarney, Westbourne and Oakville.
                     brand dealers at that time. During the boom years of the 70s, we
                     were growing and adding plants at Killarney in 1974 and                  In 2017, we became proud customer owners of Winfield United,
                     Wawanesa in 1979. We moved to our current location on                    a large member-owned distribution and service company that
                     Douglas St. in Brandon in 1976-77.                                       offers crop protection, seed, and crop nutrition products. Our
                                                                                              most recent venture is a partnership with  South East Seeds Inc.
                     We were able to purchase locations at Shoal Lake in 1980 and             of Niverville and Dugald.
                     Waskada in 1984. We also started a brand new dealership at
                     Strathmore, Alberta in 1980. We became partners with Double              We are excited about our future and the future of agriculture.
                     Diamond Farm Supply in 1988.                                             We are in the enduring business of helping to feed people. We
                                                                                              will continue to take on this challenge by committing ourselves
                     An anhydrous transloading facility (Brandon Terminal) was built in       and the way we do business to the success of our customers and
                     1986 along with anhydrous sites at Mather and Belmont in the             the products they produce for the world.
                     late 80s. Boundary Fertilizer in Lena was purchased in 1990.

                     In 1990, we purchased 75% of Munro with Dave Falk as our
                     partner. Shur-Gro and Munro have operated as on business unit                                      Ron Helwer
                     since the early 2000s, with eleven locations in southern Manitoba.                                 President, Shur-Gro Farm Services Ltd.








































                    Brandon  |  Dugald  |  Elie  |  Killarney  |  MacGregor  |  Neepawa  |  Niverville  |  Oakville

                               Portage La Prairie   |   Shoal Lake  |  Waskada   |  Wawanesa  |  Westbourne



                                                       www.shur-gro-com   |   204-729-3800]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[6  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                           THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018

        » EMERGENCY SERVICE AWARD, SPONSORED BY THE BRANDON SUN

























































        The May 19 downtown Brandon fires offered a solid reminder as to the important role that emergency personnel play. (File)
        Cheyne dedicated decades to volunteer firefighting




        BY DIANE NELSON                                                            interested in issues surrounding the  time of the year, and on the weather. He said they don’t attend
                                                                                   cemetery, handy van, and water and   too many fires anymore, especially not in the wintertime.
          It’s one thing to be nominated for                                       sewer.                                 “There’s not many winter fires – there used to be a lot of
        a Community Leader Award by an                                              “Bill assists many individuals with tasks  chimney fires, but that’s kind of gone away now, because there’s
        individual, but in this case, a single                                     whenever called upon, and is well known  less wood fires,” Cheyne said. “And there’s always a few car
        nominator, Pam Hainsworth, gave                                            for providing transportation to and from  accidents that you need to respond to.”
        the nod to Bill Cheyne on behalf of                                        medical appointments for many members  Cheyne grew up in Waskada, where he was a Red Seal
        The Municipality of Deloraine-                                             of the community,” Hainsworth wrote.  mechanic for 10 years. He moved to Deloraine in 1970 to start
        Winchester.                                                                “We feel that he is worthy of nominating  his job at the hospital and has been a fixture in the community
          Cheyne, Hainsworth said, has                                             due to his long service, commitment and  ever since.
        spent his entire adulthood in service to others in need. He joined  dedication to public service. He is an unassuming man who  And he was frank when talking about the fire department,
        the Bren Del Win Fire Department in February of 1975 as a  quietly goes about helping out people in need.”      but equally as forthcoming about his reason for being involved
        fireman. In 1983, when there was a vacancy for Fire Chief, he  Indeed, during an interview, Cheyne downplayed his  in it.  “Pay isn’t really great on the fire department, but you’ve
        was elected by his peers to that position, which he occupied  contributions, saying if he’s able to help someone, he’s interested  got to help the community out,” he said. “And you might not
        until 2001. Now, at 75 years of age, Cheyne continues to serve  in doing so. “If I can give them a hand, I go ahead,” he said.  get any calls for months. And you hope you don’t.”
        on the volunteer fire department.                       “Just try to help out, I guess. Just be there if they need you.”  As far as the Community Leader Award is concerned, Cheyne
          He also drove an ambulance for many years while working  As far as his work with the Fire Department goes, Cheyne  was taken aback, but pleasantly so, when he found out he’d
        as a maintenance engineer at Deloraine Memorial Hospital.  said the area to which it provides service is “at least 24 miles  been nominated.
        Hainsworth said he was extremely proficient in fixing any of  long, one end’s about 16 miles wide and the other end’s about  “I didn’t suspect anything,” Cheyne said. “My wife knew
        the equipment at that facility and many people sought his  13 miles wide. So there’s quite a few sections of land we have  about it but she didn’t tell me.
        guidance.                                               to cover.”                                                “I was surprised that they’d even phone me. I’m not much of
          In retirement, Cheyne is an avid woodworker and sign-maker,  And because several municipalities provide mutual aid to each  a public speaker or anything like that. I’d sooner be in the
        and was most recently elected to the newly amalgamated  other, firefighters could travel as far afield as Boissevain, Melita,  background.
        Municipality. Hainsworth said he takes a keen interest in all  Hartney, and Waskada.                              “I’m always willing to give somebody a hand if they need it.
        matters, and is never afraid to lend a hand. He is especially  Of course demands on the fire department depend on the  But I don’t expect anything in return.”

        City police officer an avid community steward





        BY DIANE NELSON

          There’s no question it’s an honour when someone you know
        – or someone you don’t – nominates you for a Community
        Leader Award. Many have described it as overwhelming,
        humbling and just plain nice.
          But when your boss who goes to the trouble of creating and
        submitting a detailed letter nominating you because of what he
        or she feels are outstanding qualifications, that’s really a thrill.
          “So he’s the guy!” Brandon Police Services Deputy Chief
        Randy Lewis said when he found out his nominator was Police
        Chief Wayne Balcaen. “Wow! But this is not really my
        personality. I certainly don’t need to be acknowledged on a
        public level in any way, shape or form. But it’s certainly pleasing
        that he thinks highly of what I do.”
          According to Balcaen, Lewis joined the Brandon Police
        Service in 1994 and has held numerous leadership positions
        within the organization.
          Lewis has led members of the Police Service on Patrol, in the
        Crime Section, Patrol Support Unit, was the department's
        firearms instructor, and was a leader of the Tactical Response
        Unit for many years.
          All of those positions demanded that he shoulder enormous
        responsibility, while also accepting the potential risk and
        challenges of those jobs. Balcaen said that Lewis recognized
        that being in law enforcement can take an emotional, physical
        and spiritual toll on officers and other staff members, which is
        why he was a proponent of the Brandon Police Service Wellness
        Team. The team includes a cross-section of civilian and police                                                                              Brandon Police Service deputy
        staff, as well as the department’s chaplain, and offers support                                                                             chief Randy Lewis speaks to
        for all Police Service employees to try to ensure positive mental,                                                                          Brandon Sun reporter Jillian
        physical and spiritual health. The Wellness Team is ready to go                                                                             Austin at BPS headquarters on
        24 hours a day, seven days a week, 365 days of the year. Before                                                                             Victoria Avenue at 10th Street
        Lewis championed the cause, the service had never before been                                                                               in this file photo.   (Tim Smith/The
        offered.                                                                                                                                    Brandon Sun)
          But Lewis doesn’t just excel on the job. A passionate
        fisherman, Lewis has turned this pursuit into a way to connect
        with the community by ensuring youth have the opportunity to  was then Curran Park teaching kids the basics of fishing. Balcaen  emphatically. “My wife and my
        engage in his favourite sport. About five years ago, he started a  said the lessons culminated with the kids having their own rods  family, friends, coworkers – they’ve all done a lot.
        local chapter of Generation Next Angler (GNA), the focus of  and reels, and time spent putting their education to action.  “I would say the majority of officers on our force right now
        which is teaching kids under 18 years of age the joys of fishing.  In addition to fishing, Lewis has volunteered in the community  are that way. They don’t just come to work to collect a
          Lewis fundraises all year long, including hosting an ice-fishing  as a baseball coach, a hockey coach for his three daughters, and  paycheque. There are countless members that have other
        derby, in order to stage an annual fishing event – this year’s will  was a volunteer with Big Brothers and Sisters in the mid 1990s.  activities in the community, so I don’t think I’m any different
        be held July 14 on Pelican Lake. All kids who enter receive  “It is my humble opinion that Randy Lewis epitomizes the  than the majority of people who work for (the Police Service).”
        prizes and spend the day learning how to fish. Through the  requirements for this award,” Balcaen said.           Family is a big focus of GNA as well, Lewis said, and the
        shared experience, the youngsters are also able to bond with  Lewis downplayed the praise, saying that GNA was an  definition of what constitutes a family is broad.
        their parents or guardians.                             opportunity for him to do what he loves to do away from his  “There’s lots of different family make-ups that we have
          “This program, in my opinion, connects kids with nature and  day job, which he also adores, and still benefit the community.  participating in our events,” he said. “Grandpas, grandmas, a
        keeps them focused on life's positives rather than taking the road  “Perhaps it keeps some youth who maybe would stray down  couple of kids, aunts, uncles, a neighbour – they all help them
        that will intersect with Randy's professional life,” Balcaen said.  the wrong path and give them some other outlets for their  have a positive experience.
          Lewis was also involved with “Keepin’ it Reel” in Winnipeg,  energies,” he said. “It’s a win-win.”              “There’s some top-notch individuals out there. Being in the
        where he volunteered his boat and his time for a day on the Red  And Lewis is quick to point out he’s not the only one involved  company of some of these folks is astounding, and I quite
        River, teaching children with disabilities and their families how  in the local GNA – numerous volunteers from all walks of life  candidly feel that there are much more qualified people who
        to fish. During the 2000s, Lewis partnered with Jig and Rig, a  have helped out over the years.                 should have been nominated for this (Community Leader
        former local fishing supply outlet, and spent a weekend at what  “It takes a lot of people to do the things we’ve done,” he said  Award).”]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                           THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018

        » VOLUNTEER AWARD, SPONSORED BY SUNRISE CREDIT UNION





































                                                                                                                                                    Linda Clark from Miniota was
                                                                                                                                                    nominated in the Volunteer cat-
                                                                                                                                                    egory for the Brandon Sun Com-
                                                                                                                                                    munity Leader Award. She
                                                                                                                                                    volunteers for many things
                                                                                                                                                    including trained vocalists and
                                                                                                                                                    students in speech arts for the
                                                                                                                                                    Birdtail River Fine Arts Festival.
                                                                                                                                                    (Melissa Verge/Brandon Sun)

        Volunteering has proven a fuflling pastime for Clark





        BY MELISSA VERGE                                        Clark Memorial Volunteer Award.
                                                                  Clark grew up in the Isabella community, and later moved to
                                                                  One of her favourite things to volunteer with is helping out“
          For Linda Clark, volunteering is a way she can stay involved  Miniota. She still stays involved with both places. In Isabella
        with the community while making a difference.           she acts as chair of different committees, including Isabella
          Clark, who lives in Miniota, volunteers to help families of  Community Women. In Miniota, she does a lot of volunteer
        people who are recently deceased, as well as those who are  work with the church.
        young and just starting out in the world.                                                                         “As a volunteer I’m never worried about being
          She officiates at funeral services, as well as volunteers helping  with the Birdtail River Fine Arts Festival. As a former teacher,  recognized, but it’s nice to know that people in
        out students in Miniota prepare for the Birdtail River Fine Arts  it enables her to remain involved with the youth in the  my community think I’m doing a good job.”
        Festival. “Working with children and working with people in  community.
        their time of grief,” Clark said, are two of the highlights of her  “I help them choose their pieces, and I help them learn them                     — Linda Clark
        volunteer work.                                         and train them to get up and use as much expression as they
          She was honoured to find out that she’d been nominated for  can,” Clark said. “Just to prepare them for being in the public  “It’s great when they [the students] get to know me and greet
        a Community Leader Award.                               eye and being on stage.” For the festival, some students choose  me when they see me outside of the school,” she said.
          “As a volunteer I’m never worried about being recognized,  to create their own speeches, and others memorize poetry.  Volunteering fills many hours for Clark, and also gives her a
        but it’s nice to know that people in my community think I’m  It’s a lot of work, but helping out with it is something that  sense of fulfillment. It’s the people that really make it enjoyable
        doing a good job,” Clark said. She juggles all her volunteer work  Clark loves to do, and will ultimately benefit the students.  for her, whatever the work she’s doing may be with the Isabella
        on top of being Reeve of Prairie View Municipality since 2014.  “At some point in their life they will need that public speaking  or Miniota community.
          Volunteering for her started at a young age, when she would  ability,” she said.                                “It’s my way to stay in touch with the youth of our community,
        help out in the local church playing the organ. It remained  She enjoys the social aspect of volunteering, working with  and hopefully to have a little bit of an impact on their life.”
        important to her as she got older as well as her husband, who  the students, as well as teachers at the school- some whom she  » mverge@brandonsun.com
        after his death had an award put up in his name called the Bill  used to work with when she was teaching there.  » Twitter: @Melverge5

        Wark-Brown helps by taking photos of furry friends




        BY MELISSA VERGE
          Mandy Wark-Brown’s clients don’t speak to
        her- at least not in English, and they won’t smile
        on command as she snaps their pictures.  She
        describes taking photos of them like
        photographing little toddlers hyped up on sugar.
          Still, it’s work she loves — she’s been
        volunteering her time since 2012 to take
        professional photos of dogs for Funds For Furry
        Friends (FFFF). That’s one of the reasons Wark-
        Brown was nominated for a community leader
        award; for the extensive work she does volunteering with FFFF.
          It started back in 2011 when she adopted her dog from them.
          “I noticed when I was searching through all the rescues that all the
        pictures weren’t visually appealing,” she said.
          That discovery prompted her to speak to the director of Funds For
        Furry Friends who also happened to be her dogs foster mom.
          “I told them that they could probably adopt out more dogs if their
        pictures were better, and I offered to do it for them,” she said. She’s been
        their photographer ever since, giving time and her skills as a professional
        photographer to help dogs get adopted more quickly.
          “I feel it’s our responsibility to look after animals, to make sure that
        they have the proper homes, they’re cared for and things like that,” she
        said.
          One certain senior citizen she’s helped over the seven years she’s been
        volunteering her time with the organization sticks out for Wark-Brown.
          Hugo was an older gentleman, a black lab mix with a grey snout who
        had been in the rescue for quite awhile. He was having problems getting
        adopted for a couple of reasons.
          “Black dogs are always the hardest to go because they say you can’t see
        their expressions on their faces, and just the old wives tale surrounding
        black animals,” Wark-Brown said.
          One day she snapped a candid photo of Hugo with the then president
        of the rescue, with a big smile on his face as the president gave him a
        hug. That photo ended up in the Westman Journal or the Brandon Sun.
          “An elderly couple spotted it [the photo] and they adopted him right
        away,” she said.
          It’s moments like these that drive Wark-Brown to continue to spend as
        much time as she does volunteering her time to help in the community.
          “It’s good, it keeps me pushing to do more,” she said. “I’m always
        messaging Jill, [the director of FFFF) ‘I have the itches coming, lets do a
        shoot,’” she said.
          The work is perfect for Wark-Brown, who said she doesn’t have the
        emotional strength to do some of the day to day stuff the rescue deals
        with, such as finding animals on the side of the highway. “I kind of just
        stick with the fundraising and the pictures and stuff like that,” she said.
          Besides FFFF, Wark-Brown also does volunteer work with KidSport,
        which provides financial assistance to athletes who would otherwise be
        unable to participate in organized sport. She’s been volunteering with
        them since 2013.
          “Probably the best part is that it gives kids an opportunity to stay out
        of trouble, and that keeps us going with what we’re doing,” Wark-Brown
        said.
          Her own kids are in soccer, so she gets to see the benefits of participating
        in sport first hand.
          For the 40-year-old whether it’s the work she does with KidSport or
        with FFFF, volunteering is something she enjoys doing. She does it to
        make a difference in the community.
          “I’m not a rich person, I don’t own my own house, but I feel like no
        matter what your position is in life you always have time to either donate
        money or donate your time,” she said.
        » mverge@brandonsun.com                                         Mandy Wark Brown kneels beside the dog she adopted from Funds For Furry Friends (FFFF).  She often takes photos for FFFF
        » Twitter: @Melverge5                                           that they can use for their website to help dogs get adopted faster. (Sabine Chorley/Sterling Images)]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Sunrise Volunteers





                          As leaders in community volunteerism, Sunrise Credit Union has a deep commitment to building strong communities. Not only do
                         Sunrise employees participate in community activities as part of their paid work, they also represent the credit union during their
                              unpaid time off. In fact, just last year, Sunrise staff volunteered 6,470 hours in service to local community organizations.









                                                                                                        500 Community
                                                                                                                       organizations received

                                                                                                                       Sunrise Credit Union

                                                                                                                       donations



























                              $52,300 Raised

                                             through independant

                                             branch fundraisers































                                                                                                                 $23,000 Sunrise

                                                                                                                               scholarships granted

                                                                                                                               to students pursuing

                                                                                                                               post-secondary
                                                                                                                               education










                                                 6,470 Staff

                                                               volunteer hours

                                                               in support of the

                                                               community





















                                                                     110 Community

                                                                                organizations that

                                                                                Sunrise staff hold
                                                                                volunteer positions in]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                          THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018






































































        Award winners and supporters listen to a speaker during The Brandon Sun’s Community Leader Awards at the Victoria Inn on Wednesday evening. (Photos by Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)

        What to look for in a leader









        BY MATT GOERZEN
          You don’t have to look very
        hard for the leaders in your
        community. They are the men
        and women who take on the
        burdens     of    ensuring
        celebrations and events go
        forward, who put on those
        skates and coach a kids’
        hockey team, or pick up that
        piece of garbage lying in a
        public park.
          They are the folks who bake
        pies for the community bake
        sale fundraiser, put in time
        setting up a stage for a local
        festival, organize a community
        fish fry, and do the heavy
        lifting for an elderly neighbour
        who needs their sidewalk
        shoveled.
          They take initiative. They
        give back. And they take the
        lead on a community project,
        help foster team spirit and
        energize their volunteers. They
        are the ones who make our
        communities worth living
        within —  our often unsung
        heroes.
          Last night, in our second
        Community Leader Awards
        event, we celebrated Westman
        individuals who have made a
        difference, either through their
        leadership, or their humble
        actions.
          In this special awards
        section, we have recounted the
        efforts of 23 individuals who
        fit the description of a
        community leader. As part of
        the process, our selection
        committee ranked each leader
        in their respective category —  Mayor Rick Chrest speaks during the Community Leader Awards presentation at the Victoria Inn on Wednesday evening.
        Coach, Teacher, Courage &
        Bravery, Above & Beyond,    to my mind, our award         •  They think ahead toward  stewards — That hockey rink  after the fact is a great way to  well, and encourage their best.
        Emergency Services, Service  winners and finalists are  the community’s future needs  needs a campaign manager,  ensure volunteers in the future  It takes more work, perhaps,
        Organization    Volunteer,  worthy of the recognition that  — It’s not just the needs of the  the cemetery lawn needs  as well.             but community leaders know
        Youth Volunteer, Volunteer,  has been bestowed upon them.  here and now — or even those  mowing, and the community  • They make tomorrow’s  that efficiency isn’t always as
        Environmental      Leader,    As you read through the   of next week — that are top  park needs to be cleaned up.  leaders possible — In addition  important as being inclusive.
        Community Builder, Seniors’  various articles written about  of mind in those who deserve  Our leaders take responsibility  to finding new volunteers,  • And lastly, they use talents
        Advocate and an overall     our community leader award  the mantle of community     for the welfare of the      community leaders also look  effectively — You just never
        Community Leader of the     winners and finalists, you may  leader. They look toward  community as a whole — its  to help build up new leaders  know who will step up to the
        Year.                       notice    some     striking  leaving  a    legacy   of  recreational facilities, its green  for  the  future.  Every  plate to lend a hand — kids
          And while they are all    similarities between them —  community building that can  spaces, and the safety of its  community needs a strong  and teenagers, seniors, the
        exceptional individuals, I note  binding characteristics that  last far longer than any one  streets.           pool of people to count on to  able-bodied,  and  those
        that we had a total of 57   define their actions, and the  event, or even one lifetime.   • They lend a hand when  get things done. Having  perhaps who aren’t so nimble
        names put forward as part of  purposes behind them. Here’s  • They are accountable —  needed — Leading by       people ready to take on new  but just want to be a part of
        the nomination process — and  what I see:               Anyone who takes on the     example often means just    leadership duties is essential  the team and have a role to
        there are plenty more in our  • They lead from beside —  responsibility of organizing an  asking “what can I do to  for the continued success of  play. A community leader uses
        region who are just as      A leader’s job is to work with  event knows all too well that  help?” and “where do you  not only an event, but the  what talents they have
        deserving of being nominated.  everyone in the community,  the people of your community  need me?” Stepping up to lend  community itself.   effectively, and play to their
          And again, as last year, most  and those who do it best work  are the beneficiaries of your  a hand is a sure way to inspire  • They foster a strong team  strengths  and  interests
        of    them   don’t   want   shoulder to shoulder with   actions — and they are also  others to help.            — You can’t do everything by  wherever possible.
        recognition. In many cases, it  those under their command.  the ones to whom you are  • They get others on board  yourself, no matter how     To all of our noteworthy
        was difficult for our scribes to  Yes, the leader has to make  accountable. Leadership is  — Sometimes people just need  talented you may be. It takes  community leaders, we give
        get nominees and award      sometimes difficult decisions,  more than how you conduct  to be asked and supported in  a village to raise a child, and  you our thanks for stepping
        winners to open up about    but they must also live the  yourself, or what orders you  order to become volunteers.  it also takes a strong  up, and for caring about your
        themselves. They believe that  principles and practices of  give, it’s about why you are  Approach them and see if they  community to make any event  communities in so many
        their work is built and     what makes a good leader. Not  volunteering or shouldering  have time to give. You might  or program successful. And to  different ways.
        solidified upon the actions and  a top-down, “do as I say”  that responsibility, and who  be surprised at the answer.  build a team, you have to
        efforts of other men and    approach, but rather by     you are doing it for.       And making sure people feel  support individuals of that  » mgoerzen@brandonsun.com
        women in the community. Yet  example.                     • They are community      appreciated for their efforts  team, motivate them to do  » Twitter: @MattGoerzen]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018 • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                          COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018  • 11

        » SELECTION COMMITTEE
































          Brett McGregor                                          Carla McMillan                                          Don Simpson



                                                                                      The Brandon Sun is pleased that
                                                                                    western Manitoba presented our
                                                                                    selection committee with such an
                                                                                    onerous task. Some of our new
                                                                                    committee members were shocked to see
                                                                                    how difficult the task was, our returning
                                                                                    members meanwhile knew all too well.
                                                                                      Westman  is rich with leadership in
                                                                                    both volunteer and vocational areas and
                                                                 Glen Parker        we at The Brandon Sun are thrilled to
                                                                                    facilitate a means to recognize a few of
                                                                these deserving individuals.
                                                                  A special thank-you goes out to our Community Leader
                                                                partners — the businesses who you
                                                                seen throughout this section — for
                                                                they too realize the wealth of
                                                                outstanding individuals in Westman
                                                                and are equally honoured to recognize
                                                                them.
                                                                  We hope you enjoy the second
                                                                edition of the Community Leader
                                                                Awards and we hope you help make
          Dale McKay                                            our selection committee’s job even  Charles Tweed         Mike Brolund
                                                                more difficult in 2019.
































          Hailey Gajadahar                                        Stacy Gill                                              Nate Andrews



































          Penny Burton                                            Rhonda Pardy                                            Rob Henderson






                                                                                                                                                 SUN STAFF


                                                                                                                                                 ON HAND

                                                                                                                                                 FOR AWARDS



                                                                                                                                                 Staff members of The Brandon
                                                                                                                                                 Sun pose for a photo after the
                                                                                                                                                 Brandon Sun's Community
                                                                                                                                                 Leader Awards at the Victoria Inn
                                                                                                                                                 on Wednesday evening.

                                                                                                                                                 (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018 • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                          COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018  • 13

        » SENIORS’ ADVOCATE AWARD, SPONSORED BY CANDO RAIL SERVICES

        “Disruptor” dedicated to seniors’ advocacy




        BY MICHAEL LEE

          Gail Freeman-Campbell has been called a “disruptor” for
        the work she does with her private home-care business
        Daughter On Call, but it’s a title she takes as a positive more
        than anything.
          “If you don’t raise the issues they never get dealt with and I
        really like a challenge,” she said.
          Freeman-Campbell is the owner and CEO of Daughter On
        Call and the visionary behind the private senior’s residence on
        Eighth Street, Kirbyson Home, which opened last November.
          Named after one of its tenants, Fay Kirbyson, and her son
        who became a major investor in the project, Kirbyson Home
        provides 24-hour care, independence and gives residents a place
        that resembles a home, with private bedrooms and bathrooms
        and a large living-room space.
          Last December, the Brandon Neighbourhood Renewal
        Corporation honoured Freeman-Campbell with a housing
        award for her Kirbyson Home residence.
          Despite the negativity she first received about Kirbyson
        Home — including criticisms that nobody would pay more to
        live in it — Freeman-Campbell said she has built up a long
        wait list and has plans to build a second residence at the corner
        of 26th Street and McTavish Avenue this summer. The building
        is expected to be completed either in late fall or early winter.
          “Every week, I have builders and investors calling and
        wanting to build and put one up for me somewhere, whether
        it’s in Brandon or rural Manitoba,” she said.
          Freeman-Campbell, a former nurse at the Brandon Reginal
        Health Centre and LPN instructor at Assiniboine Community
        College, started Daughter On Call nearly six years ago as a  Owner and CEO of Daughter On Call Gail Freeman-Campbell. (Michael Lee/The Brandon Sun)
        way to give people better care and comfort when it comes to
        health care.
          She said her career at the hospital wasn’t going in the
        direction she wanted it to go and she just didn’t have the same
        satisfaction with her job compared to when she first graduated
        from school.
          With Daughter On Call, Freeman-Campbell said she aimed
        to establish a sense of trust with her clients and build
        relationships with both them and their families.
          This move away from the “cookie-cutter approach” of
        government creates a level of service for each individual,
        Freeman-Campbell said. For example, where one person may
        require a half-hour to take a bath, another client with
        Alzheimer’s may need an hour or more.
          “So I think the public appreciates that fact, that we will do
        what they are looking for specifically,” she said.
          And as baby boomers age, Freeman-Campbell expects there
        will be more people who will want that choice between a
        personal care home or something else.
          Starting out with one health-care aide, Daughter On Call
        now employs 70 staff and has an office in Neepawa, with
        another set to open in Portage la Prairie this fall.
          The inspiration for Kirbyson Home, meanwhile, came after
        she said she saw a need for 24-hour care, in light of the long
        wait times for personal care home placements.
          And although she can’t offer the same wages as the
        government can, Freeman-Campbell said it is offset by the
        work-life balance she is able to offer her employees, whether
        it’s a single mom who has to take her child to a lesson or sports
        practice, or an employee who is going to school.
          In the end, she said she will not ask her staff to do anything
        she won’t do herself.                                                                                                                       Brandon Sun Daughter on Call
          “I think that people are looking for options and I think we                                                                               owner Gail Freeman-Campbell is
        definitely have some deficits in our health-care system, both                                                                               seen last year outside of the local
        locally and provincially, and this gives people another option,”                                                                            company’s six-unit seniors hous-
        she said.                                                                                                                                   ing complex at 1323 Eighth
        » mlee@brandonsun.com                                                                                                                       Street. (ﬁle)
        » Twitter: @mtaylorlee


        Nichols helps keep Erickson seniors active




        BY MICHAEL LEE

          Inspired by her love for people and community, Mary Nichols
        is lauded in Erickson as someone who puts the needs of others
        well ahead of her own.
          Nichols is the resource coordinator for the community group
        Services To Seniors, an organization that provides programs
        and support to seniors living in the Erickson, Onanole and the
        Sandy Lake areas.
          Since taking up the job 11 years ago, Nichols has helped
        organize coffee parties, exercise classes and arranged for seniors
        to get walkers and wheelchairs when they need them.
          “I care about the people who live in this community,” she
        said. “The main bottom line for my job is helping to keep people
        in their homes as long as possible.”
          Originally from Winnipeg, Nichols moved to Erickson with
        her husband. She said her son was already living in the area,
        while her husband fell in love with the countryside.
          “I thought I was coming here to die,” Nichols said, as she
        wondered what she would do in the country.
          It was at that point she decided to apply for a job as the
        resource coordinator for Services To Seniors after the previous
        coordinator passed away.
          Nichols admits she didn’t know too much about the position
        when she applied, but what she did know going into it was that
        the job required a caring person to fill that role.
          “The job description asked for that kind of direction (and) I
        believe I felt I had the leadership skills to do that,” she said.
          And even though the position is only part time, Nichols is
        said to have put in more hours than her job description entails.
          She has been known for calling people during snow storms,
        arranging rides to doctors appointments and filling out
        government forms for clients.
          If she knows of anyone who lives in a relatively isolated area,
        Nichols will take the time to go out and drive them to local
        events. “”It’s all about communication,” she said.
          Nichols was instrumental in moving Services To Seniors out
        of its storage-room space in the municipal office building to its
        current location down the street.
          Along with being an active member of her local Lutheran
        chuch, she has also coordinated a volunteer palliative care
        program and installs the Victoria Lifeline medical alert system
        directly into peoples’ homes herself.
          Services To Seniors has also been involved with other
        community initiatives over the years. In 2015, Services To  Senior's advocate Mary Nichols from Erickson. (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)
        Seniors and the Riding Mountain Biosphere Reserve acquired
        grant funding so they could build garden plots for a community  At 72 years old, Nichols was candid about her ongoing plans.  “I don’t see
        garden in Erickson.                                     “I’ve asked the funeral director to clean my desk when they put  myself wanting to quit this job and doing much else,” she said.
          The idea was to help seniors access good, quality produce  me in the box, that’s what’s next,” she said with a laugh.  “Other than that, I would be doing community service again.”
        and give them an opportunity to remain physically active in  Although people tell her she looks tired, as she sees it, Nichols  » mlee@brandonsun.com
        thier communities.                                      said it’s because she cares about people.               » Twitter: @mtaylorlee]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                          THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018

        » TEACHER AWARD, SPONSORED BY ASSINIBOINE COMMUNITY COLLEGE

        ‘Genuinely an inspiration,’ educator goes above and beyond



        BY DIANE NELSON
          Teachers.
          They’re among the most important people we encounter in
        the course of our lives.
          Bad ones can leave a person confused, discouraged and
        unfulfilled.
          But good ones can encourage their students to embrace new
        ways of thinking, help them develop self-reliance and confidence,
        and open them up to a world of possibilities.
          According to nominator Amber Bollman, Assiniboine
        Community College’s Amanda McGregor, who teaches
        primarily Human Resources in ACC’s School of Business, is
        an educator that goes above and beyond what’s expected of her
        — and then some.
          “Amanda has dedicated herself to her students,” Bollman
        said.
          “She always puts her students’ needs first. She tries to make
        learning exciting as well as practical. Amanda works hard to
        ensure her students have the skills they need to enter the
        workforce. She has gone as far as setting up assignments in
        conjunction with industry leaders. This has given us exposure
        to the Human Resources world. We have been given a small
        snapshot of what our careers may look like.
          “Amanda does not shy away from any task she is handed.
        She is continually upgrading her education. Her experience in
        Human Resources is vast but she is always looking for new
        professional development opportunities to better herself and
        the quality of education she provides to her students. She gives
        career, educational and emotional support and advice. She is
        always willing to go the extra mile for anyone who crosses her
        path. She is genuinely an inspiration and the world is a better
        place because of her. I am blessed to have crossed paths with
        such an amazing woman.”
          McGregor was teary when informed of the high praise
        Bollman had heaped upon her, and said while she’s grateful
        and humbled that her student thinks so highly of her, being
        nominated for a Community Leader Award is somewhat
        daunting.
          “I feel a bit overwhelmed by this whole thing,” she said. “What
        I do isn’t unusual or extraordinary. But it is so nice, especially
        coming from Amber, who has very high standards for herself,
        and for her to think that of me means a lot.”
          While she works hard to stay up-to-date with the HR industry
        and bring fresh perspectives to the classroom, McGregor said
        she really loves learning new things and sharing those discoveries
        with her pupils.
          “I have a real enthusiasm for it,” she said. “What I try to be
        is a helper as much as I can. I’ve had tons of people in my life
        who have helped me see potential in myself when I didn’t see
        it, so I just try to do the same.”
          McGregor also said she found out early on that education
        can be the key to success.
          “If you get an education it opens doors — it’s the best gift
        you can give yourself,” she said. “So to be a small part of seeing
        people better their lives, and the lives of their families, is really
        gratifying.
          “And if I can get them excited about learning and education,
        that’s wonderful to me. The highlight of my career is that I get
        to be part of something that is really important to people.”  Assiniboine Community College business administration instructor Amanda McGregor. (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)
          While she’s eager to help her students along the way, she
        refuses to take credit for their accomplishments.       of this (Community Leader) recognition because I think what  “But I work with a bunch of teachers who do an even better
          “The success the students have is their success, not mine,”  I do every day is pretty average. I think I owe it to the students  job than I can do. And I think there are lots of other teachers
        McGregor said.                                          to walk into the classroom with enthusiasm and to give the best  who are way better at things than I am who are more worthy
          “I’m just a very small part of it.  I feel somewhat unworthy  I have to give. And I think I do that.          of recognition.”

        Chorale founder shares her love for music with students




        BY DIANE NELSON

          The list of Liz Grant’s accomplishments could likely
        fill an entire newspaper.
          And the number of lives she’s impacted through her
        music teaching and choir directing might possibly
        round out two editions.
          Which is why she was nominated anonymously,
        but with a number of enthusiastic references, for the
        Community Leader Award in Teaching.
          Grant, who is now 70, founded the Brandon     love of singing and choral works in me,” said
        Conservatory Chorale in 1981 as a Master’s thesis  McLenehan.
        project. What began with 14 singers grew to 100 in  Kendra McFarland, now of Kelowna, B.C., sang
        the next eight years. That the Chorale continues today,  in the chorale from 1995 to 2013. She described
        37 years later, with 71 choristers and Grant still  Grant’s leadership as “educational, thoughtful and
        wielding the baton, is nothing short of remarkable –  direct.” She deemed Grant a great mentor who had
        and rare.                                       a major influence on the person she is today.
          Thousands of youngsters have had their musical  “She teaches a lot of life values — not just about
        chops honed in the Chorale, which exists under the  paying attention and learning musically from her —
        auspices of Brandon University’s Eckhardt-Gramatte  but also how to get through challenges and struggles
        Conservatory of Music. The groups that perform  in life,” she said.
        under the umbrella of the Chorale include the     Victoria Rust joined the Chorale in 2003 when she
        Apprentice Choir (for children in Kindergarten to  was only five years old, and stayed for 13 years. She
        Grade 3), the Concert Choir (for children in Grade 4  said Grant was “extremely patient and dedicated,”
        and up), the Chamber Choir for treble singers up to  and was grateful for Grant’s guidance as a “piano
        Grade 12, and an adult choir, Bel Canto.        teacher, voice instructor, audition coach, choral
          A gala concert, “Celebrating Liz,” was held at the  director and part-time parent.”
        end of April, and dozens of former Chorale members  Before the Chorale was formed, Grant was the
        came from far and wide to acknowledge their deep  Music Director at First Presbyterian Church, a
        respect, boundless affection and never-ending gratitude  position she still holds today, 45 years after she first
        for their talented conductor, and to work with her  began.
        once again.                                       “I was just a babe when I went there,” she said with
          Grant’s choirs have performed around the world,  a grin.
        including in England, Italy and France — and in 1991  Being nominated for a Community Leader Award
        and 1995 at the prestigious Carnegie Hall in New  in Teaching also makes her smile.  “It’s wonderful,”
        York City.                                      Grant said. “I was thrilled and honoured and
          “It was a very thrilling experience,” Grant said of  humbled.”
        the Carnegie Hall concerts in a recent Brandon Sun  When asked what continues to fuel her desire and
        story. “Very surreal, especially when you walked in  passion, she answered enthusiastically and frankly.
        there and you realized all the people that had been on  “It’s the music and people,” she said. “I get so much
        this stage before. It was very exciting.”       back from my students and my choristers that I can’t
          Many of Grant’s former pupils have made music  imagine doing anything else. And I’m certainly not
        their life’s work, saying she inspired them to have  retiring – some people thought the Celebrate Liz
        confidence, demand the best of themselves, and  concert was my retirement. No!”
        embrace music fully and completely.               And while she accepts that she’s been a major
          And as if the Chorale groups weren’t enough, Grant  influence on thousands of singers over her decades
        conceived and conducted a community choir, which  of musical activity, she said that’s a two-way street.
        performed at the Beijing Olympics in 2008. That event  “I get inspiration from them to continue on,” Grant
        was a highlight for Nicole McLenehan, who sang in  said. “It’s teamwork. I’m not a loner. I’ve got
        the Chorale from 1983 to 1989. Now the music teacher  wonderful support. And at my church, too. I’ll just
        at Tanner’s Crossing School in Minnedosa, and   keep building on what I’ve got.”
        involved in community musicals and performing     While the outpouring of love from her former
        groups, she told the Brandon Sun that Grant was an  students and choristers is thrilling, being nominated
        ongoing inspiration.                            for a Community Leader Award is especially
          “So many of my most memorable musical         meaningful.
        experiences have been in performances with her at  “It’s the community at large – it’s not just the music
        the helm and I am very grateful she has instilled a  community,” Grant said. “That makes it very special.”  Elizabeth Grant is being recognized for her contributions through education. (Submitted)]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[CONGRATULATIONS






               to all of the Community





               Leaders Award Recipients!















               Thank you for everything you do to make



               our community a better place.]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018 • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                          COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018  • 17

        » ENVIRONMENTAL LEADER AWARD, SPONSORED BY KOCH FERTILIZER








































































         Mireille Saurette is an environmental leader in the community. She has volunteered a lot of her time doing things like picking up garbage. (Melissa Verge/Brandon Sun)
        Saurette cleaning up her community one piece at a time




        BY MELISSA VERGE                                                                                                  Saurette also makes a point of recycling clothes and other
                                                                                                                        items so she doesn’t create unnecessary waste.
          For Mireille Saurette, 200 days over the past two years have                                                    She’s been part of the Brandon Environment Committee for
        involved picking up garbage.                                                                                    the past five years. She’s also a strong advocate for fair trade,
          It’s gross, smelly, and seemingly thankless work, but Saurette                                                which has its own impacts on the environment.
        doesn’t do it for the recognition.                                                                                “In conventional trade things can get moved around a lot like
          She has volunteered a lot of her time to helping the                                                          form one side of the world to the other, and it’s a real drain on
        environment and doing things such as picking up garbage,                                                        transport costs and has major environmental costs,” she said.
        because it’s something she cares deeply about. It’s a way she                                                   “The supply chain in the fair-trade market is shortened
        can help make the community of Brandon as well as the world  take care of it, but not the only one.             substantially.”
        a cleaner, better place.                                  Protecting the environment is something that she believes so  The volunteer work Saurette does in the community easily
          Her garbage pick-up sometimes takes place where she works  strongly about that she encouraged her partner to get rid of the  adds up to 20 hours a week, but she doesn’t pick up garbage or
        by the Assiniboine Community College in Brandon, or near  SUV they owned for a more environmentally friendly vehicle.  stay involved with the Brandon Environment Committee to be
        her house. Sometimes it’s by Clear Lake in Riding Mountain  “I just can’t drive that, I can’t,” she said.       recognized. For Saurette, it’s all about ensuring the planet is as
        National Park. Wherever she is, she makes a point to spend 30  So, they switched over to a hybrid vehicle.      well taken care of as possible.
        minutes picking up garbage, or until she fills a bag, whichever  With an environmentally friendly car, Saurette still tries to  “I believe in protecting Mother Earth because she is greatest
        comes first.                                            reduce the amount of time she spends behind the wheel. She  mother, and we need to honour that relationship,” she said.
          “Our environment is our home, we depend on it everyday,”  often makes a point of biking to work when the weather is  “If we’re on auto pilot and we just kind of go with the motions
        Saurette said. “We’re interconnected to the water that we drink  warm.                                          and try to keep up with the Jones’ and get that latest toy or
        and the food that we eat, if we take care of the planet it takes  “Every choice we make has an impact on the planet and in  whatever, those actions have repercussions on our planet.”
        care of us.”                                            the world, and I want to be a role model for citizens in Brandon,”  » mverge@brandonsun.com
          Picking up litter is one of the ways the 44-year-old is helping  she said.                                    » Twitter: @Melverge5

        Teacher enlists another generation of environmental stewards



        BY TYLER CLARKE

          Instilling her love of environmental stewardship in the students
        she teaches, Coleen McKellar has proven herself a leader in the
        the field.
          Growing up, the Crocus Plains
        Secondary School teacher said that she
        was always interested in the sciences,
        but that there was something about
        becoming a researcher that didn’t quite
        resonate with her.
          With education the closes thing she
        could do to remain in the sciences, she
        became a teacher.
          It’s a decision that she has remained
        satisfied with, and which she proudly
        notes has resulted in others taking up the environmental causes
        she’s passionate about.
          “I have managed to pass, I think, some of the knowledge
        along, and hopefully it’ll make a bit of a difference,” she said.
        “I just want people to be aware that little things make a
        difference, and every little bit helps.”
          In addition to teaching environmentally-themed classes to
        Crocus Plains students, McKellar also brought Water Festival
        to Brandon, which since 2010 has taught environmental
        stewardship and water conservation to grades 1 to 4 students
        from throughout Brandon.
          Crocus Plains students walk the younger students through a
        number of stations, which teach them the implications of things
        like brushing their teeth with the water off while doing so, and
        taking shorter showers.
          McKellar said that the students tend to take these messages
        home with their parents and become teachers themselves.
          On the teaching front, she said that Crocus Plains students
        also learn how to instruct others in environmental stewardship,
        which allows the passion to spread even wider.
          “The big kids are so good with the little kids,” she said. “A
        big smile always comes on their face when they see them.”
          McKellar also helps organize the annual Envirothon at the
        Riverbank Discovery Centre, which has high school students
        from across the region compete in various areas of
        environmental stewardship.                              Crocus Plains Regional Secondary School Science teacher Coleen McKellar is pictured in her classroom. (Tyler Clarke/The Brandon Sun)
          These and other efforts are fuelled by what McKellar’s drive
        to keep the world a healthy place to live for future generations.  that live in the water, that’s the basis for our food chain, and if  with.
          But, it’s not long-term ideas such as this that she said best  the food chain goes away how do we feed ourselves?”  It’s this trickle down impact of our actions which she strives
        fuels others’ passion to help out, but the more immediate real-  While Manitobans are lucky to have an abundance of clean  to install in her students, whom she said spread the web of
        world implications of their actions.                    water, she said that we’re also expanding farmland and taking  information far beyond the school’s walls.
          As such, she said that this is what she tends to focus on.  away wetlands, which help absorb this water and prevent  » tclarke@brandonsun.com
          “We need a healthy place to live, and if we kill off the things  flooding such as those Westman residents are all to familiar  » Twitter: @TylerClarkeMB]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[18  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                          THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018

        » ABOVE & BEYOND AWARD, SPONSORED BY GUILD INSURANCE BROKERS































































        Steve and Joanne Malkowich. (Jim Mihaly/The Brandon Sun)
        Couple filling their retirement by helping others





        BY DIANE NELSON                                         background, volunteered at the BRHA greeting patients before  Steve also thinks Brandon should be doing more to promote
                                                                their surgeries to give them an encouraging word.”      itself. And if he ever came into a bunch of money, he knows
          Steve and Joanne Malkowich are nothing if not busy.     According to Lamont, Steve and Joanne also volunteer  exactly what he’d do with.  “There are other things we need,”
          All. The. Time.                                       regularly at St. Augustine of Canterbury Church.        he said. “If you’re driving down the Trans-Canada Hightway,
          Since returning to the Wheat City 25 years ago, the now 82-  They greet people at the door, are Eucharistic ministers and  what would make you stop in Brandon? I’ve told (Brandon
        year-olds have been volunteering their time and support for  are part of the church’s CWL (Catholic Women’s’ League) and  Mayor) Rick Chrest if I ever won the lottery, you know the East
        numerous organizations, giving everything they can for the  the Knights of Columbus.                            End water tower? How about a gondola from there up to ACC
        betterment of their beloved Brandon.                      Within their seniors’ complex, they’ve helped organize the  (the North Hill Campus)? Wouldn’t that make all kinds of people
          From attending concerts and musical productions to watching  annual garage sale, the monthly Happy Hours and take their  stop in?”
        the Wheat Kings, volunteering for the Riverbank Centre, helping  turn assisting with Friday morning coffee. They’ve continued  Steve also thinks it’s important that more be done to encourage
        with the Rotary Book sale, selling poppies for Legion, the  to do these things as they’ve aged, as giving back to the  young people to remain in Brandon.
        Malkowiches have done it all. They’ve volunteered for Tourism  community is something they both believe in.       “A lot of money is spent foolishly and it should be focused
        Brandon, the Royal Manitoba Winter Fair, curling events,  “Often, I receive phone calls from their friends and family  on the kids,” he said. “If you have stuff for them to do and they
        Canada Day celebrations, and the Arabian Horse show.    asking where Steve and Joanne are, and all I know is that they  like it here, they’re not going to move away – they’re going to
          “They are delighted to ask visitors where they are from, and  are volunteering somewhere,” Lamont said.  While both  stay.”
        eager to direct them to places to eat and shop in the community  Malkowiches are keen to offer assistance wherever it’s needed,  Joanne credits all of her volunteering to her innate enjoyment
        of Brandon,” said nominator Louise Lamont, their daughter.  Steve has a particular fondness for helping out the city’s youth,  of people and a strong desire to make Brandon an even better
          “Steve was the person that believed we needed a skateboard  hence his involvement in the Kristopher Campbell Memorial  place to call home.
        park and spent countless hours talking to the city and community  Skate Plaza.                                    “It’s just my personality,” she said. “I love Brandon – I enjoy
        leaders to find the funds to build the Kristopher Campbell  “When I was doing security at The Towne Centre, there were  living here – we’ve been back for 25 years.
        Memorial Skate Plaza. Before this occurred, Steve could often  all these signs that said ‘No Skateboarding,’” Steve said. “And  “We get out and we socialize and we make friends.”
        be found down at the old park checking on the youth and  I thought, ‘If they can’t skateboard here, where are they going  And there’s no end to the contributions she’s interested in
        establishing relationships with them. Joanne, having a nursing  to go?’”                                        making.

        Iwasiuk has been helping women for decades




        BY DIANE NELSON                                without her tireless efforts.”
                                                         It’s Iwasiuk’s quiet compassion mixed with an
          Being nominated for a Community Leader Award  upbeat and positive approach that make her so
        is a lovely thing. But knowing that you’ve helped  wonderful, Campbell said. And Iwasiuk said seeing
        change even one person’s life for the better is reward  her clients not only survive, but thrive, is a source of
        enough for Kim Iwasiuk.                        tremendous satisfaction.  “I’m truly hopeful that
          “I’m surprised and overwhelmed,” Iwasiuk said of  things can get better for folks,” she said. “And I think
        the nomination. “Because I’m just doing my job.”  it’s that hope that keeps me going. And you get these
          When Iwasiuk, a Women’s Resource Centre      amazing moments that actually propel you forward.”
        counsellor who focuses primarily on cases of domestic  One of the reasons Iwasiuk is such a sympathetic
        violence and sexual assault, learned her nominator  and supportive advocate is because she’s lived through
        was a former client, Leah Campbell, she struggled to  some of the same experiences her clients have. And
        contain her emotions.  “Knowing it was Leah just  that empathy, and her eagerness to do all she can to
        makes me feel more overwhelmed and grateful,”  assist, sets her apart in the eyes of the women she
        Iwasiuk said. “I’m so honoured to be thought about.  advises.
        This is bringing me to tears – I had no idea.    “From myself personally, I think that lived
        Sometimes we just do this work and we don’t know  experience is what helps me continue to help others,”
        the impact we have on individuals and families.”  Iwasiuk said. “Because it can get better. There’s help.”
          According to Campbell, Iwasiuk has been      That wasn’t the case in the days before The Women’s
        supporting the women of Brandon for more than  Resource Centre came into being. But while external
        three decades at The Women’s Resource Centre.  supports weren’t available, Iwasiuk said she had a
        Iwasiuk, along with her co-workers, is responsible for  wonderful grandmother who was her rock.
        providing training to emergency personnel and those  “And often there’s this amazing family member
        involved in handling domestic violence and sexual  that is just there,” she said. “So I come back to that
        assault situations. The training includes teaching them  collective family, that connection, all the time.
        what they might expect from victims, how best to  “Counselling happens for an hour once a week or
        deal with them, and about the services and help that  more. But it’s also encouraging women to be
        can be found in and around the community.      empowered themselves. Because we all have those
          In the wake of the #metoo movement, Campbell  tools in our toolkit. So it’s not just a hand out – it’s a
        said, community support workers like Iwasiuk are  hand up. And it’s building a safety net for these
        doing what they’ve always done – going above and  women – who’s your friend, who’s your sister, who’s
        beyond to ensure all women have access to the  your grandmother.
        supports, counselling and help they need. Whether  “So it’s holistic — that’s the word I use. It’s a
        it’s helping them transition to a new stage of life, deal  collective that comes together to support and to
        with the aftermath of a traumatic experience, or have  advocate for this person or family.”
        someone with whom to attend meetings,            Iwasiuk credits not only her co-workers, but also
        appointments, and other engagements, Campbell said  the Resource Centre’s board of directors, for making
        Iwasiuk has proven herself to be an outstanding  the Centre accomplishments so thorough and so
        community leader.                              valuable.  But there’s still plenty more to be done.
          “Through our working relationship, starting in  “We need to change systems,” Iwasiuk said. “Women
        2014, she has become much more than just my    need to make a living wage and have accessibility to
        counsellor and advocate,” Campbell wrote in her  housing – that’s one of the things that keeps women
        nomination letter. “Kim has taken on the role of  in domestic violence. And making sure women have
        mentor, support, friend, and even family, filling  more of an understanding of the justice system –
        whatever void necessary to ensure I have a well-  that’s always a challenge.”  While Iwasiuk said her
        rounded support system in my life. I cannot even  retirement is a long way off, when it does comes, she
        imagine the countless number of other women in  still plans to be an activist for women.
        Brandon and area that she has helped in this way. I  “I don’t think there’s a top for me,” she said. “If
        would not be the person I am today without her  somebody needs something, I’m going to advocate
        continued support and hard work.               for them as best I can. I just do the work. And it’s
          “Kim’s role in the community is an excellent  more than that for me. This is my life. I just hope at
        example of a person going above and beyond to serve  the end of the day I have done some small part so  Kim Iwasiuk, supervising women's counsellor with the Women's Resource Centre in
        others, and I do not think Brandon would be the same  that women can live happy lives.”        Brandon. (Matt Goerzen/The Brandon Sun)]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[CONGRATULATIONS TO ALL THE



                                         COMMUNITY LEADERSHIP WINNERS!




                                             Thanks for everything you do to make our


                                                              community a better place.










                                          ENJOY

























                                                             THE

























                                           VIEW!






































                                       PROVIDING PEACE OF MIND THROUGH INSURANCE



                                                       AND RISK MANAGEMENT SOLUTIONS




                                   At Guild HMS, we take a panoramic view of your entire life and


                                     business to ensure you are properly covered. So you can sit


                                                                back, relax, and enjoy the view.







                                  GUILD INSURANCE BROKERS & HMS INSURANCE AGENCIES


                                                                 www.guildhmsinsurance.ca]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[20  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                          THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018

        » COURAGE/BRAVERY AWARD, SPONSORED BY TIM HORTONS



























































        Former Brandon Wheat Kings defenceman Don Dietrich of Deloraine has remained busy following his Parkinson’s diagnosis. (Perry Bergson/The Brandon Sun)
        Mentor forges a path forward, despite the challenges of Parkinson’s



        BY DIANE NELSON                                         Dietrich has also mentored all the local community teams as  “I also have a great family that’s been with me a hundred per
                                                                well as the Southwest Midget AAA Cougars team. He’s a   cent through the whole thing.”
          Not many people are able to say they’ve accomplished their  member of Canada’s National Coach Mentorship Program and  Dietrich is tremendously honoured to be nominated for a
        life’s ultimate goal. But Deloraine’s Don Dietrich can.  was inducted into the Manitoba Hockey Hall of Fame in 2011  Community Leader Award, saying he was “very surprised”
          “I actually am a very lucky man – I got to live the dream,”  in the Builders’ category.                       when he heard the news.
        the now 57-year-old said. “And my dream was to play in the  “And you can’t think about Don without appreciating how  “That’s so nice!” he said.
        National Hockey League. I was drafted underage by Chicago  much courage and bravery he displays every day while fighting  According to Crepeele, it’s hard not to be inspired by a story
        in 1980 – I played 17 games with them and I also played 11  with his own body,” Crepeele said.                  such as his, of a life well lived despite tremendous difficulties.
        games with New Jersey.                                    “Throughout all of these accomplishments since being home,  “In 1999, that’s when I had my first cancer surgery,” Dietrich
          “Then I played more than 350 American Hockey League   he has also accomplished living life with Parkinson’s. One year  said. “They gave me six to nine months then.
        games. And I played in Germany and Switzerland as a player  after moving back to Deloraine at the young age of 34, Don  “I guess when I was told that, I think I cried for about 20
        and assistant coach. I developed a coaching strategy over there:  was diagnosed with this incurable disease. But he was  seconds. And I could hear all my good coaches over my life tell
        When in doubt, I’d just put myself out!”                determined … that it wouldn’t stop him from doing the things  me to get up off the ice. Get up and play the game of life.”
          That his sense of humour remains intact is only part of the  he loves.                                          Which he’s certainly done. But while he never complains, he’s
        reason nominator Breigh Crepeele felt Dietrich was worthy of  “He also didn’t let his first, second or third diagnoses with  frank about the fact that dealing with his disease is no picnic.
        being a contender for the Community Leader Bravery and  cancer deter him. And throughout all his health battles, he never  “Every day is a struggle with Parkinson’s – I always refer to him
        Courage Award. Through his hockey accomplishments, Dietrich  stopped giving back to his community and his sport. Don is a  as ‘my old pal’ because everywhere I go, he goes,” Dietrich said.
        has inspired others to follow their dreams, and over the years  true inspiration for all ages and this is evident in his courageous  “He’s not invited, but he’s always there.”
        has been a mentor for coaches, for parents and for young players.  fight to live ‘his’ life, and he should be commended for the  When asked if he had any words of wisdom to offer others
          Born and raised in Deloraine, Dietrich moved back there with  bravery he shows every day to keep moving forward despite his  who might now or one day be fighting the same battles he is,
        his wife and three sons in 1994 after his days of playing  many health challenges.”                             Dietrich was straightforward.  “I consider myself a warrior,”
        professional hockey were through. Since then, he’s constantly  So where does that sort of determination come from? Dietrich  he said. “Every day I have to get up and fight. And sometimes
        volunteered his time to help young hockey players improve their  credits his favourite sport with giving him the courage and the  you don’t win the war but you win the battle.
        skills, and also assisted in developing the Breakfast Club program  acceptance to take things as they come and be grateful for each  “I’m a real believer in you’ve got to play the cards you’re dealt.
        in Deloraine which has since spread across Manitoba. Free of  day.  “I think it’s been more or less my hockey background that’s  I wrote a book called ‘No Guarantees,’ and in that book I made
        charge, kids attend the rink in the early morning hours, where  helped with that,” Dietrich said. “Knowing that you have to  the statement, that that’s why I love sports so much, because
        they’re coached for 40 minutes and have 20 minutes to play  play the card you’re dealt. In hockey, you don’t get to pick the  you never know the outcome. And such is life, right? You never
        around on the ice, then are fed breakfast and sent to school.  team you line up against.                        know what’s going to happen day to day.”
        Mother’s devotion perseveres following the tragic loss of her husband



        BY DIANE NELSON

          For journalists, a passion for meeting, talking with and
        discovering more about people is a mandatory part of the job.
        And while everyone is fascinating for one reason or another,
        and everybody has a story — or many stories — to tell, over
        the course of a career, there are certain folks who just stand out.
          That was certainly the case for former Brandon Sun reporter
        Ian Froese.
          When he talked with Caryn Waldon and wrote her story for
        Sun readers, he was tremendously moved by her strength in the
        face of terrible tragedy. So touched was he, in fact, that he
        nominated the young woman for the Community Leader Award
        in the Courage/Bravery category.
          Waldon was pregnant with her and her husband Bryce’s first
        child when Bryce died suddenly while building their dream
        home in December of last year. Sophia Bryce Waldon was born
        on Feb. 9, and rather than wallowing in the depths of her grief,
        Caryn Waldon is instead focused on the miracle that is her
        daughter.
          “I’m so blessed to have Soph,” she said.
          “And I got that from Bryce. She makes it easier for me to be
        happy because she makes me happy.
        And she has his smile. That was one
        of the things I loved most about him,
        was his smile. So every day when I
        walk through that door and get Soph
        from her crib and she smiles at me, I
        know today’s going to be a good day.”
          That’s not to say that Waldon doesn’t
        have down times, when she sheds tears
        over her loss, the fact that Sophia will
        never meet her father and that Bryce didn’t have the chance to
        be a parent. But she credits a legion of supporters for helping
        her through the roughest of times.                      Caryn Waldon holds her daughter Sophia Bryce Waldon in Sophia's nursery at her home in Brandon's south end. Caryn's husband Bryce
          “I’m just doing what I have to do,” Waldon said. “I couldn’t  passed away while Caryn was pregnant with Sophia. The nursery is full of reminders of Bryce including photos and a stuffed bear made
        have gotten through it without Bryce’s parents and my parents  out of some of his clothing.  (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
        and the communities rallying around me – and his friends even.
        I had about ten people a day texting me. No one ever left me  real help, Waldon said, to talk to someone who really understood  Waldon has found particular inspiration in her Uncle Brad,
        alone, even when I was grumpy.”                         what she was going through.                             who’s lost a son, a wife and a grandon. “And he’s a very good
          Waldon said being nominated for a Community Leader      And sadly, she said, her and Jarvis’s situation is not all that  help to me because I just look at him and how he stays so
        Award was “overwhelming” and said that she’s just doing what  uncommon.                                         positive,” Waldon said through tears. “He’s lost more than I
        she has to do to continue to live.  “I don’t really think I’m that  When Waldon heard about Oak River’s Kaitlyn Ramsey, who  have and I admire how he goes through every day being
        brave,” she said.                                       is currently pregnant with her second child and whose husband  positive.”
          “It was all those people who helped me. They’re the ones who  Marty was killed in a snowmobile accident on March 11 of this  The people who helped her when Bryce died and who
        are brave. If I’m ever having a really bad day, I can call any one  year, Waldon paid it forward and contacted Ramsey to offer  continue to do so to this day, along with Jarvis and Ramsey and
        of those people and they’ll bring me back. So that’s where I get  her support. The two are now each other’s best friends and  Waldon’s Uncle Brad, are the real award-worthy heroes in
        my courage, if you want to call it that. From all the people who  biggest supporters, bonded by mutual tragedy.  Waldon’s estimation.
        are there for me. So I don’t know if I deserve an award.”  “Kaitlyn and I — we text every day,” Waldon said. “We both  “They’re the ones who were brave,” she said. “In a way, there’s
          When word of Waldon’s tragedy spread throughout the   had a Plan A, and Plan A didn’t work, so we’ve adopted Plan  a lot of people who have been through a lot worse things that I
        Brandon and Deloraine communities, Waldon was contacted  B — that’s what we call it. Taking things one day at a time. We  have. This is kind of what I had to do, and Bryce wouldn’t want
        by Jenny Jarvis, whose husband Blaine had died in a     have to move forward – not move on, but move forward.   me to be sad for the rest of my life. He’d want me to be there
        snowmobile accident when their child was a year old. It was a  Develop a new normal. Together we’re doing that.”  for Soph.”]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[In memory of Craig Pardy






                                       Proudly Salutes








                                                             all of the







                            Community Leader








                                  Award Nominees
















                                                                                                          th
                                                   Shoppers Mall, 18 Street,



                                     Victoria Avenue, BRHC, #1 Highway,




                                            Virden, and Neepawa locations




                                              are proud supporters of many




                                               Westman community events.













                                              Congratulations to






                                                                 all those in






                                                  Westman who go







                                                     “Above and








                                                                Beyond”]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[22  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                          THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018

        » SERVICE ORGANIZATION VOLUNTEER AWARD, SPONSORED BY WESTOBA CREDIT UNION




























































        George Haggerty is nominated for a Community Leader Award in the Service Organization Volunteer category. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
        Haggerty a devoted mentor to local Cadets





        BY DIANE NELSON                                         Certificate for years of dedicated service, Lifetime Membership,  He’s volunteered for the Brandon & District United Way, as
                                                                Certificates of Appreciation from Vice-Admiral Chief of the  a sandbagger for the 2011 Flood of the Century, and for Hillcrest
          Born and raised in Brandon, George Haggerty has dedicated  Maritime Staff, and the Detachment Commander’s Outstanding  Place Personal Care Home. Haggerty was active on the City of
        much of his life to Brandon’s Royal Canadian Sea Cadets and  Achievement Award and Certificate of Service. He is proud of  Brandon’s Veterans’ Memorial Committee and Wall of
        Navy League Cadets, as well as the Navy League of Canada  his CIC Lifetime Achievement through the Department of  Remembrance, has helped out with the 26 Field Regiment RCA
        Brandon Branch.                                         National Defence.                                       XII Manitoba Dragoons Museum since 2012, and has been the
          His list of accomplishments is vast and impressive, as is his  But was working with the Royal Canadian Sea Cadets, the  organizer of the Battle of Atlantic Parade Brandon since 2013.
        selfless dedication to the many causes with which he has been  Navy League Cadets and the Navy League of Canada all he  When he’s not doing those things, he canvasses for the
        involved and championed.                                did? Not by a long shot! References Debbie McArthur of the  Canadian Cancer Society and Diabetes Canada. And when
          A Navy League Cadet from age 11 to 13, Haggerty became  Cadets and Sharon Fisher of the Canadian Cancer Society call  downtown Brandon suffered its devastating fire on May 19th,
        a Sea Cadet until he was 18. He then volunteered to work with  Haggerty “a perfect example of volunteerism!”    Haggerty heard there was a need for people to help sort clothing
        the Navy League Corps as a cadet officer. Haggerty also worked  Consistent and reliable, they say, his “can do” attitude has  for the displaced residents of Massey Manor. So he stepped up
        with the Royal Canadian Sea Cadet Corps Swiftsure as an officer  helped several entities successfully complete many projects.    to help do that as well.  So why all the effort? Why not sit back
        in the mid-1970s.                                         “George is a team player and a valuable member of the many  and enjoy retirement?
          He’s held many positions within Cadets, including     organizations who are lucky enough to have him as a volunteer,”  “I think I like to be busy,” Haggerty said. “And I think there’s
        Commanding Officer. While he and his ilk were referred to as  Fisher and McArthur said. “Many of the people who have  a community need. There’s always a need for people to step up
        Cadet Instructor Cadre, in the mid-1990s they became Naval  worked with him in these various organizations consider him  and help out.”
        Reserves and part of the Department of National Defence. In  to be a mentor. His whole life has been dedicated to youth and  His aim is always “to make everybody’s life a little better.”
        the late 1990s he became the Cadet Harassment and Abuse  ensuring our society creates compassionate and responsible  And he says he receives as much from volunteering as he gives.
        Prevention Officer and took the certification course to teach  citizens. Many compliments have been made to the Sea Cadet  “Oh – I get so much back!” he said. “Kenny Vanderhooft (his
        abuse and harassment prevention to cadets.              Corps for this.”                                        Little Brother) did as much for me as I did for him. It was a
          In 2010, Haggerty “aged out” from being in uniform, and  Haggerty was also a Big Brother in 1972 and is still in touch  good match.”
        retired from the Naval Reserves as a Lieutenant (N) that same  with his Little Brother Ken Vanderhooft. He was a media  It appears to be Haggerty’s nature to give and to lend a hand
        year.                                                   statistician in the 1980s for the City of Brandon’s International  when it’s necessary. And he’s self-effacing, too.
          At the same time, Haggerty wore many hats with the Navy  Hockey Tournament of Champions. He was a member, then  “I think there’s a lot of people out there who do a lot of good,”
        League of Canada Brandon Branch, including those of     Co-Chair, of the Friends of HMCS Brandon Committee from  Haggerty said. “It’s humbling to be acknowledged this way. For
        President and Vice President. He’s received many accolades  1999 to 2017, as well as a member, then Chair, of Brandon  me to be nominated for an award like this is overwhelming —
        and honours from the Navy League of Canada: an Honour   Salutes.                                                it’s quite a privilege.”


        Rotarian spending her retirement doing ‘rewarding’ volunteer work



        BY MELISSA VERGE

          Dayle Hughson was in her car delivering flowers for Mother’s
        Day — one of the many projects this Sunset Rotary Club
        member is a part of —  when she got the call that she’d been
        nominated for a Community Leader Award.
          “It’s a great honour, I think that its nice to have volunteerism
        recognized,” she said, adding that just getting the phone call
        was exciting.
          Delivering flowers for Mother’s
        Day is one of the many projects that
        Hughson has volunteered to help out
        with in the community.
          She’s lived in Brandon for 15 years,
        and she estimates that she spends
        about 20 hours on average per week
        participating in various volunteer
        positions.
          She’s the director of the provincial exhibition as well as co-
        chair of the summer fair. She’s also a member of the Sunset
        Rotary Club, which does a lot of volunteer work around the
        community, including the highly popular new event, Ribfest,
        and providing guest services at the summer and winter fairs.
        She’s also involved with Child and Family Services of Westman,
        and she works with the Interprovincial Association for Native
        Employment.
          It’s a lot of commitments, but Hughson said working full-
        time before she retired was good practice for the amount of
        time she spends volunteering. For 32 years she worked for a
        private company that was involved with employing individuals
        with handicaps and disabilities, something that she has continued
        to stay involved with through volunteer work.
          “I’m kind of used to scheduling things and being able to do
        two or three things at once, women can multitask,” Hughson
        said.
          At 71-years-old she’s been retired since 2012, and volunteering
        is a very important part of her life now.
          “It keeps you from getting bored and old it keeps me young
        because I’m working with the young people,” Hughson said.
          She recalls one memorable moment she had as a volunteer  Dayle Hughson is involved with many different things in the Brandon community, including the Sunset Rotary Club. Here, Hughson
        with the Rotary Club at the Brandon Correctional Centre. The  delivers free Pete the Cat books to children in Marla Medwid's grade one class at Riverview School. (Tim Smith/Brandon Sun)
        club donates books to the program, and inmates who have
        children take the books and read them onto a recorded CD.  It helps that her commitments are spaced out a little bit, and  she said that other people, who maybe have yet to give it a try,
        They then send the book and CD to the inmate’s child, who  that some don’t require as much work as others so that Hughson  would really enjoy doing.
        can then hear their parent reading stories to them.     is able to juggle them all.                               “It’s very interesting and rewarding work, I’m sure that
          “Somebody told me that the mother was reading to her    “Some just entitle a meeting once a month, so that’s not too  anybody that wanted to get involved with any organization as
        daughter, and when they brought the little one to visit she  much,” she said.                                   a volunteer would really find it very interesting,” she said.
        recognized her mothers voice from the tape,” Hughson said.  Despite all the volunteer work she does in the community
        “She hadn’t seen her mother since she was very tiny, so that  with various organizations, Hughson doesn’t think she does  » mverge@brandonsun.com
        was really rewarding.”                                  anymore than the average person. Volunteering is something  » Twitter: @Melverge5]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[24  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                          THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018

        » COMMUNITY BUILDER AWARD, SPONSORED BY VANGUARD CATALYST CREDIT UNION




























































        Former Brandon Police Service chief Ian Grant sheds light on the legalization of recreational cannabis, during a public meeting last year. (Tyler Clarke/The Brandon Sun)
        Community Mobilization proponent commended




        BY JILLIAN AUSTIN

          Growing up on the east coast of Canada, Ian Grant recalled
        how the importance of “giving back” was instilled in him from
        a young age.
          “My folks always told me to give back to the community that
        you lived in — they did in many different ways,” Grant said.
          Perhaps it was that message that inspired him to pursue a
        career in law enforcement. He began his policing career with
        the RCMP in 1980, and served in Brandon, Wasagaming and
        Flin Flon detachments. In April 1985, he became a member of
        the Brandon Police Service. Grant served as Brandon’s chief of
        police from 2013 until his retirement in 2017 .
          Throughout his career, Grant was involved in many areas of
        the police department, from the tactical response unit to the
        crime division, and said he enjoyed them all.                                                                                               Brandon Police Service chief Ian
          “The one thing that really kind of stood out, is… the                                                                                     Grant fields questions about the
        community still respects, to a great extent, the work that police                                                                           2015 BPS annual report in mid-
        officers do,” he said. “And I think they look at police officers                                                                            2016. (ﬁle)
        as being leaders in the community — at least I hope that people
        do. And based on what my parents had taught me growing up,
        I really wanted to become involved in the community and make
        the community better.”                                  if he ever had the chance. That opportunity came about once  probation officer and other people had actually came and asked
          Grant was nominated for the Community Builder Award for  he became chief.                                     her if she needed help,” he said. “They weren’t there to arrest
        his many years of leadership and his efforts to spearhead  He received “overwhelming support” from the local    her, they weren’t there to assign blame to her, they were offering
        Community Mobilization in Brandon.                      community and its agencies, and the initiative officially launched  help and assistance.”
          Community  Mobilization  is the gathering together of  in Brandon in 2015.                                      This particular woman had been dealing with addictions
        government and non-government human service professionals  “(They) supplied fantastic people to sit at the Hub table that  issues, and CFS had been involved. With the help she received,
        for the purpose of identifying individuals or families who are  meets twice a week, to look at situations where people are at  she was able to get her life back on track.
        at acutely elevated risk. The goal is to reach out to individuals  acutely elevated risk,” Grant said. “They’ve done great work  “In the letter, she wrote… ‘it felt the help that you gave me
        or families and connect them to supports and services before  over the last few years.”                         took a 300-pound backpack off my back’,” he said.
        the situation escalates or a tragedy occurs.              Currently sitting at the Community Mobilization table are  Grant said after hearing this success story, it’s a reminder of
          Grant first heard about the concept at a conference in Regina  BPS, RCMP, Brandon School Division, Child and Family  how it is all worth the effort.
        back in 2011, where a former Prince Albert police chief spoke  Services of Western Manitoba, Dakota Ojibway Child and  “It wasn’t easy to get everybody to the table, and there was a
        about community mobilization in their city. It originated in  Family Services, Prairie Mountain Health, Probation Services,  lot of heavy lifting,” he said. “That’s one case… I’m sure other
        Glasgow, Scotland.                                      Brandon Correctional Centre, Westman Family Services and  people probably feel the exactly the same way.”
          “It was the first of its kind anywhere in Canada that took a  Brandon Friendship Centre.                        Grant said he feels “deeply honoured” to be nominated for a
        risk-driven approach to try and deal in a coordinated fashion  Grant is proud of the work being done, which he said has  community leader award.
        (with) the different human service agencies,” he said. “It was  had a positive impact on the community. He recalled one case  “I never really thought of myself that way but was just doing
        having an impact, and helping them to their job better and more  that has stayed with him, where a woman wrote a thank-you  what I felt I should do,” he said.
        effectively, to try and bring down their calls for service.”  letter, describing her situation.                 » jaustin@brandonsun.com
          Grant said he was inspired him to bring the idea to Brandon,  “She couldn’t actually believe that a police officer and a  » Twitter: @jillianaustin
        Fuelled by empathy and compassion, Longstreet tackles the meth crisis



        BY ERIN DEBOOY
          Kim Longstreet has walked the walk, and now she’s talking
        the talk.
          Always up to fight for the underdog, Longstreet has used her
        personal experience, empathy and passion to advocate for a
        better community.
          “I’m very touched that somebody feels that I’m worthy to put
        my name forward (for a Community Leader Award),”
        Longstreet said.
          “You do what you do because you know it’s the right thing
        to do. I don’t do what I do for people to tell me that I’m doing
        a great job or give me awards, I do it because if you don’t, who
        else is going to?”
          A member of the Brandon Bear Clan since the group’s
        inception last June, Longstreet said she has never missed a patrol.
          The group has embarked on 105 patrols so far, walking
        countless kilometres and dedicating numerous hours to making                                                                                Kim Longstreet has become an
        downtown Brandon a safer place.                                                                                                             advocate for more resources to
          Through the Bear Clan, Longstreet set up a GoFundMe page                                                                                  help with addiction recovery after
        within 24 hours of Massey Manor residents were evacuated                                                                                    watching her son deal with an
        from their home after a devastating fire ripped through                                                                                     addiction to methamphetamine.
        downtown Brandon on May Long Weekend, which has raised                                                                                      (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)
        more than $13,500 to date.
          But the biggest piece of Longstreet rests with the lack of
        resources in the community for people who are struggling with  an wrote 11 letters to politicians from the federal level down,  Manitoba.
        substance abuse.                                        receiving responses from each and every one of them.      The foundation’s ultimate goal is to develop a healing centre
          Longstreet’s son is an IV meth user.                    She presented her struggles to city council and held a town  in the Westman area that will provide holistic (body, mind,
          In his 20s, Longstreet’s son started getting wrapped up in the  hall to discuss the addiction plaguing Brandon, sending a ripple  spirit) treatment for those that are struggling with substance use
        drug scene, she said. The first time she was aware there was a  effect through the community with her call to action.   disorders.
        problem was when he overdosed on ecstasy that had horse   Longstreet said she’s currently focused on helping the  Although sometimes the length of time things can take to
        tranquilizer in it.                                     Addictions Foundation of Manitoba expand their facility in  happen can be frustrating, Longstreet said she feels optimistic
          When meth came into the picture, her son became homeless.  Brandon in order to create long-term rehabilitation for recovering  that change is on the horizon.
        In more recent months, Longstreet said she has witnessed her  addicts.                                            “I’m a fighter, I’ve always been a fighter,” Longstreet said. “I
        son try and get help with his addiction, but wait times and short  Through her foundation, the RJ Streetz Foundation,  would rather give than receive … It’s really important to me to
        treatment programs have created a hindrance rather than  Longstreet said she plans to continue fundraising  to enhance  give back to the community.”
        providing help.                                         the programs and services for people who have substance abuse  » edebooy@brandonsun.com
          In May 2017, Longstreet took a leave of absence from work  issues, in conjunction with the Addictions Foundation of  » Twitter: @erindebooy]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[26  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                          THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JULY 21, 2018

        » YOUTH VOLUNTEER AWARD, SPONSORED BY BRANDON UNIVERSITY

        Newcomer already making a signifcant impact on Brandon



        BY MELISSA VERGE
          Martina Francisco has only been in
        Brandon for about a year, but she’s
        already making a significant impact in
        the community through her volunteer
        work.
          Francisco moved from the Philippines
        to Brandon when she was in Grade 10.
        Now, she’s in Grade 11 and staying
        involved with various programs
        including the Youth Revolution group, which creates and
        organized activities and events to reduce drug and alcohol use
        in children and youth.
          Francisco is also part of the Brandon Youth Ambassadors.
          Through these groups, she’s helped better the community
        of Brandon.
          The 17-year-old was part of the Push For Change Program
        that helped to raise awareness for homeless youth across
        Canada.
          The initiative was started by Joe Roberts, who was a
        homeless youth who decided to push a shopping cart across
        Canada to raise awareness about youth homelessness.
          Francisco  had a role in the initiative, “I provided support
        during the fundraising activities held here in Brandon,” she
        said.
          She’s also participated in bake sales to help raise funds for
        the Youth Centre.
          Her role volunteering in the community has not only
        benefited others, but also helped her adjust to life in Canada.
          “At first it was really challenging to start a new life here, but
        I think that volunteering also helped me adapt to the
        surroundings,” she said.
          “I met a lot of great friends which share the same idea of
        helping.”
          Francisco, who currently attends Vincent Massey High
        School in Brandon, has been able to get some of her classmates
        at school on board as well. Some are only in Grade 9 or Grade
        10, but are now helping out at the Brandon Youth Centre.
          “I feel like by doing the small things I can start inspiring
        other people to do the same, because it [volunteering] doesn’t
        really cost anything, just your time and your effort,” she said.
          She already has big goals for the future. They still involve
        helping people, just in a different way then she is now.
          “I’m planning to attend pre-medical school and probably be
        a doctor some day,” she said.
          Although Francisco doesn’t get paid for the work she does
        throughout the community on top of attending school, it’s
        rewarding for her in other ways.
          Like, when she see’s the benefit of the work she’s doing in
        the community, whether it’s something small like doing a bake
        sale, or helping out with the Push For Change program in
        Brandon.
          “I think this is a great opportunity to tell other people that
        volunteering is great and it’s not worthless, like you can gain
        something from it,” she said.

        » mverge@brandonsun.com
        » Twitter: @Melverge5



































                                                                                                                                                    Anna Zayvoda stands inside of
                                                                                                                                                    Vincent Massey High School
                                                                                                                                                    where she currently goes to
                                                                                                                                                    school. (Melissa Verge/Brandon Sun)



        Volunteering to help seniors a win-win for Zayvoda




        BY MELISSA VERGE                            It turned out to be beneficial to her as well as
                                                  the people she was helping out with her
          A year ago, Anna Zayvoda was living in  volunteer work.
        Ukraine and unable to speak English.        “Volunteering helped me learn English a lot
          Since the 17-year-old has moved to Brandon,  because a lot of people who I volunteer with
        she’s not only learned to speak the language but  help me to experience a lot of things and learn
        given a lot to the community through her  English,” she said.
        volunteer work. English is the newest of four  Zayvoda enjoys the social aspect of
        languages that Zayvoda speaks — the others  volunteering where she has met a lot of different
        are French, Russian, and Ukrainian.       people in the community.
          Since moving to Canada she’s become a     Besides the work she’s done with seniors,
        member of Youth Revolution at Vincent     she’s also volunteered at the Brandon Youth
        Massey School, where she’s in Grade 11. It’s a  Centre. There, she volunteered with kids where
        group that does charitable activities throughout  she played with them and kept them
        the community.                            entertained.
          One of the activities they recently did was  She also volunteered for the initiative Push
        visit a senior’s home in Brandon, where they  For Change, that helped to raise awareness for
        had cookies, talked, and played games.    homeless youth across Canada. The initiative
          Volunteering with seniors is something that  was started by Joe Roberts, who was a homeless
        Zayvoda really enjoys.                    youth who decided to push a shopping cart
          “I really like to help people, and help people  across Canada to raise awareness about youth
        who maybe don’t have enough communication  homelessness. Zayvoda helped raise money for
        with others, and some of them really needed  homeless youth by participating in various
        to talk to someone,” Zayvoda said.        fundraising events, such as a barbecue.
          She also enjoys the work she does with    For her, volunteering is becoming a part of
        senior’s specifically because of the knowledge  who she is and her daily life, “a hobby” as she
        they have to offer.                       called is.
          “They teach [me] some stuff, they’re really  “I feel happy after doing this because I know
        interesting people,” she said.            we’re helping people and maybe change
          She started volunteering not long after she  someone’s life,” she said.
        moved to Canada, when her English teacher at
        Vincent Massey brought it up to her after a  » mverge@brandonsun.com
        month of living in Brandon.               » Twitter: @Melverge5]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018 • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                          COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018  • 27
















                    Brandon Sun publisher
                       Jim Mihaly speaks
                         during the Sun’s
                       Community Leader
                      Awards presentation
                     at the Victoria Inn on
                     Wednesday evening.
                       (Photos by Tim Smith
                         /The Brandon Sun)

























































































        Award winners, finalists and those accepting awards on a winners behalf pose for a photo after The Brandon Sun's Community Leader Awards at the Victoria Inn on Wednesday evening.



















































        LEFT: Charles Tweed, left, and Rob Henderson mingle during the Community Leader Awards on Wednesday evening. RIGHT: Brandon Sun editor Matt Goerzen, left, and sales and marketing director Glen
        Parker MC the award presentation last night.]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[28  • COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018                                                                                          THE BRANDON SUN  • THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018































        LEFT: Service Organization Volunteer category finalist Dayle Hughson, Penny Burton with sponsor Westoba Credit Union and winner George Haggerty pose for a photo during the Brandon Sun’s Community
        Leader Awards at the Victoria Inn on Wednesday evening. MIDDLE: Youth Volunteer category finalist Anna Zayvoda, Rob Henderson representing sponsor Brandon University and winner Martina Francisco.
        RIGHT: Volunteer category finalist Mandy Wark Brown, Mike Brolund with sponsor Sunrise Credit Union and Pat Lelond accepting the award on behalf of winner Linda Clark. (Photos by Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)




          AWARD WINNERS

















































        LEFT: Courage & Bravery category finalist Caryn Waldon (second from left), sponsors Mackenzie Baird (left), Rhonda Party (centre), Brad Pardy (right) representing Tim Hortons in memory of Craig Pardy,
        and winner Don Dietrich (second from right). RIGHT: Emergency Services category finalist Randy Lewis, Brett Kotyk and Kendra Dyck with sponsor Joe Beeverz Canadian Pub and winner William Cheyne.





































        LEFT: Environmental Leader category finalist Coleen McKeller and winner Mireille Saurette pose for a photo on Wednesday evening. This category was sponsored by Koch Fertilizer. MIDDLE: Teacher
        category finalist Elizabeth Grant, Jeff Harwood representing sponsor Assiniboine Community College and Kristen Andrews accepting on behalf of winner Amanda McGregor. RIGHT: Seniors Advocate category
        finalist Mary Nichols and James Montgomery accepting the award on behalf of winner Gail Freeman-Campbell pose for a photo during The Brandon Sun’s Community Leader Awards at the Victoria Inn on
        Wednesday evening. Cando Rail Service sponsored this category.


























        LEFT: Above & Beyond category finalist Kim Iwasiuk, Nate Andrews with sponsor Guild Insurance Brokers and winners Joanne and Steve Malkowich. MIDDLE: Coach category finalist Glen Tosh, Dale McKay
        with sponsor Shur-Gro Farm Services and winner Bob Caldwell. RIGHT: Community Builder Award category finalist Kim Longstreet, Leanne DeVliegere with sponsor Vanguard Catalyst Credit Union and
        winner Randy Lewis.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, JUNE 21, 2018 • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                          COMMUNITY LEADER AWARDS 2018  • 29






















































































          LUHOWY NAMED COMMUNITY LEADER OF THE YEAR


          Community Leader of the Year Award Winner Cory Luhowy and Don Simpson with sponsor BDO pose for a photo during The Brandon Sun's Community Leader Awards at the Victoria Inn on Wednesday
          evening. (Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>