<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="12"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[DECEMBER 12, 2019 • MANITOBA 150 • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                                                             1

Canadian Ssenator John Nesbitt Kirchhoffer, Mrs. Clara Louisa Kirchhoffer, Earl Grey and Lady Grey with secretary (on ground) at Kirchhoffer
Grounds, Branddoonn,, 11990000.. ((CCoouurrtteessyy MMaanniittoobbaaAArrcchhiviveess))

                                                                                                                                                      2019 Special Supplement]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[2                                                                                               THE BRANDON SUN • MANITOBA 150 • DECEMBER 12, 2019

Manitoba

marking

its 150th

in style                                                                                         Philippe Mailhot, former director of the St. Boniface Museum, talks to a visitor near a large photo of
                                                                                                 Louis Riel at the museum in Winnipeg last year. As the leader of Manitoba in its earliest days, Riel will
                                                                                                 be a dominant figure throughout the year-long Manitoba 150 celebration. (File)

By Geoff Kirbyson                         Olympian to win multiple medals in                     Westman
                                          both the Summer (cycling) and Win-
   Manitoba is getting ready to party     ter (speed skating) Games; and A.A.                    Dr. Gordon Rust
like it’s 1870.                           Milne’s Winnie-the-Pooh was in-                        Dr. Allan G. Martin
                                          spired by a black bear named Winnie                    Dr. Patrick Lavigne
   The Keystone province will cele-       who was named after our capital city.                  Dr. Aimee Hatcher
brate its 150th anniversary of joining    And every parent with a microwave
Confederation on May 12, 2020 — a         has Paul Faraci to thank for inventing                 Hours:
move that made Canada a country of        Pizza Pops in Winnipeg in 1964.
ﬁve provinces, following Quebec, On-                                                             Monday    8:30a.m.–7p.m.
tario, New Brunswick and Nova Sco-           All this history has Stuart Murray
tia.                                      excited. Murray is co-chair of Manito-                 Tuesday   8:30a.m.–4p.m.
                                          ba 150, the not-for-proﬁt, non-parti-
   Manitoba was the ﬁrst province to      san, volunteer-driven host committee                   Wednesday 8:30a.m.–6p.m.
join through Indigenous leadership        overseeing a wide-ranging celebration
thanks, in large part, to the efforts of  of all things Manitoba.                                Thursday  8:30a.m.–7p.m.
Louis Riel. He was far from the only
inﬂuential person to leave his mark          The plan is to celebrate throughout                 Friday    8:30a.m.–7p.m.
on the province and, indeed, the en-      the entire year starting 150 days be-
tire country.                             fore Manitoba Day of our anniversary                   Sat. (Sept. - June) 9:00a.m.–12p.m.
                                          year. The festivities kick off on Dec.
   There was also Nellie McClung,         14 with an event called Illuminate 150                 204-571-3800 | 801B – 10th St, Brandon
whose activism led to Manitoba be-        where 300,000 lights will be switched
coming the ﬁrst province to grant         on at the Manitoba Legislature fol-                    Tuesday & Thursday 1pm – 5pm
women the right to vote in provincial     lowed by a unique performance by X
elections; spymaster Sir William Ste-     Games athletes doing ﬂips and turns
phenson, who was the inspiration for      on snowmobiles.
James Bond; writers Carol Shields,
Margaret Laurence, Miriam Toews              “We’re trying to engage the pub-
and Gabrielle Roy; world-renowned         lic with the most public building we
musicians such as Neil Young, Burton      have,” Murray said.
Cummings and Randy Bachman of
the Guess Who, Chantal Kreviazuk,            Manitoba 150 has already an-
the Crash Test Dummies and the            nounced several programs to help take
Watchmen; Bobby Hull, who became          the celebrations to the next level.
the world’s ﬁrst million-dollar hockey
player here; Clara Hughes, the only                                       » Continued on Page 3]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[DECEMBER 12, 2019 • MANITOBA 150 • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                               3

» Continued from Page 2                    will range from $10,000 to $70,000       Explore 150, an app that encourages all      providing a platform for First Nations
                                           and will cover up to 70 per cent of an   Manitobans to discover our province’s        to tell their stories and highlight their
   Honour 150 calls upon Manitobans        event’s total cost.                      beauty; Tour 150, a mobile gallery that      legacies in Manitoba.
to nominate people for their outstand-                                              will visit fairs and festivals this spring;
ing contributions to the province and         Other exciting programs include       and sponsorship of the Manitoba 150             “Some people see Riel as a hero,
who are quietly committed to giving        Mural 150, which invites communi-        River Trail at The Forks.                    others as a traitor. We have to tell that
back to the community.                     ties to apply for a chance to receive a                                               story. He’s our father of Confedera-
                                           contemporary outdoor mural; Learn           As the leader of Manitoba in its          tion,” Murray said.
   The best part is that most of the       150, which will offer learning resourc-  earliest days, Riel will be a dominant
honourees will be unfamiliar to resi-      es about diversity, reconciliation, and  ﬁgure throughout the year-long cel-             Organizers are quick to note that
dents, as they can’t be elected ofﬁcials   healthy living to Manitoba educators;    ebration. Equally important will be          Manitoba is celebrating its 150th anni-
or people who have recently been for-                                                                                            versary, not birthday, as they recognize
mally honoured by major awards, such                                                                                             Indigenous people were here long be-
as the Order of Canada or the Gover-                                                                                             fore European settlers arrived.
nor General’s Award. Nominees must
be residents of Manitoba who have                                                                                                   “This milestone is one that’s worth
volunteered or contributed to the com-                                                                                           celebrating — to think back to our
munity in a signiﬁcant way.                                                                                                      past, learn from it about our people,
                                                                                                                                 natural beauty, culture and heritage,”
   Build 150 will provide $1.2 million                                                                                           said fellow co-chair Monique La-
for projects that will leave a legacy in                                                                                         Coste, a natural in the position as she
communities around the province.                                                                                                 has both Franco-Manitoban and Mé-
Applicants can submit their ideas for                                                                                            tis roots.
infrastructure or brick-and-mortar
projects to their local community foun-                                                                                             She believes the year of celebration
dation. Each foundation will decide                                                                                              should serve as a good reminder to all
which projects to fund, ranging from                                                                                             Manitobans, but particularly to youth,
$5,000 to $300,000, and will receive                                                                                             of what a great province we call home.
matching grants from Build 150 for a
total investment of $2.5 million across                                                                                             “It’s a tremendous opportunity to
the province.                                                                                                                    remind our young people that Manito-
                                                                                                                                 ba is a great place to make a living, raise
   Celebrate 150, which closed to ap-                                                                                            a family and have plenty of opportuni-
plications last month, will support                                                                                              ties to contribute,” she said.
communities and non-proﬁt organiza-
tions in hosting events such as concerts,                                                                                           The festivities won’t end after Man-
art shows and food festivals. Grants                                                                                             itoba Day. On June 27, a huge stage will
                                                                                                                                 be erected for a full day of free Manito-
                                                                                                                                 ba programming featuring iconic mu-
                                                                                                                                 sical acts and cultural celebrations.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4 THE BRANDON SUN • MANITOBA 150 • DECEMBER 12, 2019

Manitoba 150 co-chairs Stuart Murray (speaking) and Monique LaCoste unveiled three celebratory programs as part of Manitoba’s upcoming 150th anniversary. (Winnipeg Free Press)

Message from the co-chairs

   As Manitoba celebrates its 150th anniversary, it     been home to Indigenous peoples for centuries.        tunity to tell stories, to explore our land, to high-
is an opportunity for all of us, from north to south,   That legacy is a vital piece of our identity, as we   light successes, and to demonstrate the joy that can
from urban and rural regions to come together. In       proudly celebrate being the only province to join     come from honouring our shared past as Manitoba
2020, we will share stories and strengthen our con-     Canada under Indigenous leadership.                   moves into the future.
nections to each other and the land we share as we
explore our past and leave legacies for the future. As     In 1870, the tiny but powerful Manitoba joined        Manitoba 150 will strengthen our commitment
co-chairs of The Manitoba 150 Host Committee            Canada as its ﬁfth province. The pride of being a     to this incredible province we call home as we dis-
Inc. (Manitoba 150), we are excited to be “United       strong, distinct voice in this great country of ours  cover our beauty, meet our people, experience our
in celebration — Unis dans la fête.”                    deﬁnes us as the geographic heart of Canada.          cultures and explore our history.

   The land known today as Manitoba, a name                Manitoba 150 is not a single event, nor a sin-        We have so much to celebrate in Manitoba. We
believed to originate from the Cree word mani-          gle program, and certainly not a single voice. It is  hope you’ll join us in a celebration that is over 150
tou-wapow or the Ojibwa word manidoobaa, both           a year-long celebration of the chorus of voices that  years in the making!
meaning “straits of Manitou, the Great Spirit,” has     comprise Manitoba.
                                                                                                              STUART MURRAY and MONIQUE LaCOSTE
                                                           Our 150th anniversary celebration is an oppor-
                                                                                                              Co-chairs]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[6                                                                                                      THE BRANDON SUN • MANITOBA 150 • DECEMBER 12, 2019

Westman
key part of
Manitoba’s
long history

By Bud Robertson                                  government and the Canadian government                The Brandon House cairn marks the location of a bustling fur-trading hub just east of where Brandon
                                                  resulted in the passage of the Manitoba Act,          now sits. (Submitted)
   Manitoba is turning 150 years old next         which received royal assent on May 12, 1870.
year, and western Manitoba played a vital                                                                   SERVING MANITOBA
role in its rich and colourful history.              It created the Province of Manitoba and                    FOR 115 YEARS
                                                  provided for its entry into Confederation.
   Depending on who you ask, the name                                                                                              The only card
“Manitoba” is either an Indigenous word              For his efforts, Riel ﬂed into exile and was                                  you need on
meaning “the god who speaks” or “water of         later hanged for treason in Regina in 1885.                                      the road.
the prairie” because of all the lakes and rivers
with which it is blessed.                            Back then, Manitoba was only a fraction                                       Insurance
                                                  of the size it is now — a square 1/18 of its                                     Travel
   A traditional territory of several First       current size, to be exact — and was thus                                         Roadside
Nations, European fur traders ﬁrst arrived        dubbed the “postage stamp province.”                                             Rewards
in this rugged patch of forest and prairies
during the late 17th century, with the French        Technically speaking, the area we now              In Brandon:                Toll-free: 1.800.222.4357
under La Vérendrye setting up several trad-       know as western Manitoba was not even                 Unit — 305 18th Street N.  Toll-free cell: *222®
ing post forts in the area, according to Wiki-    part of the new province of Manitoba in               Tel: 204.571.4100
pedia.                                            1870; rather, it was part of the Northwest                                       www.caamanitoba.com
                                                  Territories, said Gordon Goldsborough,
   In 1670, Britain declared sovereignty          president and head researcher of the Man-
over the watershed of Hudson’s Bay, making        itoba Historical Society.
it part of Rupert’s Land under the authori-
ty of the Hudson’s Bay Company. In 1763,             Manitoba’s borders were expanded in
New France was dissolved, and Rupert’s            1881, taking land from the Northwest Terri-
Land expanded to include where the French         tories and the District of Keewatin, but On-
forts had been.                                   tario claimed a large portion of the Keewatin
                                                  land; the disputed portion was awarded to
   Lord Selkirk established the ﬁrst colony       Ontario in 1889.
in Rupert’s Land of Assiniboia, or the Red
River Colony, in 1811.                               It grew to its current size in 1912.
                                                     Long before Manitoba even became
   Eight years later, in 1818, Britain and the    a province, a booming fur-trading busi-
United States agreed to establish the 49th        ness was going on just east of what is now
parallel as the ofﬁcial border and assign that    Brandon, Goldsborough said, with three
portion of Rupert’s Land south of the paral-      fur-trading companies at one time compet-
lel to the United States.                         ing for business with Indigenous trappers.
                                                     “Brandon House was the very ﬁrst inland
   Rupert’s Land was ceded to Canada in           post of the Hudson’s Bay Company,” Golds-
1869 and incorporated into the Northwest          borough said, adding the company initially
Territories.                                      did all of its trading at the main headquar-
                                                  ters at York Factory on Hudson Bay.
   Meanwhile, the Métis of the Red River             “Basically, Indigenous people had to go
valley, seeing their concerns ignored by the      there to do their trading,” he said. “Well, of
new authority, launched the Red River Re-         course, that’s a long way to go.”
bellion under Louis Riel, and established a
provisional government that named the area                                       » Continued on Page 8
as Manitoba.

   Negotiations between the provisional]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[DECEMBER 12, 2019 • MANITOBA 150 • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                                                                 7

A view of Rosser Avenue in a photo taken by photographer Ernest Jerrett, who operated a photographic studio at 115 10th St., after moving to Brandon in     MAKING PLANS
1931. This picture of Brandon’s Rosser Avenue was likely taken in the 1930s — the postcard image in the Brandon Sun archives does not state an exact date.
(Photo by Ernest Jerrett)                                                                                                                                      There will be lots going on next year to
                                                                                                                                                            celebrate Manitoba’s 150th anniversary.

                                                                                                                                                               Some two dozen community leaders
                                                                                                                                                            from various organizations in Brandon and
                                                                                                                                                            Westman have been networking, sharing
                                                                                                                                                            ideas and discussing the possibilities, said
                                                                                                                                                            Manitoba 150 steering committee mem-
                                                                                                                                                            ber Karen Chrest, member of the Mani-
                                                                                                                                                            toba 150 Host Committee Inc. board of
                                                                                                                                                            directors.

                                                                                                                                                               “These are from a diverse cross section
                                                                                                                                                            of organizations in business, arts, sports,
                                                                                                                                                            education, (Brandon Urban Aboriginal
                                                                                                                                                            Peoples’ Council), heritage, tourism and
                                                                                                                                                            more,” Chrest said.

                                                                                                                                                               A number of groups have also applied
                                                                                                                                                            for event funding through the Celebrate
                                                                                                                                                            150 program. The deadline for those appli-
                                                                                                                                                            cations has now passed, and after the suc-
                                                                                                                                                            cessful applicants are made known there
                                                                                                                                                            will be numerous announcements around
                                                                                                                                                            Brandon and Westman, Chrest said.

                                                                                                                                                               Chrest noted they are looking for nom-
                                                                                                                                                            inations from around the province for
                                                                                                                                                            those “unsung heroes” in all of our com-
                                                                                                                                                            munities who could be honoured in 2020
                                                                                                                                                            through the Honour 150 program.

                                                                                                                                                               Applications should be emailed to hon-
                                                                                                                                                            our@manitoba150.com.

                                                                                                                                                               Honour 150 awardees will receive a
                                                                                                                                                            MB150 Medal of honour. This medal
                                                                                                                                                            will be designed by a Manitoba artist, and
                                                                                                                                                            manufactured in Manitoba.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8 THE BRANDON SUN • MANITOBA 150 • DECEMBER 12, 2019

» Continued from Page 6                          Brandon became an instant city with the arrival of the railway in 1882. The original Eighth Street Bridge is visible in the right background.

   Instead, HBC decided to take the busi-        (Lawrence Stuckey Collection/Brandon University Archives)
ness to the Indigenous traders, and at least
three Brandon House sites were established       27,000 inhabitants. The 1881 Census of
along the Assiniboine River, near shallow        Canada ranked it in 19th place for cities with
rapids about 18 kilometres east of where         more than 5,000 inhabitants.
Brandon now sits.
                                                    From 1881 to 1891, the population of the
   Two other companies, the North West           Canadian Prairies increased from 118,000 to
Company (which later merged with HBC)            251,000 and was located mainly in southern
and XY Company also set up shop.                 Manitoba.

   “If you had to identify, going back a cou-       In 1901, the region of Winnipeg had al-
ple of centuries, the busiest area in Manitoba,  most 45,000 inhabitants.
I mean, it was that area.”
                                                    Now, 150 years young, Manitoba has
   Jump now to 1882, and the arrival of Ca-      grown to be bustling province in the centre
nadian Paciﬁc Railway in western Manitoba.       of Canada, with a population of close to 1.4
                                                 million. Brandon’s population, meanwhile,
   That, said Goldsborough, led to the in-       has grown to nearly 49,000 souls since its
stant creation of Brandon and all the com-       birth in 1882.
merce that would follow.
                                                    Here’s to the next 150 years.
   “Brandon is entirely a product of the rail-   » brobertson@brandonsun.com
way,” he said, adding it opened up travel to
and from the capital, Winnipeg, transporting
both people and goods.

   “It was a busy, busy place,” Goldsborough
said.

   “People began to ﬂood into southwestern
Manitoba. They arrived in Brandon and of
course then they spread out in every direction
and began taking up farms,” he said.

   “That’s basically when you see a lot of the
communities in southern Manitoba being
established. It’s the railway that made them
all come.”

   Before then, settlers had to rely on ox
carts or horse-drawn carriages to establish
homesteads on the Prairies.

   “It was really an arduous process getting
to western Manitoba,” he said.

   The majority of people who immigrat-
ed to Manitoba during the 1870 and 1880
decades were from Ontario, according to
Library and Archives Canada, an arm of the
Government of Canada.

   “The new arrivals obviously devoted
themselves to agriculture, but also established
businesses,” the Archives says on its website.

   “They became politicians, lawyers, nota-
ries public and doctors. These people arrived
in Manitoba with, at most, some members of
their immediate families.”

   Between 1871 and 1881, the popula-
tion of Winnipeg increased from 1,000 to
9,000 inhabitants. In 1891, it had more than

Sun compiling Top 150 list

   What makes Westman so great?                  brandonsun.com, or written submissions can     TUESDAY DECEMBER 31ST
   This is your chance to share your thoughts    be mailed or dropped at The Brandon Sun,
and win a nice prize at the same time.           501 Rosser Ave., Brandon MB, R7A 0K4.                    CANAD INNS DESTINATION CENTRE BRANDON
   The Brandon Sun is looking to name the                                                                       (1125 18th Brandon MB, 204-727-1422)
Top 150 people, places or things that make          There will be a $500 grand prize drawn
our communities great. The list and brief        from all the nominations along with weekly
description will be included in the May 12       prizes that may include Manitoba 150 swag.
Manitoba 150 Special Section we are pub-
lishing.                                            As well, on the third Thursday of every
   People can nominate a person, place or        month, the Sun will publish a photo of a
thing with a brief description (a few sentenc-   building or person of historic signiﬁcance.
es) as to why they are deserving. It could be
an exceptional volunteer, a great attraction,       We will make a draw for prizes each time
a special place to visit — it’s your choice.     from entries that correctly identify the pho-
Nominations will be accepted online via          to.

                                                    This contest will run from January
                                                 through December.

                                                 » The Brandon Sun]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[DECEMBER 12, 2019 • MANITOBA 150 • THE BRANDON SUN                                                                                       9

Building a lasting legacy

By Geoff Kirbyson                                Here’s how it works: Applicants can      munities in which we live and do busi-         ty foundations. Ultimately, they represent
                                              submit their ideas for infrastructure or    ness. We’ve seen the beneﬁt that doing         and understand their community’s inter-
   Most geo-political anniversaries are       brick-and-mortar projects to their local    so can have on the community and its           ests far better than we could,” he said.
punctuated by cake and ﬁreworks.              community foundation. Each foundation       residents. Helping provide infrastructure
                                              will decide which projects to fund and set  and amenities and tying it to something           Manitoba 150 and The Winnipeg
   Manitoba 150 is not most anniversa-        their own application deadlines. For each   tangible that’s left behind in communi-        Foundation agreed to make the funding
ries.                                         successful application, foundations will    ties, that’s where we feel it can have a real  available across Manitoba in as equitable
                                              receive matching grants from Build 150      impact.”                                       and fair a way as possible. For example,
   Of course, there will be ﬁreworks to       ranging from $5,000 to $300,000.                                                           The Winnipeg Foundation took less
celebrate Manitoba becoming a province                                                       JRSL was founded by James Richard-          than one-quarter of the total while the
150 years ago in 1870, but organizers            Most of the community foundations        son in 1857. The company started out in        remaining funds were distributed across
want to leave a legacy that lasts longer      are already accepting applications and      grain merchandising and has grown its          the 54 community foundations outside
than a few — albeit exciting — minutes.       are expected to make funding announce-      operations to encompass oil and gas, real      of Winnipeg. To avoid creating extra bu-
                                              ments within the next three to six months.  estate, agriculture and ﬁnancial services.     reaucracy, the Build 150 funds are being
   Through the Build 150 Program, The                                                     It employs more than 2,500 employees           integrated into the existing granting pro-
Manitoba 150 host committee’s idea of            It’s only ﬁtting that James Richardson   throughout Canada and the U.S., many           cess.
celebration is to leave a lasting legacy for  & Sons, Limited and Afﬁliated Compa-        of them in Manitoba.
future Manitobans. Build 150 will fund        nies, is a major donor to Build 150 — it                                                      Larger centres, such as Brandon, Por-
brick-and-mortar projects throughout          has provided $500,000 to the cause —           Endow Manitoba is co-ordinating and         tage la Prairie, Selkirk and Dauphin,
Manitoba.                                     considering the family-owned business       managing the community applications.           which have been building up foundation
                                              has had operations in Manitoba since the    Director Alan Goddard said the goal is         resources for many years, are expected to
   To have a truly provincewide impact,       late 1800s.                                 to create lasting legacy projects that rec-    be able to grant more than $100,000 back
the program runs in conjunction with 55                                                   ognize the province’s anniversary in a way     into their communities as part of the an-
community foundations across the prov-           “More than anything, we’re hopeful       that leverages the good work that’s being      niversary celebrations.
ince.                                         and we anticipate the program will have     done on a regular basis by the 55 founda-
                                              a lasting impact in Manitoba and leave      tions. Every year, they provide more than         So, what’s going to get built? Decisions
   Manitoba 150 has made up to $1.22          a lasting legacy in the province,” said     $55 million in grants and other support        still have to be made but Goddard said
million in grant matching funds available     Dan Hursh, a director of JRSL and a         to the province’s charitable sector.           he has heard everything from beautiﬁca-
to those foundations. Endow Manitoba,         sixth-generation member of the team.                                                       tion projects for small parks and building
an initiative of The Winnipeg Founda-                                                        “It was critical for us to keep the deci-   playgrounds to support for mountain bike
tion, is matching that money to bring the        “Our family business has long believed   sion-making power within the communi-          trails and Indigenous art projects.
total amount of funding investment up to      in giving back and supporting the com-
nearly $2.5 million.

Sharing stories to inspire future leaders

By Jennifer McFee                                         tions — Manitoba 150 and WE Charity — on a new              Both Stuart Murray and Monique LaCoste, co-
                                                          educational resource called Learn 150.”                  chairs of the Manitoba 150 host committee, are in-
   A new made-in-Manitoba learning resource is                                                                     spired by the Learn 150 launch.
sure to make the grade with educators across the             These teaching tools will encourage discussions
province.                                                 in both ofﬁcial languages about Manitoba’s past,            “While Manitoba is celebrating its 150th anniver-
                                                          present and future for students of all ages across the   sary in 2020, its land, people, beauty and culture go
   Learn 150 is a bilingual teaching tool that will       province.                                                back much further,” Murray said. “We are delighted
be available to download online starting in January                                                                to celebrate Manitoba’s anniversary, and Learn 150
2020. The resource has been created in conjunction           “Designed for Manitoba students in kindergarten       reminds us of our rich past, our diverse community
with WE Day and in partnership with Canad Inns.           to Grade 12, Learn 150 teaches about our shared          and the potential our future holds. By supporting the
                                                          history and encourages dialogue about diversity, rec-    next generation, we are helping to ensure our next
   Lea Ledohowski, the president of Canad Inns, is        onciliation and healthy living,” Ledohowski said.        celebration will be even more momentous.”
excited about the partnership.
                                                             “Today’s youth are tomorrow’s leaders, and educa-        “Created in conjunction with WE Day,” LaCoste
   “Canad Inns is about community. Through our            tion is empowerment. We are so excited to be able to     said, “this learning resource will enhance the work of
Canad Inns Foundation, it is our mission to support       play a role in providing knowledge and skills that will  Manitoba teachers in developing the skills Manitoba
initiatives that improve the quality of life in the com-  help shape a better future for our province.”            students in kindergarten through Grade 12 need to
munities we serve,” she said.                                                                                      be the leaders of tomorrow, with a focus on diversity,
                                                             The learning resource will also address the im-       reconciliation, and healthy living.”
   “Manitoba’s 150th anniversary is a celebration of      portance of making healthy choices and leading a
special signiﬁcance to our company that is Manitoba       healthy lifestyle. The goal is to ensure that strong        More information about Learn 150 is available on
owned, Manitoba grown and Manitoba proud. We              community ethics and good citizenship remain key         the Manitoba 150 website at manitoba150.com.
are thrilled to partner with two amazing organiza-        components in Manitoba for future generations.]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10 THE BRANDON SUN • MANITOBA 150 • DECEMBER 12, 2019

Prepare to be dazzled

By Geoff Kirbyson                           said the wow factor of Illuminate 150 is       “We’re going to have games, hot             will make a sensational backdrop for a
                                            sure to spark a year-long supernova of      chocolate, and an exhilarating snowmo-         gravity-defying acrobatic snowmobile
   Get ready to ﬂick the switch and get     celebrations.                               bile performance. We want to engage the        show, with X Games athletes soaring,
the party started to celebrate a century                                                public with the most public building we        ﬂipping, twisting and pulling off other
and a half for our province.                   “This is just the start!” LaCoste said.  have,” Murray said.                            daring feats of ﬂight.
                                            “The glowing lights on the Legislative
   Manitobans won’t have to wait until      Building grounds will keep that feel-          The fun begins with a holiday open             The lights of Illuminate 150 will also
2020 (the 150th anniversary of Manito-      ing going through the ﬁrst half of the      house at the legislature from 3-5 p.m.         be visible from the Manitoba 150 River
ba joining Canadian Confederation) to       year. With each new Manitoba 150 an-        along with family-friendly program-            Trail behind the legislature, so get ready
revel, as Manitoba 150 is ready to kick     nouncement and event, the excitement        ming outside, including games and ac-          to lace up those skates later this winter.
the party off with a brilliant ﬂourish,     will grow and grow, creating warm and       tivities for kids raring to start the holiday
precisely 150 days before Manitoba Day      lasting memories for all Manitobans. By     season, a snowshoe obstacle course, in-           Illuminate 150 is also working with
2020, on Saturday.                          the end of 2020, we hope Manitobans         ner-tube slide races and complimentary         Lights of the North, which will design
                                            will feel a deeper connection to their      hot cocoa and coffee from Tim Hortons.         illuminated, Manitoba-inspired art-
   Welcome to Illuminate 150.               province and to each other.”                                                               works to decorate the legislative grounds.
   Once the sun has set at 5:30 p.m.,                                                      Lights Unlimited, a local compa-
Manitobans will want to get their cam-         You’ll want to get down to the legis-    ny best known for its work during the             There’s a double signiﬁcance to the
eras ready and hold their breath, be-       lature well before the light show as the    holiday season and in the many Busi-           location as the home of the Golden Boy
cause, at the ﬂick of a switch, more than   merriment begins at 3 p.m., with plen-      ness Improvement Zones (BIZ) around            will celebrate an anniversary of its own
300,000 lights will illuminate the Man-     ty of free and fun events for the whole     Winnipeg, started putting up the lights        in 2020, turning 100. So the open house
itoba Legislative Building and grounds.     family.                                     in August. Those lights will keep shin-        at the Manitoba legislature is a great way
It will be a sight you won’t want to miss.                                              ing on the beauty of Manitoba until after      to connect with our province’s history
( Just who will hit the switch remains a       Manitoba 150 co-chair Stuart Mur-        Canada Day. And don’t worry, they won’t        as we launch into a year of celebration.
bit of a surprise.)                         ray said it’s not often he hopes for a big  harm the environment — they’re ener-           Donations of non-perishable food items
   Monique LaCoste, co-chair of Man-        dump of snow in early December, but         gy-efﬁcient LED bulbs.                         for the Christmas Cheer Board will be
itoba 150, the not-for-proﬁt, non-par-      he’ll make an exception this year as our                                                   welcomed at the open house. Illuminate
tisan, volunteer-driven host committee,     province shows it can celebrate with the       The festivities on Saturday won’t end       150 is completely free and everyone is
                                            best of them.                               with the light show. The dazzling glow         welcome!

Let’s honour our everyday heroes

By Jennifer McFee                                        such a fantastic place.”                                volved. Our hope is that they will just go for it.”
                                                            Thanks to additional funding from Canada Life, a        The nomination deadline is Jan. 31, 2020. An in-
   Most Manitobans know someone who has humbly
endeavoured to improve our community. So it’s worth      $500 community donation will be made in tribute to      dependent advisory committee will select the Honour
taking a moment to nominate them for the Honour          each of the 150 Honour recipients, representing an in-  150 award recipients, who will receive a commemora-
150 initiative, which aims to recognize Manitobans for   vestment of $75,000 throughout Manitoba.                tive medal and be invited to a dinner to celebrate their
their outstanding work that contributes to the better-                                                           achievements next fall.
ment of the communities they call home.                     Hugh Moncrieff, executive vice-president of the
                                                         advisory network and industry affairs at Canada Life,      At the ceremony, each Honour 150 recipient’s
   “Maybe it’s the kid down the street who has a yearly  said the organization believes in the power of caring.  achievements will be lauded in a biography written by
lemonade stand to raise money for the charity of his or                                                          Red River College Creative Communications students
her choice,” said Stuart Murray, co-chair of the Man-       “It’s made us who we are today. We are a company     with guidance from a communications mentor.
itoba 150 host committee. “Maybe it’s the person who     that has grown out of all the best of Manitoba. Being
gets up at four in the morning to ﬂood the local rink,   in this community with our head ofﬁce here, this is        For journalism instructor Joanne Kelly, the Honour
or who knits preemie caps for local hospitals. We’re     something that we absolutely wanted to be part of,”     150 program provides an opportunity to teach the stu-
looking for local people who go about their business,    he said. “We think this effort is about more than just  dents how to be communicators while also recognizing
quietly making a difference in communities all across    money. It’s actually bringing people together, which    the importance of community. “The students will get
the province. That’s the spirit of Manitoba.”            we’re excited about.”                                   to meet incredible, hardworking people who are mak-
                                                                                                                 ing a difference in the community and they get to help
   Manitoba 150 is encouraging nominations from             In addition to recognizing today’s hidden heroes,    them share their story,” she said. “It shows the students
every part of Manitoba, including remote and rural       Moncrieff hopes the program will inspire volunteerism   how we’re all connected and how communication is
regions, to honour people of all ages and backgrounds.   and community engagement.                               such a vital part of building our community.”

   “We realize that Manitobans are humble people,”          “At the end of the day, it would be great if Honour     Manitoba artists and graphic designers, as well as
added Monique LaCoste, Murray’s co-chair. “We are        150 could get the next generation of volunteers in-     manufacturers, are welcome to submit their qualiﬁ-
counting on friends, neighbours, and colleagues to       volved. Individual Manitobans can make a difference,”   cations for the MB150 medal design competition by
nominate these special Manitobans so we can recog-       he said. “I really encourage people to check out the    Jan. 31, 2020. More information about Honour 150
nize their important contribution to making Manitoba     Manitoba 150 website to see how they can leverage       and the medal design RFP is available at manitoba150.
                                                         this program and the other great initiatives. I think   com.
                                                         Manitobans will have a lot of opportunities to get in-]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[DECEMBER 12, 2019 • MANITOBA 150 • THE BRANDON SUN  11

Jerry Rugg, a.k.a birdO, of Toronto, paints a colourful new mural adjacent to the Kristopher Campbell Memorial Skate Plaza on Princess Avenue at Ninth Street earlier this year — just in time for Manitoba’s 150th.
(Tim Smith/The Brandon Sun)

                                                                                         Corral Centre

                                                                                 CORNER OF 18TH STREET & PARK AVENUE]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Get

HOLIDAY READY

with your

SOBEYS EXTRA

Entertaining Trays  Floral Arrangements/ Poinsettias

Christmas Confections | Nut Trays | Bulk food | Chocolates

HELPING HANDS       $5.00 & $10.00

HAMPERS             a gift for those who are in need

                    1570 18th Street | Shoppers Mall | 204-725-1134]]></page></pages></Search>