<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="52"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[IN PARTNERSHIP WITH]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                              3
                         Canada’s Family                                                                                                                         EDITOR’S NOTE



                                                                                                                                                                 Manitobans are a well-traveled lot.
                                                 Grocery Store                                                                                                   We love our cross-country summer road trips down those big highways and byways
                                                                                                                                                                 that criss-cross the continent.  And we all too often look with longing in our eyes to
                                                                                                                                                                 the attractions abroad that call to our sense of adventure.
                                                                                                                                                                 Don’t believe me? Just check your friends’ social media posts for pictures of their
                                                                                                                                                                 latest jaunt to Montreal, Vancouver, or even Halifax. Indeed, we always seem to be
                                                                                                                                                                 leaving the province to visit somewhere else – winging away to that beach in Mexico
                                                                                                                                                                 to get away from Manitoba’s winters, or driving to Calgary to take in the rodeo.
                                                                                                                                                                 Don’t get me wrong – I love to travel as much as any other Manitoban. But it’s all
                                                                                                                                                                 too easy to forget that our own backyard has its charms too, and is deserving of our
                                                                                                                                     PUBLISHER                   attention and pride.
                                                                                                                                      Jim Mihaly                 Fact is, the last several months of the COVID-19 pandemic have given us even more
                                                                                                                                                                 reason to be tourists within our own province — to enjoy the unique and diverse
                                                                                                                                       EDITOR                    aspects of our heritage, culture, geography and the natural beauty of this historic
                                                                                                                                     Matt Goerzen                region. And with travel restrictions still, the norm now is likely the best time to
                                                                                                                                                                 experience Manitoba with fresh eyes and open hearts.
                                                                                                                             GRAPHIC DESIGN/LAYOUT               The 150 Things to do in Westman guide now in your hands is meant to celebrate
                                                                                                                                   Nikita Lindenberg             Manitoba’s 150th anniversary, which was unfortunately interrupted last year with the
                                                                                                                                   Melanie Maslaniec             onset of the coronavirus. The list of events and locations in this guide which include
                                                                                                                                    Prince Zapanta               a few suggestions ouside of the region too — was created with the assistance of
                                                                                                                                                                 Brandon Sun readers and citizens in Westman who answered our call, made prior to
                     Locally Owned and Operated                                                                                     MARKETING                    the pandemic, to provide us with “things they like to do” in the region.

                                                                                                                                      Karen Low                  To all those who took the time to send us their submissions, we thank you. While a
                                                                                                                                 Lisa Merckx-Deutscher           few of the attractions and amenities listed in these pages may still, be closed to the
                                                                                                                                    Suzanne Mihaly               public for a little while longer, they remain wonderful additions to our region and
                     Delivery and Pick Up Service                                                                                                                our province and will be accessible in the years ahead.

                                                                                                                                   DISTRIBUTION                  We invite you to use this guide to plan your days off and outdoor activities in the
                                                                                                                                      Lori Timms                 coming seasons. From a wide array of community fairs and cultural activities to our
                                                                                                                                                                 province’s vibrant sports, food and entertainment scenes, there is much to see and do.
                     Offering Local Manitoba products                                                                                On the cover:               Interest in staycations and local amenities has grown considerably over the past

                                                                                                                              A woman takes a photo of the       year. Perhaps the silver lining in all this is that Manitobans may grow to have a new
                                                                                                                              Devil’s Punch Bowl in Spruce       appreciation for the province they call home!
                                                                                                                                 Woods Provincial Park
                     Ready to Eat Meals, Just Grab and Go                                                                                                        Matt Goerzen

                                                                                                                              Photo by Salvador Maniquiz/        Editor
                                                                                                                                     Shutterstock

                                                                                                                               150 THINGS TO DO IN                                     SPECIAL THANK YOU
                                                                                                                                     WESTMAN
                                                                                                                            is a production of The Brandon Sun     The Brandon Sun would like to thank the Manitoba 150 Host Committee for
                                                                                                                             in partnership with the Manitoba             partnering with us to produce this commemorative magazine.
                                                                                                                                 150 Host Committee



                                                                                                Sobeys BDN South



      1570 18  Street  |  Shoppers Mall  |  204-725-1134
                     th]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                              3
 Canada’s Family                              EDITOR’S NOTE



                                              Manitobans are a well-traveled lot.
 Grocery Store                                We love our cross-country summer road trips down those big highways and byways
                                              that criss-cross the continent.  And we all too often look with longing in our eyes to
                                              the attractions abroad that call to our sense of adventure.
                                              Don’t believe me? Just check your friends’ social media posts for pictures of their
                                              latest jaunt to Montreal, Vancouver, or even Halifax. Indeed, we always seem to be
                                              leaving the province to visit somewhere else – winging away to that beach in Mexico
                                              to get away from Manitoba’s winters, or driving to Calgary to take in the rodeo.
                                              Don’t get me wrong – I love to travel as much as any other Manitoban. But it’s all
                                              too easy to forget that our own backyard has its charms too, and is deserving of our
                 PUBLISHER                    attention and pride.
                   Jim Mihaly                 Fact is, the last several months of the COVID-19 pandemic have given us even more
                                              reason to be tourists within our own province — to enjoy the unique and diverse
                   EDITOR                     aspects of our heritage, culture, geography and the natural beauty of this historic
                 Matt Goerzen                 region. And with travel restrictions still, the norm now is likely the best time to
                                              experience Manitoba with fresh eyes and open hearts.
         GRAPHIC DESIGN/LAYOUT                The 150 Things to do in Westman guide now in your hands is meant to celebrate
                Nikita Lindenberg             Manitoba’s 150th anniversary, which was unfortunately interrupted last year with the
               Melanie Maslaniec              onset of the coronavirus. The list of events and locations in this guide which include
                 Prince Zapanta               a few suggestions ouside of the region too — was created with the assistance of
                                              Brandon Sun readers and citizens in Westman who answered our call, made prior to
 Locally Owned and Operated  MARKETING        the pandemic, to provide us with “things they like to do” in the region.

                   Karen Low                  To all those who took the time to send us their submissions, we thank you. While a
             Lisa Merckx-Deutscher            few of the attractions and amenities listed in these pages may still, be closed to the
                 Suzanne Mihaly               public for a little while longer, they remain wonderful additions to our region and
 Delivery and Pick Up Service                 our province and will be accessible in the years ahead.

                DISTRIBUTION                  We invite you to use this guide to plan your days off and outdoor activities in the
                   Lori Timms                 coming seasons. From a wide array of community fairs and cultural activities to our
                                              province’s vibrant sports, food and entertainment scenes, there is much to see and do.
 Offering Local Manitoba products  On the cover:   Interest in staycations and local amenities has grown considerably over the past

           A woman takes a photo of the       year. Perhaps the silver lining in all this is that Manitobans may grow to have a new
           Devil’s Punch Bowl in Spruce       appreciation for the province they call home!
              Woods Provincial Park
 Ready to Eat Meals, Just Grab and Go         Matt Goerzen

           Photo by Salvador Maniquiz/        Editor
                  Shutterstock

            150 THINGS TO DO IN                                     SPECIAL THANK YOU
                  WESTMAN
        is a production of The Brandon Sun      The Brandon Sun would like to thank the Manitoba 150 Host Committee for
         in partnership with the Manitoba              partnering with us to produce this commemorative magazine.
              150 Host Committee



 Sobeys BDN South



 1570 18  Street  |  Shoppers Mall  |  204-725-1134
 th]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4                                                                          150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                              5














                                                                                                                           BRANDON’S HISTORIC
                                                                                                                           WINTER FAIR


                                                                                                                           The Royal Manitoba Winter Fair (RMWF) is
                                                                                                                           an annual agricultural fair near the end of March,
                                                             INTERNATIONAL PEACE                                           hosted by the Provincial Exhibition of Manitoba
                                                                                                                           at the Keystone Centre. It’s one of the largest
                                                             GARDEN                                                        agricultural events in Western Canada. Check out
                                                                                                                           provincialexhibition.com for more details.
                                                             Located approximately 100 km south of Brandon,
   01          RIDING MOUNTAIN                               and cactus gardens defined by nature, not borders. Plan                                                          07           SOURIS SWINGING BRIDGE
                                                             experience acres of uninterrupted prairie, radiant floral,
                                                             your trip to the Peace Garden.
               NATIONAL PARK
                                                             For more detail go to peacegarden.com
                                                                                                                                                                                           The Souris Swinging Bridge is one of Manitoba’s
   Riding Mountain National Park is a national park in Manitoba.                                                                                                              Star Attractions. Since its construction, it has become a popular
   The park sits atop the Manitoba Escarpment consisting of                                                                                                                   visitor attraction and it is estimated that over 5,000 visitors cross
   2,969 km of protected area.                                                                                                                                                the bridge every year.

   For more details check out                                                                                              MANITOBA MAPLE SYRUP                               For more details go to sourismanitoba.com
   pc.gc.ca/en/pn-np/mb/riding
                                                                                                                           FESTIVAL OF MCCREARY

                                                                                                                           Held in April, the festival features horse & wagon
                                                                                                                           rides, working sugar bush, maple taffy on snow, tree
                                                                                                                           tapping clinics, bannock on a stick, music all day,
                                                                                                                           children’s games/crafts and more!
                                                                                                                           For details check out mbmaplesyrupfest.com






                                                             A HOST OF INDOOR
                                                             AND OUTDOOR POOLS
                                                             THROUGHOUT WESTMAN

                                                             Enjoy a dip in the pool at the various pools located
                                                             throughout the region!                                        WHL’S BRANDON WHEAT KINGS
               pc.gc.ca/en/pn-np/mb/riding                                                                                 The Brandon Wheat Kings are a Canadian junior                  sourismanitoba.ca
                                                                                                                           ice hockey team based in Brandon, Manitoba. They
               204-848-7275                                                                                                are members of the Western Hockey League since                 204-483-5200
                                                                                                                           joining the league in the 1967–68 season.
               pc.info-riding@canada.ca                                                                                    Check out wheatkings.com                                       sg.cao@mtsmail.com]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[4  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                     5














        BRANDON’S HISTORIC
        WINTER FAIR


        The Royal Manitoba Winter Fair (RMWF) is
        an annual agricultural fair near the end of March,
 INTERNATIONAL PEACE   hosted by the Provincial Exhibition of Manitoba
        at the Keystone Centre. It’s one of the largest
 GARDEN  agricultural events in Western Canada. Check out
        provincialexhibition.com for more details.
 Located approximately 100 km south of Brandon,
 01  RIDING MOUNTAIN     and cactus gardens defined by nature, not borders. Plan   07  SOURIS SWINGING BRIDGE
 experience acres of uninterrupted prairie, radiant floral,
 your trip to the Peace Garden.
 NATIONAL PARK
 For more detail go to peacegarden.com
                                                                       The Souris Swinging Bridge is one of Manitoba’s
 Riding Mountain National Park is a national park in Manitoba.   Star Attractions. Since its construction, it has become a popular
 The park sits atop the Manitoba Escarpment consisting of   visitor attraction and it is estimated that over 5,000 visitors cross
 2,969 km of protected area.                               the bridge every year.

 For more details check out   MANITOBA MAPLE SYRUP         For more details go to sourismanitoba.com
 pc.gc.ca/en/pn-np/mb/riding
        FESTIVAL OF MCCREARY

        Held in April, the festival features horse & wagon
        rides, working sugar bush, maple taffy on snow, tree
        tapping clinics, bannock on a stick, music all day,
        children’s games/crafts and more!
        For details check out mbmaplesyrupfest.com






 A HOST OF INDOOR
 AND OUTDOOR POOLS
 THROUGHOUT WESTMAN

 Enjoy a dip in the pool at the various pools located
 throughout the region!  WHL’S BRANDON WHEAT KINGS
 pc.gc.ca/en/pn-np/mb/riding  The Brandon Wheat Kings are a Canadian junior   sourismanitoba.ca
        ice hockey team based in Brandon, Manitoba. They
 204-848-7275  are members of the Western Hockey League since          204-483-5200
        joining the league in the 1967–68 season.
 pc.info-riding@canada.ca  Check out wheatkings.com                    sg.cao@mtsmail.com]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[6                                                                          150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                              7














                                                                                                                           BRANDON’S ICONIC DOME
                                                                                                                           BUILDING


                                                                                                                           Built-in 1913, Brandon’s iconic Dome Building
                                                                                                                           has become a symbolic celebration of history and
                                                                                                                           agriculture. Officially known as Dominion Exhibition
                                                                                                                           Display Building No. 2, it is the only known surviving
                                                                                                                           building associated with the Dominion Exhibition,   11      SAILING ON PELICAN LAKE
                                                                                                                           an annual agricultural fair held across Canada in
                                                                                                                           different towns and cities from 1879 to 1913.               Pelican Lake is the largest navigable lake in
                                                                                                                                                                              southwestern Manitoba. The lake area is popular for boating,
                                                                                                                                                                              sailing, fishing, a wide variety of water activities for cottagers
                                                                                                                                                                              and homeowners. The lake is located near the town of Ninette.








                                                                                                                                                                                   ONLY
                                                                                                                                                                                     L L
                                                                                                                                                                                   1 HOUR
                                                                                                                                                                                    FROM
                                                                                                                                                                                   BRANDON
                                                                                                                           GOLF COURSES THROUGHOUT
                                                                                                                           WESTERN MANITOBA

                                                                                                                           There are plenty of amazing nine and 18 hole courses
                                                                                                                           to choose from in our region.









                                                                                                                                                                                       #83       #10
                                                                                                                                                                                           #1    Brandon
                                                                                                                                                                                      Reston  #2
                                                                                                                                                                                    Saskatchewan  Manitoba  #10

                                                                                                                           MELITA BANANA FESTIVAL                                      #83  Canada
                                               Hours of Inspiration                                                                                                                        U.S.A.

             Open Monday to Saturday 9:00am – 7:00pm | Sunday 11:00am – 5:00pm                                             The annual event in Melita features activities for
                                                                                                                           the whole family to enjoy. Traditionally held in
                         1329 Rosser Ave. E., Brandon, MB | Call: 204.727.5884                                             August, you can find more detail via Facebook at
                                                                                                                           MelitaBananaDays.
            greenspotbrandon.com  •  bloomboxonline.com  •  chezangela.ca
                                                                                                                                                                                9-Hole Golf Course  •  Full-Service Campground with FREE Firewood & WI-FI]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[6  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                     7














        BRANDON’S ICONIC DOME
        BUILDING


        Built-in 1913, Brandon’s iconic Dome Building
        has become a symbolic celebration of history and
        agriculture. Officially known as Dominion Exhibition
        Display Building No. 2, it is the only known surviving
        building associated with the Dominion Exhibition,   11      SAILING ON PELICAN LAKE
        an annual agricultural fair held across Canada in
        different towns and cities from 1879 to 1913.               Pelican Lake is the largest navigable lake in
                                                           southwestern Manitoba. The lake area is popular for boating,
                                                           sailing, fishing, a wide variety of water activities for cottagers
                                                           and homeowners. The lake is located near the town of Ninette.








                                                                ONLY
                                                                  L L
                                                               1 HOUR
                                                                 FROM
                                                                BRANDON
        GOLF COURSES THROUGHOUT
        WESTERN MANITOBA

        There are plenty of amazing nine and 18 hole courses
        to choose from in our region.









                                                                    #83      #10
                                                                        #1    Brandon
                                                                  Reston  #2
                                                                 Saskatchewan  Manitoba  #10

        MELITA BANANA FESTIVAL                                      #83  Canada
 Hours of Inspiration                                                   U.S.A.

 Open Monday to Saturday 9:00am – 7:00pm | Sunday 11:00am – 5:00pm  The annual event in Melita features activities for
        the whole family to enjoy. Traditionally held in
 1329 Rosser Ave. E., Brandon, MB | Call: 204.727.5884  August, you can find more detail via Facebook at
        MelitaBananaDays.
 greenspotbrandon.com  •  bloomboxonline.com  •  chezangela.ca
                                                             9-Hole Golf Course  •  Full-Service Campground with FREE Firewood & WI-FI]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8                                                                          150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                              9
                                                                                                                                         THE OXBOW NATURE                                           CLAY BANKS –
                                                                                                                                         TRAIL                                                      BISON JUMP

                                                                                                                                         Oxbow Nature Trail is a                                    This site in the Municipality of
                                                                                                                                         3.1-kilometre loop trail located near                      Cartwright-Roblin, north of the
                                                                                                                                         Minnedosa that features a river and                        Village of Cartwright, is believed to
                                                                                                                                         is good for all skill levels. The trail is                 be where from about 2,000 to 1,200
                                                                                                                                         primarily used for hiking and running.                     years ago, Indigenous people of the
                                                             CAMPING AT A VARIETY OF                                                     For more details check out                                 Besant culture stampeded bison over
                                                                                                                                         alltrails.com
                                                                                                                                                                                                    the cliffs, later carving the carcasses
                                                             LOCATIONS                                                                                                                              for use as food, tools, shelter, and
                                                                                                                                                                                                    clothing.
                                                             No shortage of camping options in Westman!
                                                                                                                                         MINNEDOSA LOWER                                            CP STATION
                                                                                                                                         WEST BIKING TRAIL
   12         THE NORTHERN LIGHTS                                                                                                        The trail connects Heritage Village                        (CPR) station at Virden is a rare
                                                                                                                                                                                                    The former Canadian Pacific Railway
                                                                                                                                                                                                    Manitoba fieldstone station.  It was
                                                                                                                                         to the Rotary Swinging Bridge. From
                                                                                                                                                                                                    built by CPR in 1900.
             Although the phenomenon is most spectacular in the
   northern reaches of this country, the natural wonder known as the                                                                     there to the Oxbow Trail and then
                                                                                                                                         onto the trail to the dam.
   northern lights or the Aurora Borealis can be seen throughout all
   of Manitoba. Look for the latest aurora forecast on the Astronomy
   North website:
   astronomynorth.com/aurora-forecast/
                                                             ASESSIPPI SKI AREA AND
                                                             RESORT

                                                                                                                                                                                                       TRY SOMETHING
                                                             Discover Manitoba’s Largest Ski Resort! Asessippi
                                                             boasts 26 downhill runs, three chair lifts, two terrain
                                                             parks, and four snow tubing lanes.                                                                                                            DIFFERENT
                                                                                                                                                                                                        THIS SUMMER!
                                                             More details at asessippi.com














                                                                                                                        Perfect for Birthday Parties,
                                                             DAKOTA FIRST NATION                                        Stag/Stagettes & Corporate Events.

                                                             WINTER FEST                                                Visit our website for more information
         WE’VE GOT WHAT YOU’RE LOOKING FOR TONIGHT!          Sioux Valley Dakota Nation stage its annual Winter         kickinaxethrowing.com
           Whether you want to join us for dine in or enjoy our    Fest for four days at the end of January. The event is   204-730-5425
            delicious food on your home patio this evening!   a long-standing tradition in western Manitoba and
          Give us a call at 204-726-0207 to make a reservation    is a combination of cultural and aboriginal sports.   Contact us for hours at our new location
                                                                                                                        across from The Dock on Princess.
                  or place your order for takeout!           Check out the Facebook account Dakota-Nation-
                                                             Winterfest.

    612 ROSSER AVENUE, BRANDON | 204-726-0207 | BENNYS.RESTAURANT]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[8  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                     9
                     THE OXBOW NATURE                                           CLAY BANKS –
                     TRAIL                                                      BISON JUMP

                     Oxbow Nature Trail is a                                    This site in the Municipality of
                     3.1-kilometre loop trail located near                      Cartwright-Roblin, north of the
                     Minnedosa that features a river and                        Village of Cartwright, is believed to
                     is good for all skill levels. The trail is                 be where from about 2,000 to 1,200
                     primarily used for hiking and running.                     years ago, Indigenous people of the
 CAMPING AT A VARIETY OF   For more details check out                           Besant culture stampeded bison over
                     alltrails.com
                                                                                the cliffs, later carving the carcasses
 LOCATIONS                                                                      for use as food, tools, shelter, and
                                                                                clothing.
 No shortage of camping options in Westman!
                     MINNEDOSA LOWER                                            CP STATION
                     WEST BIKING TRAIL
 12  THE NORTHERN LIGHTS  The trail connects Heritage Village                   (CPR) station at Virden is a rare
                                                                                The former Canadian Pacific Railway
                                                                                Manitoba fieldstone station.  It was
                     to the Rotary Swinging Bridge. From
                                                                                built by CPR in 1900.
 Although the phenomenon is most spectacular in the
 northern reaches of this country, the natural wonder known as the   there to the Oxbow Trail and then
                     onto the trail to the dam.
 northern lights or the Aurora Borealis can be seen throughout all
 of Manitoba. Look for the latest aurora forecast on the Astronomy
 North website:
 astronomynorth.com/aurora-forecast/
 ASESSIPPI SKI AREA AND
 RESORT

                                                                                   TRY SOMETHING
 Discover Manitoba’s Largest Ski Resort! Asessippi
 boasts 26 downhill runs, three chair lifts, two terrain
 parks, and four snow tubing lanes.                                                     DIFFERENT
                                                                                     THIS SUMMER!
 More details at asessippi.com














     Perfect for Birthday Parties,
 DAKOTA FIRST NATION   Stag/Stagettes & Corporate Events.

 WINTER FEST  Visit our website for more information
 WE’VE GOT WHAT YOU’RE LOOKING FOR TONIGHT!   Sioux Valley Dakota Nation stage its annual Winter   kickinaxethrowing.com
 Whether you want to join us for dine in or enjoy our    Fest for four days at the end of January. The event is   204-730-5425
 delicious food on your home patio this evening!   a long-standing tradition in western Manitoba and
 Give us a call at 204-726-0207 to make a reservation    is a combination of cultural and aboriginal sports.   Contact us for hours at our new location
     across from The Dock on Princess.
 or place your order for takeout!  Check out the Facebook account Dakota-Nation-
 Winterfest.

 612 ROSSER AVENUE, BRANDON | 204-726-0207 | BENNYS.RESTAURANT]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                     22. VISIT THE BISON ENCLOSURE            11
                HAMIOTA CHUMAH &                                           PIERSON BOUNDARY
                PITLOCHRY TRAILS                                           TRAIL

                The trails are located upon the                            There are several places in Edward
                abandoned railway line providing for                       municipality where the original trail
                excellent use in all seasons.                              to mark the 49th parallel can be seen.
                Check out hamiota.com/trails/                              The same trail was used in 1874 by
                                                                           the North-West Mounted Police on
                                                                           their trek west to bring law and order
                                                                           to what was then the Northwest
                                                                           Territories.



                VISIT THE BISON                                            SHOAL LAKE TRANS
                ENCLOSURE                                                  CANADA TRAIL

                Riding Mountain National Park                              The Roseburn Subdivision of the
                (RMNP) has a special area called the                       TransCanada Trail runs through
                Lake Audy Bison Enclosure, which                           the northern portion of the Rural
                holds a captive herd of approximately                      Municipality of Shoal Lake. A scenic
                40 Plains Bison.                                           picnic area is located where the trail
                                                                           passes through Oakburn.















         White Bread  •   Monster Cookies                                            Gift Certificates

         Sticky Buns                 •   Butter Pan Buns                                 Available!























                                                                                 “Our Buns Don’t Jiggle”


                                                                                  1411–1  Street, Brandon
                                                                                           st
                                                                                              204-728-3023]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[10  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN           22. VISIT THE BISON ENCLOSURE            11
 HAMIOTA CHUMAH &   PIERSON BOUNDARY
 PITLOCHRY TRAILS  TRAIL

 The trails are located upon the   There are several places in Edward
 abandoned railway line providing for   municipality where the original trail
 excellent use in all seasons.    to mark the 49th parallel can be seen.
 Check out hamiota.com/trails/  The same trail was used in 1874 by
 the North-West Mounted Police on
 their trek west to bring law and order
 to what was then the Northwest
 Territories.



 VISIT THE BISON   SHOAL LAKE TRANS
 ENCLOSURE  CANADA TRAIL

 Riding Mountain National Park   The Roseburn Subdivision of the
 (RMNP) has a special area called the   TransCanada Trail runs through
 Lake Audy Bison Enclosure, which   the northern portion of the Rural
 holds a captive herd of approximately   Municipality of Shoal Lake. A scenic
 40 Plains Bison.  picnic area is located where the trail
 passes through Oakburn.















 White Bread  •   Monster Cookies  Gift Certificates

 Sticky Buns   •   Butter Pan Buns  Available!























 “Our Buns Don’t Jiggle”


 1411–1  Street, Brandon
 st
 204-728-3023]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[12                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                              13














                                                             CROW’S GENERAL STORE                                          PICKLEBALL ANYONE?


                                                             Step back in time at Crow’s General Store in                  Enjoy a leisurely game of Pickleball at Brandon’s
                                                             Brandon -  33 17th St. East.                                  Stanley Park, where former tennis courts have been
                                                             You can find more information via Facebook.com/               renovated for this fast-growing sport.
                                                             crows.generalstore/
                                                                                                                                                                              31         REEVE’S RAVINE ON A BIKE




                                                                                                                                                                                         Reeves Ravine, near McCreary,  is a fast, flowy all-
   24            THE ROYAL CANADIAN                                                                                                                                           mountain ride. It is as challenging as you want it to be. Ride it
                                                                                                                                                                              slow and take in the amazing vistas and views or rip down and
                 ARTILLERY MUSEUM
                                                                                                                                                                              make it an all-mountain technical challenge. More details at

   The Royal Canadian Artillery Museum at Shilo is Canada’s                                                                                                                   trailforks.com/trails/reeves-ravine/
   national artillery museum. It is dedicated to telling the
   complete story of the more than 200,000 Canadian Gunners                                                                ENJOY THE RIVERBANK
   who have served Canada in war and peace since 1855. Check
   out their website at https://en.rcamuseum.com/                                                                          DISCOVERY CENTRE AND
                                                             CROSS COUNTRY SKIING                                          TRAIL SYSTEM

                                                                                                                           The Riverbank has become Brandon’s “Central Park,”
                                                             For those who enjoy cross country skiing there are            providing a serene and beautiful place for families to
                                                             several trails throughout Westman.
                                                                                                                           gather. More details at riverbank.mb.ca




















                                                             GO ON A HUNTING ADVENTURE                                     WAKPA TANKA LOOKOUT

               https://en.rcamuseum.com/
                                                             Manitoba offers hunters some world-class hunting.             This is a world-class single component site and the
                                                             Fly, drive or travel by boat with one of many                 only one of its kind in all of Canada. It is situated at
               204-765-3000 (Ext. 3570)
                                                             experienced outfitters for moose, deer, black bear and        the beginning of the Silver Trail near Miniota.
                                                             caribou. For more information check out the Travel            Check out Prairie View Municipality for more
               RCAMuseum@forces.gc.ca
                                                             Manitoba website at: travelmanitoba.com                       details.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[12  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   13














 CROW’S GENERAL STORE  PICKLEBALL ANYONE?


 Step back in time at Crow’s General Store in   Enjoy a leisurely game of Pickleball at Brandon’s
 Brandon -  33 17th St. East.   Stanley Park, where former tennis courts have been
 You can find more information via Facebook.com/  renovated for this fast-growing sport.
 crows.generalstore/
                                                           31         REEVE’S RAVINE ON A BIKE




                                                                      Reeves Ravine, near McCreary,  is a fast, flowy all-
 24  THE ROYAL CANADIAN                                    mountain ride. It is as challenging as you want it to be. Ride it
                                                           slow and take in the amazing vistas and views or rip down and
 ARTILLERY MUSEUM
                                                           make it an all-mountain technical challenge. More details at

 The Royal Canadian Artillery Museum at Shilo is Canada’s   trailforks.com/trails/reeves-ravine/
 national artillery museum. It is dedicated to telling the
 complete story of the more than 200,000 Canadian Gunners   ENJOY THE RIVERBANK
 who have served Canada in war and peace since 1855. Check
 out their website at https://en.rcamuseum.com/  DISCOVERY CENTRE AND
 CROSS COUNTRY SKIING  TRAIL SYSTEM

        The Riverbank has become Brandon’s “Central Park,”
 For those who enjoy cross country skiing there are   providing a serene and beautiful place for families to
 several trails throughout Westman.
        gather. More details at riverbank.mb.ca




















 GO ON A HUNTING ADVENTURE  WAKPA TANKA LOOKOUT

 https://en.rcamuseum.com/
 Manitoba offers hunters some world-class hunting.   This is a world-class single component site and the
 Fly, drive or travel by boat with one of many   only one of its kind in all of Canada. It is situated at
 204-765-3000 (Ext. 3570)
 experienced outfitters for moose, deer, black bear and   the beginning of the Silver Trail near Miniota.
 caribou. For more information check out the Travel   Check out Prairie View Municipality for more
 RCAMuseum@forces.gc.ca
 Manitoba website at: travelmanitoba.com  details.]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                              15












                                                              Photo by Anne Latimer
                                                             OUTDOOR ART GALLERY                                           THE LINEAR MOUNDS
                                                                                                                           NATIONAL HISTORIC SITE
                                                             The pride of Boissevain is not only for the present
                                                             and future but is also a reflection of the past. The          Linear Mounds located near the Souris River was
                                                             town’s outdoor art gallery is also a Manitoba Star            designated as a national historic site of Canada in 1973.
                                                             Attraction.                                                   The site contains some of the most spectacular and
                                                             See boissevain.ca/visitors/outdoor-art-gallery                best-preserved examples of mortuary mounds belonging
                                                                                                                           to the Devil’s Lake-Sourisford Burial Complex.
   32          THE CITY LOOP TRAIL                                                                                                                                                                                   Photo by Kayla Evans


               SYSTEM


                                                                                                                                                                                          TRAIL
   The City Loop Trail in Brandon covers approximately 20 kms                                                                                                                 39          HIKE THE GORGE CREEK
   of walking, running and biking trails. Download or view the
   map featuring the City Loop Trail System at                                                                                                                                Gorge Creek Trail is an 11.6 kilometer moderately trafficked
   brandon.ca/images/pdf/Recreation/CityTrailLoop.pdf                                                                                                                         out and back trail located near Division No. 17 in Riding
                                                                                                                                                                              Mountain National Park that features beautiful wildflowers
                                                                                                                                                                              and is rated as moderate. The trail is primarily used for hiking,
                        BRANDON’S ONLY                       SOURIS RIVER BEND TRAILS                                      DISCOVER TURTLE MOUNTAIN                           walking, nature trips, and bird watching and is best used from
                             FURNITURE                       The network of trails passes through rolling mixed-           PROVINCIAL PARK                                    May until September.

                            SUPERSTORE                       grass prairie, reclaimed grasslands, aspen forests, and
                                                             riparian woodlands, and provides spectacular views of         Make a new discovery at the top of every rolling hill,
                                                             the Souris River from the valley edge.                        along the shores of more than 200 lakes and wetlands,
     Furniture   Bedding   Appliances                                                                                      or amidst the rich hardwood forests of aspen, Manitoba
           Electronics   Home décor                                                                                        maple, elm, black poplar, ash and birch. The provincial
                                                                                                                           park is also home to an abundance of wildlife.












                                                             STARGAZING UNDER A
                                                             PRAIRIE SKY


                                                             What else needs to be said? Take in the experience at         ACC COUGARS                                                    pc.gc.ca/en/pn-np/mb/riding
                                                             any one of western Manitoba’s many campgrounds, or
                                                             for a more scientific approach, check out the Brandon         Cheer on the ACC Cougars teams in action during                204-848-7275
                                                             University Astronomical Observatory during a public           the course of the year.  Look for details including
             3635 VICTORIA AVENUE, BRANDON                   viewing event. brandonu.ca/observatory                        schedules for the variety of sports at assiniboine.net/        pc.info-riding@canada.ca
          204-727-4444 • Toll Free 1-800-267-4441
                Monday-Saturday 9 a.m. to 6 p.m.  |  Sunday 12 noon to 5 p.m.
     .ca               Locally Owned and Operated]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[14  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   15












 Photo by Anne Latimer
 OUTDOOR ART GALLERY  THE LINEAR MOUNDS
        NATIONAL HISTORIC SITE
 The pride of Boissevain is not only for the present
 and future but is also a reflection of the past. The   Linear Mounds located near the Souris River was
 town’s outdoor art gallery is also a Manitoba Star   designated as a national historic site of Canada in 1973.
 Attraction.   The site contains some of the most spectacular and
 See boissevain.ca/visitors/outdoor-art-gallery  best-preserved examples of mortuary mounds belonging
        to the Devil’s Lake-Sourisford Burial Complex.
 32  THE CITY LOOP TRAIL                                                                          Photo by Kayla Evans


 SYSTEM


                                                                       TRAIL
 The City Loop Trail in Brandon covers approximately 20 kms   39       HIKE THE GORGE CREEK
 of walking, running and biking trails. Download or view the
 map featuring the City Loop Trail System at               Gorge Creek Trail is an 11.6 kilometer moderately trafficked
 brandon.ca/images/pdf/Recreation/CityTrailLoop.pdf        out and back trail located near Division No. 17 in Riding
                                                           Mountain National Park that features beautiful wildflowers
                                                           and is rated as moderate. The trail is primarily used for hiking,
 BRANDON’S ONLY  SOURIS RIVER BEND TRAILS  DISCOVER TURTLE MOUNTAIN   walking, nature trips, and bird watching and is best used from
 FURNITURE  The network of trails passes through rolling mixed-  PROVINCIAL PARK  May until September.

 SUPERSTORE  grass prairie, reclaimed grasslands, aspen forests, and
 riparian woodlands, and provides spectacular views of   Make a new discovery at the top of every rolling hill,
 the Souris River from the valley edge.  along the shores of more than 200 lakes and wetlands,
 Furniture   Bedding   Appliances  or amidst the rich hardwood forests of aspen, Manitoba
 Electronics   Home décor  maple, elm, black poplar, ash and birch. The provincial
        park is also home to an abundance of wildlife.












 STARGAZING UNDER A
 PRAIRIE SKY


 What else needs to be said? Take in the experience at   ACC COUGARS   pc.gc.ca/en/pn-np/mb/riding
 any one of western Manitoba’s many campgrounds, or
 for a more scientific approach, check out the Brandon   Cheer on the ACC Cougars teams in action during   204-848-7275
 University Astronomical Observatory during a public   the course of the year.  Look for details including
 3635 VICTORIA AVENUE, BRANDON  viewing event. brandonu.ca/observatory  schedules for the variety of sports at assiniboine.net/  pc.info-riding@canada.ca
 204-727-4444 • Toll Free 1-800-267-4441
  Monday-Saturday 9 a.m. to 6 p.m.  |  Sunday 12 noon to 5 p.m.
 .ca  Locally Owned and Operated]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[16                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                     41. BIRDING AT DOUGLAS MARSH             17
                DUBS AT THE LAKE VW                                        BIRDING AT DOUGLAS
                SHOW                                                       MARSH


                The gathering of Volkswagen                                Douglas Marsh is located east of the
                enthusiasts in southwestern Manitoba                       city of Brandon. The Trans-Canada
                is staged annually on the third                            Highway runs along the northern
                weekend of August in Killarney.                            border and the community of Shilo
                                                                           lies to the south. Birders come here to
                                                                           see the Yellow Rail one of the most
                                                                           secretive species of birds. Several
                                                                           other marsh and grassland species are
                                                                           also known to occur in the marsh.


                J.A.V. DAVID MUSEUM                                        NATIONAL HISTORIC
                                                                           CAMP

                The J.A.V. David Museum in                                 National Historic Camp was a
                Killarney features native and pioneer                      Canadian military training camp,
                artifacts, war relics, photographs,                        located in the Municipality of North
                cameras, maps, trophies, textiles, art,                    Cypress – Langford west of the town
                and a restored historic post office.                       of Carberry. It was used for Army
                                                                           training from 1909 to 1934 and as
                                                                           a communications station from the
                                                                           early 1960s until 1991.













                     WEST END





     CELEBRATE SUMMER


     Everything you need for perfect picnics
     and BBQ triumphs.
     Our fresh Departments and our in-store
     Express Liquormart are ready to make
     this a summer to remember!




      Shop yourself, or let us shop for you with
            delivery or curbside pickup.
      Email your list and contact information to
      sobeyswestendbrandon @gmail.com and
           let our shoppers do the rest.


    3409 VICTORIA AVENUE   |   BRANDON   |   204-727-3443                         bdnsobeyswest      bdnsobeyswest]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[16  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN          41. BIRDING AT DOUGLAS MARSH              17
 DUBS AT THE LAKE VW   BIRDING AT DOUGLAS
 SHOW  MARSH


 The gathering of Volkswagen   Douglas Marsh is located east of the
 enthusiasts in southwestern Manitoba   city of Brandon. The Trans-Canada
 is staged annually on the third   Highway runs along the northern
 weekend of August in Killarney.  border and the community of Shilo
 lies to the south. Birders come here to
 see the Yellow Rail one of the most
 secretive species of birds. Several
 other marsh and grassland species are
 also known to occur in the marsh.


 J.A.V. DAVID MUSEUM  NATIONAL HISTORIC
 CAMP

 The J.A.V. David Museum in   National Historic Camp was a
 Killarney features native and pioneer   Canadian military training camp,
 artifacts, war relics, photographs,   located in the Municipality of North
 cameras, maps, trophies, textiles, art,   Cypress – Langford west of the town
 and a restored historic post office.  of Carberry. It was used for Army
 training from 1909 to 1934 and as
 a communications station from the
 early 1960s until 1991.













 WEST END





 CELEBRATE SUMMER


 Everything you need for perfect picnics
 and BBQ triumphs.
 Our fresh Departments and our in-store
 Express Liquormart are ready to make
 this a summer to remember!




 Shop yourself, or let us shop for you with
 delivery or curbside pickup.
 Email your list and contact information to
 sobeyswestendbrandon @gmail.com and
 let our shoppers do the rest.


 3409 VICTORIA AVENUE   |   BRANDON   |   204-727-3443   bdnsobeyswest   bdnsobeyswest]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[18                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                              19














                                                             CAMPING AT ADAM LAKE                                          MANITOBA SUMMER FAIR


                                                             Adam Lake campground offers both basic and                    The Manitoba Summer Fair takes place in June
                                                             electrical sites, while Max and William Lakes offer           in Brandon featuring a variety activities including
                                                             basic service sites. Located south of Brandon.                midway rides, petting zoo, horse and cattle show,
                                                                                                                           classic car show and so much more. Check out
                                                                                                                           provincialexhibition.com/manitoba-summer-fair for
                                                                                                                           more details.
                                                                                                                                                                              51         SPLASH PARKS


                                                                                                                                                                                         THROUGHOUT WESTMAN
   44            TAKE IN THE BRANDON                                                                                                                                          Along with the many splash parks in Brandon, there are some

                 HILLS

                                                                                                                                                                              region, including in Souris, Wawanesa, Killarney, Neepawa,
   Located in the RM of Cornwallis, the Brandon Hills has long   VISIT THE CRIDDLE/VANE                                                                                       great options for kids and their families to cool off around the
   been a haven for outdoor recreation and wildlife. With rolling   HOMESTEAD PROVINCIAL                                                                                      Virden, Reston and Carberry.
   hills and aspen-oak parkland, this beautifully forested area
   offers the perfect setting for nature lovers and photographers.   HERITAGE PARK                                         KILLARNEY’S ANNUAL FAIR IN
   The trail system is comprised of a variety of pathways ranging
   in distance from 2 km to 7.5 km. A map at the starting point   The park is located in southwestern Manitoba about       JUNE
   outlines each loop.                                       40 kilometres southeast of Brandon, and is composed
                                                             of a 130-hectare area that preserves and protects             The summer kicks off with the annual Agricultural
                                                             the heritage value of the former homesteads of the            Fair, held each year on the last weekend in June. The
                                                             Criddle/Vane family.                                          fair is a true celebration of our rural roots. Livestock
                                                                                                                           and home craft displays combined with talented local
                                                                                                                           entertainment and fun and games for the kids make it
                                                                                                                           the perfect opportunity to take in a country fair.










                                                             CANOE & KAYAK THE HISTORIC

                                                             ASSINIBOINE RIVER ROUTE

                                                             Canoe or kayak the historic Assiniboine River
                                                             Route - The Assiniboine is a great river for the              CLEAR LAKE CHAMBER MUSIC
               www.gov.cornwallis.mb.ca                      beginner. Winding through three Manitoba cities,              FESTIVAL
                                                             the Assiniboine is generally slow moving and safe
               204-725-8686                                  for even the inexperienced paddler. For much of its           The fourth week of July marks the annual Clear
                                                             length it flows by well-populated farmland, but it is         Lake Chamber Music Festival directed by pianists
               info@gov.cornwallis.mb.ca                     remarkably unaffected by human habitation.                    Alexander Tselyakov and Daniel Tselyakov.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[18  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   19














 CAMPING AT ADAM LAKE  MANITOBA SUMMER FAIR


 Adam Lake campground offers both basic and   The Manitoba Summer Fair takes place in June
 electrical sites, while Max and William Lakes offer   in Brandon featuring a variety activities including
 basic service sites. Located south of Brandon.  midway rides, petting zoo, horse and cattle show,
        classic car show and so much more. Check out
        provincialexhibition.com/manitoba-summer-fair for
        more details.
                                                           51         SPLASH PARKS


                                                                      THROUGHOUT WESTMAN
 44  TAKE IN THE BRANDON                                   Along with the many splash parks in Brandon, there are some

 HILLS

                                                           region, including in Souris, Wawanesa, Killarney, Neepawa,
 Located in the RM of Cornwallis, the Brandon Hills has long   VISIT THE CRIDDLE/VANE   great options for kids and their families to cool off around the
 been a haven for outdoor recreation and wildlife. With rolling   HOMESTEAD PROVINCIAL   Virden, Reston and Carberry.
 hills and aspen-oak parkland, this beautifully forested area
 offers the perfect setting for nature lovers and photographers.   HERITAGE PARK  KILLARNEY’S ANNUAL FAIR IN
 The trail system is comprised of a variety of pathways ranging
 in distance from 2 km to 7.5 km. A map at the starting point   The park is located in southwestern Manitoba about   JUNE
 outlines each loop.  40 kilometres southeast of Brandon, and is composed
 of a 130-hectare area that preserves and protects   The summer kicks off with the annual Agricultural
 the heritage value of the former homesteads of the   Fair, held each year on the last weekend in June. The
 Criddle/Vane family.  fair is a true celebration of our rural roots. Livestock
        and home craft displays combined with talented local
        entertainment and fun and games for the kids make it
        the perfect opportunity to take in a country fair.










 CANOE & KAYAK THE HISTORIC

 ASSINIBOINE RIVER ROUTE

 Canoe or kayak the historic Assiniboine River
 Route - The Assiniboine is a great river for the   CLEAR LAKE CHAMBER MUSIC
 www.gov.cornwallis.mb.ca  beginner. Winding through three Manitoba cities,   FESTIVAL
 the Assiniboine is generally slow moving and safe
 204-725-8686  for even the inexperienced paddler. For much of its   The fourth week of July marks the annual Clear
 length it flows by well-populated farmland, but it is   Lake Chamber Music Festival directed by pianists
 info@gov.cornwallis.mb.ca  remarkably unaffected by human habitation.  Alexander Tselyakov and Daniel Tselyakov.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[20                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                              21

                                                                                                                                                                                                               Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg











                                                             SKATING OVAL IN BRANDON                                       ROLAND PUMPKIN FAIR


                                                             In addition to great outdoor skating, the oval features       The annual Roland Pumpkin Festival event features
                                                             a warming shack, portable washrooms, floodlighting,           a pancake breakfast, craft sale, agricultural and
                                                             ambient music, and fire pits to cook or warm-                 educational displays, fair exhibits, great pumpkin and
                                                             up. Lights go off at 11 p.m. Parking is located at            vegetable commonwealth weigh-off, pumpkin patch tea
                                                             McGregor Avenue or Hilton Avenue.                             room and more. The event is staged in October.

                                                                                                                                                                              59          TAKE IN A BLUE BOMBERS


                                                                                                                                                                                          GAME IN WINNIPEG
   52          DAUPHIN’S                                                                                                                                                      Check out the Blue Bombers’ schedule for a date that works

               COUNTRYFEST


   Canada’s longest-running country music festival has a history                                                                                                              best for you.
   of providing first-class entertainment to the many loyal fans   Photo by Kira Paterson
   who have attended the festival over the past 25 years. The event
   usually takes place on the first weekend of July. For more details   WALKING PATH AT NEEPAWA’S                          WESTMAN MULTICULTURAL
   check out countryfest.ca
                                                             BIRD SANCTUARY                                                FESTIVAL IN BRANDON

                                                             The Bird Sanctuary has become a popular resident              Formerly called the Lieutenant Governor’s Winter
                                                             and tourist destination. Nestled on the South of              Festival, this city-wide celebration features pavilions
                                                             Town by Park Lake, the sanctuary is home to emu’s,            that focus on the culture, education, cuisine, and
                                                             pheasants, peacocks, ducks, geese, rabbits, and other         entertainment of several different countries. The event
                                                             animals. The facility is operated by volunteers.              is usually staged in January.


















                                                             TURTLE STATUE                                                 CANADA DAY ACTIVITIES
               countryfest.ca                                                                                              THROUGHOUT WESTMAN
                                                             The statue greets visitors to the small town of
               800-361-7300 or 204-622-3700                  Boissevain. The idea for the Tommy the Turtle statue          Canada Day celebrations, including fireworks, are
                                                             was developed by the local Chamber of Commerce in             staged in several Westman Communities. Brandon’s                      (204) 728-3777
                                                             1969 and represents the Turtle Mountain area.                 gathering spot is the Riverbank Discovery Centre.               chemtradelogistics.com

                                                                                                                                                                                       8080 Richmond Ave E, Brandon]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[20  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   21

                                                                                            Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg











 SKATING OVAL IN BRANDON  ROLAND PUMPKIN FAIR


 In addition to great outdoor skating, the oval features   The annual Roland Pumpkin Festival event features
 a warming shack, portable washrooms, floodlighting,   a pancake breakfast, craft sale, agricultural and
 ambient music, and fire pits to cook or warm-  educational displays, fair exhibits, great pumpkin and
 up. Lights go off at 11 p.m. Parking is located at   vegetable commonwealth weigh-off, pumpkin patch tea
 McGregor Avenue or Hilton Avenue.  room and more. The event is staged in October.

                                                           59          TAKE IN A BLUE BOMBERS


                                                                       GAME IN WINNIPEG
 52  DAUPHIN’S                                             Check out the Blue Bombers’ schedule for a date that works

 COUNTRYFEST


 Canada’s longest-running country music festival has a history   best for you.
 of providing first-class entertainment to the many loyal fans   Photo by Kira Paterson
 who have attended the festival over the past 25 years. The event
 usually takes place on the first weekend of July. For more details   WALKING PATH AT NEEPAWA’S   WESTMAN MULTICULTURAL
 check out countryfest.ca
 BIRD SANCTUARY  FESTIVAL IN BRANDON

 The Bird Sanctuary has become a popular resident   Formerly called the Lieutenant Governor’s Winter
 and tourist destination. Nestled on the South of   Festival, this city-wide celebration features pavilions
 Town by Park Lake, the sanctuary is home to emu’s,   that focus on the culture, education, cuisine, and
 pheasants, peacocks, ducks, geese, rabbits, and other   entertainment of several different countries. The event
 animals. The facility is operated by volunteers.   is usually staged in January.


















 TURTLE STATUE  CANADA DAY ACTIVITIES
 countryfest.ca  THROUGHOUT WESTMAN
 The statue greets visitors to the small town of
 800-361-7300 or 204-622-3700  Boissevain. The idea for the Tommy the Turtle statue   Canada Day celebrations, including fireworks, are
 was developed by the local Chamber of Commerce in   staged in several Westman Communities. Brandon’s   (204) 728-3777
 1969 and represents the Turtle Mountain area.  gathering spot is the Riverbank Discovery Centre.  chemtradelogistics.com

                                                                   8080 Richmond Ave E, Brandon]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[22                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             23
                                                                                                                                         HIKE THE BALD HILL                                         NARCISSE SNAKE DENS

                                                                                                                                         Bald Hill Trail via North Escarpment                       Tens of thousands of snakes live in
                                                                                                                                         Trailhead is a 24.8 kilometer lightly                      Manitoba’s Narcisse Snake Dens
                                                                                                                                         trafficked out and back trail located                      and the best time to see them is
                                                                                                                                         near McCreary that offers the chance                       during the spring mating season.
                                                                                                                                         to see wildlife and is rated as difficult.                 The dens are located in provincial
                                                                                                                                                                                                    wildlife management area in the
                                                                                                                                                                                                    Rural Municipality of Armstrong
                                                             MB ANTIQUE AUTO MUSEUM                                                                                                                 approximately six kms north of
                                                                                                                                                                                                    Narcisse, Manitoba.
                                                             Located in Elkhorn, the museum is open seasonally,
                                                             from May 1 to September 30; daily from 9 a.m. to 6
                                                             p.m. Check out mbautomuseum.com.
                                                                                                                                         ROCK LAKE,                                                 TREESBANK FERRY
                                                                                                                                         CARTWRIGHT                                                 MONUMENT

                                                                                                                                                                                                    When the Treesbank Bridge opened
                                                                                                                                         The second largest navigable lake
   60            OPEN GARDEN TOURS IN                         Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg                                         in southwestern Manitoba. It is                            upstream, in September 1989, this
                                                                                                                                         approximately 13 kms long.
                                                                                                                                                                                                    long-established crossing closed after
                 BRANDON
                                                                                                                                                                                                    109 years of service. The first Treesbank
                                                                                                                                                                                                    Ferry gave access to the Dominion
   Volunteers open up their personal yards to the public and allow                                                                                                                                  Land Office of 1880 on the west side
   them to tour their creative gardens. Check out brandon.ca/                                                                                                                                       of the Assiniboine River. For more
   events/open-garden-tours for the 2021 dates.                                                                                                                                                     details go to mhs.mb.ca/docs/sites/
                                                                                                                                                                                                    treesbankferry.shtml.
                                                             TOUR THE MANITOBA
                                                             LEGISLATURE


                                                             Located in Winnipeg, appointments for tours can be
                                                             made by calling (204) 945-5813 or please visit the
                                                             Visitor Tour Program page for more information and
                                                             to download a tour registration form. The building is
                                                             open every day from 8:00 a.m. – 8:00 p.m. for self-
                                                             guided tours.


















                                                             MUSIC IN THE PARKS

                                                             Make sure to take in Brandon’s Music in the Park
                                                             concert series,  Music in the Parks takes place every
                                                             Tuesday from June to August.
                                                             Check out brandon.ca/events/music-in-the-park for
                                                             more details.]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[22  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   23
                     HIKE THE BALD HILL                                         NARCISSE SNAKE DENS

                     Bald Hill Trail via North Escarpment                       Tens of thousands of snakes live in
                     Trailhead is a 24.8 kilometer lightly                      Manitoba’s Narcisse Snake Dens
                     trafficked out and back trail located                      and the best time to see them is
                     near McCreary that offers the chance                       during the spring mating season.
                     to see wildlife and is rated as difficult.                 The dens are located in provincial
                                                                                wildlife management area in the
                                                                                Rural Municipality of Armstrong
 MB ANTIQUE AUTO MUSEUM                                                         approximately six kms north of
                                                                                Narcisse, Manitoba.
 Located in Elkhorn, the museum is open seasonally,
 from May 1 to September 30; daily from 9 a.m. to 6
 p.m. Check out mbautomuseum.com.
                     ROCK LAKE,                                                 TREESBANK FERRY
                     CARTWRIGHT                                                 MONUMENT

                                                                                When the Treesbank Bridge opened
                     The second largest navigable lake
 60  OPEN GARDEN TOURS IN   Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg  in southwestern Manitoba. It is   upstream, in September 1989, this
                     approximately 13 kms long.
                                                                                long-established crossing closed after
 BRANDON
                                                                                109 years of service. The first Treesbank
                                                                                Ferry gave access to the Dominion
 Volunteers open up their personal yards to the public and allow                Land Office of 1880 on the west side
 them to tour their creative gardens. Check out brandon.ca/                     of the Assiniboine River. For more
 events/open-garden-tours for the 2021 dates.                                   details go to mhs.mb.ca/docs/sites/
                                                                                treesbankferry.shtml.
 TOUR THE MANITOBA
 LEGISLATURE


 Located in Winnipeg, appointments for tours can be
 made by calling (204) 945-5813 or please visit the
 Visitor Tour Program page for more information and
 to download a tour registration form. The building is
 open every day from 8:00 a.m. – 8:00 p.m. for self-
 guided tours.


















 MUSIC IN THE PARKS

 Make sure to take in Brandon’s Music in the Park
 concert series,  Music in the Parks takes place every
 Tuesday from June to August.
 Check out brandon.ca/events/music-in-the-park for
 more details.]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[24                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             25
                ARTS MOSAIC,                                               PONDEROSA DAYS,
                VIRDEN                                                     CARTWRIGHT

                At any given time there are over 100                       Celebrate Ponderosa Days on the
                works made by over 30 artisans for                         August long weekend. For more
                sale. Check out their website for more                     details cartwrightroblin.ca/node/2127
                details, artsmosaic.ca.


                                                                                                                           COMMONWEALTH AIR
                                                                                                                           TRAINING MUSEUM IN

                                                                                                                           BRANDON

                SEE CABREA THE                                             FALL SUPPERS                                    The Commonwealth Air Training Plan Museum is
                SNOW GOOSE                                                 AROUND MANITOBA                                 an aviation museum located at Brandon Municipal
                                                                                                                           Airport, Brandon. Check out their website at
                In 2000, a statue of Cabrea the Snow                       Fall suppers are a tradition in rural           airmuseum.ca.                                      75          ART GALLERY OF
                Goose was erected in Dunrea, in what                       Manitoba communities. Follow event                                                                             SOUTHWESTERN
                is now the Rural Municipalities of                         dates here:
                Prairie Lakes, to recognize its location                   facebook.com/ManitobaFallSuppers/                                                                              MANITOBA, BRANDON
                in the centre of the North American
                goose flyway.                                                                                                                                                 The Art Gallery of Southwestern Manitoba is an art museum in
                                                                                                                                                                              Brandon, Manitoba located in the Town Centre on Rosser Ave.
                                                                                                                                                                              For more details check out agsm.ca






                                                                                                                                                                                      EXPERIENCE HISTORY
                                                                                                                           FISHING AT RIVERS DAM                                             WITH A BANG!

                                                                                                                                                                                                 At The RCA Museum
                                                                                                                           Just a 25-minute drive from Brandon, the dam at
                                                                                                                           Rivers and Lake Wahtopanah, known as the Rivers           CANADA’S NATIONAL ARTILLERY MUSEUM
                                                                                                                           Reservoir, offer some excellent fishing in both       LE MUSÉE NATIONAL DE L’ARTILLERIE DU CANADA
                                                                                                                           summer and winter months.                                             Au Musée de L’ARC
                                                                                                                                                                                       FAITES DE L’HISTOIRE

                                                                                                                                                                                            AVEC UN BANG!











                                                                                                                                                                                          CFB Shilo 204.765.3000 ext. 3570
                                                                                                                                                                                         BFC Shilo 204.765.3000 poste 3570
                                                                                                                           COOL DOWN WITH COOL                                                  www.rcamuseum.com
                                                                                                                           TREATS
                                                                                                                                                                                 Visit Manitoba’s Star Attraction
                                                                                                                           Plenty of ice cream to go around at various stops in          Military Museums.
                                                                                                                           Westman.
                                                                                                                                                                                Visitez les Attractions Étoiles des
                                                                                                                                                                                  Musées Militaires au Manitoba.]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[24  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   25
 ARTS MOSAIC,   PONDEROSA DAYS,
 VIRDEN  CARTWRIGHT

 At any given time there are over 100   Celebrate Ponderosa Days on the
 works made by over 30 artisans for   August long weekend. For more
 sale. Check out their website for more   details cartwrightroblin.ca/node/2127
 details, artsmosaic.ca.


        COMMONWEALTH AIR
        TRAINING MUSEUM IN

        BRANDON

 SEE CABREA THE   FALL SUPPERS   The Commonwealth Air Training Plan Museum is
 SNOW GOOSE  AROUND MANITOBA  an aviation museum located at Brandon Municipal
        Airport, Brandon. Check out their website at
 In 2000, a statue of Cabrea the Snow   Fall suppers are a tradition in rural   airmuseum.ca.  75  ART GALLERY OF
 Goose was erected in Dunrea, in what   Manitoba communities. Follow event   SOUTHWESTERN
 is now the Rural Municipalities of   dates here:
 Prairie Lakes, to recognize its location   facebook.com/ManitobaFallSuppers/  MANITOBA, BRANDON
 in the centre of the North American
 goose flyway.                                             The Art Gallery of Southwestern Manitoba is an art museum in
                                                           Brandon, Manitoba located in the Town Centre on Rosser Ave.
                                                           For more details check out agsm.ca






                                                                   EXPERIENCE HISTORY
        FISHING AT RIVERS DAM                                             WITH A BANG!

                                                                             At The RCA Museum
        Just a 25-minute drive from Brandon, the dam at
        Rivers and Lake Wahtopanah, known as the Rivers           CANADA’S NATIONAL ARTILLERY MUSEUM
        Reservoir, offer some excellent fishing in both       LE MUSÉE NATIONAL DE L’ARTILLERIE DU CANADA
        summer and winter months.                                             Au Musée de L’ARC
                                                                   FAITES DE L’HISTOIRE

                                                                         AVEC UN BANG!











                                                                       CFB Shilo 204.765.3000 ext. 3570
                                                                      BFC Shilo 204.765.3000 poste 3570
        COOL DOWN WITH COOL                                                  www.rcamuseum.com
        TREATS
                                                              Visit Manitoba’s Star Attraction
        Plenty of ice cream to go around at various stops in          Military Museums.
        Westman.
                                                             Visitez les Attractions Étoiles des
                                                              Musées Militaires au Manitoba.]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[26                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             27]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[26  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[28                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             29














                                                             SKI VALLEY, MINNEDOSA                                         ARGYLE MUSEUM

                                                             Located seven kilometres north of Minnedosa on                When visiting Baldour check out the many exhibits
                                                             Highway 10, Ski Valley has nine distinctive runs for          at the Argyle Museum along with the oldest Icelandic
                                                             all levels of skiers and snowboarders. The resort also        Lutheran Church in Canada (built-in 1889). You can
                                                             offers licensed dining, ski and snowboard rentals and         find more information at
                                                             instruction, snow blade rents, and special group and          rmofargyle.ca/p/history-of-baldur.
                                                             school rates.
   76          CRUISE NIGHT                                                                                                                                                   83            HERITAGE HOME OF THE


                                                                                                                                                                                            ARTS
               Watch for the Cruise Night car show which takes
   place May through September downtown on Rosser Avenue,                                                                                                                     The gallery is housed in a beautiful heritage home. You can
   Brandon.
                                                                                                                                                                              find more details by checking out their website at
                                                                                                                                                                              killarneyarts.com






         AS WE MARK MANITOBA 150
                                                             INSPIRE STUDIO OF FINE ART
                                                                                                                           HANBURY HILL IN BRANDON
                                                             The gallery featuring local artists in a variety of
                                                             disciplines has become a “must see” destination for the       Toboggan in the winter or enjoy the bike and hiking
                                                             community of Minnedosa.                                       paths.





















                                                             DINE OUT AT A WESTMAN                                         CHECK OUT AUTUMN COLOURS

                                                             RESTAURANT
                                                                                                                           With lush forests and amazing parks, Manitoba was
                                                             Several scrumptious homegrown options to choose               made for leaf-peeping. From September to October,
        MAYOR &                                              from in addition to the chains you have come to know.         foliage throughout the province turns every shade.
       COUNCIL]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[28  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   29














 SKI VALLEY, MINNEDOSA  ARGYLE MUSEUM

 Located seven kilometres north of Minnedosa on   When visiting Baldour check out the many exhibits
 Highway 10, Ski Valley has nine distinctive runs for   at the Argyle Museum along with the oldest Icelandic
 all levels of skiers and snowboarders. The resort also   Lutheran Church in Canada (built-in 1889). You can
 offers licensed dining, ski and snowboard rentals and   find more information at
 instruction, snow blade rents, and special group and   rmofargyle.ca/p/history-of-baldur.
 school rates.
 76  CRUISE NIGHT                                          83           HERITAGE HOME OF THE


                                                                        ARTS
 Watch for the Cruise Night car show which takes
 place May through September downtown on Rosser Avenue,    The gallery is housed in a beautiful heritage home. You can
 Brandon.
                                                           find more details by checking out their website at
                                                           killarneyarts.com






 AS WE MARK MANITOBA 150
 INSPIRE STUDIO OF FINE ART
        HANBURY HILL IN BRANDON
 The gallery featuring local artists in a variety of
 disciplines has become a “must see” destination for the   Toboggan in the winter or enjoy the bike and hiking
 community of Minnedosa.  paths.





















 DINE OUT AT A WESTMAN   CHECK OUT AUTUMN COLOURS

 RESTAURANT
        With lush forests and amazing parks, Manitoba was
 Several scrumptious homegrown options to choose   made for leaf-peeping. From September to October,
 MAYOR &  from in addition to the chains you have come to know.  foliage throughout the province turns every shade.
 COUNCIL]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[30                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                              31
        87. ASSINIBOINE PARK & ZOO                                                      Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg
                                                                                                                                         TURTLE MOUNTAIN                                            COUNTRY COURT
                                                                                                                                         FLYWHEEL CLUB                                              BUILDING
                                                                                                                                         HISTORIC VILLAGE                                           Constructed in 1884, when the

                                                                                                                                         A large display building that houses as                    surrounding district was in its earliest
                                                                                                                                         many as one hundred engines located in                     stage of settlement. Located in
                                                                                                                                         Killarney.                                                 Neepawa the historic site once housed
                                                                                                                                                                                                    the county and municipal offices,
                                                                                                                                                                                                    a circuit judges’ courthouse, police
                                                                                                                                                                                                    station, and theatre.





                                                                                                                                         MARRINGHURST                                               ASSINIBOINE PARK &
                                                                                                                                         HERITAGE HOUSE,                                            ZOO
                                                                                                                                         PILOT MOUND                                                Assiniboine Park Zoo is an 80-acre

                                                                                                                                         The heritage site was built in 1909 and                    zoo that was established in 1904 at
                                                                                                                                         in the summer is currently operating as                    the West end of Assiniboine Park
                                                                                                                                         a turn-of-the-century farmhouse and                        in Winnipeg. It is managed by the
                                                                                                                                         museum.                                                    Assiniboine Park Conservancy.

                                                                                                                                                                                                    More information can be found at
                                                                                                                                                                                                    assiniboineparkzoo.ca













                                                                                                                               LARGE SELETION OF RV AND
                                                                                                                             TRAILER PARTS  -  FULL SERVICE



                                                                                                                         Camper                 Horse           Cattle Hauling







                                                                                                                                            www.aats.ca

                                                                                                                                          1-888-571-8899


                                                                                                                                           204-729-8989

                                                                                                                              770 Highland Avenue, Brandon







                                                                                                                          MPI ACCREDITED / HITCH AND WIRING SPECIALIST]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[30  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   31
 87. ASSINIBOINE PARK & ZOO  Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg
                     TURTLE MOUNTAIN                                            COUNTRY COURT
                     FLYWHEEL CLUB                                              BUILDING
                     HISTORIC VILLAGE                                           Constructed in 1884, when the

                     A large display building that houses as                    surrounding district was in its earliest
                     many as one hundred engines located in                     stage of settlement. Located in
                     Killarney.                                                 Neepawa the historic site once housed
                                                                                the county and municipal offices,
                                                                                a circuit judges’ courthouse, police
                                                                                station, and theatre.





                     MARRINGHURST                                               ASSINIBOINE PARK &
                     HERITAGE HOUSE,                                            ZOO
                     PILOT MOUND                                                Assiniboine Park Zoo is an 80-acre

                     The heritage site was built in 1909 and                    zoo that was established in 1904 at
                     in the summer is currently operating as                    the West end of Assiniboine Park
                     a turn-of-the-century farmhouse and                        in Winnipeg. It is managed by the
                     museum.                                                    Assiniboine Park Conservancy.

                                                                                More information can be found at
                                                                                assiniboineparkzoo.ca













            LARGE SELETION OF RV AND
          TRAILER PARTS  -  FULL SERVICE



      Camper                Horse            Cattle Hauling







                        www.aats.ca

                       1-888-571-8899


                       204-729-8989

           770 Highland Avenue, Brandon







       MPI ACCREDITED / HITCH AND WIRING SPECIALIST]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[32                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             33
                THE WASKADA                                                THE CLASSIC
                MUSEUM                                                     GARDEN, BIRTLE


                The museum has a collection ranging                        The Classic Garden features
                from antique cars, trucks, and a silent                    three well-equipped studios to
                movie projector along with multiple                        accommodate pottery, carpentry, arts,
                buildings where specific collections                       and sewing. For more details check
                are showcased.                                             out theclassicgarden.ca








                ANCHORAGE                                                  HERITAGE WALKING
                GARDENS                                                    TOUR

                Scheduled tours usually take place in                      Listen to a tour guide through your
                July and August featuring an elegant                       smartphone as you explore Brandon!
                landmark located near Boissevain.                          Keep the professional tour guide;
                The site features handcrafted metal                        ditch the crowded tour groups, tight
                sculptures, recycled materials, paths,                     schedules and high prices! Download
                and perennial gardens.                                     the Tripvia app on your smartphone
                                                                           today!





        Relax at home...Enjoy your own back yard!





























                                                               BOOK NOW FOR 2021

                                                                       PLEASE PHONE 204-726-8488
                                                             FOR AN APPOINTMENT TO INQUIRE ABOUT OUR
                                                               SUNROOMS OR OUR FANTASTIC PRODUCTS
                                                                           • FREE ESTIMATES •                                                                                             89. THE CLASSIC GARDEN, BIRTLE

                        204-726-8488  |  View all our products at www.sunspacesunrooms.com
                                            |  155 Prairie Crescent Brandon  |  sales@elitesunrooms.ca]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[32  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   33
 THE WASKADA   THE CLASSIC
 MUSEUM  GARDEN, BIRTLE


 The museum has a collection ranging   The Classic Garden features
 from antique cars, trucks, and a silent   three well-equipped studios to
 movie projector along with multiple   accommodate pottery, carpentry, arts,
 buildings where specific collections   and sewing. For more details check
 are showcased.  out theclassicgarden.ca








 ANCHORAGE   HERITAGE WALKING
 GARDENS  TOUR

 Scheduled tours usually take place in   Listen to a tour guide through your
 July and August featuring an elegant   smartphone as you explore Brandon!
 landmark located near Boissevain.   Keep the professional tour guide;
 The site features handcrafted metal   ditch the crowded tour groups, tight
 sculptures, recycled materials, paths,   schedules and high prices! Download
 and perennial gardens.  the Tripvia app on your smartphone
 today!





 Relax at home...Enjoy your own back yard!





























 BOOK NOW FOR 2021

 PLEASE PHONE 204-726-8488
 FOR AN APPOINTMENT TO INQUIRE ABOUT OUR
 SUNROOMS OR OUR FANTASTIC PRODUCTS
 • FREE ESTIMATES •                                                    89. THE CLASSIC GARDEN, BIRTLE

 204-726-8488  |  View all our products at www.sunspacesunrooms.com
                   |  155 Prairie Crescent Brandon  |  sales@elitesunrooms.ca]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[34                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             35
                TAKE IN THE                                                KENTON DAM SITE                                                                                                                     Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg
                WESTMAN REPTILE                                            Kenton Dam, located south of
                GARDENS                                                    Kenton, was developed for camping,
                                                                           swimming, and fishing, and makes an
                Located near Douglas, the Westman                          ideal location for the annual Canada
                Reptile Gardens is an indoor exhibit                       Day celebrations. The dam was first
                of North America’s most varied                             constructed on the Brierwood Creek in
                collection of reptiles, amphibians, and                    1969.                                                                     Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg
                arachnids under one roof. For more
                details go to reptilegardens.ca.                                                                           VISIT THE MANITOBA MUSEUM
                                                                                                                           IN WINNIPEG


                                                                                                                           Set off on a thrilling voyage of excitement and
                TOUR THE MARGARET                                          VISIT THE CARBERRY                              discovery at the Manitoba Museum in Winnipeg. In
                                                                                                                           the Museum Galleries, you can travel through time.
                LAURENCE HOUSE                                             PLAINS MUSEUM                                   Check out their website at manitobamuseum.ca

                Margaret Laurence, an internationally                      Visit the Carberry Plains Museum                                                                   99          THE FORKS IN WINNIPEG
                renowned author, was born and raised                       and experience early prairie life. Next
                in Neepawa. Laurence lived here in                         door to the Museum, visit the fully-                                                                           The Forks have been a meeting place for
                her grandfather’s house from l935 to                       restored Gingerbread House. For                                                                    over 6,000 years. Situated at the junction of the Red and
                l944. Built ca. l894, the house, and                       more details go to townofcarberry.ca/                                                              Assiniboine Rivers, this year-round, historical landmark
                her grandfather John Simpson figured                       carberry-plains-museum.                                                                            delights with its exceptional culinary offerings, unique
                prominently in the Manawaka novels.                                                                                                                           shopping, diverse attractions, and memorable events.
                See neepawatourism.ca                                                                                                                                         For more details go to theforks.com




                                                                                                                           NATIONAL INDIGENOUS                                       HERITAGE HOME FOR THE ARTS
                                                                                                                           PEOPLES DAY CELEBRATION                                         Killarney’s Community Arts & Culture Centre

                                                                                                                           National Indigenous Peoples Day, June 21, is a                            • Art Exhibitions
                                                                                                                                                                                                     • Performing Arts
                                                                                                                           day recognizing and celebrating the cultures and                   • Workshops for all Ages & Experience
                                                                                                                           contributions of the First Nations, Inuit, and Métis              • Rentals for Special Events & Meetings
                                                                                                                           Indigenous peoples of Canada.
                                                                                                                                                                                                  44 Water Avenue, Killarney
                                                                                                                                                                                                      Open All Year
             Things To Do and See                                                                                                                                                             Tuesday to Saturday, 12 noon to 4:00 pm

      • Manitoba Automobile Museum
      • Pioneer Home Museum
      • CPR Historic Center & Arts Mosaic
      • Elkhorn Golf Course
      • Virden Wellview Golf Course
      • Elkhorn Spray Park
      • Virden Swimming Pool
      • Eternal Springs
      • Kenton Dam and Campground                                                                                          TAKE IN SCENIC VIEWS BY
      • Virden Lions Campground                                                                                            HORSEBACK
      • Elkhorn Campground                                                                                                 Spring, summer and fall are the best seasons to

   Check out our trendy shops and dining                                                                                   horseback ride while enjoying some of Manitoba’s                          For more information call 431-734-0394
                                                                                                                           most scenic views. Check out travelmanitoba.com/
       and more unique experiences at                                                                                      things-to-do/outdoor/horseback for more details.                           or email ktmartscouncil@gmail.com
                                                                                                                                                                                                          www.killarneyarts.com
       www.prairiegatewaytourism.ca
     Facebook @prairiegatewaytourism                                                                                                                                                                   @heritagehomeforthearts  @killarneyarts
                                                                                                                                                                                                           @KillarneyTurtleMountainArtsCouncilConcerts]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[34  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   35
 TAKE IN THE   KENTON DAM SITE                                                              Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg
 WESTMAN REPTILE   Kenton Dam, located south of
 GARDENS  Kenton, was developed for camping,
 swimming, and fishing, and makes an
 Located near Douglas, the Westman   ideal location for the annual Canada
 Reptile Gardens is an indoor exhibit   Day celebrations. The dam was first
 of North America’s most varied   constructed on the Brierwood Creek in
 collection of reptiles, amphibians, and   1969.  Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg
 arachnids under one roof. For more
 details go to reptilegardens.ca.  VISIT THE MANITOBA MUSEUM
        IN WINNIPEG


        Set off on a thrilling voyage of excitement and
 TOUR THE MARGARET   VISIT THE CARBERRY   discovery at the Manitoba Museum in Winnipeg. In
        the Museum Galleries, you can travel through time.
 LAURENCE HOUSE  PLAINS MUSEUM  Check out their website at manitobamuseum.ca

 Margaret Laurence, an internationally   Visit the Carberry Plains Museum   99  THE FORKS IN WINNIPEG
 renowned author, was born and raised   and experience early prairie life. Next
 in Neepawa. Laurence lived here in   door to the Museum, visit the fully-  The Forks have been a meeting place for
 her grandfather’s house from l935 to   restored Gingerbread House. For   over 6,000 years. Situated at the junction of the Red and
 l944. Built ca. l894, the house, and   more details go to townofcarberry.ca/  Assiniboine Rivers, this year-round, historical landmark
 her grandfather John Simpson figured   carberry-plains-museum.  delights with its exceptional culinary offerings, unique
 prominently in the Manawaka novels.                       shopping, diverse attractions, and memorable events.
 See neepawatourism.ca                                     For more details go to theforks.com




        NATIONAL INDIGENOUS                                      HERITAGE HOME FOR THE ARTS
        PEOPLES DAY CELEBRATION                                         Killarney’s Community Arts & Culture Centre

        National Indigenous Peoples Day, June 21, is a                            • Art Exhibitions
                                                                                  • Performing Arts
        day recognizing and celebrating the cultures and                  • Workshops for all Ages & Experience
        contributions of the First Nations, Inuit, and Métis              • Rentals for Special Events & Meetings
        Indigenous peoples of Canada.
                                                                               44 Water Avenue, Killarney
                                                                                   Open All Year
 Things To Do and See                                                      Tuesday to Saturday, 12 noon to 4:00 pm

     • Manitoba Automobile Museum
     • Pioneer Home Museum
     • CPR Historic Center & Arts Mosaic
     • Elkhorn Golf Course
     • Virden Wellview Golf Course
     • Elkhorn Spray Park
     • Virden Swimming Pool
     • Eternal Springs
     • Kenton Dam and Campground  TAKE IN SCENIC VIEWS BY
     • Virden Lions Campground  HORSEBACK
     • Elkhorn Campground  Spring, summer and fall are the best seasons to

 Check out our trendy shops and dining   horseback ride while enjoying some of Manitoba’s   For more information call 431-734-0394
        most scenic views. Check out travelmanitoba.com/
 and more unique experiences at   things-to-do/outdoor/horseback for more details.  or email ktmartscouncil@gmail.com
                                                                                       www.killarneyarts.com
 www.prairiegatewaytourism.ca
 Facebook @prairiegatewaytourism                                                    @heritagehomeforthearts  @killarneyarts
                                                                                        @KillarneyTurtleMountainArtsCouncilConcerts]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[36                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             37














                                                             ANTLER RIVER HISTORICAL                                       MANITOBA AGRICULTURE
                                                             MUSEUM, MELITA                                                MUSEUM


                                                             The Antler River Historical Society Museum was                The museum is dedicated to collecting vintage farm
                                                             opened in 1972. It replaced an 1905 eight-room public         machinery and buildings from 1900 and before.
                                                             elementary school on the corner of Summit and Ash             Located on 50 acres near Austin, Manitoba.
                                                             Streets.
                                                                                                                                                                                                              Photo provided by Daly House Museum
                                                                                                                                                                              107              DALY HOUSE MUSEUM,


   100              KEYSTONE CENTRE –                                                                                                                                         Daly House Museum is located in Brandon, Manitoba. Much of
                                                                                                                                                                                               BRANDON

                    YEAR-ROUND ACTIVITIES


                                                                                                                                                                              brick fireplace, and an oak staircase. More details can be found at
   The Keystone Centre is a multi-purpose facility located in                                                                                                                 the original architecture is intact, including hardwood floors, a
   Brandon featuring a 5,102-seat arena which is known as                                                                                                                     dalyhousemuseum.ca.
   Westoba Place. It is the home of the Brandon Wheat Kings of                                                             TIPI TOURS LEGACY PROJECT
   the Western Hockey League and the annual Royal Manitoba
   Winter Fair.                                              HILLCREST MUSEUM, SOURIS                                      A committee sponsored by the Brandon Friendship
                                                                                                                           Centre received a grant to help establish in Brandon a
                                                             The Museum, originally known as “Squire Hall”, was            legacy for Indigenous culture and missing and murdered
                                                             built in 1910. The building features an etched glass          Indigenous women and girls. The money was put
                                                             entrance, ornate wooden staircase, unique stained glass       toward the Tipi Tour Legacy Project of Brandon, which
                                                             windows, pressed tin ceilings and original woodwork.          was inspired by the Walking With Our Sisters exhibit
                                                             The museum is designated as one of Canada’s most              that visited the city in 2016. The group hopes to have
                                                             important heritage properties.                                more than 20 tipis placed around the city by 2021.





                                                                                                                                                                                      Borrow from our physical collection,
                                                                                                                                                                                           enjoy eResources at home,
                                                                                                                                                                                    and attend a variety of virtual programs.
                                                                                                                                                                                            All free with membership.







               https://keystonecentre.com/                   WILDLIFE MUSEUM                                               WHEAT CITY WHISKEY JACKS

               204-726-3500                                  Explore the Irvin Goodon International Wildlife               Make sure to take in the Wheat City Whiskey Jacks
                                                             Museum in Boissevain which features over 4,000                Expedition League baseball action at Andrews Field.
               info@keystonecentre.com                       square feet of displayed wildlife.                            Check out their website wheatcitywhiskeyjacks.com
                                                                                                                           for more details.
                                                                                                                                                                                       info@wmrl.ca • 204-727-6648]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[36  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   37














 ANTLER RIVER HISTORICAL   MANITOBA AGRICULTURE
 MUSEUM, MELITA  MUSEUM


 The Antler River Historical Society Museum was   The museum is dedicated to collecting vintage farm
 opened in 1972. It replaced an 1905 eight-room public   machinery and buildings from 1900 and before.
 elementary school on the corner of Summit and Ash   Located on 50 acres near Austin, Manitoba.
 Streets.
                                                                                           Photo provided by Daly House Museum
                                                           107             DALY HOUSE MUSEUM,


 100  KEYSTONE CENTRE –                                    Daly House Museum is located in Brandon, Manitoba. Much of
                                                                           BRANDON

 YEAR-ROUND ACTIVITIES


                                                           brick fireplace, and an oak staircase. More details can be found at
 The Keystone Centre is a multi-purpose facility located in   the original architecture is intact, including hardwood floors, a
 Brandon featuring a 5,102-seat arena which is known as    dalyhousemuseum.ca.
 Westoba Place. It is the home of the Brandon Wheat Kings of   TIPI TOURS LEGACY PROJECT
 the Western Hockey League and the annual Royal Manitoba
 Winter Fair.  HILLCREST MUSEUM, SOURIS  A committee sponsored by the Brandon Friendship
        Centre received a grant to help establish in Brandon a
 The Museum, originally known as “Squire Hall”, was   legacy for Indigenous culture and missing and murdered
 built in 1910. The building features an etched glass   Indigenous women and girls. The money was put
 entrance, ornate wooden staircase, unique stained glass   toward the Tipi Tour Legacy Project of Brandon, which
 windows, pressed tin ceilings and original woodwork.   was inspired by the Walking With Our Sisters exhibit
 The museum is designated as one of Canada’s most   that visited the city in 2016. The group hopes to have
 important heritage properties.  more than 20 tipis placed around the city by 2021.





                                                                   Borrow from our physical collection,
                                                                        enjoy eResources at home,
                                                                 and attend a variety of virtual programs.
                                                                         All free with membership.







 https://keystonecentre.com/  WILDLIFE MUSEUM  WHEAT CITY WHISKEY JACKS

 204-726-3500  Explore the Irvin Goodon International Wildlife   Make sure to take in the Wheat City Whiskey Jacks
 Museum in Boissevain which features over 4,000   Expedition League baseball action at Andrews Field.
 info@keystonecentre.com  square feet of displayed wildlife.  Check out their website wheatcitywhiskeyjacks.com
        for more details.
                                                                    info@wmrl.ca • 204-727-6648]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[38                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             39














                                                             FOOD TRUCK WARZ                                               HARVEST MOON FESTIVAL


                                                             Since its inaugural year in 2017, this Brandon-based          Through partnership and consultation with the
                                                             event has been growing by leaps and bounds. Over              local residents of Clearwater, Manitoba the Harvest
                                                             the course of three days, competitive food trucks face        Moon Society purchased the town’s elementary
                                                             off, battling to be voted the best food truck by hungry       school and converted the building and grounds into
                                                                                                                           the Harvest Moon Learning Centre. More details at
                                                             guests. Check bdnmb.ca for further information.
   108              THRESHERMEN’S                                                                                          harvestmoonsociety.org.                            115             TOUR FARMERY ESTATE
                    REUNION & STAMPEDE



   Manitoba’s rural history comes alive at Canada’s largest pioneer                                                                                                                           BREWERY
   heritage festival in Austin! Experience over 100 acres of pioneer                                                                                                          Privately owned and based in Neepawa. Check out their
   living demonstrations, vintage farming activities and rodeo                                                                                                                website at farmery.ca for more details.
   action. This year’s event is slated to be held from July 29 to
   August 1.                                                                                                                                                                             HOSPITALITY




                                                             ROCKIN’ THE FIELDS                                            HARVEST SUN FESTIVAL

                                        WATER                                                                                                                                                       Hospitality
                                        PARKS                The three-day rock festival is held on the August long        Riding Mountain National Park is the ideal backdrop
                                                             weekend near Lake Minnedosa.                                  for the Harvest Sun Music Festival, a grass roots Prairie
                                                                                                                           festival dedicated to showcasing Canadian musicians.
                                                                                                                           More details at the harvestsun.com.















                                                             MANITOBA STAMPEDE &
                                                             EXHIBITION IN MORRIS                                          FISHING MANITOBA’S MANY
                                                                                                                           LAKES
                                                             A pro-rodeo event on the Canadian Tour circuit,
                                                                                                                                                                                                        #hamiota
                                                             the Morris, Manitoba Stampede attracts top names              With its many freshwater lakes and rivers, Manitoba         *Camp      *Swim      *Golf      *Relax      *Hike      *Paint      *Explore Nature
                                                             in bull riding, bronco- busting, tie-down roping,             has some of the best sport fishing in North America.   Come make a splash in Hamiota! Just 50 minutes northwest of Brandon; Hamiota is a perfect example of
                                                                                                                                                                                the slogan, “Friendly Manitoba”. Enjoy your choice of leisure activities all year round, whether it is crafting
              2 LOCATIONS IN MANITOBA                        bareback riding, and steer wrestling circles.  This           Check out some popular fishing spots in western     at the arts centre, curling or skating at the Hamiota & District Sports Complex, snowshoeing, sledding, cross
       • MORDEN & MINNEDOSA •                                year’s event is planned for July 22-25. Check out             Manitoba and see if you can “catch the big one.”    country skiing along our groomed trails or taking a refreshing swim in the outdoor heated leisure pool, we
                                                             manitobastampede.ca.
                                                                                                                           tourismwestman.ca/fishing/
              FUN ONLY A SPLASH AWAY                                                                                                                                           are sure you’ll agree- we are worth the visit. Many more summer activities include golfing, camping, hiking
                                                                                                                                                                                our nature trails and many community events! Local businesses provide a wide variety of products and
        www.splishsplashwaterpark.com                                                                                                                                                     services. Enjoy “cool eats and treats” on those hot summer days!
                                                                                                                                                                                                   www.Hamiota.com]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[38  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   39














 FOOD TRUCK WARZ  HARVEST MOON FESTIVAL


 Since its inaugural year in 2017, this Brandon-based   Through partnership and consultation with the
 event has been growing by leaps and bounds. Over   local residents of Clearwater, Manitoba the Harvest
 the course of three days, competitive food trucks face   Moon Society purchased the town’s elementary
 off, battling to be voted the best food truck by hungry   school and converted the building and grounds into
        the Harvest Moon Learning Centre. More details at
 guests. Check bdnmb.ca for further information.
 108  THRESHERMEN’S   harvestmoonsociety.org.              115             TOUR FARMERY ESTATE
 REUNION & STAMPEDE



 Manitoba’s rural history comes alive at Canada’s largest pioneer          BREWERY
 heritage festival in Austin! Experience over 100 acres of pioneer   Privately owned and based in Neepawa. Check out their
 living demonstrations, vintage farming activities and rodeo   website at farmery.ca for more details.
 action. This year’s event is slated to be held from July 29 to
 August 1.                                                            HOSPITALITY




 ROCKIN’ THE FIELDS  HARVEST SUN FESTIVAL

 WATER                                                                           Hospitality
 PARKS  The three-day rock festival is held on the August long   Riding Mountain National Park is the ideal backdrop
 weekend near Lake Minnedosa.  for the Harvest Sun Music Festival, a grass roots Prairie
        festival dedicated to showcasing Canadian musicians.
        More details at the harvestsun.com.















 MANITOBA STAMPEDE &
 EXHIBITION IN MORRIS  FISHING MANITOBA’S MANY
        LAKES
 A pro-rodeo event on the Canadian Tour circuit,
                                                                                     #hamiota
 the Morris, Manitoba Stampede attracts top names   With its many freshwater lakes and rivers, Manitoba   *Camp      *Swim      *Golf      *Relax      *Hike      *Paint      *Explore Nature
 in bull riding, bronco- busting, tie-down roping,   has some of the best sport fishing in North America.   Come make a splash in Hamiota! Just 50 minutes northwest of Brandon; Hamiota is a perfect example of
                                                             the slogan, “Friendly Manitoba”. Enjoy your choice of leisure activities all year round, whether it is crafting
  2 LOCATIONS IN MANITOBA  bareback riding, and steer wrestling circles.  This   Check out some popular fishing spots in western   at the arts centre, curling or skating at the Hamiota & District Sports Complex, snowshoeing, sledding, cross
 • MORDEN & MINNEDOSA •  year’s event is planned for July 22-25. Check out   Manitoba and see if you can “catch the big one.”   country skiing along our groomed trails or taking a refreshing swim in the outdoor heated leisure pool, we
 manitobastampede.ca.
        tourismwestman.ca/fishing/
 FUN ONLY A SPLASH AWAY                                     are sure you’ll agree- we are worth the visit. Many more summer activities include golfing, camping, hiking
                                                             our nature trails and many community events! Local businesses provide a wide variety of products and
 www.splishsplashwaterpark.com                                         services. Enjoy “cool eats and treats” on those hot summer days!
                                                                                www.Hamiota.com]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[40                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                              41














                                                             CAMPING AT SALT LAKE –                                        VIRDEN RODEO AND WILD
                                                             CARLTON BEACH                                                 WEST DAYS


                                                             Located near Strathclair, Manitoba, there are 32 power        Virden is widely known for its Virden Indoor Rodeo
                                                             lots, swimming, and beach area.                               and Wild West Daze.  This event, held in late August,
                                                                                                                           attracts cowboys and visitors from a large area.


                                                                                                                                                                              123            BU BOBCATS


   116          THE WESTERN MANITOBA                                                                                                                                          Bobcats action.  Check out their website at gobobcats.ca.
                                                                                                                                                                                             Make sure to take in Brandon University
                CENTENNIAL AUDITORIUM


   The WMCA is a multi-purpose auditorium located next
   to the Queen Elizabeth II Music Building of Brandon
   University. The auditorium is Brandon’s main concert                                                                    HISTORIC AUD THEATRE
   hall, and plays host too many musical, dance and theatre   WAR MEMORIALS
   performances throughout the year. Check out wmca.ca for                                                                 The historic building which houses The Aud Theatre
   performance schedules.                                    THROUGHOUT WESTMAN
                                                                                                                           in Virden was built in 1911. A local acting group                           A GREAT PLACE
                                                             The Forrest War Memorial is one of more than 200              performs plays within the building along with a host of
                                                             such memorials that grace Manitoba communities.               activities. Check out their website at hevirdenaud.com.                      TO LIVE, WORK
                                                             These are proud reminders of the heroism and the                                                                                                AND PLAY
                                                             sacrifice that describes the character of so many
                                                             Manitoba places.
                                                                                                                                                                                                          Serving the areas of
                                                                                                                                                                                                       Onanole, Sandy Lake and
                                                                                                                                                                                                                 Newdale


                                                                                                                                                                               • Beautiful Lakes

                                                                                                                                                                               • Golf Courses
                                                                                                                           VISIT THE CANADIAN FOSSIL
                                                                                                                           DISCOVERY CENTRE                                    • Hiking Trails

                                                                                                                           Located in Morden, the Canadian Fossil Discovery    • Restaurants
                                                                                                                           Centre provides a great interpretation of life in the
               www.wmca.ca                                   ETERNAL SPRINGS PARK                                          Western Interior Seaway from the late Cretaceous    • Shopping
                                                                                                                           period of earth’s prehistory. The extensive collection of
               204-728-9510                                  Have you visited this lesser-known spot in Manitoba?          marine reptile fossils is the largest in Canada and is very   & much more!
                                                             The “Eternal Springs” area is located 11 kms east of          well represented in our gallery space. More details at
                                                             Virden and features a cute swinging bridge.                   discoverfossils.com.


                                                                                                                                                                                 For information call 204-848-7614  | www.harrisonpark.ca]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[40  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   41














 CAMPING AT SALT LAKE –   VIRDEN RODEO AND WILD
 CARLTON BEACH  WEST DAYS


 Located near Strathclair, Manitoba, there are 32 power   Virden is widely known for its Virden Indoor Rodeo
 lots, swimming, and beach area.  and Wild West Daze.  This event, held in late August,
        attracts cowboys and visitors from a large area.


                                                           123            BU BOBCATS


 116  THE WESTERN MANITOBA                                 Bobcats action.  Check out their website at gobobcats.ca.
                                                                          Make sure to take in Brandon University
 CENTENNIAL AUDITORIUM


 The WMCA is a multi-purpose auditorium located next
 to the Queen Elizabeth II Music Building of Brandon
 University. The auditorium is Brandon’s main concert   HISTORIC AUD THEATRE
 hall, and plays host too many musical, dance and theatre   WAR MEMORIALS
 performances throughout the year. Check out wmca.ca for   The historic building which houses The Aud Theatre
 performance schedules.  THROUGHOUT WESTMAN
        in Virden was built in 1911. A local acting group                           A GREAT PLACE
 The Forrest War Memorial is one of more than 200   performs plays within the building along with a host of
 such memorials that grace Manitoba communities.   activities. Check out their website at hevirdenaud.com.  TO LIVE, WORK
 These are proud reminders of the heroism and the                                         AND PLAY
 sacrifice that describes the character of so many
 Manitoba places.
                                                                                       Serving the areas of
                                                                                    Onanole, Sandy Lake and
                                                                                              Newdale


                                                            • Beautiful Lakes

                                                            • Golf Courses
        VISIT THE CANADIAN FOSSIL
        DISCOVERY CENTRE                                    • Hiking Trails

        Located in Morden, the Canadian Fossil Discovery    • Restaurants
        Centre provides a great interpretation of life in the
 www.wmca.ca  ETERNAL SPRINGS PARK  Western Interior Seaway from the late Cretaceous   • Shopping
        period of earth’s prehistory. The extensive collection of
 204-728-9510  Have you visited this lesser-known spot in Manitoba?   marine reptile fossils is the largest in Canada and is very   & much more!
 The “Eternal Springs” area is located 11 kms east of   well represented in our gallery space. More details at
 Virden and features a cute swinging bridge.  discoverfossils.com.


                                                             For information call 204-848-7614  | www.harrisonpark.ca]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[42                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             43
        124. CHECK OUT THE MUNICIPAL                                                                                                     CHECK OUT THE                                             HIKE TIGER HILLS
        HERITAGE SITES IN BRANDON
                                                                                                                                         MUNICIPAL HERITAGE                                        Located south of  Threherne the 18 km
                                                                                                                                         SITES IN BRANDON                                          hike is considered intermediate.

                                                                                                                                         A complete list of heritage sites
                                                                                                                                         in Brandon can be found at
                                                                                                                                         heritagebrandon.ca.










                                                                                                                                         SHOAL LAKE MOUNTED                                        NORTH CYPRESS-
                                                                                                                                         POLICE MUSEUM                                             LANGFORD

                                                                                                                                         Shoal Lake is the home to one of the longest              RECREATION TRAILS
                                                                                                                                         servicing police detachments in Canada and                The trails in Manitoba are located on
                                                                                                                                         hosts Manitoba’s official museum honoring                 the original lands of the Anishinaabe,
                                                                                                                                         the North-West Mounted Police (NWMP).                     Cree, Oji-Cree, Assiniboine, Dakota
                                                                                                                                         Built-in 1984 in Lakeview Park, the museum                and Dene Peoples, and the homeland
                                                                                                                                         is a replica of the NWMP barracks established             of the Métis Nation.
                                                                                                                                         at the south end of Shoal Lake in 1875. It also
                                                                                                                                         houses tourist information. Find more details via
                                                                                                                                         Facebook at shoallakemountedpolicemuseum.]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[42  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   43
 124. CHECK OUT THE MUNICIPAL   CHECK OUT THE                                   HIKE TIGER HILLS
 HERITAGE SITES IN BRANDON
                     MUNICIPAL HERITAGE                                         Located south of  Threherne the 18 km
                     SITES IN BRANDON                                           hike is considered intermediate.

                     A complete list of heritage sites
                     in Brandon can be found at
                     heritagebrandon.ca.










                     SHOAL LAKE MOUNTED                                         NORTH CYPRESS-
                     POLICE MUSEUM                                              LANGFORD

                     Shoal Lake is the home to one of the longest               RECREATION TRAILS
                     servicing police detachments in Canada and                 The trails in Manitoba are located on
                     hosts Manitoba’s official museum honoring                  the original lands of the Anishinaabe,
                     the North-West Mounted Police (NWMP).                      Cree, Oji-Cree, Assiniboine, Dakota
                     Built-in 1984 in Lakeview Park, the museum                 and Dene Peoples, and the homeland
                     is a replica of the NWMP barracks established              of the Métis Nation.
                     at the south end of Shoal Lake in 1875. It also
                     houses tourist information. Find more details via
                     Facebook at shoallakemountedpolicemuseum.]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[44                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             45














                                                             ATTEND A WESTERN                                              TAKE IN A DRIVE-IN MOVIE
                                                             MANITOBA FAIR                                                 The two operating Drive-in theatres in Manitoba

                                                                                                                           are located in southern Manitoba.  The Stardust in
                                                             From the Boissevain Christmas Festival and the Souris/        Morden and the Shamrock in Killarney drive-inn
                                                             Glenwood Fair to the National Ukrainian Festival in           theatres offer a truly unique movie experience.
                                                             Dauphin and McCreary’s annual Maple Syrup Festival,
   128            OAK HAMMOCK MARSH
                                                             western Manitoba communities know how to celebrate.
                  INTERPRETIVE CENTRE



   Oak Hammock Marsh near Stonewall is one of the North                                                                                                                       135            LAGASSE’S STUDIO OF
   America’s birding hotspots. This 36 km wildlife management                                                                                                                                FINE ART, SOURIS
   area features a restored marsh and 30 kms of trails to explore.
   Check out oakhammockmarsh.ca.
                                                                                                                                                                              The Lagasse’s Studio of Fine Arts supports close over 170 artists
                                                             TAKE IN SOME JUNIOR A                                                                                            throughout Manitoba and also provides workshops both in the
                                                                                                                                                                              studio as well as the surrounding community.
    COME JOIN THE FUN & EXPERIENCE GOLF AT THE               HOCKEY                                                        GET OUT AND PLAY TENNIS                            Check them out on Facebook for more details at facebook.com/
                                                                                                                           If you’re into the swing of things, there are plenty of   kathleenlagassestudio
                                                             The Manitoba Junior Hockey League is one of ten               tennis courts around the region. Check the province’s
                                                             Junior ‘A’ Hockey Leagues in Canada and is a member           handy court finder here:
                                                             of the Canadian Junior Hockey League (CJHL). The
                                                             CJHL is an association of ten Junior ‘A’ leagues in           http://tennismanitoba.com/clubs/court-finder/
                                                             Canada. Westman teams include the Neepawa Natives
       Nestled in the scenic Pembina Valley at the south end of Pelican   (soon to be renamed), the Dauphin Kings, the Swan
     Lake, this 18-hole Championship golf course offers elevations rising   Valley Stampeders, the Waywayseecappo Wolverines,
       up 125ft and large undulating greens.  Tree lined fairways and   and the Virden Oil Capitals.
     meandering creek make your game fun for all skill levels.  An outdoor
             patio offers a scenic view after a round of golf.

      NOTHING QUITE LIKE IT!
     •  Licensed Clubhouse and Restaurant
           •  9 Hole Putting Green
        •  Golf Cart Rentals and Clubs
                                                                                                                           READ A BOOK BY A MANITOBA

                                                                                                                           AUTHOR
                                                             ENJOY THE AMAZING BEACHES IN
                                                             SOUTHERN MANITOBA                                             Manitoba is home to some wonderfully talented and              www.facebook.com/kathleenlagassestudio
                                                                                                                           internationally acclaimed authors and writers. For
                                                             For a full list of some of the best beaches and               a few ideas to add to your reading list, check here:           204-741-1221
                                                             swimming spots in the province, visit                         listchallenges.com/40-greatest-novels-by-manitoba-
                                                             theswimguide.org/beaches/manitoba                             authors.                                                       slagasse@mts.net

       Corporate & Group Bookings Welcome • 204-537-2487
         www.pleasantvalleygolfclub.ca]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[44  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   45














 ATTEND A WESTERN   TAKE IN A DRIVE-IN MOVIE
 MANITOBA FAIR  The two operating Drive-in theatres in Manitoba

        are located in southern Manitoba.  The Stardust in
 From the Boissevain Christmas Festival and the Souris/  Morden and the Shamrock in Killarney drive-inn
 Glenwood Fair to the National Ukrainian Festival in   theatres offer a truly unique movie experience.
 Dauphin and McCreary’s annual Maple Syrup Festival,
 128  OAK HAMMOCK MARSH
 western Manitoba communities know how to celebrate.
 INTERPRETIVE CENTRE



 Oak Hammock Marsh near Stonewall is one of the North      135            LAGASSE’S STUDIO OF
 America’s birding hotspots. This 36 km wildlife management               FINE ART, SOURIS
 area features a restored marsh and 30 kms of trails to explore.
 Check out oakhammockmarsh.ca.
                                                           The Lagasse’s Studio of Fine Arts supports close over 170 artists
 TAKE IN SOME JUNIOR A                                     throughout Manitoba and also provides workshops both in the
                                                           studio as well as the surrounding community.
 COME JOIN THE FUN & EXPERIENCE GOLF AT THE  HOCKEY  GET OUT AND PLAY TENNIS  Check them out on Facebook for more details at facebook.com/
        If you’re into the swing of things, there are plenty of   kathleenlagassestudio
 The Manitoba Junior Hockey League is one of ten   tennis courts around the region. Check the province’s
 Junior ‘A’ Hockey Leagues in Canada and is a member   handy court finder here:
 of the Canadian Junior Hockey League (CJHL). The
 CJHL is an association of ten Junior ‘A’ leagues in   http://tennismanitoba.com/clubs/court-finder/
 Canada. Westman teams include the Neepawa Natives
 Nestled in the scenic Pembina Valley at the south end of Pelican   (soon to be renamed), the Dauphin Kings, the Swan
 Lake, this 18-hole Championship golf course offers elevations rising   Valley Stampeders, the Waywayseecappo Wolverines,
 up 125ft and large undulating greens.  Tree lined fairways and   and the Virden Oil Capitals.
 meandering creek make your game fun for all skill levels.  An outdoor
 patio offers a scenic view after a round of golf.

 NOTHING QUITE LIKE IT!
 •  Licensed Clubhouse and Restaurant
 •  9 Hole Putting Green
 •  Golf Cart Rentals and Clubs
        READ A BOOK BY A MANITOBA

        AUTHOR
 ENJOY THE AMAZING BEACHES IN
 SOUTHERN MANITOBA  Manitoba is home to some wonderfully talented and   www.facebook.com/kathleenlagassestudio
        internationally acclaimed authors and writers. For
 For a full list of some of the best beaches and   a few ideas to add to your reading list, check here:   204-741-1221
 swimming spots in the province, visit   listchallenges.com/40-greatest-novels-by-manitoba-
 theswimguide.org/beaches/manitoba  authors.                           slagasse@mts.net

 Corporate & Group Bookings Welcome • 204-537-2487
 www.pleasantvalleygolfclub.ca]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[46                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             47














                                                             ARDEN CROCUS FESTIVAL                                         OAK LAKE PROVINCIAL PARK


                                                             The World’s Largest Crocus Monument welcomes                  The provincial park is a day-use area that offers two
                                                             visitors year-round at the north end of Arden.                brand new play structures for the kids, a sand beach,
                                                             Thousands of natural crocuses bloom each April on a           walking trail, ball diamonds, basketball court, beach
                                                             vibrant native Prairie grassland site.                        volleyball, and group shelters for picnics.


                                                                                                                                                                              143             THE SETON CENTRE


   136             SPRUCE WOODS                                                                                                                                               buildings, the Seton Centre is a small museum, art gallery, and
                                                                                                                                                                                              Housed in one of Carberry’s many heritage
                   PROVINCIAL PARK
                                                                                                                                                                              gift shop dedicated to the life and works of Ernest Thompson
                                                                                                                                                                              Seton.
   Spruce Woods Provincial Park is located in south-central Manitoba,
   where the Assiniboine River passes through the delta of sediment
   left by the last glaciation. Spirit Sands, an area of open and
   stabilized sand dunes within the park, provide habitat to species of   TAKE PART IN A VACATION                          GRAND VALLEY PROVINCIAL PARK
   plants and animals not found elsewhere in Manitoba. Don’t forget
   to visit the Devil’s Punch Bowl — a 10 km moderately trafficked   FARM OR FARM STAY                                     Grand Valley Provincial Park located in the
   loop trail located in the park near Glenboro-South Cypress. The                                                         Assiniboine River Valley in Manitoba, about 13
   trail                                                     Check out tourismwestman.ca/vacation-farms for                kilometres west of Brandon. It is 26.19 hectares in
   is rated as moderate and offers a number of activity options.    details.                                               size. It was designated as a Provincial Park in 1961.
   It is best to attempt from April until October.                                                                         The park is located in the Stockton eco-district
                                                                                                                           within the Aspen Parkland eco-region.

















                                                             FORT ELLICE – FORMER SITE
                                                             OF THE FUR TRADING POST                                       SHOP WESTMAN –
                                                                                                                           SUPPORT LOCAL BUSINESSES
                                                             A stone monument marks the former site of the
                                                             fur trading post of Fort Ellice of the Hudson’s               There are plenty of great places to shop in Brandon and
               www.gov.mb.ca/sd/parks/park-maps-and-         Bay Company, situated in what is now the Rural                western Manitoba. Check out our locally-owned stores
               locations/western/spruce.html                 Municipality of Ellice-Archie.                                and restaurants, and help support local business.]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[46  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   47














 ARDEN CROCUS FESTIVAL  OAK LAKE PROVINCIAL PARK


 The World’s Largest Crocus Monument welcomes   The provincial park is a day-use area that offers two
 visitors year-round at the north end of Arden.   brand new play structures for the kids, a sand beach,
 Thousands of natural crocuses bloom each April on a   walking trail, ball diamonds, basketball court, beach
 vibrant native Prairie grassland site.  volleyball, and group shelters for picnics.


                                                           143             THE SETON CENTRE


 136  SPRUCE WOODS                                         buildings, the Seton Centre is a small museum, art gallery, and
                                                                           Housed in one of Carberry’s many heritage
 PROVINCIAL PARK
                                                           gift shop dedicated to the life and works of Ernest Thompson
                                                           Seton.
 Spruce Woods Provincial Park is located in south-central Manitoba,
 where the Assiniboine River passes through the delta of sediment
 left by the last glaciation. Spirit Sands, an area of open and
 stabilized sand dunes within the park, provide habitat to species of   TAKE PART IN A VACATION   GRAND VALLEY PROVINCIAL PARK
 plants and animals not found elsewhere in Manitoba. Don’t forget
 to visit the Devil’s Punch Bowl — a 10 km moderately trafficked   FARM OR FARM STAY  Grand Valley Provincial Park located in the
 loop trail located in the park near Glenboro-South Cypress. The   Assiniboine River Valley in Manitoba, about 13
 trail    Check out tourismwestman.ca/vacation-farms for   kilometres west of Brandon. It is 26.19 hectares in
 is rated as moderate and offers a number of activity options.    details.  size. It was designated as a Provincial Park in 1961.
 It is best to attempt from April until October.  The park is located in the Stockton eco-district
        within the Aspen Parkland eco-region.

















 FORT ELLICE – FORMER SITE
 OF THE FUR TRADING POST  SHOP WESTMAN –
        SUPPORT LOCAL BUSINESSES
 A stone monument marks the former site of the
 fur trading post of Fort Ellice of the Hudson’s   There are plenty of great places to shop in Brandon and
 www.gov.mb.ca/sd/parks/park-maps-and-  Bay Company, situated in what is now the Rural   western Manitoba. Check out our locally-owned stores
 locations/western/spruce.html  Municipality of Ellice-Archie.   and restaurants, and help support local business.]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[48                                                                         150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                                             49














                                                             LAKE OF THE PRAIRIES


                                                             Lake of the Prairies is located near the Manitoba/
                                                             Saskatchewan border, north of the community of Russell.
                                                             The man-made lake measuring 67 kilometres long is one
                                                             of the larger lakes in the western half of the province and
                                                             a popular recreation destination for water sports.            FARMERS’ MARKETS & U-PICKS
   144              TAKE IN SOME AMATEUR                                                                                   Take in one of the many farmers’ markets throughout

                    SPORTS
                                                                                                                           Westman, including Brandon. Also, for a list of
                                                                                                                           U-Picks in western Manitoba, check out:
                                                                                                                           pickyourown.org/CNMBwestern.htm
   Manitobans have a great love of organized sports in any season.                                                                                                            150              TRAPPIST MONASTERY
   Whether it be curling, baseball, hockey or rugby, cheer on your                                                                                                                             RUINS, WINNIPEG
   local amateur teams be it College, University or your local teams.
   Search for your favourite sport and participating associations
   here: sportmanitoba.ca/partners/                                                                                                                                           The Trappist Order came to St. Norbert in 1892 and built
                                                             WATCH A WATERSKIING                                                                                              a self-sufficient monastery in 1903-1905, including milking

                                                             PERFORMANCE                                                                                                      barns, stables, a cheese house, apiary, sawmill, and cannery. The
                                                                                                                                                                              beautiful stone shell, set in a park is one of many sites developed
         The Riverbank                                       The Club de Skinautique at Lake Metigoshe, in its 62nd                                                           along the Red River.

                                                             season, is made up of both Canadian and American
                                                             skiers and performs a variety of shows throughout the
                                                             summer for both American and Canadian audiences on
        Considered Brandon’s ‘central park’                  both sides of the lake. Cottagers and other visitors sit on
      providing a serene and beautiful place                 the hill overlooking the lake where the show takes place
                for everyone to enjoy!                       or watch from boats out on the water.

                                                               Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg


     Riverbank Discovery
         Centre is open
         7 days a week                                                                                                     SANDHILLS CASINO, CARBERRY

                                                                                                                           Try your luck on one of your favourites or take one of
                                                                                                                           the newest casinos in Manitoba for a spin, with over
                                                             CANADIAN MUSEUM FOR                                           300 machines to choose from.
                                                             HUMAN RIGHTS

                                                             The Canadian Museum for Human Rights (CMHR) is                                                                               www.gov.mb.ca/sd/parks/park-maps-and-
                                                             a Canadian Crown Corporation and national museum                                                                             locations/central/trappist.html
                                                             located in Winnipeg, adjacent to The Forks. The
     Stay up-to-date on everything Riverbank-related         purpose of the museum is to “explore the subject of
               via our social media channels!                human rights with a special but not exclusive reference
                                                             to Canada. For more detail go to humanrights.ca



                   www.riverbank.mb.ca]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[48  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN  150 THINGS TO DO IN WESTMAN                                                   49














 LAKE OF THE PRAIRIES


 Lake of the Prairies is located near the Manitoba/
 Saskatchewan border, north of the community of Russell.
 The man-made lake measuring 67 kilometres long is one
 of the larger lakes in the western half of the province and
 a popular recreation destination for water sports.  FARMERS’ MARKETS & U-PICKS
 144  TAKE IN SOME AMATEUR   Take in one of the many farmers’ markets throughout

 SPORTS
        Westman, including Brandon. Also, for a list of
        U-Picks in western Manitoba, check out:
        pickyourown.org/CNMBwestern.htm
 Manitobans have a great love of organized sports in any season.   150      TRAPPIST MONASTERY
 Whether it be curling, baseball, hockey or rugby, cheer on your            RUINS, WINNIPEG
 local amateur teams be it College, University or your local teams.
 Search for your favourite sport and participating associations
 here: sportmanitoba.ca/partners/                          The Trappist Order came to St. Norbert in 1892 and built
 WATCH A WATERSKIING                                       a self-sufficient monastery in 1903-1905, including milking

 PERFORMANCE                                               barns, stables, a cheese house, apiary, sawmill, and cannery. The
                                                           beautiful stone shell, set in a park is one of many sites developed
 The Riverbank  The Club de Skinautique at Lake Metigoshe, in its 62nd   along the Red River.

 season, is made up of both Canadian and American
 skiers and performs a variety of shows throughout the
 summer for both American and Canadian audiences on
 Considered Brandon’s ‘central park’   both sides of the lake. Cottagers and other visitors sit on
 providing a serene and beautiful place   the hill overlooking the lake where the show takes place
 for everyone to enjoy!  or watch from boats out on the water.

 Photo provided by Tourism Winnipeg


 Riverbank Discovery
 Centre is open
 7 days a week  SANDHILLS CASINO, CARBERRY

        Try your luck on one of your favourites or take one of
        the newest casinos in Manitoba for a spin, with over
 CANADIAN MUSEUM FOR   300 machines to choose from.
 HUMAN RIGHTS

 The Canadian Museum for Human Rights (CMHR) is                        www.gov.mb.ca/sd/parks/park-maps-and-
 a Canadian Crown Corporation and national museum                      locations/central/trappist.html
 located in Winnipeg, adjacent to The Forks. The
 Stay up-to-date on everything Riverbank-related   purpose of the museum is to “explore the subject of
 via our social media channels!  human rights with a special but not exclusive reference
 to Canada. For more detail go to humanrights.ca



 www.riverbank.mb.ca]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[As you engage in the activities described in this magazine, do not forget to
                                                                                                                         maximize your health, mobility and independence by seeing a physiotherapist
                                                                                                                         near you if needed.

                                                                                                                         Physiotherapists have an advanced understanding of how the body moves, what
                                                                                                                         keeps it from moving well and how to restore mobility. They are skilled in the
                                                                                                                         assessment and management of a broad range of conditions that affect the        Physiotherapists should
                                                                                                                         musculoskeletal, circulatory, respiratory and nervous systems. Physiotherapists   be the ﬁrst choice for
                                                                                                                         treat and help prevent many physical problems caused by illness, disability and
                                                                                                                         disease, sport and work-related injuries, aging and periods of inactivity.        soft tissue injuries,
                                                                                                                                                                                                           as the primary care
                                                                                                                         You do not need a referral to access their services. Physiotherapists provide   provider with advanced
                                                                                                                         services at private clinics throughout Manitoba, as well as through the province’s   assessment skills to
                                                                                                                         regional health authorities.
                                                                                                                                                                                                         ensure timely, effective
                                                                                                                         You can find physiotherapy clinics near your home or workplace. Ask your        management of injuries
                                                                                                                         friends and family where they have had a good experience or visit the MPA        before they become
                                                                                                                         website’s Find a Physiotherapist search feature for assistance in selecting a          chronic.
                                                                                                                         physiotherapy clinic that provides treatment for your situation.




                                                                                                                       Did you know?

                                                                                                                       Physiotherapists can help you get
                                                                                                                       back to work                                                         Physiotherapists         Physiotherapists
                                                                                                                                                                                               can help                 can help
                                                                                                                                                                                               athletes                  seniors
                                                                                                                                                                                            safely return to          stay engaged in
                                                                                                                                                                                              their game             their communities
      SMITTY’S RESTAURANTS                               SPORTSLINE LOUNGE & VLTs
      Shoppers Mall & Hwy locations                      Mall Location Only

      • Weekday Breakfast Specials                       • Daily Happy Hour Specials
      • Signature Breakfast Specialty Menu               • 10 Draft beers on tap with Daily Specials
      • Signature Burger Specialty Menu                  • Monday & Wednesdays are Buck up Nights                                                                                           Physiotherapists
                                                                                                                                                                                               can help
      • 55 Plus Value Menu 4PM to 7PM Daily                5PM to Close                                                                                                                        women
                                                         • Tuesday & Thursdays are Wing Nights                                                                                                with urinary
                                                           5PM to Close                                                              You don’t need a                                      incontinence after
                                                                                                                                                                                              childbirth
      SMITTY’S GARAGE                                    • Friday & Sundays are 40% OFF Appetizers                                referral for physiotherapy
                                                           5PM to Close
      (Ghost Kitchen)

       Separate menu from Smitty’s Restaurants                                                                              YOUR PHYSIOTHERAPIST HAS THE ABILITY TO USE A BROAD RANGE OF TREATMENT TECHNIQUES TO HELP YOU GET BETTER.
           Available through Skip the Dishes,             41 VLTS TO TRY YOUR LUCK ON
           DoorDash, Xdine & Take-Out ONLY
                                                                                                                                                                                                                   in your area, visit
                                                                                                                                                                                          www.mbphysio.org
      #58 1570-18th Street (Shoppers Mall) 204-571-3160 | 1790 Highland Avenue 204-571-3152]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[As you engage in the activities described in this magazine, do not forget to
      maximize your health, mobility and independence by seeing a physiotherapist
      near you if needed.

      Physiotherapists have an advanced understanding of how the body moves, what
      keeps it from moving well and how to restore mobility. They are skilled in the
     assessment and management of a broad range of conditions that affect the         Physiotherapists should
     musculoskeletal, circulatory, respiratory and nervous systems. Physiotherapists   be the ﬁrst choice for
     treat and help prevent many physical problems caused by illness, disability and
     disease, sport and work-related injuries, aging and periods of inactivity.         soft tissue injuries,
                                                                                        as the primary care
     You do not need a referral to access their services. Physiotherapists provide    provider with advanced
     services at private clinics throughout Manitoba, as well as through the province’s   assessment skills to
     regional health authorities.
                                                                                      ensure timely, effective
     You can find physiotherapy clinics near your home or workplace. Ask your         management of injuries
     friends and family where they have had a good experience or visit the MPA         before they become
     website’s Find a Physiotherapist search feature for assistance in selecting a           chronic.
     physiotherapy clinic that provides treatment for your situation.




    Did you know?

    Physiotherapists can help you get
    back to work                                                         Physiotherapists         Physiotherapists
                                                                           can help                  can help
                                                                            athletes                  seniors
                                                                         safely return to         stay engaged in
                                                                           their game             their communities
 SMITTY’S RESTAURANTS   SPORTSLINE LOUNGE & VLTs
 Shoppers Mall & Hwy locations  Mall Location Only

 • Weekday Breakfast Specials  • Daily Happy Hour Specials
 • Signature Breakfast Specialty Menu  • 10 Draft beers on tap with Daily Specials
 • Signature Burger Specialty Menu  • Monday & Wednesdays are Buck up Nights   Physiotherapists
                                                                           can help
 • 55 Plus Value Menu 4PM to 7PM Daily    5PM to Close                      women
 • Tuesday & Thursdays are Wing Nights                                    with urinary
   5PM to Close   You don’t need a                                      incontinence after
                                                                           childbirth
 SMITTY’S GARAGE   • Friday & Sundays are 40% OFF Appetizers   referral for physiotherapy
   5PM to Close
 (Ghost Kitchen)

 Separate menu from Smitty’s Restaurants   YOUR PHYSIOTHERAPIST HAS THE ABILITY TO USE A BROAD RANGE OF TREATMENT TECHNIQUES TO HELP YOU GET BETTER.
 Available through Skip the Dishes,   41 VLTS TO TRY YOUR LUCK ON
 DoorDash, Xdine & Take-Out ONLY
                                                                                                in your area, visit
                                                                      www.mbphysio.org
 #58 1570-18th Street (Shoppers Mall) 204-571-3160 | 1790 Highland Avenue 204-571-3152]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>