<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[MANITOBA










                                               D AY


















                                                                 MAY 12 , 2021
                                                                                           th













                                                 WE ARE GRATEFUL]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[B2     MANITOBA DAY 2021     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                                    THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  MAY 6  2021
                                 n
            n



                                                        Celebrate Manitoba Day



                          Manitoba 150 is more than a moment in time, it’s an opportunity for us to build a legacy for the
                           future. It’s a chance to enrich our connections to each other and the land, long into the future.



                         Even with the COVID-19 pandemic, we still have much to cherish in Manitoba, and we will have

                              even more to celebrate in the years to come. We hope that with each new celebration of
                                    Manitoba Day, this section will shine a light on all that makes Manitoba amazing.




                                            How Manitoba Day came abouT . . .




                         The land that we now call Manitoba has been home to Indigenous peoples for thousands of years.


                           Manitoba is the birthplace of the Métis, a people whose leader, Louis Riel, was responsible for

                          negotiating the terms under which Manitoba joined confederation, as Canada’s fifth province.



                         The Manitoba Act was passed by the Parliament of Canada, and received Royal Assent on May 12,
                          1870. The act was proclaimed on July 15, 1870, when Manitoba joined Canadian Confederation.
                         In 1986  the Government of Manitoba designed May 12 as Manitoba Day and it has grown into an

                                                 annual community event since Manitoba’s centennial in 1970.







                               All programs and dates are subject to change due to provincial health guidelines. Please

                                 continue to follow all health & safety guidelines as set by the Manitoba Government.



















                                                     www.manitoba150.com                      Follow us on social media
                                                                                               #MB150 @manitoba150]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  MAY 6  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                              WETSMAN THIS WEEK     MANITOBA DAY 2021     B3
                                                                                                                                                    n
                                                                                                                                                                          n






                               CELEBRATING








                               MANITOBA DAY








                                                                    MAY 12 , 2021
                                                                                          th























































































                               so many reasons to celebrate manitoba!



                        After more than a year navigating COVID, we may not be able to gather for Manitoba 150

                       celebrations this spring; however, we can still come together in spirit. After all, to celebrate
                           means so much more than simple revelry; it is also an expression of pride, wonder, and

                       appreciation. Manitoba 150 encourages Manitobans to be proud of who we are, to stand in
                      awe of our province’s beauty, to appreciate the cultures that surround us, and to respect our

                                     past and how it has created this unique experience of being Manitoban.


                       Manitobans are creative and resilient, and with that knowledge, we hope you will find your
                        unique way to celebrate Manitoba! Whether you crank up your favourite Manitoba band

                        in your living room, explore your Manitoba roots or challenge your neighbours to a virtual
                      Manitoba Pancake Breakfast cook-off, we hope you discover your next reason to fall in love

                                                                               with Manitoba!


                                   On Manitoba Day, and every day, let’s celebrate this great province of ours!












             150 Things to Do in Westman!





             Commemorating Manitoba’s 150th



             Find your copy in the May 20th

             edition of The Brandon Sun!]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[B4     MANITOBA DAY 2021     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                                    THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  MAY 6  2021
                                 n
            n
                HONOUR 150 WESTMAN RECIPIENTS
































                Eunice Buhler                         John Devins                            Muriel Gamey                           Barb Hanishewski

                Killarney                             Souris                                 Neepawa                                Minnedosa
                Building a sustainable and fully-     Diagnosed with a rare bone             A passion for helping others learn     Barb Hanishewski supports
                funded gallery and space for          infection at a young age, Devins       new activities                         Minnedosans through struggles,
                artists                               shines as Souris volunteer             Donation made to                       victories, and the small moments
                Donation made to Killarney Turtle     Donation made to                       Union Gospel Mission                   in between
                Mountain Arts Council                 Souris Railway Museum                                                         Donation made to Valley Life
                                                                                                                                    Recreation, Minnedosa
































                Chris Heide                           Ron Helwer                             Don Huisman                            Noreen Johnston

                Brandon                               Brandon                                Erickson                               Lake Metigoshe

                No such thing as downtime for this    Giving back to the community           Connecting surrounding                 Each small-town recreational
                volunteer                             Donation made to Samaritan House       communities, to aid one-another        facility has a story: this is the one

                Donation made to The Counselling      Food Bank and Resource Centre          in development, growth and             about the Deloraine-Winchester
                                                                                                                                    Community Complex
                Centre for Hope and Healing                                                  sustainability
                                                                                             Donation made to                       Donation made to Deloraine-
                                                                                             Services to Seniors                    Winchester Community Complex
                                                                                                                                    and Lake Metigoshe Improvement
                                                                                                                                    Assoc.































                Tanya LaBuick                         Keith Loney                            Catherine McLaren                      Judy Morningstar

                Brandon                               Carberry                               Brandon                                Goodlands

                Helping local businesses, people,     The community of Carberry would        Supporting the education               Quilter-extraordinaire, teaching
                and organizations succeed             not be the same without the efforts    of women in need through               quilting and sewing to all ages
                Donation made to Southwestern         of Keith “Gopher” Loney                scholarships, grants, awards, and      Donation made to Goodlands Forget-
                                                                                             loans
                Manitoba Animal Rescue Team           Donation made to                                                              Me Knot Quilters
                                                      Carberry & Area Foundation             Donation made to
                                                                                             CancerCare Manitoba









                                                                                                   LOVE LETTER TO MANITOBA

                             INSPIRATION GUIDE                                                                   SHARE THE LOVE!

                       SAFE IDEAS FOR EVERY CELEBRATION                                   Submit stories, memories, and photos showing what
                       From creating a Manitoba Garden to                                  you love best about Manitoba. Until August 31, 2021,
                          hosting a Manitoba Book Club,                                   each submission is a chance to win weekly prizes or

                         there’s a safe idea for everyone!                               the grand prize of $2,000 airfare courtesy of Calm Air.
                                 Find your inspiration!                                  More details to come on how to submit Love Letters to
                                                                                                 Manitoba on our website brandonsun.com]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  MAY 6  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                              WETSMAN THIS WEEK     MANITOBA DAY 2021     B5
                                                                                                                                                    n
                                                                                                                                                                          n


























                Mary Murray                           Ryan Pandolfi                          Edgar “Sandy”                          Amy Smart

                Neepawa                               Brandon                                Rothnie                                Carberry
                Quilting for those who sacrifice for   Bringing his community together       Strathclair                            Trucking in the cash for Cancer
                their country                         while advocating for mental health                                            Care Manitoba in annual Potato

                Donation made to Neepawa              awareness through entertainment        Time off leads to a life of volunteerism  Truck Pull
                Hospital’s Cancer Care Unit           Donation made to                       Donation made to The Manitoba          Donation made to

                                                      Brandon Housing First                  Association of Agricultural Societies  CancerCare Manitoba










                                                                                               Honour 150


                                                                   In early 2020, Honour 150 presented by Canada Life invited

                                                            Manitobans to recognize people from across the province who make
                                                                         Manitoba an amazing place to live, work, and play.

                                                           Honorees will receive a commemorative medal that has incorporated
                                                              copper salvaged from the Legislative Building. The medal features

                                                                a design created by Manitoba artist Takashi Iwasaki who drew
                                                              inspiration from our prairie sky, rivers, villages, and farming roots.
               Joan Trott                                    In addition, Canada Life will make a $500 donation to the charity of


               Hamiota                                                                       each Honoree’s choice.
               Vision creates an inclusive, welcoming
               arts community in Hamiota                   Red River College students wrote about the 150 recipients who make
               Donation made to                                                     us proud to call ourselves Manitoba.
               Mid-West Arts Council                                              Read their stories at manitoba150.com!]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[B6     MANITOBA DAY 2021     WESTMAN THIS WEEK                                                                                    THE BRANDON SUN   n  THURSDAY  MAY 6  2021
                                 n
            n
                                                                                                    Explore 150
                             MANITOBA 150                                                           150 LANDMARKS TO EXPLORE


                               AT A GLANCE                                                          Discover your next reason to fall in love

                                                                                                    with Manitoba. Download the free Explore

                 Build 150                                                                          150 MB app to find challenges that take you
                                                                                                    around the province to experience Manitoba’s
                 240+ BRICKS-AND-MORTAR PROJECTS                                                    history, people, culture and beauty. Download,

                                                                                                    Discover, and Win! *The Explore 150 app will be available
                 As a legacy initiative, James Richardson                                           for download when provincial health guidelines allow.

                 & Sons, Limited and Affiliated Companies,
                 Endow Manitoba and Manitoba 150 are                                                Unite 150
                 providing $2.5 million for community based                                         MUSIC WITH A MANITOBA HEARTBEAT

                 initiatives across the province.
                                                                                                    Tune in to Bell MTS on August 28th to
                 Celebrate 150                                                                      see an incredible line up of homegrown
                                                                                                    musical acts, including Bachman Cummings,
                 YOUR COMMUNITY, YOUR CELEBRATION:                                                  showcasing Manitoba’s diverse culture!

                 UNIQUELY YOU


                 Providing $1.3 million for 85 unique and
                 exciting celebrations of Manitoba’s 150th
                 anniversary.


                 Our province has once again proven how

                 resilient and creative we are by planning
                 COVID-safe events and programs!


                 Honour 150


                 RECOGNIZING 150 AMAZING MANITOBANS

                 Presented by Canada Life, these once-in-

                 150-years awards recognize Manitoba’s
                 unsung heroes. Representing all regions

                 across the province, these individuals
                 demonstrate why Manitoba’s people
                 deserve to be celebrated.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[THURSDAY  MAY 6  2021   n  THE BRANDON SUN                                                                              WETSMAN THIS WEEK     MANITOBA DAY 2021     B7
                                                                                                                                                                          n
                                                                                                                                                    n
                                                Mural 150






               Seven Manitoba communities will receive outdoor murals in celebration of Manitoba’s history, culture, people and
               beauty through Mural 150, presented by CWB National Leasing and in partnership with Wall-to-Wall Mural & Culture
               Festival’s Rural Mural Tour.

               Synonym Art Consultation, one of the organizers of Wall-to-Wall,
               will connect each of the seven communities with contemporary
               Manitoba-based artists who will work with that community to
               share their unique story. The seven communities that will receive a
               contemporary mural are:

               • Falcon Lake  • Flin Flon  • Gimli  • Norway House First Nation

               • Pilot Mound  • Roseau River First Nation  • The Pas
               Each piece will tell the story of the community in which it resides,
               and will inspire art, storytelling, and pride of place for all who see
               and visit the murals.

               Stay tuned for the mural reveals over the summer - especially the
               one in Westman’s own Pilot Mound!
                                                                                                       Boissevain, BNB Studios and Wall to Wall Mural & Cultural Festival 2019




               Bringing art to you!                                                         This  fully  accessible  exhibition,  with  vehicle support from
                                                                                            Birchwood Automotive Group, will travel across Manitoba this
               Manitoba’s Credit Unions present Tour 150, featuring                         May through September to bring an inspiring collection of Inuit
               Nakatamaakewin: Bringing art to you! in partnership with the                 art directly to your community and schools!
               Winnipeg Art Gallery. This unique mobile exhibition will travel
               across the province to your communities and schools for years
               to come! It all starts this May in celebration of Qaumajuq, the
               new Inuit art centre at the Winnipeg Art Gallery, and Manitoba’s
               150th anniversary of being a province.

               The  Tour  150  van  is  wrapped  in  the  beautiful art  of  Inuit
               multidisciplinary visual artist Kailey Sheppard. Sheppard uses
               their art as a way to connect with and learn about their Inuit
               culture.
               Tour 150: Nakatamaakewin – Bringing art to you! incorporates
               both in-person and online components such as an interactive
               experiential exhibit that features contemporary art and artists
               from the four regions of Inuit Nunangat, educational resources
               on Inuit art  and culture,  and engaging  information about
               Manitoba 150.

               The program is designed to be flexible and adapt to various
               health and safety guidelines determined by the Manitoba                            Tour 150
               Government. Program plan will adjust according to regulations.




                  Relax at home...Enjoy your own back yard!








                                                                                              BOOK NOW FOR 2021


                                                                                                          PLEASE PHONE 204-726-8488

                                                                                           FOR AN APPOINTMENT TO INQUIRE ABOUT OUR

                                                                                               SUNROOMS OR OUR FANTASTIC PRODUCTS

                                                                                                                • FREE ESTIMATES •






























































                            204-726-8488  |  View all our products at www.sunspacesunrooms.com

                                                  |  155 Prairie Crescent Brandon  |  sales@elitesunrooms.ca]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>