<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="24"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Emma Yanchycki plays
                      At Home                                                                   in her grandfather’s
                                                                                                colourful rain garden
                      Gardening                                                                 on Patricia Avenue.


                      Takes Root











                                                                                   2021 Special Supplement




                                                                                                     tempered glass
                                                                                                      featuring
                                                                                                    water wave pattern

                                       ﬁbreglass ribs
                     crank style
                     system
                     for ease of
                     opening  Hanging Patio Umbrella

                     aluminum
                      pole                                                                                  handwoven

                                                                                                            resin wicker
                                                                                          3-Pc. Bistro Set
                                                 3-Pc. Sectional Set  Includes 2–Pc. sectional and table.   Includes table and 2 chairs.
                    Proudly Canadian Since 1971
                                          1858 - 18th Street North   •   Brandon   •   204-726-9225   •   www.thebrick.com          Locally Owned & Operated












                  .]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Ryan Whibbs prepares a salad from a recipe written in 1596 for a web series
                                                                produced by ACC called “Cooking with Culinary” in 2020. Whibbs, chair of
                                                                the Brandon Food Council, said he has also noticed the trend toward gar-
                                                                dening, whether at home or in the city’s various community gardens. (File)
                                                                Home, community



                                                                gardens bloom



                                                                during pandemic






                                                                BY DREW MAY              interest but probably no time
                                                                                         … I think that’s become a
                                                                  With the pandemic keep- new hobby for sure.”
                                                                ing people at home, many    With the rise in the pop-
                                                                Brandonites have turned their  ularity of gardening, Grif-
                                                                attention to their  own back- fin said it’s important to do
                                                                yards to develop their green  your research before putting a
                                                                thumbs.                  plant in the ground, including
                                                                  Karin Griffin, co-owner of  what does and what doesn’t
                                                                Alternative Garden Centre,  grow well on the Prairies.
                                                                said more and more people   “We do find sometimes
                                                                are discovering gardening,  people want plants that don’t
                                                                both indoors and outdoors.  do well in Manitoba. Our
                                                                Vegetables to plant in gardens  zone is really low … because
                                                                are as popular as ever, as are  we get to -50 C. Your peren-
                                                                house plants.            nials, shrubs and stuff have to
                                                                  “I think when people had  be the proper zone,” she said.
                                                                to be at home for so long and   “When it  comes to  an
                                                                just looking at everything, I  investment like that in your
                                                                think they just wanted to be  yard or your home … I think
                                                                just greener,” she said.  going to a local greenhouse to
                                                                  “Even people who weren’t  find out what is best for you is
                                                                interested in it before, or  important.
                                                                maybe they had a little bit of   » Continued on Page 3]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                   3

              » Continued from Page 2

                 As people are learning
              more about looking after
              plants,  they’re  looking  more
              and more for the supplies to
              keep them healthy.
                 Alternative carries its own
              soil mixes, as well as pots,
              plants and anything else for a
              backyard garden. Griffin said
              the greenhouse will also soon
              have raised planters in stock,
              which can be filled with soil
              and used as a garden.
                 Jeff  Fawcett,  co-owner  of
              D&B Sprinklers, said he has
              also noticed a trend toward
              people putting more attention
              into their backyards, includ-  Karin Griffin, co-owner of Alternative Garden Centre, said more and more people are discovering gardening, both
              ing into their gardens. Limit-  indoors and outdoors. Vegetables to plant in gardens are as popular as ever, as are house plants. (Submitted)
              ed travel opportunities mean
              Brandonites want to enjoy  turn a home into a “weather  ter usage.           water responsibly,” he said.
              the spring, summer and fall in  station.” The system monitors   “I think people are spend-  Sprinkler systems can also
              their backyards.          temperature and rainfall and  ing more time in (backyards)  be installed in backyard gar-
                 Wi-Fi-enabled sprinkler  can adjust watering levels ac- and they’re trying to be more  dens as well, which can auto-
              systems are especially popular  cordingly — meaning greener  conscious … they do want to  matically water plants.
              lately, Fawcett said, which can  lawns and more efficient wa- water and they do want to   » Continued on Page 4
                                                                        “YOUR #1 CHOICE FOR PROFESSIONAL
                                                                                LOCAL SECURITY”












                                                                                              Automation systems to
                                                                                              control your lights, locks,
                                                                                              thermostats, and alarm
                                                                                              system from anywhere
                                                                                              in the world



                                                                      High definition camera
                                                                      systems for your home or
                                                                      business

                  Our innovative and professional design team can
                  help you create cabinetry or countertop solutions         Residential and commercial alarm systems
                   for any part of your home. Let us show you how
                       easy it is to create your dream home!
                                                                      204-717-5599
                                                                   www.westmansecurity.ca
                                                                                              Locally Owned & Operated
                                                                       FREE alarm switchovers with 3 months of FREE monitoring]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[4                            THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021


            » Continued from Page 3            I think with people having more time  works best for them. Herbs, such as dill,
                                               at home and also finding food can be  basil, mint or lavender, are often safe bets
               Ryan Whibbs, chair of the Brandon  in short supply or there isn’t the selec- in Manitoba and can open up a whole
            Food Council, said he has also noticed  tion they wanted or they just want to try  new world of food.
            the trend toward gardening, whether at  gardening — these things have all driv-  “Herbs can help us live healthier, they
            home or in the city’s various commu- en attention to this move to garden,” he  can help us add a lot of flair to food with-
            nity  gardens.  In 2020,  there  were only  said.                    out the sodium or the other additives, so
            a handful of vacant plots left across the   Gardening can also be a financial de- there’s a lot of knock on effects of being
            city.                              cision, Whibbs said. For approximately  a bit adventurous and different places it
               Seeds for vegetables like garlic and  $2, you can buy a bunch of parsley at the  will actually leave you by the end of the
            shallots were at times especially hard to  grocery  store,  or  buy  a  plant  and  have  summer.”
            get hold of as Brandonites flocked to try  fresh parsley all summer.
            their hand at growing them.          Whibbs suggest people new to the  » dmay@brandonsun.com
               “There is a lot we can do here, and  hobby try a variety of plants to see what  » Twitter: @DrewMay_










































            Kathy and Jim Jackson just moved to Brandon in March and purchased their new home in the city. These former Brantford, Ont., residents are enjoying
            the slower pace of Prairie life. (Kimberley Kielley/The Brandon Sun)
            Real estate market still going strong





            BY KIMBERLEY KIELLEY      $90,000 over the asking price. payment on their home in  Brantford would have cost
                                        “We thought it should  Brandon.                  them.
               Kathy and Jim Jackson just  go for $600,000 and the   Their experience is a typi-  “We wanted to move years
            bought a house in Brandon  real estate  agent said,  “Ask  cal one in Canada’s hot hous- ago in Brantford, but to sell in
            in March. They moved here  $650,000.”               ing market.              Brantford and buy in Brant-
            from Brantford, Ont.        When it was all said and   The home they purchased  ford, you can’t do it,” Kathy
               The  retired  couple  sold  done, the Jacksons walked  in  Brandon  was a  fraction  said.
            their house in Brantford for  away with a nice little down  of the price a new home in   » Continued on Page 5]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                   5

              » Continued from Page 4   March 16, they were sitting  country in a pandemic, they   Today, the Jacksons are
                                        in their new 1,550-square- hired a moving compa- a stone’s throw from their
                 Their home in Brant- foot house in Brandon.     ny that packed and hauled  daughter, her partner and
              ford was 1,175 square feet,   Their daughter played a  their furniture for them.  grand-doggies.
              a back split with three bed- pivotal role in securing the   “That cost $11,000,” Jim   It’s a move that has made
              rooms  and two  bathrooms.  house in Brandon for her  said.                  the retired crane operator
              The home they purchased  parents, too.                Their car was shipped  and former nurse embrace
              in Brandon has four bed-    She lives in Shilo, where  separately at a cost of  the slower pace of life Bran-
              rooms, three full bathrooms,  she and her partner are in  $1,600. Then, there was the  don offers.
              a  double garage,  a devel- the  military.  She  was  in- hotel stay and flight.  Ultimately, they’re closer
              oped basement and yard.   strumental  in  securing  a   The house they bought  to their only child, and that
                 The offer, which was ac- house for her parents, sight  in Brandon will take about  makes them both pretty
              cepted, was just over half of  unseen.             $30,000 in renovations they  happy.
              what they  sold  their  home   “She videoed the house  estimate, once they pull   The Jacksons’ experience
              for in Brantford.         for us. She walked through  the carpet from two bed- with selling a home in a hot
                 Jim explained the bid- it with the real estate agent  rooms and replace it with  housing market in a short
              ding war he left in Brant- and we bought the house  hardwood  flooring,  change  turnaround time and pur-
              ford, which saw 10 bids  in  sight unseen,” Kathy ex- the cupboards in the kitch- chasing another home just
              four  days.  The  new  owner  plained.             en and upgrade one of the  as quickly is pretty typical
              made his bid unconditional,   There’s a lot of trust  bathrooms.             of what’s occurring in Can-
              which meant there were no  between the Jacksons and   The couple will do the  ada and the Brandon area,
              requests to change the orig- their daughter.       renos themselves as much as  according to Jen Pearson,
              inal bid. In fact, the new   “She’s the kind of kid  they can, but realize there’s  executive officer for Bran-
              owner pushed to move into  who  would  call  us  every  a  lumber shortage in  the  don Area Realtors.
              the Jacksons’ home as soon  night  even  though  she  country brought on by the   The organization covers
              as possible.              didn’t have to.”         pandemic and are willing to  a large area.
                 On Jan. 28, they accepted   Rather than pack them- wait until supplies are more
              the offer on their home. By  selves and drive across the  readily available.        » Continued on Page 6


                 There’s never been a better time to invest in your nest!


                     Time to update your kitchen, renovate a
                  bathroom, develop your basement, add a deck?
                         Whatever you need, we can help.
                          Personal Loans up to $10,000!  *

                        RATE        %     • Payments as low as

                        3.9                 $117 bi-weekly
                                          • Convenient automatic
                        fixed over a 4 year term    payments
                      Don’t delay, contact one of our loans officers today
                         for complete details and to finalize your loan.
                                E-Signatures Now Available!
                                    *Some restrictions apply.








                                                       www.compasscu.ca
                           ROSSER: 204-729-4800  •  THOMAS MALL: 204-729-4820  •  ERICKSON: 204-636-7771]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[6                            THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021



            » Continued from Page 5   have sold since Jan. 1, 2021.   “We’ve had a lot of prop-  Economic spinoffs from
                                      For the same  period  last  erties  selling  on the  first  a booming housing market
               “We have 270 realtor  year, only 72 sold.        day, but there are no exact  can’t be ignored either.
            members in our board,” she   Pearson said the national  numbers.”               Lawyers’ fees, movers,
            said.  “We are about as far  market is showing upwards   “Our entire board is see- house inspections and so
            east as Portage la Prairie, as  of a 48 per cent increase in  ing a busier spring market  on are placed in the melting
            far north as Thompson, as  home sale prices.        than last year,” she said.  pot.
            far south as the U.S. border   “We’re  not  experienc-  Generally, the entire   That helps stimulate the
            and right to the Saskatche- ing anything like that,” she  province  is  experiencing  economy as well, Pearson
            wan border.”              pointed out.              rapid growth in the housing  noted.
               As in the rest of Canada,   Year-to-date, the aver- market.                  At a 2021 Market In-
            real  estate  in  the  Brandon  age price for a single family   Virtual tours of hous- sights event held in Febru-
            area has exploded.        home is up by 12 per cent.  es due to the pandemic do  ary, the Winnipeg Regional
               “Residential sales for  Condo sales are up too.  not appear to have slowed  Real Estate Board (WR-
            Brandon are up 54 per cent   “This year, it’s jumped  things  down either. Real- REB) president Kourosh
            over 2020,” she explained.  significantly.”         tors  are  changing  the  way  Doustshenas pointed out
            Condominium sales are       The average length of  they do business.         how important the real es-
            up by 58 per cent over the  time a house is on the mar-  “They’re   adapting. tate  industry  sector  as a
            same time period.         ket today is 31 days, said   They’re doing virtual tours  whole is in its contribution
               “COVID didn’t really  Pearson. In 2020, the aver- and getting as good a show- to the economy. With every
            affect us until the end of  age length of time a house  ing as you can from across  sale, there is a $53,000 eco-
            March 2020. It was a bit of  was on the market was 52  the country,” Pearson said.  nomic spinoff.
            a slow start.”            days. Pearson said houses   Sellers  are  rejoicing   February Statistics from
               However, by the end of  that have been on the mar-  while buyers are bowing  the Manitoba Real Estate
            March this year, 158 resi- ket for 300 days have just  down to the market.   Association for the residen-
            dential single-family homes  recently sold.           “There’s a low inventory  tial housing market for the
                                                                and high demand.”        province showed new list-
                                                                  At a 1.6 per cent  lend- ings had increased by 0.06
                                                                ing rate, interest rates are  per cent compared to the
                                                                the lowest they’ve ever  same period last year.  The
                                                                been. People who normally  number of properties sold
                                                                wouldn’t be able to afford a  increased by 48.2 per cent,
                                                                down  payment  for  a house  but the biggest increase
                                                                are in the unique position  was felt in the total dollar
                                                                of having extra cash from  volume at $411.6 million, a
                                                                working at home, spending  69.7 per cent increase com-
                                                                less on incidentals and kids’  pared to the same time last
                                                                activities.              year.
                                                                  The list goes on and on.   Pearson thinks even after
                                                                No longer is it as big a deal  the pandemic, people aren’t
                                                                to live in an urban cen- going to return to the urban
                                                                tre.  Workdays involve the  areas they once frequented.
                                                                kitchen table and Zoom      “People are going  to
                                                                meetings.                continue  to  work  from
                                                                  “People are spending  home.  They’re seeing that
                                                                more  time  hanging  out  at  as one of the bigger driving
                     At Guild HMS we have the right             home, realizing what their  factors in larger areas which
                                                                needs are,” Pearson said.  always influences the whole
                   product at the right price to ensure         Based on the hot housing  market.”
                     we have you properly covered.              market, it appears people   Potentially, they will give
                                                                are looking at their options  up the small condo down-
                                                                and moving into bigger or  town to move to the sub-
                                                                smaller homes, away from  urbs and live for less, stay
                                      2830 Victoria Ave & Shoppers Mall  the hustle and bustle of a  home and work.
                                         Brandon • 204-729-4949  large city.                Or, like the Jacksons,
                                         www.guildhmsinsurance.ca  “We really had a ‘steady  they’ll move to Brandon to
                                          WAWANESA • VIRDEN     as she goes’ market for the  be closer to their kids.
                                           CARBERRY • SHILO     last five years until this
                                                                year.”                   » kkielley@brandonsun.com]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                   7

              Pinterest fuels interest in woodwork, renovations



              BY TYLER CLARKE           pandemic killed travel op-  On this front, exotic  a year ago, she said, “We lit-
                                        tions  worldwide,  people woods have been flying off  erally  worked  18-hour  days
                 Surging interest in home   found themselves with more  the shelves.       for months and months just
              renovations and crafts has  time on their hands.      The growing demand has  to keep up.”
              driven up lumber prices,    “People were stuck at  driven up prices to such a   New builds were steady,
              leaving Windsor Plywood in  home and on Pinterest be- degree that Behrens said he’s  she said, with the real uptick
              Brandon scrambling to keep  cause they’re coming in and  surprised to see demand con- taking place in home renova-
              up with demand.           doing projects,” Behrens said  tinue seemingly unabated.  tions.
                 “We’ve  got a  full  yard  of the social media platform   “It’s like being in a war,   “We’re finding people are
              —  we really stocked up,”  that shows people examples  where you’re short of this  looking for serene,” she said,
              manager Peter Behrens said.  of various craft projects.  and short of that and you’re  adding people are striving to
              “We’ve got a pile of stuff be-  People were looking  at  not sure you’ll be able to get  make their homes a “peaceful
              cause I think in the next cou- the same walls every day  it,” he said. “I think it’s just  place” because they’re spend-
              ple months there’s going to  and figuring they should do  weird for everybody.”  ing more time there.
              be all kinds of stuff you won’t  something to improve the   JT  Interiors  Design  Calm colours have been
              be able to get.           surroundings they were stuck   Group owner and design- popular, with people seeming
                 “We’ve got more stuff  in, he added.            er Jolene  Toder expressed  to prioritize blues, and peo-
              than we’ve ever had, here, but   “I’m surprised at how  a similar sentiment, noting  ple want to make their space
              the  thing  is,  it’s  a  big  ques- many young people are tak- things have been busier than  cosy, comfortable and clean
              tion mark … We wouldn’t be  ing up just the craftsman part  ever.            —  “the  three  Cs  everyone
              surprised  with  what’s  going  of it — doing things like spe-  After a week’s pause when  is looking for, no matter the
              to happen next because it has  cial  epoxy  projects,  building  everyone was wondering  style.”
              been so weird.”           furniture — it’s really neat to  what was going on when the
                 When the COVID-19  see that.”                   pandemic first hit more than     » Continued on Page 8



                                         TIME FOR A
                                         CHANGE?




                 Whether you’re renovating or building your
                 dream house, we can help MAKE IT HOME!
                 Custom packages designed to suit your style and your budget
                 3D or Virtual Reality Renderings help you visualize your space
                         in advance – saving you time & money
                           In-Home or Online Consultations

                     Professional Organization Service Also Available.
                             One room or an entire house













                  For more information or to book your consultation,
                                call 204-748-5422
                         Find us on     jtinteriorsdesign]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[8                            THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021


            » Continued from Page 7
                                                    KEEP BUILDING PERMITS IN MIND
               Meanwhile, the added demand has re-
            sulted in a supply chain that is “not only
            cracked, it’s shattered.”                 City of Brandon building permits  siding or exterior finishing doesn’t
               As such, Toder urges people to come   related to residential renovations  require a permit — it’s mainly addi-
            up with a succinct plan — something     increased slightly last year, from 52  tions that require permits.
            designers are integral in drafting — and   in 2019 to 62 in 2020, though this   Fischer also wants people to be
            make sure all the materials are on site be-  only scratches the surface of what  aware of the municipality’s Sewer
            fore work begins.                       has transpired, since not all renova- Backup Subsidy Program, which
               “I drove to Selkirk to get a sink for a   tions require permits.   offers funding for property owners
            client, otherwise they wouldn’t get it until   Those who are uncertain as to  wanting to install a sump pump and
            July,” she said, adding another client had   whether they require a building  pit and/or backwater valve in their
            a home gym constructed only to find the   permit should phone a city inspec- home or business.
            exercise equipment he’d wanted would not   tor, building safety manager Murray   The subsidy is available for up
            be available for months.                Fischer said.                 to 75 per cent of materials and in-
               If not for strong planning, people could   “Usually, our inspectors are a lit- stallation costs to  a maximum of
            be missing integral components for long   tle bit quicker to answer the ques- $2,500 for the sump pump and pit
            periods of time, and/or spend more than   tion than have someone go to our  and a maximum of $1,500 for the
            they’d initially planned as prices continue   website and go through the bylaw,”  backwater valve.
            to fluctuate.                           he said. “There’s a lot of content in   The effort is a result of a Bran-
               “Builders are there to build, draftsmen   the bylaw.”              don City Council budgetary de-
            are there to draw, and designers are there   Adding a bathroom, putting in  cision, for which they earmarked
            to plan,” she said.  “It’s just being smart   a horizontal addition, finishing a  $100,000, in response to last year’s
            with your planning.”                    basement and expanding a window  flood event triggered by heavy rain-
                                                    size all require permits.     fall.
                                                      Replacing existing things such as  » The Brandon Sun
            » tclarke@brandonsun.com
            » Twitter: @TylerClarkeMB








































            Windsor Plywood Brandon manager Peter Behrens is seen with some of the exotic wood available at the store, which has proven popular during the
            pandemic. (Tyler Clarke/The Brandon Sun)]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                   9
              What is grandmillennial style?






                 Grandmillennial style, also  and other decor with ruffles,
              known as granny chic, offers a  pleats,  fringe  and  scalloped
              new take on an old tradition.  edges. Extravagant chande-
              In opposition to minimal- liers and ornate mirrors are
              ist white spaces, this eclectic  also on theme.
              style embraces  patterns,  ruf-  • Traditional  collections.
              fles and heirloom furniture  Unearth that old collection
              but juxtapo ses them with ab- of decorative china, antique
              stract art and mo dern accents. figurines or bohemian crystal
                                        and proudly display it.
              GET THE LOOK                •  Needlepoint  pillows.
                 Raid  your parents’ or  Without  a doubt, no grand-
              grandparents’ basement or  millennial bed room or liv-
              head to local flea markets,  ing room would be complete
              thrift stores and furniture  without at least one of these.
              shops to stock up on the fol- Bonus points if it’s inscribed
              lowing:                   with a sassy saying.
                 • Patterned everything.   Keep in mind that the co-
              Curtains, rugs and furniture  lour scheme of grandmillen-
              in classic prints like toile, flo- nial style is generally mono-
              ral and plaid are a must.  chromatic or analogous. This
                 •  Embellished  items. allows the space to be layered
              Look for accessories, lamps  yet still feel cohesive.

                                                                   SERVING WESTMAN SINCE 1997

                                                                BOOK NOW FOR 2021


                                                                         PLEASE PHONE 204-726-8488
                                                               FOR AN APPOINTMENT TO INQUIRE ABOUT OUR
                                                                  SUNROOMS OR OUR FANTASTIC PRODUCTS
                                                                            • FREE ESTIMATES •























                              204-726-8488  |  View all our products at www.sunspacesunrooms.com
                                                 |  155 Prairie Crescent Brandon  |  sales@elitesunrooms.ca]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10                            THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021

            Start early to get your house retirement-ready




            BY LIZ WESTON                                                                wheelchair) are relatively low-
               Many people want to re-                                                   cost upgrades, for example.
            main in their homes after they                                               Costlier changes include wid-
            retire rather than move to a                                                 ening doorways and hallways,
            senior living facility or com-                                               adding a curbless shower, in-
            munity. Unfortunately, most                                                  stalling non-slip flooring and
            homes aren’t set up to help us                                               creating a zero-step entry.
            age safely and affordably.                                                      Ideally, your home would
               If your goal is to  “age in                                               have just one level, but a home
            place,” some advance prepa-                                                  with stairs can work if it has a
            ration could help make that                                                  bedroom and full bath on the
            possible — or point to better                                                entry level. If that’s your sit-
            alternatives.                                                                uation, you could focus your
               “Somewhere in your 50s,                                                   renovations on making those
            hopefully, you’re starting to                                                spaces accessible rather than
            think seriously about are you                                                trying to remake your whole
            going to be able to stay in                                                  house.
            the house you’re in? Or are  This April 2017 file photo provided by NerdWallet shows Liz Weston, a col-  Sometimes there’s sim-
            you going to need to make  umnist for personal finance website NerdWallet.com. (NerdWallet via AP, File)  ply too much that needs to
            changes?” says DeDe Jones, a                                                 be done or your home has
            certified financial planner in   pliances can help. In sunnier  isn’t ideal for many people, fi- features you can’t affordably
            Denver.                   climates, solar panels can dra- nancial planners say. Few peo- modify. Even if you think you
            CONSIDER WHAT YOU         matically reduce your energy  ple get much if any tax bene- can manage a bunch of stairs
                                                                fit from their mortgages, and  or a home that’s far from your
                                      costs.
            NEED TO CHANGE              Consider upkeep, as well.  having to make the payments  neighbours, your living situ-
               Start by thinking about  You  might  want  to  replace  a  can cause people to deplete  ation could worry your loved
            how you would live in your  labour-intensive grass yard  their retirement savings more  ones, Jones notes.
            home if you had less mobility,  and planting beds with low- rapidly.            “Moving might give you
            less energy and potentially less  er-maintenance landscaping.   Planners say you shouldn’t  the chance to live closer to
            money.                    You could swap out siding  prioritize paying off your  your support  system,”  she
               Unexpected expenses for  that needs to be painted every  mortgage over saving for re- says. “Makes it easier on them,
            major home repairs or up- few years with a more durable  tirement and for emergencies.  makes it easier on you.”
            grades were the most com- option, such as vinyl, fibre ce- And you probably shouldn’t   Certified financial planner
            monly   reported  financial ment or modified wood. De- take money from retirement  Melissa Brennan of Plano,
            shocks experienced by retir- cluttering can make your place  funds to pay off a mortgage.  Texas,  says  she  and  her  hus-
            ees, according to a 2015 study  easier to navigate and to clean. But once you’re on track with  band are at least a decade away
            by the Society of Actuaries.                        your savings goals, you could  from retirement and still have
            Those big-ticket costs can be  BUILD YOUR EQUITY    make extra principal pay- two teenagers at home. But
            devastating on a fixed income.   You may still face big bills  ments to pay down the loan  they recently traded a two-sto-
            The society recommends a  or have trouble making ends  more rapidly.  You also can  rey, four-bedroom, four-bath
            home inspection before re- meet in retirement. In that  avoid having a mortgage in re- home on an oversized lot for
            tirement so you can identify  case, your home’s equity could  tirement by opting for short- a smaller, one-storey house
            and budget for those costs.  be helpful.  You could access  er loans when you refinance.  with tiled floors and a wheel-
            But you also could schedule  your home’s value by selling  If you’re 50, for example,  chair-accessible bathroom.
            some of the expensive stuff —  it, using a reverse mortgage or  you might choose a 15-year    Brennan said they were
            replacing a roof, for instance,  getting a home equity line of  loan  over  one  that  lasts  30  mindful of the problems their
            or upgrading the heat and air  credit.              years.                   parents had navigating their
            conditioning system — while   But you can’t tap equity                       houses as they aged, and the
            you’re still working.     you don’t have. In 2016, 46 per   ASSESS ACCESSIBILITY  bigger house was already
               Likewise, investments in  cent of homeowners age 65 to   Consider  incorporating seeming like more of a burden
            energy efficiency could help  79 still had mortgage debt, ac-  accessibility features into any  than a blessing.
            you avoid big bills when  cording to Harvard Universi- planned renovations. Grab   “We don’t want to spend
            you’re less able to afford them.  ty’s Joint Center for Housing  bars in bathrooms, lever-style  the rest of our lives maintain-
            Adding insulation, install- Studies. The  median  balance  handles on doors and faucets,  ing this ginormous house that
            ing a smart thermostat and  owed was $77,000.       and rocker-style light switches  we don’t need,” Brennan says.
            choosing  energy-efficient ap-  A mortgage in retirement  (preferably accessible from a  » Associated Press]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                  11
              Four steps to patch up drywall






                 If you want to repair dents  ty or spackling compound.
              and shallow holes in drywall,  The product should over-
              here are four simple steps to  flow slightly around the
              ensure you get the best possi- edges. Once it dries, you can
              ble result.               sand down the filler until it’s
                 1. Sand down the edges.  smooth and blends in with
              This  step  ensures  the  wood  the wall. If the hole isn’t com-
              putty or spackling compound  pletely  filled,  you’ll  need  to
              adheres to the wall. Use a  repeat this step until the sur-
              fine-grit  sandpaper  (120  or  face is even.
              150) to lightly sand the area   4. Repaint the entire wall.
              around the hole.          While it might be tempt-
                 2. Clean the surface. Once  ing to only paint the affect-
              you finish sanding, vacuum  ed  area,  the  repair  work  will
              up dust and debris clinging to  likely be noticeable if you
              the wall, then wipe down the  do. For seamless results, take
              area with a damp cloth. Be  the time to repaint the entire
              sure to let the wall dry com- wall.
              pletely before you apply the   To find all  the materials
              filler and paint.         you need to complete this
                 3. Apply enough product.  repair, visit your nearest hard-
              Use a trowel to completely  ware or home improvement
              fill the hole with wood put- store.
                                                  IT'S TIME FOR A CHANGE




                                                                    NEW RETAIL STORE
                                                  Opening in May 2021




                                                                   WELCOMING RETAIL PARTNERS
















                                                   Hours of Inspiration Open Monday to Saturday 10:00am – 6:00pm | Closed Sunday
                                                             1329 Rosser Ave. E., Brandon, MB | Call: 204.727.5884]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Converting alcove tubs



                                                                into walk-in showers:


                                                                the pros and cons




                                                                  Do you want to get rid of
                                                                          HOME backs of converting a tub into
                                                                          IMPROVEMENTS
               Everything You Need to                           your alcove bathtub and re- a shower is the cost.  You’ll
                                                                place it with a walk-in show- spend more or less money de-
                Get Ready for Summer!                           er? If so, here are the advan- pending on the materials you
                                                                tages and drawbacks.     use, the accessories you install
                                                                                         and  the  overall  condition  of
                                                                PROS                     your bathroom.
                                                                  A walk-in shower is an    In addition, if it’s the only
                                                                attractive feature that adds  bathtub in your home, remov-
                                                                a modern focal point to any  ing it may lo wer the resale
                                                                bath room. In addition, stand- value of your house. However,
                                                                alone showers are highly  this might not be an issue if
                                                                functional. Getting  in and  you don’t live in a neighbour-
                                                                out of one is easy when com- hood that typically attracts
                                                                pared to getting in and out of  young families.
                                                                a bathtub. Plus, most walk-in   When weighing the pros
                                                                showers can accommodate  and cons of converting your
                                                                a bench, making it easy to  tub into a shower, you should
                                                                shave, wash and relax. Lastly,  also consider whether you in-
                                                                a walk-in shower, especially  tend to live in your house for
                                                                a large one, can be a major  the next 10 or more years. If
                                                                attraction to buyers when it’s  so, do what suits your lifestyle
                                                                time to sell your home.  and makes you happy. Re-sale
                                                                                         values are important, but so
                       • 3-SEASON SUNROOMS                      CONS                     is enjoying yourself and your
                 • VINYL FENCING & DECK BOARDS                    One of the biggest draw- home.
                        • ALUMINUM RAILING

                      • ARMADILLO COMPOSITE
                • TIMBER FRAMING/ROUGH LUMBER


















              1840 – 18   TH  STREET NORTH, BRANDON
              204-728-4243
              Fax: 204-727-2619
              Toll-Free: 1-800-224-7506
              www.windsorplywood.com
              Store Hours: Mon. – Fri. 8:00 am – 6:00 pm;
              Sat. 9:00 am – 5:00 pm; Closed Sunday]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[This undated photo shows tomato being planted in a garden in New Paltz,
              N.Y. One week after the “average date of the last killing frost” for your
              garden is the time when it’s generally safe to plant out tomato transplants.
              (Lee Reich via AP)
              Time to try growing some

              vegetable or flower transplants



              BY LEE REICH                Better to hone your trans-
                                        plant-raising  skills  with  a
                 If you’ve never grown your  plant  that  really  does  need
              own transplants for your gar- to  be grown this way,  such
              den, perhaps this is the year  as tomatoes. In much of the
              to do it. It’s economical, it al- country, we need to start to-
              lows you to grow varieties you  matoes indoors so the plants
              might  not  be  able  to  buy  as  have enough time to ripen a
              transplants, it’s satisfying and  decent yield out in the garden.
              it’s easy.
                 If you’re new to the trans- GERMINATION
              plant game, start with a flow-  To get started with trans-
              er or vegetable that’s relatively   plants, you’ll need a suitable
              easy to raise from seed. Zin-  container and soil. The con-
              nia, calendula and cosmos are   tainer need not — should not
              some of the easiest. Among   — be too big, but does need
              vegetables,  choose  from  to be two to four inches deep.
              among lettuce, kale, cabbage   Plastic yogurt containers
              and  — that  most  widely   are good, even egg cartons (for
              grown vegetable of all — to-  “jumbo” eggs), and, of course,
              mato.                     those cell packs in which your
                 There are some vegetables   purchased transplants once
              that shouldn’t be grown as   lived. Perhaps you still have
              transplants. Beans, peas and   some lying around.
              okra fall into that category   Most important is that any
              because the yield is small from   container have one or  more
              each  plant. Outdoors,  in  the   holes in the bottom, so excess
              garden, you sow these plants   water can drain out.
              in a furrow with seeds only a   Garden soil, even good gar-
              few inches apart. That would   den soil, is not suitable because
              take a lot of transplants! For   it doesn’t drain quickly enough
              some other vegetables, such as   in the confines of a container.
              carrots and parsnips, the roots   Drainage of a  “potting mix”
              don’t take kindly to being
              transplanted.                   » Continued on Page 14]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[14                            THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021

            How to use architectural


            lighting to revamp your home


               Architectural  lighting TO SET THE MOOD WITH
            enhances the structure of a   WALL WASH LIGHTING
            space to create a cohesive   Wall washing  is  a  tech-
            experience. It’s something   nique that directs light at
            to be considered during ev-  a wall to draw attention to
            ery building and renovation   the smooth, vertical surface.
            project,  and  the  earlier  the   The fixtures can be recessed
            better.  This is because this   in the ceiling or mounted to
            type of lighting is integrat-  it. If you prefer to create an
            ed directly into the space,   uplighting effect, install the
            blending in with the features   lights on the floor.
            of your home. Here are some
            ways  architectural  lighting  is
            used.                     TO LIGHT YOUR WAY
                                        Illuminate stairways by
            TO EMPHASIZE CEILINGS     adding  pot  lights  on both
               If you have architectural  sides of the bottom step, ei- focuses light where it’s most  inets, to lighting up built-in
            ceilings, rather than installing  ther  on  the  lowest  riser  or  needed.  shelving and other custom
            pot lights, consider adopting  the wall. Alternatively, add   There are many other pos- features. For the best possible
            lighting that blends into the  lighting within each riser.  sibilities  when  it  comes  to  results, make sure to  speak
            mill work and moulding. This  Uplighting can create height  architectural lighting, from  with an architect before you
            could work well on a beamed,  and drama, and when used to  il luminating the underside  start your renovation or build-
            coffered, coved or tray ceiling. illuminate staircases, it also  of kitchen counters and cab- ing project.

            » Continued from Page 13           are warm on top; that could be a suitable   Another option for light is a grow-
                                               place. Same for near a radiator. A ther- light, either fluorescent or LED. Al-
            (“potting soil”) is enhanced by the inclu- mostatically  controlled seed mat offers  though these lights look bright, they
            sion of some coarse material such as per- more control.              don’t compare with good old sunshine.
            lite, vermiculite or sand. If you have little   To keep moisture from evaporating  Light intensity falls off rapidly with dis-
            experience raising transplants, buy a pot- from your container, cover it with a pane  tance from a light, so keep the light just a
            ting mix. It will already have the drainage  of clear glass or plastic, or enclose the  few inches above the plants. Or combine
            material mixed in.                 container in a plastic bag.       a sunny window and a grow-light.
               Fill the containers with the potting                                Be careful not to overwater or under-
            mix and firm it down. Not too much,  THE EXCITEMENT BEGINS           water. I lift a container and its weight tells
            though. Then sow seeds, three or four per   Now for the exciting part, waiting to  me if water is needed. The ideal for stocky
            container or cell, as insurance. Do this by  see little, green sprouts. Remove all but  growth is keeping plants just slightly un-
            poking a hole a few times the thickness of  the sturdiest sprout from each container  derwatered.
            a seed into the mix, and drop in the seed.  or cell, being careful not to disturb the   In four to six weeks, most transplants
            Smooth over the potting mix to cover the  roots of the sprout that remains.  should be two to three times the height
            seeds, and firm it again.            Your goal now is to grow sturdy, stocky  of their containers, stocky and ready for
               Water the container by standing it in  transplants that can tolerate a move to the  the outdoors. Or almost ready. Acclimate
            a pan with water reaching about half as  great outdoors. For this, you need abun- them to their future environment with
            high as the height of the container. After  dant light and cooler temperatures. Even  a week of being outdoors somewhere
            a few hours, lift the container up out of  tomatoes, a summer vegetable, grow best  shielded from the full brunt of sun, wind
            the water.                         as transplants with temperatures between  and cold. Then plant them in the garden.
               Seeds need warmth to germinate, the  60 F and 70 F. Don’t worry if you can’t   Perhaps you’ll be inspired next year to
            amount varying with the kind of seed. A  achieve ideal growing conditions; what’s  grow more of your own transplants.
            good average for just about all seeds is  possible in a commercial greenhouse of-  Lee Reich writes regularly about garden-
            about 75 F. Beyond their optimum ger- ten isn’t feasible in a home.  ing for The Associated Press. He has authored
            mination temperatures, seeds will still   A sunny, south-facing window works  a number of books, including “Weedless Gar-
            germinate, but more slowly.        well, especially if it’s in a cool room. Ro- dening” and “The Pruning Book.” He blogs
               Most seeds don’t need light to germi- tate the plants daily so they grow uni- at leereich.com/blog. He can be reached at
            nate.  So  a suitable  place  is almost any- formly, rather than one side always bend- garden@leereich.com.
            where in your home. Some refrigerators  ing toward the light.        » Associated Press]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                  15
              Four essentials of opening your cottage




                 Once the weather gets                                                     a faucet followed by the main
              warmer, you’ll likely  be ea-                                                water shut-off valve. Let the
              ger to take advantage of your                                                water run for about five min-
              summer cottage. However,                                                     utes. Wait until the hot water
              it’s a good idea to inspect the                                              tank is full before you connect
              property  and  complete  any                                                 and inspect the heater.
              necessary  upkeep  before  the
              start of the season. Here are                                                CHECK THE
              four things you should do.                                                   SEPTIC SYSTEM
                                                                                              Make sure there aren’t leaks
              IDENTIFY AND                                                                 in the pipes connected to your
              FIX PROBLEMS                                                                 septic system and that they’re
                 During your first visit of   hire a professional.  through wires over the win-  other wise in good condition.
              the season, be on the lookout                      ter. If you detect any issues, be   Additionally, it’s important
              for unpleasant surprises. If   INSPECT THE         sure to contact an electrician.  to empty and clean your sep-
              there’s water damage, an in-  POWER SUPPLY                                   tic tank every few years. This
              festation or a broken window,   Whether your cottage runs   TURN THE         type  of  maintenance  requires
              take note of the work that  on propane or electricity, you’ll   WATER BACK ON  specialized  equipment,  so  it’s
              needs to be done. Avoid put- need to make sure the sys-  If your cottage is equipped  best to hire a plumber to com-
              ting off repairs so your cottage  tem’s various components are  with a pump that draws water  plete the job.
              will be ready to use as soon  in good condition before you  directly from a lake, follow the   By taking care of your cot-
              as possible. For major issues  restore the power. For exam- manufacturer’s  instructions. tage now, you’ll be able to kick
              such as cracks in the founda- ple, there might be a gas leak,   If you have a regular plumb- back and enjoy the rest of the

              tion or a leaky roof, it’s best to  or mice could have chewed  ing system, start by opening  season without worry.






                                                                                       FARM,
                                                                                       FARM,
                                                                              RESIDENTIAL &
                                                                              RESIDENTIAL &
                                                                               COMMERCIAL
                                                                               COMMERCIAL
                                                                                  PROPERTY
                                                                                  PROPERTY
                                                                                APPRAISERS
                                                                                APPRAISERS
                                                                           Serving Western Manitoba Since 1977
                                                                           Serving Western Manitoba Since 1977


                                                                                 ROLAND WEIR






                                                                                   204-727-7100
                                                                                   204-727-7100
                                                                               Suite 30A, 1015   th
                                                                               Suite 30A, 1015 – 26  Street, Brandon
                                                                            Fax: 204-727-1563  Email: weir1@mymts.net
                                                                            Fax: 204-727-1563  Email: weir1@mymts.net]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[16                            THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021

            How to style your curtains




               Are you considering up- best reserved for drapes that
            dating your curtains? If so,  stay open since they need to
            here’s  what’s  fashionable be restyled every time they’re
            when it comes to this window  opened or closed. Curtains
            treatment.                that skim the floor shouldn’t
                                      hang more than 1.5 cen-
            HANG HIGH                 timetres above it.
               Installing curtain rods
            closer to the ceiling will make   GET WIDE
            the room feel larger. The ex-  Add visual width to your
            tra height visually increases  windows by opting to go
            the vertical space occupied by  broad with your curtains.
            the windows and creates the  Mount rods that extend 7.5 to
            illusion of a higher ceiling. If  15 centimetres past the win-
            possible, hang your curtains  dow frame on either side. Al-
            10 to 15 centimetres above  though you can go even wid-
            the windows to maximize  er, the curtain rod shouldn’t
            their impact.             be more  than one-and-one-
                                      third the width of the win-
            GO LOW                    dow.                      you have enough fabric to  to two-and-a-half times the
               Contemporary curtains are                        adequately cover the intend- width of the window.
            long and should hit the floor   GO FULL             ed area.  The rule of thumb   To find curtains you love
            or even puddle onto it. How-  Curtains look best when  is  that  the  combined  width  or the fabric to make them,
            ever, pudd ling curtains are  they’re full, so make sure  of the panels should be two  shop at stores in your area.






                                SAVE UP TO 50% WATER WITH PREDICTIVE WATERING™



                    SAVE                          MANAGE                                 SERVICE
                   HYDRAWISE                    SITES FROM ANYWHERE                     SYSTEM PROBLEMS
               PREDICTIVE WATERING               AROUND THE WORLD                       WHEN THEY OCCUR










                  CELEBRATING 40 YEARS SERVING WESTMAN



              A healthy, beautiful garden needs just the right amount of water to thrive.
                 Hydrawise automatically adjusts watering based on highly accurate,
              internet-sourced local weather data. The system looks at the forecast and
               past history to ensure that just the right amount of irrigation is applied.


                     204-728-0650  |  1515 Percy Street, Brandon  |  www dandbsprinklers.com]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                  17
              Foundation cracks: when to worry





                 The best way to ensure                                                    aren’t conti nuing to expand.
              a  crack  in your foundation                                                 Thin cracks can be filled with
              doesn’t threaten the structur-                                               grout, and slightly wider ones
              al integrity of your home is                                                 should be filled with a caulk
              to consult an expert. How-                                                   that’s compatible with con-
              ever, some general guidelines                                                crete.
              can help you determine if you
              have a serious problem.                                                      WIDE CRACKS
                                                                                              Any crack that’s wider
              HAIRLINE CRACKS                                                              than  half  an  inch  should  be
                 Concrete shrinks slightly                                                 inspected by a professional. In
              as it cures, and hairline cracks                                             particular, those with a bulge
              (about the width of sewing                                                   may indicate structural prob-
              thread) are a normal result                                                  lems. Additionally, a crack in
              of it settling.  They pose no                                                your foundation that’s hori-
              structural threat and tend                                                   zontal rather than vertical or
              to appear within a year of                                                   diagonal presents more of a
              construction. How ever, you                                                  risk.
              should  take steps  to  patch                                                   If  you  have wide  cracks,
              them.                                                                        horizontal cracks or cracks
                                        that can’t be classified as hair- ly to be a serious problem.  that are getting worse, be sure
              NARROW CRACKS             line but are no wider than a  However, this is only the case  to call a foundation contractor
                 Vertical or diagonal cracks  quarter of an inch are unlike- if the cracks are stable and  or structural engineer.]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[18                            THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021

            Five hardwood floor finishes: What they’re best for




               Do you need to refinish your hardwood floors? If so, here’s a
            brief guide to five common types that are available.
               1. Water-based polyurethane is ideal for floors in need of a
            quick-drying, clear finish. This is a product that’s low in vola-
            tile organic compounds and ages without yellowing. However,
            it does little to hide scratches.
               2. Oil-based polyurethane is best for floors in high-traffic
            areas. It’s highly durable and easy to maintain. On the down-
            side, it’s slow to dry, high in VOCs and yellows over time.
               3. Moisture cure urethane is well suited to floors that re-
            quire a very tough finish. It resists moisture, scratches, stains
            and general wear. However, it has high levels of VOCs and
            applying it requires you to vacate your home.
               4. Wax is great anywhere you want a low-sheen finish. Un-
            fortunately, it’s not very durable and tends to darken over time.
            It can scuff and scratch easily and doesn’t mix well with water.
               5. Penetrating oil sealer is ideal for subtly highlighting the

            natural grain of wood, es pecially in a historic home. This prod-
            uct needs to be reapplied every few years and re quires a wax
            topcoat.
               You’ll find these products at your local hardware store.
            For top-notch results, consider hiring a professional to s
            trip and sand your wood floors and then expertly apply the
            finish.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                  19
              Should you invest in a sump pump?





                 A sump pump is a device that can be installed in a base-
              ment, either beneath or above the floor. It’s designed to pump
              out water collected in a sump basin and discharge it to the out-
              doors. Consequently, your home is kept safe from the damage
              that can occur as a result of flooding.
                 If your basement is at risk of flooding, you should con-
              sider  buying  a  sump  pump,  especially  if  you  live  some-
              where with a high water table. If possible, select a submers-
              ible rather than a pedestal pump, as they’re less noisy when
              covered with a lid. You should also opt for a model with an
              iron core since it’s more durable than the plastic alternative.
              Plus, you should think about getting a pump with an alarm
              that alerts you if the water in the basin reaches a dangerous
              level.
                 In addition, you may want to install a secondary sump
              pump next to the first one, especially if you have a finished
              basement. This way, if your primary pump fails or becomes
              overtaxed, the secondary pump will automatically take over.
                 A battery backup pump can also be installed. In the event
              of a power outage, this type of pump will continue to work for
              up to two days.
                 To install a sump pump in your home, speak with a quali-
              fied plumber in your area.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[20                            THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021














































            Yakisugi is considered an environmentally friendly material because the treatment and maintenance of the wood doesn’t require the use of chemicals or
            other harmful products.
            Yakisugi: the charred-wood trend





               Shou sugi ban is a tradi-  In addition to its unique
            tional Japanese technique of  appearance, yakisugi is re-
            burning wood planks — usu- nowned for its durability. The
            ally cedar or larch — to pre- process of scorching planks
            serve the wood and protect  in a controlled environment
            it against UV rays, moisture,  eliminates  moisture  and
            insects and other sources of  hardens the wood. In fact, it’s
            damage.  The result of this  estimated that this material,
            weatherproofing process is a  when correctly made, has a
            striking, charcoal-black wood  usable lifespan of at least 80
            plank known as yakisugi.  years.  What’s more, burnt
               While yakisugi was tradi- wood is resistant to fire.
            tionally used as a material for   In terms of care, these
            siding, this blackened wood is  treated wood planks have the
            becoming increasingly popu- benefit of requiring virtual-
            lar for other applications. The  ly no maintenance. Howev-
            product can now be found in- er, applying a natural oil to
            doors on walls and floors and  the surface every 15 years or
            outdoors to construct fences  so  can help  protect  yakisugi
            and decks.                from the elements.]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[COMING                                                Brandon’s
                    SOON






                                                                            1  Pocket
                                                                                st





                                                      Neighbourhood









                                                                           New Concept for Brandon

                                                                        • New custom built 1 or 2 bedroom homes
                                                                          from 500sf – 900sf are being developed
                                                                        • Energy efficient: oriented to the sun, well
                                                                          insulated, warm in the winter and cool in
                                                                          the summer, fresh air with HRV, triple pane
                                                                          windows
                                                                        • Luxury vinyl plank flooring, drywall finish
                                                                        • Soft close drawers and custom cabinets
                              *Not exactly as illustrated.
                                                                        • Quality Kohler fixtures and Delta faucets
                   Pocket Neighbourhoods are designed                   • Digital programmable heat / air
                    with common spaces where you can                      conditioning / ventilation
                   get to know your neighbours, but have                • Front porch, storage shed, parking
                      your own space and privacy too.
                                                                        • Affordable to buy starting at $125,000
                        Small homes are modern, low                     • Affordable to operate: low energy use, low
                   maintenance – leaving you with lots of                 maintenance finishes
                      time to relax and put your feet up!               • Quality built by
                                                                          Conquest Manufacturing
                       Live small without compromise at
                   235 Glen Avenue on Brandon’s North Hill







                                                                           260 Glen Avenue, Brandon
                                                                          204-726-3398 (Office)
                                                                            204-724-7907 (Cell)]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[22                            THE BRANDON SUN • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021

            Shaking off a dark winter with a spring cleaning, refresh



               A spring cleanup and décor refresh
            have always been able to lift moods. But
            after this long pandemic winter, there’s
            special satisfaction in clutter removal,
            extra joy in being creative, particular
            pleasure in making a space even more
            your own.
               “This time of year, I can often feel
            buried after so much time indoors, and
            with many of us working from home,
            this is even more crucial,” says designer
            Mel Bean in Tulsa, Okla.
               Or  as  New  York-based  designer
            Thom Filicia puts it: “Be brave. The new
            year is a chance to create spaces that al-
            low you to live your most beautiful life.”
               Some  suggestions  from  the  experts
            on bringing a sense of harmony and
            happiness home this spring:
                                               This image provided by Tom Stringer Design Partners shows a kitchen and dining room. Colour is a
            A GOOD CLEAR-OUT                   simple way to create an upbeat feel, says John Cialone of Tom Stringer Design Partners in Chicago.
               “‘Bright and light’ is my motto, and  The firm recently completed a Palm Springs, Calif., project where they brought in a vibrant kiwi
            when the days get warmer, I can’t wait  green. (Jorge Gera/Tom Stringer Design Partners via AP)
            to purge and donate some things,” says
            New York designer Michael Wood. He   Thomas of  Thomas Guy Interiors in  pieces you touch most every day. “Your
            gives to Housing  Works, a New  York   Lake Charles, La.             home should not only be a place where
            City non-profit fighting AIDS and    “Heirlooms are a great way to acces- you feel inspired and energized, but also
            homelessness.                      sorize and bring happiness into a home.  where you can kick back and relax. Cre-
               Wood takes the change of season as   Those ancient trinkets and doodads  ate an environment that allows you to re-
            an opportunity to get a professional firm   found while spring cleaning could make  charge,” he says.
            in to deep clean.                  for a wonderful coffee table conversa-  “Bedding, pillows and throws create
               “Every piece of furniture is lifted   tion piece,” he says. “There’s something  those welcoming environments.”
            and cleaned by the crew — all light-  special about preserving memories and   Paint or paper a wall, replace a rug, or
            ing fixtures, fans, walls, blinds/drapery   respecting history that feeds the soul.”  reupholster a chair, he suggests.
            and ceilings are wiped,” he says. “They                                Colour is a simple way to create an
            clean the outside, inside and behind all   LITTLE IMPROVEMENTS       upbeat feel, says John Cialone of  Tom
            appliances,  inside  closets, shelving  and   Not up for anything big? After you’ve   Stringer Design Partners in Chicago. The
            cabinetry, all windows inside and out.  done a declutter, reward yourself by   firm recently completed a Palm Springs,
            Everything feels new again!”       bringing home some green.         Calif., project where they brought in a
               Hiring pros might not be doable for   “Plants are known to boost mood and   vibrant kiwi green. Cialone also likes cor-
            all of us, however. Thankfully, cleaning  productivity,”  says  designer  Jay  Jeffers.   al on walls or furniture for “giving you a
            can be free therapy.               “Add a floor plant in ample natural light   healthy glow.”
               Organizing  expert  Marie  Kondo  to elevate your space, and put smaller   BIGGER FIXES
            says that visualizing what a happy home  plants where you spend most of your
            would look like to you is a good first  time, like your kitchen or your desk.”  Changing finishes or buying larger
            move on the de-cluttering, cleaning   There  are  lots  of  easy-care  options,   furniture costs more, but packs a punch.
            journey.                           like succulents (including aloe and jade   Jeffers suggests drawing inspiration
               “Think about what kind of house you  plants) and pothos. Or try cut flowers.  from your favourite destinations. “Think
            want to live in, and how you want to live   “Investing in a pretty vase and making   about the places where you feel happiest.
            in it,” she says. “When you imagine your  a commitment to fresh flowers is a great   Whether it’s a beach with tranquil blue
            ideal lifestyle, you are really clarifying  way to bring happy into your space,” says   water and warm white sand, or a cosy
            why you want to tidy and envisioning  Houston designer Mary Patton.  “Even   cabin surrounded by evergreen trees, in-
            your best life. The tidying process rep- if you’re Instacarting, you can have in-  corporating  design  elements  from  your
            resents a turning point.”          expensive flowers delivered. Flower ar-  most-loved destinations will mentally
               Decluttering might spark some new  ranging is an easy, creative activity.”  bring you back,” he says.
            ideas for old belongings, says Lance   Filicia advises paying attention to the     » Continued on Page 23]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[THURSDAY, APRIL 29, 2021 • YOUR HOME YOUR WAY • THE BRANDON SUN                                  23

              » Continued from Page 22  into the smallish, back-of-the-
                                        house space and improved the
                 At-home gyms have been  vibe in many ways, Lisa said.
              one of his most requested ad-  “The light, definitely, but
              ditions this year. Whether you  we’re surprised how much big-
              set up a few pieces of equip- ger it looks,” she says. “Hard to
              ment or just some mats and  say if that’s why I find it more
              pillows, that private oasis can  pleasant, or if it’s because it
              pay off in both your fitness  looks so much more current.”
              level and your mindset, Jeffers   Philadelphia-based interi-
              says.                     ors firm Marguerite Rodgers
                 Changing the finish or co- added a playful, cheery red
              lour of kitchen cabinets can be  pocket door to a recent kids’
              a big job, but the payoff, Cia- room project on the Jersey
              lone says, is also big.   Shore.
                 As the pandemic waged    “The pop of colour really
              on, Lisa and Peter Kinsman  ties  the  space  together,”  says
              of Westchester County, N.Y.,  designer Kaitlyn Murphy.
              got  fed  up  with  their  kitch- “You can easily refresh existing
              en’s dark cherry cabinetry and  millwork by adding a wall-
              black countertops. Inspired by  covering, textile or a fun paint
              a photo Lisa saw of a kitchen  colour.”             This image provided by Marguerite Rodgers Interior Design shows a child’s
              designed by Studio McGee,   Kim Cook is a freelance writ-  room. Philadelphia-based interiors firm Marguerite Rodgers added a
              the couple chose a creamy gray  er covering design, décor and   playful, cheery red pocket door to a recent kids’ room project on the Jersey
              paint  to  cover  the  cabinets,  lifestyles topics. Follow her on   Shore. “The pop of colour really ties the space together,” says designer
              and changed out the counters  Instagram @kimcookhome.  Kaitlyn Murphy. “You can easily refresh existing millwork by adding a wall-
              for crisp white Silestone. The                      covering, textile or a fun paint colour. (Halkin | Mason Photography/Marguerite
              updates brought more light  » Associated Press      Rodgers Interior Design via AP)


                                                            CHECK OUT OUR NEW LOCATION
                                                                       320 6th Street North































                              320 6th Street N, Brandon  |  204-729-8252  |  Toll-free 1-877-729-8252
                                                 universaldoors.ca]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Commercial & Residential Services

                                                                   • Complete Design/Build & Consultation Services
                                                                   • Full service landscape installation
                                                                   • Complete Softscape and Hardscape, outdoor living spaces



                   Retail Store with                                                • Lechuza Planters (self watering)
                 Professional Advice                                                • Annuals & Perennials
                                                                                    • Shrubs & Trees
               APRIL 12-JUNE 26  SPRING/SUMMER                                      • Water Features & Pond Materials
               Monday - Friday 9am-6pm *
               Saturday 9am-5pm                       CHECK OUT OUR                 • Gardening & Landscaping supplies
               Sunday 11am-5pm                                                      • Soils & Fertilizers
               *subject to change                  NEWLY RENOVATED  &               • Giftware and so much more
                                                EXPANDED GREENHOUSES!
               NEW FOR 2021
               Our Brick & Bulk yard will be open
               Sundays from May 2- June 20th *                                    Concrete Dealer


















                                                                                  • All-year-round services for your landscapes
                We offer proposal per job or hourly rates                            • Spring clean   • Monthly mowing
                    for operator and equipment.                                          • Fiesta Weed Control










                  Let our team make your dreams a reality!                                     Richmond Ave.

                     Southeast corner of 34  Street and Patricia Ave.                                 34 th  St.  Shoppers   Mall  18 th  St.
                                                th
                           Sales 204-727-7289    |    Toll Free 1-866-727-7289
                       Fax 204-727-7531    |    info@alternativelandscapingltd.com             Patricia Ave.
                                                                                                Alternative Landscaping
                                                                                                Alternative Landscaping
                                www.alternativelandscapingltd.com]]></page></pages></Search>